Hey Vsauce!
Michael here.
And here.
Michael here!
hey vsauce!
what is here?
…. what is there?
what is there?
What REALLY exists?
Do waves exist or are there just things that
are wavy?
When does a piece of food I’ve eaten stop
being food and become me?
Do chairs exist?
Ontology is the philosophy of existence.
And chairs are what philosophers call ORDINARY
OBJECTS.
Ordinary objects are the plain old common
sense things we deal with every day: spoons,
buckets, rocks, stuff like that.
Their existence is as obvious as possible
but the more we try to sus out where they
are, the more sus they become.
First of all, sure, this could all be a dream.
Maybe we’ve all been hallucinating chairs
all these years.
Or this could part of the simulated reality
pumped into our brains while our bodies are
harvested for energy.
But underneath that skepticism there’s a
deeper ONTOLOGICAL question that we need to
answer first.
Regardless of whether this spoon is made of
real atoms or simulated atoms, is it really
possible to be “made of” something?
Take a look at these two things.
As we all know, two minus one is … TWO?!
There ARE two things here:
An origami crane AND a piece of paper.
I’m kidding, of course, there’s really
just one: the crane and the piece of paper
are the same.
But watch this.
Where’d the crane go?
If the paper and the crane were truly identical,
they would share everything in common.
But clearly they don’t: the paper can survive
being unfolded, the crane cannot.
Also, I made the crane, but I didn’t make
the paper.
And the paper was around before the crane.
For two things that are the same, they sure
are different.
This relationship is called CONSTITUTION:
paper constitutes the crane.
It’s a one-to-one relationship, but there’s
another kind of “being made of” going
on here, too.
This paper is made not of ONE other thing,
but of sextillions of things: fundamental
subatomic particles: electrons and quarks,
or strings, or physical and virtual fields.
This many-to-one relationship is called COMPOSITION.
Philosophers call whatever it is that matter
is ultimately composed of SIMPLES: a simple
is a thing that, unlike a piece of paper,
has no parts.
No substructure.
Not even a top or bottom.
It could be the case that there are no simples,
that there’s just a never-ending chain of
smaller and smaller substructure.
Philosophers call such a reality a GUNKY universe.
If structure never ends in the other direction
and everything turns out to be part of something
bigger with no final complete composite, that’s
what’s known as a JUNKY universe.
Point is: believing ordinary objects exist
and are made up of smaller things is quite
common.
It’s called ontological reductionism.
It’s the position that wholes are NOTHING
MORE than their parts.
But our cranes and our paper challenge that notion.
it seems like being MADE OF some things IS different than
just BEING those things.
Let’’s agree on what it means to exist.
Let’s say that for something to exist is
simply for there to be more than zero of it.
Pegasus exists if we mean “are there any
winged horses in works of fiction and mythology?”
And pegasus does not exist if we mean, “are
there any physical, flesh-and-blood winged
horses that evolved on Earth through natural
selection.”
okay, so if we can agree on that, then of course chairs
exist!
There’s this one right here.
I can see it and feel it and taste it.
yea. It’s dry and .. a little bit salty.
Dry and salty are what we call PROPERTIES.
Properties tell us what things are LIKE.
For example, this slice of cheese is FLOPPY.
By noticing and sharing properties, we can
let each other know what to expect from things.
And we all more or less agree on what things
there are.
We give names to stuff and if they catch on,
we put them in dictionaries with the word
“noun” next to them.
But are all of these nouns an inventory of
the universe … or an inventory of things
we MADE?
Let me put it this way: do islands exist?
Well, it’s in the dictionary and a quick
look around confirms that there are more than
zero islands, so yes.
Islands exist.
But what about incars?
An incar is a car that is IN a garage.
As a car leaves a garage, an incar diminishes
at the threshold until it collapses into nonexistence.
Later, an extremely similar incar may emerge
at the same threshold when the car returns.
Are there any cars in garages right now?
If so, then incars exist.
You might be thinking, “that’s not a thing.
you just made that up.
And it’s silly: “being in a garage”
is just a property that a car can have.
Stop trying to make incars a thing.”
Ok, first of all, I didn’t make it up, Eli
Hirsch did.
And second of all, if you think incars aren’t
things, wait till you hear about islands.
An incar might just be a relation between
a car and a garage but an island is just a
relation between land and some water.
Now, “island” might be a more useful concept
than “incar,” but does that make islands
OBJECTIVELY more real than incars?
And what about trogs?
A trog is an object whose parts are a tree
and whatever dog is nearest.
Here’s a picture of one.
Do you see the trog? this is its tree part
and this is its dog part.
You might be thinking, come on, how can THAT
be a thing?
The tree and the dog aren’t even connected!
well so what?
These two pieces of fabric aren’t connected
and yet they’re a thing called a bikini.
Now sure, if we cut down this tree and burn
it for warmth, we wouldn’t feel the need
to apologize to what’s left of the trog
for destroying its tree part.
But maybe we should?
What if some extraterrestrials showed up and
said they thought dogs and trees composed
trogs — would they be wrong?
Could we convince the otherwise?
Ontological realists believe that we could.
That there really is a mind-independent answer
to the question, “what is there?”
People like Theodore Sider believe that the
universe has “joints” and we can cut up reality
up into objective, real things by finding
them.
Ontological anti-realists disagree.
Their position is that what we think there
is is just one way to cut up reality.
It’s a good one for us and our needs, but
it’s not objectively more true than any
other.
So who’s right?
Hmm… well if these blocks compose
a tower … what do they compose now?
Just because we don’t have a name for .. this..
doesn’t necessary mean that I haven’t
accidentally built something. Does it?
When DO two or more things compose something
else?
Peter Van Inwagen calls this the special composition
question.
In MATERIAL BEINGS he considers possible answers:
maybe things compose something only when they’re
in contact.
That’s a good thought, but it doesn’t
explain how a BIKINI can be a thing.
Or why two books are still just two books
when one is stacked on top of the other.
you know,
Maybe a certain degree of FIXATION is required.
Or a ‘melding’ … if a surgeon sewed
us together and the skin healed with no seam
and we shared the same blood supply … you
know, even then it would seem wrong to say
that we’d become some new kind of animal.
There’d still just me and you.
But like, stuck together.
The philosophy of parts and wholes is called
mereology and
Mereological Universalism is the belief that
there’s an answer to the special composition question
and the answer is this: any assortment of stuff, no matter
how strange or scattered across time and space
composes a thing.
some pages compose these books but I don't just have two books here. Oh no, there's also a third thing
let's call it a "took" because it's parts are Two Books.
There is also something composed of my left ear,
the northern third of every brown trout in
England, and the Eiffel tower.
Just because it has no name and no one’s
ever talked about it before just shows a lack
of intrest on our parts.
To a universalist, eliminating some composites
but not others is just too arbitrary.
We may as well accept them all.
Eliminativism is any belief that accepts some
composites, but eliminates others.
Peter Van Inwagen, for example, believes that
there are no ordinary objects, no chairs or
shirts or shoes.
Right here there are just some simples — atoms or whatever
— arragned show-wise.
There isn;t something else here called a shoe.
But he thinks that because people believe
they themselves exist, and he can’t see
how something could believe it existed without
existing in the first place to even think
that, there must be people.
He goes further, though, to argue that ALL
living thigns exist.
While admiting he doesn’t have any “knock-down”
agruments in their favor, he mentions that
because simples that are part of a living
organism maintain the organism —
— while shedding some members and gaining
others, all while remaining individuated from
other organisms, unlike, say, waves of water
at the moment of collision, clearly, simples
in the act of a life must compose something.
That position is ORAGANICISM.
It’s been called the belief that people
exist, but that none of them wear clothes.
Mereological Nihilism is less generous.
It’s the belief that there aren’t any
trogs or incars OR dogs or trees.
Because nothing ever composes.
The nihilist doesn’t believe that there
is NOTHING here.
There are lots of simples, but that’s it.
That might sound puzzling: how can a bunch
of fundamental particles, arranged into atoms
and molecules that are arranged like this
NOT be a chair?
That’s JUST IS what a chair is!
Good question.
Let’s call that deflationism: the belief
that this is all silly and that all of these
positions are talking past each other: they
all agree on what reality contains: they all
believe that there are simples here and that
those simples are arranged in a chair shape.
Since that’s just what a chair IS, they
all believe in chairs.
Those who say they don’t just being weird
and contrarian.
Deflationism has many supporters.
And it truly is the heart of our issue today.
But to address it, we should first see why
it would be nice if all of these parts did not
form a chair.
Let’s begin with over-determination: If
chairs really do exist, shouldn’t they be
able to interact with us?
The thing is, though, everything this alleged
chair can do can be described by referencing the behavior of
simples here and any other simples
that come along.
An account of the activities of every ATOM in this room, leaves nothing
for the chair to explain.
Composites are causally redundant.
Believing in chairs is like believing that,
while yes, the burning gas from my stove completely
describes why the water in a pot boils, there’s
ALSO a magical invisible substance called
boil-o that comes out of my stove that does
the same thing as the flame at the same time
and if there was no boil-o the flame would
warm the water just the same, but there is
boil-o.
Chairs are no more real than boil-o.
Composites over-determine what happens in the world.
They also lead to over-COUNTING.
For more on that, let’s say hello to this
video’s sponsor.
Hi.
I’m Michael Stevens.
You may know me from such films as ”Lady
Gaga - Judas PARODY!
Key Of Awesome #42” and The Emoji Movie.
But today, I’m here to talk to you about
the Curiosity Box.
This season, subscribers will be receiving
many things, including a shirt celebrating
the Sherman line, a kit to find out what bacteria
is growing on you, a puzzle that celebrates
the average color of neptune and yes, uranus,
and the first ever at-home demonstration of
impossible colors.
And right now, if you subscribe with code BOGO, we’ll
also send you our entire summer box  completely free.
just pay shipping
How many THINGS will you be receiving for
one ridiculously low price?
You might think 15: 8 things plus 7 things.
But don’t forget that you’re ALSO
getting this entire collection and THIS entire collection.
That’s 17 things!
ORder now.
That’s a good deal, but the ontology seemed
wrong.
If I count some parts, I shouldn’t also
count the whole they compose.
But if you believe in composite objects you
MUST do this, right?
After all, the composite exists.
So if this chair contains, say, 100 sextillion
atoms, then there are actually AT LEAST 100
sextillion and one things here: all of these
atoms and also a chair.
That seems wrong.. but wait, there’s more.
If I take a knife and scrape off a tiny part
of this chair … is it still a chair?
I think most of us would say yes.
It would still be a chair even if I removed
a tiny bit again.
And again.
A series of tiny innocuous removals is called
a SORITES SEQUENCE.
The trouble they cause is that while it seems
we must accept that each individual step doesn’t
annihilate the chair, clearly, ENOUGH minute
removals WILL eventually leave us with no
chair.
Nothing at all, in fact.
But how can that be?
How subtracting zero over and over again EVER
give a different result?
Clearly, there must be a point at which a
tiny change DOES make a difference.
Different people might give different answers
as to where that line is — but, you know,
we could just stipulate the boundaries: we
could define “chair” in some extreamly
precise way.
If we did that, if we defined the shape, function,
history, and use that makes something a chair
so precisely that the even the smallest deviation
would make or break its status as a chair
… how could we know if it’d done it right?
If we called up God and said, “hey dude,
watch this, see this chair?
Okay, now we’re going to remove a single
atom from it.
Ta da!
It’s no longer a chair is it?”
Would God would be like, “pwha!
Correct! you guys nailed it.
That is exactly right.
It was a chair before and now, in my infinite
wisdom, I can confirm that that single atom
was what made the difference.”
Unless there’s some explanation for why
a boundary should be drawn in a precise way
instead of some other way, our stipulations
are just arbitrary.
Ordinary objects may be unredeemably vague.
But being vague may actually be a feature of ordinary
objects.
For example, how many people is a crowd?
10 people standing together in a huge empty
park might be more of a group, but 10 people
standing further apart in a tiny waiting room
will feel way more CROWDED.
The fact that our terms depend on context,
that they’re PLASTIC, make it seem less
and less like they’re describing THINGS
and more and more like they’re pragmatic.
That rather than telling what there is, they
tell us to expect.
Peter Unger has pointed out that there’s
at least one kind of thing that CAN survive
a sorities sequence without paradox: stuff.
If you innocuously remove pieces from something
that is just “some stuff” you will still
have some stuff after each step until you
reach a clear and unambiguous boundary: when
the last piece is removed, there will no longer
be any stuff.
This might show that there ARE composite objects:
stuff.
As soon as we pretend that some stuff is a
THING, though, vagueness sets in.
Suddenly we’re talking about a thing that
can lose parts but also can’t lose parts
and unless contradictions can exist, words
like “chair” don’t really refer to any
thing in the universe.
Sorites seqeunces lead to other problems,
too.
Like: the PROBLEM OF THE MANY.
If removing a tiny number of atoms from this chair still
leaves me with a chair, how many chairs are
here?
I mean, there’s this one.
And then there’s this one, which is really similar to the first but doesn't have these atoms on top of
it.
I don’t even have to remove atoms for this
to be a problem.
All I have to do try to define which atoms
here are part of the chair and which aren’t.
At the atomic level, there isn’t a definite
boundary.
Near the edge, it will hard to tell whether
a particular molecule is part of the moisture
in the chair or part of the ambient humidity.
Instead of there being a single chair here,
it seems like REALLY there are billions and
billions of candidates for the chair.
Which one is the chair?
But now, suppose that instead of removing
pieces like in a sorities sequences or choosing
pieces like in the problem of the many, we
instead discard pieces and replace them with
new, similar pieces.
This is the set up to the famous SHIP OF THESEUS
paradox.
Suppose I buy a boat and name it THESEUS.
Over time, parts of the boat wear out and
I replace them with brand new parts.
After, say 10 years, I might realize that
not a single part of my boat was part of the
boat on the day I bought it.
Do I now own a different boat?
Have I owned TWO boats?
But now suppose the someone has been following
me all these years and has been picking up
each old part I throw out and storing them
in a warehouse.
After I replaced all the original parts they
take them and join them back the way
they way there were 10 years ago.
Which boat is THESEUS?
Both?
If we conclude that ordinary objects don’t
exist, the problems of sorites, the many,
theseus, over-determination, and over-counting
all evaporate.
If there are only simples and they never compose
anything, then which one is the ship of theseus
is easy to answer: neither!
Neither are the boat and nothing ever was
the boat.
All that happened was that some simples got
moved around.
The simples the scavenger has are the simples
I possessed when I bought the boat, but there’s
no mystery of persistence: removing or exchanging
a piece of stuff never left me with the same
stuff.
There’s no mystery as to which of the billions
of chair candidates here is THE chair and
the removal of no specific atoms will ever
stop it from being a chair because it there
is no chair here and there never was.
There are only simples arranged chair-wise.
The illusion that there ARE composites
that can survive changes in parts is an artifact
of our minds.
It’s a helpful one that allows us to track
certain properties and ignore others, but
when taken seriously, it obviously isn’t
really how the universe works.
And that’s okay.
We shouldn’t be embarassed when we talk
about boats or chairs.
Our words for ordinary objects really do refer
to actual phenomena and therefore are more
correct than believing that, say, the sun
turned into a black hole yesterday.
Unlike the false statement that chairs exist,
there is NO evidence saying the sun turned
into a black hole yesterday could even be
INCORRECTLY describing.
Because of this, Trenton Merricks calls the
belief in ordinary objects false but, “nearly
as good as true.”
This is all silly, though, right?
Of course there are chairs.
If you believe that there are some simples
arranged chair-wise, then you admit that there’s
a chair!
Because that’s just what a chair IS.
It’s not some additional THING over-and-above
these simples: it just IS them.
Each is still an atom or electron or whatever,
but TOGETHER they are a chair.
Not so fast there, chair-lover.
What do you MEAN “a chair IS simples arranged
chair-wise?”
the phrase “simples arranged chair-wise”
just picks out these simples.
There’s nothing else for that phrase to
refer to.
There aren’t all of these simples and then
ALSO some OTHER simples that are the simples
arranged chair-wise.
So do you mean that “chair” is a disguised
plural?
That it refers to lots of things like the
phrase “these books”?
Because “these books” only commits us
to the existence of this book and this book
but not an additional single
object that’s called a “these books.”
Likewise, if “chair” just means this simple
and this simple and this simple, then it points
to a whole bunch of things and not one of
them is a chair.
Sure, “chairs” exist if by chair we mean
a word for all these simples.
But if by chair we mean an actual object in
the universe, there just aren’t any, my
friend.
Except… maybe there is no chair over-and-above
the simples, but instead something happens
when an assortment of simples are arranged
into a chair-shape.
Each member continues to be a single atom
or whatever, but COLLECTIVELY they all simultaneously
BECOME one thing: a chair.
Okay, so then either there’s no chair here,
just simples; or somehow a miraculous contradiction
has appeared: many things and ALSO one thing
that, despite both clearly differing in that
respect, are still identical!
It looks like chairs can’t be identical
to the parts they’re supposedly composed
of..
but chairs also can’t be DIFFERENT from
their composite parts because there’s nothing
else there and, after counting and accounting
for their parts, there’s nothing left for
the existence of a chair to cause or explain.
To rescue chairs from non-existence, we need
to find a way to show that a chair is independent
of its atoms — and therefore distinct from
them — but not SO distinct that it’s impossibly
over-and-above them.
We need to find a way to make chairs ONTOLOGICALLY
INNOCENT.
To have our cake and not have it, too.
Amie Thomasson does this in a very clever
way.
She points out that if I ask you, “hey,
is there anything in the fridge?” and you
open it, see that’s it empty, and say, “there’s
nothing in here” it would be weird if I
came over, looked inside, found a single eyelash
in the corner and said, “ummm EXCUSE me?
What is this?! you said there was no THING
in the fridge, but there was an eyelash and,
gosh dangit, the whole things is actually
FULL!
Of AIR.”
That would be weird because when I asked if
there was anything in the fridge, it was implied
that I meant anything TO EAT.
By arguing that the empty fridge is not REALLY
empty, I was using the word “thing” in
what Thomasson calls a “neutral sense.”
I used it to mean any and all entities that
could possibly be described.
But you took me to be using “thing” in
what she calls a “sortal” sense.
A sortal is a term that tells us what a thing
is in way that allows us to count how many
there are AND know when there is or isn’t
one.
“Water” is not a sortal.
If I told you there was water in my basement
and you asked, “how many waters?”
I’d have to use a sortal to answer you.
For example, “gallons of water.”
Thomasson argues that the neutral use of “thing”
is meaningless when used to ask questions.
For example, if I used thing in a neutral sense and asked how many orange things are in this video
you would have no idea how I wanted you to carve it all up
thus, there would be no would be no single correct answer.
You might say, "uh, one orange thing? Your shirt?"
But then I could say, “what, no there's my left sleeve, my right sleeve, the inside of the shirt, the outside of the shirt. Come on, there's way more than one."
Unless we use a sortal net, any search for
what things there are will end in confusion.
Not because there are no things, but because
it hasn’t been made clear what conditions
to apply when searching.
For Thomasson, this means that what we find
depends on what APPLICATION CONDITIONS we
use.
If I ask if there’s anything here that the
condition “smaller than a molecule” applies
to, you could note each such thing and give
me an inventory.
“Chair” would not be on the list.
But if I asked you if there were any medium-sized
rigid-acording-to human strength things here,
“chair” would probably go on your list,
and no single atom would.
If an application condition is satisfied in
the wrold, then the thing is descrbes exists.
So CHAIRS do exist.
If the application conditions for one thing
are also sufficient for something else, then,
if we find the first thing, we have found
the other because it’s existence is entailed
ANLYTICALLY by the existence of the first
thing — that is, by meaning and logic alone.
For example, if I say that I live in a house
you can conclude — without looking! — that
I live in a building.
There’s no paradox here, I don’t live
in a house AND a building — two distinct
things that defy the laws of physics by being
co-located.
Instead, the conditions that apply to a house
are also sufficient for building.
So a single chair is not impossibly identical
to some collection of many.
Nor is it somehow over-and-above its parts.
Instead, atoms arranged chair-wise merely
logically ENTAIL a chair.
The entailment connects things differentiated
by distinct application conditions.
When we ask which one is the ship of theseus,
a puzzle erupts because we’re being too
neutral.
We need to say what we mean by “ship of
theseus”: if we mean the original parts,
then this is it.
Do we mean the thing registered to me by the
boat authorities?
well then it’s this one.
“But which is the REAL one” is an incomplete
pseudoquestion.
When it come to sorites sequences, I think
we need to just stipulate where the boundary
is.
I don’t think there’s an objective answer
provided by the universe or God as to exactly
what is and isn’t a chair, but that doesn’t
HAVE to mean that there aren’t any chairs,
it can just mean that every single collection
of simples is it’s own unique object independent
of our minds and that we get to decide which
we will call chairs.
Vagueness comes from our minds and our language
but there are no vague objects in the universe.
We don’t have to believe that our reality
is simulated, but I do think we have to believe
that it’s stipulated: it is a reality that
contains not what intelligent machines have
decided to give us, but what we have decided
we have.
There’s no fact of the matter as to whether
calling this a star is the TRUE way to carve
up this stuff.
It’s a pretty useful way to do it, and helpful
for at least human purposes, but “STAR”
is a thing WE imposed on the world.
As Michael Jubien puts it, “there are no
things, but as a consequence there are as
many things as we like.”
As for the problem of the many, we can simply
just admit that there really are billions
of slightly different chairs here.
Some include a few boundary atoms that others
don’t, but since they all act and react
pretty much in unison, in our daily lives
it doesn’t matter which exact material collection
we mean when we say “this chair.”
However, let’s go back to our cranes.
When we talked about holes we said that holes
might be ONTOLOGICALLY parasitic.
That their existence seems to require the
existence of something ELSE: something that
can HOST the hole.
Perhaps this crane is holey, too.
Not a physical thing in its own right, but
a disturbance IN some paper.
There is no material crane here, there is
only some paper that is arranged crane-wise.
But once we start entertaining that notion,
we realize that nearly EVERYTHING we see and feel
all ordinary obejcts and even ourselves are ontological parasites
Michael Jubien calls our tendency to think
that what is true of a “chair” is true
of the material that is chairing OBJECT FIXATION
or PROPERTY REPRESSION.
Object fixation is useful and “nearly as
good as true” but when paradxoes loom, we
should remember that while chairs exist, they
aren’t made out of matter and can’t be
touched or or felt or tasted.
All I can do is taste some stuff while it
chairs.
If it looks like a duck, swims like a duck,
and quacks like a duck, then it’s not a
duck, but it is arranged duck-wise.
I think that the only concrete physical things
in our universe are simples — or, since
our universe could be gunky — the material
world only contains stuff.
And yes, this stuff is chair-ing, but the
road paved by the idea that that makes this
stuff A chair leads to paradox.
To see how we could have made that mistake,
let’s remember the famous Clintonian dictum
that often “it depends on what the meaning
of “is” is”
There’s the “is” of predication, which
tells us what some thing is like, as in, this
cheese IS floppy.
And then there’s the “is” of identity
which tells us what is the same as what for
example, 2+2 IS 4.
To believe that chairs are made of matter
— to be believe that YOU are made of matter
— is to confuse these two ISes.
When a collection of properties are extremely
thorough in telling us what to expect from
some stuff, we tend to just go ahead and NOUN
them: collapse them into a single word and
believe it doesn’t just describe some stuff,
but REFERS to it.
I think we have an intuitive sense of the
thoroughness of properties and this can be
seen in how we order our adjectives.
“Big” can mean many things.
A big diamond and big house are very different
in size.
“Blue” tells me a bit more about what
to expect, but CHEESEBURGER, oooh that’s
specific.
So specific, in fact, that we call it a noun.
This increasing thoroughness may be partly
responsible for the fact that “big blue
cheseburger” sounds fine, but blue big cheeseburger”
sounds kind of weird.
When we embrace the idea that cheseburgers
are not physical objects, but instead, exist
as an abstract set of properties like juicy,
warm, soft, and so on, the specter of ontolgical
paradox dissipates.
You and I are not physical objects either.
“Michael-ing” is a bunch of different
properties and most of them are very vague.
They include things like, “knowing who Kevin
is, being more or less a certain height, having
a roughly continous relationship with the
stuff that Mcihaeled yesterday and that that’s
Michael-ing today” and so.
Some of what it means to Michael does concern
composition, like, the fact that I will still
exist even if I shave off the stuff I call
my beard.
If I shaved off my beard, there would still
be some stuff Michael-ing, but it would be
different stuff than before.
We’re able to lose parts and change and
grow because we aren’t made of matter, we’re
hosted by matter.
There’s no thing that is you and no thing
that is ME.
As Alan Watts would say, the universe doesn’t
contain people, the universe PEOPLES.
Chairs and tables and rocks and buckets and people are not made of atoms, they are preformed by atoms.
We are disturbances in stuff and none of it
is us.
This stuff right here is not me. It's just me-ing.
We are not the universe seeing itself, we
ARE the seeing.
I am not a thing that dies and becomes scattered,
I AM death and I AM the scattering
And
as always, thanks for watching.
as always, links to read and learn more can be found in the description down below
there's also a link down there to subscribe to the curiosity box
if you subscribe now, this will be your first box
but remember, use code BOGO and we'll you are summer box as well completely free
give your brain a treat.
support vsauce, support Alzheimer's research, and creators everywhere
by joining today
I'll see you there. And as always, thanks for watching.