Deep in tropical jungles lie floating kingdoms
ruled by beautiful and deadly masters.
They're sort of the high elves of the ant kingdoms,
talented architects that create castles
and city-states.
But they are also fierce,
and, expansionist warriors and
their kingdoms are ensnared in a never-ending
war for survival -
Oecophylla Weaver ants.
Oecophylla Weavers walk on long legs,
have slender bodies and large eyes which make them
look pretty cute, although their strong mandibles
and the ability to shoot acids also
make them pretty good at killing, but
more on that later.
Their colonies usually have two to three worker classes
that vary dramatically in size - Majors,
Minors, and sometimes, even tiny
Minim workers. Depending on location and
species, they vary in colour from dark brown
to emerald green.
Other than their fancy looks, what makes
weavers special is that they're in the kingdom building
business. They like to build at pretty much all
heights, starting in shrubs a few centimetres above the
ground, and up to ten metres in the three canopy.
But they're not satisfied with ruling just one plant.
Weavers will look for twigs or lianas
that bridge the gap to other tress, and expand
to every plant they can reach.
This way, colonies spread upwards and sideways
through the treetops.
The largest Weaver ant kingdoms we know of, occupy
up to 1600 square metres,
around four basketball courts.
A lot of ground to cover for tiny ants,
and impossibly hard to control, so
Weaver ants construct dozens of
nests, scattered all over their territory.
Outposts to defend the kingdom, tubes or
balls made from leaves and ghostly silk sheets.
These masterpieces of high-end architecture
are created by the Weaver Majors, the larger worker
ants, which are responsible for the more dangerous jobs
like fighting, foraging and
nest construction.
To start a new nest, a Major tries to bend
different leaves in her surroundings into a tube.
If one of the leaves is flexible enough, more workers will
arrive to help.
Chains of workers pull the leaf edges together,
or reach across gaps and grab distant leaves to
add them to the construction.
While the bending and pulling is going on, other workers carry
larvae from the closest nest to the construction site.
Usually, ant larvae spin themselves a cocoon
to protect themselves, but the Weaver ant
larvae give all of their silk to the colony
as building material. So when the workers tap
the larvae's heads on the leaf, they release their sticky thread
like tiny, cute glue guns. This way,
the workers sew the bent leaf onto itself,
so it won't unfold anymore.
This creates a central chamber that's used
as the basis for up to three hundred more leaves that
are wound around it.
Together, they form little pockets, and act as
additional rooms for the new outpost. To make it even
more cozy, Minor workers use the larvae
to weave additional floors and chambers.
Nests are usually constructed as barracks on
the territory's borders, or as storage for brood and
food supplies. This way, the ants don't need
to cross vast distances to the headquarters,
but have soldiers close to any potential point of conflict-
apart from one special nest in the middle of the network,
which is reserved for the queen, and her guards.
Here, she produces hundreds of eggs a day, which get transferred
to suitable nests with brood chambers.
So a colony is a network of little
castles and moats, connected by
suspension bridges made from leaves, lianas,
and twigs.
An established colony easily has half a million
individuals that need to be fed.
Fortunately, Weaver ants evolve to have very
close and beneficial relationships with their hosts,
shrubs, and trees.
The tree gives the ants a home and access to
sweet sap to drink. But maybe even more importantly,
it allows them to cultivate cattle, like aphids,
or caterpillars that produce honey dew for them.
This would usually hurt a tree,
but these insects belong to a small group of
V.I.Ps - only a few selected neighbours
and the ants' cattle are allowed on the fruit tree.
Many other insects, and even larger herbivores
are scared off. Or, even killed,
and eaten. So, in most cases,
the tree only has to tolerate acceptable levels of
damage, while being protected from more dangerous pests.
The Weaver ant kingdom could be an ant paradise -
if there wasn't competition.
Mostly from other kingdoms,
just like medieval humans,
every queen seeks to conquer others, and make their land
their own.
Controlling fertile land is the key
to survive in the jungle.
And, if a kingdom loses to much of it, it shrinks and
is overrun, or starves to death.
So, expanding and defending their borders, is
critical to keep the colony alive.
When a kingdom invades another, it first gathers an
army of a few thousand Majors, who make their
way towards the opposing colony. The goal
is to steal a bit of territory, and take it over.
Defending Weaver patrols quickly spot the invaders,
and immediately release an alarm pheromone.
Some rush to the front to defend, while others
rush to the closest outpost for help, marking their route
with pheromones.
Whenever they meet other sisters, they jerk
their bodies as if in a fight, to signal them to follow the pheromone
trail to the front-line.
At the site of battle, Majors from both parties raise their
bodies, circle each other with mandibles wide open,
and try to seize their opponents. If
an ant gets a hold of her opponent, the victim is pulled into
a group of allied Majors, and pinned down.
The ants then rip the victim apart, clipping off
antennae and legs, and slicing open their
abdomens.
To slow down the advance of the attackers, the
defending Majors squirt formic acid over the battlefield
to chemically burn their targets.
This is soon answered in the same way by the attackers.
In the chaotic battle, both parties lose
countless fighters on the increasingly acidic battlefield.
After a few minutes, the backup from the outposts arrive,
and the time window for a successful attack, slowly
closes. This is when the battle turns.
The defenders slowly push back the attack party.
In the end, the attackers can't keep up, and have to
retreat.
For both parties, it was a costly battle.
Thousands of corpses lie piled up on the ground under the
battlefield, and many ants are severely injured.
The defending colony's nests and brood,
are safe though.
The attackers' attempt to steal new, valuable territory
has failed, for today. They'll try
again soon.
But the kingdom will be ready.
For the high ants of the floating kingdoms, war is
nothing special - it's just a fact of life,
because as we know, empires never ever
have enough, and the Weaver ants are ready
to fight.