Three reasons why we continue to use nuclear energy :)
First, nuclear energy saves lives.
In a study conducted by NASA in 2013, nuclear energy
prevented about 1.8 million deaths.
Even including deaths from nuclear accidents at Chernobyl and Fukushima,
nuclear energy has the lowest ranking of deaths per unit of production.
Although nuclear waste is very dangerous, it is usually stored somewhere.
However, by-products of fossil fuels are released into the air.
We breathe every day.
So, by reducing the use of fossil fuels, countless types of cancer
or lung disease and accidents in coal mines can be avoided.
The first seems more sensible if there is a choice between storing the high-risk material in a deep pit and
releasing it into the air, very very very very very dangerous
.
Nuclear energy still feels more dangerous.
One fatal event is imprinted in our memory, while coal and oil quietly kill.
This is similar to the death rate of flight accidents and traffic accidents.
Even the best-case scenario
would take 40 years to convert to 100% renewable energy.
So, while we use fossil fuels, nuclear energy
saves more lives than it destroys.
Second, nuclear energy reduces carbon dioxide emissions.
Nuclear energy is arguably less harmful to the environment.
In terms of climate change rather than fossil fuels, our main energy source.
Since 1976, 64 billion tonnes of greenhouse gases have
not been released into the air thanks to nuclear energy.
In addition, it will be 80-240 billion tonnes by the middle of the 21st century
.
Human energy consumption is steadily increasing.
According to the US government's forecast, China alone
would build one 600MW coal plant every 10 days for 10 years.
China already burns 4 billion tonnes of coal annually.
Coal is cheap, relatively abundant and easy to obtain.
So, it is unlikely that humans will soon stop using it.
Nuclear energy is the only way to combat climate change.
And it prevents the catastrophic global warming caused by mankind.
Compared to other things we can do, nuclear energy is relatively clean.
So, if you have a good idea of not using nuclear energy in the long run, it wi
l be a good solution for 100 years or so.
compared to other energy sources.
Third: New technologies
Perhaps new technologies will solve the problems of nuclear waste and hazardous nuclear power plants.
Most of the reactor technologies used so far are outdated.
This is because technological innovation related to nuclear technology stopped in the 1970s.
An example is the thorium reactor, which
solves all the problems at once.
Thorium is abundant and difficult to use as a nuclear weapon.
It is 100 times less wasteful than current nuclear reactors.
Waste material is only dangerous for a few hundred years,
whereas nuclear reactors are only dangerous for about 2000 years.
One ton of thorium is estimated to provide the same energy as 200 tonnes of uranium or 3.5 million tonnes of coal
.
Since it's unclear whether alternative nuclear technology will deliver on its promise, can't
we do more research
to advance our chances of solving humanity's current problems?
It's not an easy challenge, but that doesn't stop us.
So, should we use nuclear energy?
There are dangers in the great passions of man.
And we must make well-thought-out decisions rather than relying on intuition.
If you would like to hear the other side's argument or
see a brief introduction to nuclear energy, click here!!!!!!