Until 1918.
until the Bolsheviks reformed Russian spelling, they always put a hard sign at the end of words after consonants.
Why?
Some people think that since there is a soft sign and it denotes softness, the hard sign denotes hardness.
Probably the Komsomol activist from Platonov's novel "Kotlovan" would agree with this opinion:
"Of the words denoted by the line slogans and the hard sign is more useful to us than the soft sign. The soft sign is to be abolished, while the hard sign is inevitable for us:
it makes rigidity and clarity of wording."
But. is this really the case?
The short answer is:
Of course not.
In the Old Russian language until the twelfth century there was a sound law: all syllables had to end in a vowel. Well,
those are the rules, there's no getting around it.
For example, the syllables in modern Japanese are arranged in a similar way:
At the same time, Old Russian also had two vowel sounds that we don't have now.
They were written with these letters. And attention: they're only now called hard and soft signs, but before that they were called
"yer" and "yer" respectively; also in science they are called
reduced.
The letter "yer" denoted a very short sound [ɪ],
The letter "yer" was just as short [ɤ].
tt'm zl'l'pis
that evil dog.
But in the XII century a phonetic change took place: according to a certain scheme, about the nuances of which we will keep silent here for brevity, all
reduced into strong and weak.
The strong ones turned into full vowels:
The "ъ" became "o" and the "ъ" became "e".
The weak ones simply disappeared or, as they say, fell. So all that happened is called the fall of the reduplicated.
You should agree that now the language has become much more similar to the modern language both in sound and in writing.
Pronunciation from the 13th century:
that zol dog
sie reaper reaps flax da rye with oats
With time we stopped writing yerows in the middle of words, but they remained at the end of words, and this habit held on in our spelling until
1918, until the Bolshevik boot trampled the dilapidated yer.
Of course, we can assume that they continued to write the final yer by tradition, but that is a bad explanation - there is a better one.
The point is that in the Middle Ages they wrote without spaces. More or less often blanks appeared in Russian books and manuscripts only in
XVII century.
Finally the gap became firmly established only in the eighteenth century, when typography was converted to the Western manner.
In continuous writing the yer was a reliable point of reference between words. When you see it, you know immediately that a new word
a new word begins. This made reading a bit easier.
Especially shrewd onlookers might ask: why wasn't it easier to go straight to the space?
The thing is that in ancient times you should have taken care of saving writing material first of all, but not about the convenience of reading,
And spaces take up too much space.
Also, in antiquity word division was not necessary for the same reason that it is today. Now we have a different reading psychology:
We almost always read to ourselves without saying the words. In this way of reading, it's very important for the eye to distinguish
because we perceive them as a whole, almost like a hieroglyph. "This is proved by that wonderful experiment..,
where they swapped the different letters of words, except for the final and initial letters.
It is only the overall appearance of the word and the context that allows us to understand everything correctly, and to read it quickly.
We don't focus on every single letter, we only do that when stuttering or when reading
unfamiliar words. As you can see, all of this would be impossible when reading text without spaces.
Let us also not forget that people used to have many times less
reading practice, and so they were generally less literate; there was also variability in spelling, and so many read just syllable by syllable.
When you read syllables, you don't really need spaces.
But you should be very clear about where the syllable ends, so that you could make fewer mistakes in syllabication.
And the ending yer just allowed not to mix the last syllable of one word that ends in a consonant, with the first syllable of the next word.
And there it is, the addition of the argument against the space. Remember, we need to save writing material; now reason:
we only need to write yer after words that end in a consonant, and we need to write the space after all words -
it takes a lot of space, and we don't need it for easy reading.
Okay, well, now we understand why yer was necessary in the old Russian script.
But why wasn't it removed in the 18th century, say, under Peter?
a lot of letters were taken out of the alphabet, and the language was changing rapidly;
people read like the Western educated public: no longer aloud, but to themselves, why didn't they take out the yer?
It must be said that the first cases where the final yer was dropped appeared long before the eighteenth century, namely right after the fall of the reduplicating
in the 12th century. And it occurred, of course, not in books, not in any official documents, but in everyday writing, namely in birch bark writings.
So, for example, in the tenth birch-bark parchment from Staraya Russa in most positions the final yer is not written. For example:
"...in horodishchanykh...", "...pololosh of noblemen
pacil ...".
Even before the end of the 18th century manuscripts often contained such a way of abbreviating a word as a final carried consonant.
As a general rule, yer was not used after expletive consonants, and even if we took it as a sign of the end of a word, it would be
The consonant rises above the rest of the letters, and shows expressly where the word ends.
The first books without a consonantal eir were printed at the end of the 13th century.
For instance, in several books of academic notices
In 1781 a whole section of the latest works of various academies was printed for the sake of experiment without the eeir.
In the nineteenth century there were already many different un-erased editions and, remarkably, mostly
opposition to the regime.
In 1904 the Ministry of Internal Affairs even issued a special circular banning the printing of books without yer.
But there was no mass rejection of the ultimate yer, even in personal documents. One would think, why not write otherwise: it would be easier,
it would be quicker, but no. The fact is that the interests of the reader must always be
above the interests of the writer, because one writes alone, and
reads a lot. And people who have now read a lot of the old spelling,
have noticed that when there's an er, it's easier to read, a little bit even faster, because
If in modern spelling we have only one symbol that marks the boundary of a word, it's a space;
then in the old orthography we often had a sequence of characters, i.e., er + space.
That is why there are generally fewer spaces in pre-revolutionary fonts than in modern ones. Also, the benefit of the final eer is clearly visible when reading
It is also very useful in the reading of the handwritten texts because the width of the space is different there.
There is another explanation of why it took so long to leave the trailing edge. I personally do not find it convincing, but it sounds interesting. It was quoted in his article
1918, the artist Boris Nikolaevich Nikolayev. Let's take a look at it:
there is a letter that seems to look against the direction of reading - from right to left;
there are standing letters; and there are those that look from left to right.
And reading a text where most of the letters look from left to right - in the reading direction,
is the easiest. Compare, there are three lines: in the first, most of the letters look against the direction of reading; in the second, most of the letters
standing, looking nowhere; and in the third, most of the letters look in the reading direction.
In Russian texts, in total, there are far fewer letters that look in the reading direction than in Latin texts
European languages. That's why Cyrillic is, in some ways, slightly more difficult to see than Latin.
And what happens is: the yer looks in the reading direction;
because it is at the end of the word, it gives direction to the whole word, and so it is kind of easier for our eye to read.
This function of the yer is very well seen in eighteenth-century books, where it was often written with a capital letter:
in this way it marked the end of the word even more explicitly, and perhaps reading was made a little easier that way.
However, early twentieth-century linguists found all these nuances unimportant.
The reformers, on the other hand, proceeded from the statistics, according to which the final yer was taking up to 3.5 percent
of the text and, by that alone, was an impediment to saving paper.
The idea of eliminating the end yer was discussed all through the 19th century, but only the Bolshevik government
to put this audacious idea into practice.