Until
1918, until the Bolsheviks reformed Russian spelling, a solid sign was always written at the end of words after consonants.
What for?
Some people think that since there is a soft sign and it denotes softness, then the hard one also denoted hardness.
Probably, a Komsomol activist from Platonov’s novel “The Pit” would agree with this opinion:
“Slogans are indicated by a line from words and a hard sign is more useful to us than a soft one.  This soft must be abolished, and hard is inevitable for us:
it makes the wording rigid and clear.
But... is it really so?
Short answer: of
course not.
In the Old Russian language, until the twelfth century, such a sound law operated: all syllables had to end in a vowel.  Well,
such rules, nowhere to go.
For example, a syllable is structured in a similar way in modern Japanese:
At the same time, Old Russian also had two vowel sounds, which we do not have now.
They were written with these letters.  And attention: they are only now called hard and soft signs, and earlier they were called
"er" and "er" respectively;  also in science they are called
reduced.
The letter "er" denoted a very short sound [ɪ], the
letter "er" - the same short [ɤ].
yt zl ps
that evil dog
But in the XII century there was one phonetic change: according to a certain scheme, the nuances of which we will now keep silent for brevity, all the
reduced ones were divided into strong and weak.
The strong ones became full vowels:
"ъ" became "o", and "ь" became "e".
The weak simply disappeared or, as they say, fell.  Therefore, everything that happened is called the fall of the reduced.
Agree, now the language has become much more similar to the modern one both in sound and in writing.
Pronunciation of the XIII century:
that angry dog
reaps flax and rye with oats Over
ime, they stopped writing eps in the middle of words, but they remained at the end of the word, and this habit lingered in our spelling right up to 1918,
until the Bolshevik boot trampled the dilapidated ep  .
Of course, one can assume that the final ep continued to be written according to tradition, but this is a bad explanation - there is a better explanation.
The fact is that in the Middle Ages they wrote without spaces.  More or less often gaps appear in use in Russian books and manuscripts only in the
17th century.
The gap was finally established only in the eighteenth, when the typography was turned to the Western style.
With continuous writing, ep served as a reliable guideline for the boundary between words.  You see it - and you immediately understand that
a new word begins next.  This made it a little easier to read.
Particularly astute viewers here may ask: why then was it not easier to immediately jump to the gap?
The fact is that in ancient times it was necessary first of all to take care of saving writing material, but not about the convenience of reading, while
spaces take up too much space.
Also, in ancient times, the division into words was not necessary for the same thing as it is now.  Right now we have a different psychology of reading:
we almost always read to ourselves, without saying a word.  With this manner of reading, it is very important for the eye to distinguish between
individual words, because we perceive them as a single whole, almost like a hieroglyph: “This is proved by that very wonderful experiment,
where different letters of words were swapped, except for final and initial ones.
Only the general form of the word and the context allow us to understand everything correctly, moreover, to read quickly.
We don't focus on every single letter, we only do this when we stumble or when reading
unfamiliar words.  As you understand, all this would be impossible when reading the text without spaces.
Let's also not forget that earlier people had many times less
reading practice, and therefore, in general, they were less literate;  there was also discord in spelling, and therefore many read simply by syllables.
When reading by syllables, spaces in general are not particularly needed.
But you need to understand very clearly where the syllable ends in order to make fewer mistakes in syllable division.
And the final ep just allowed not to mix the last syllable of one word, which ends in a consonant, with the first syllable of the next word.
And here it is the complement of the argument against the space.  Remember that we need to save writing material;  Now consider:
we need to write ep only after those words that end in a consonant, and a space needs to be written after all words - it
takes up a lot of space, but we don’t need it for readability.
Okay, okay, now we understand why er was needed in Old Russian writing.
But why was it not removed in the 18th century, say, under Peter, because then
many letters were removed from the alphabet;  and in general the language changed rapidly;  and there were gaps everywhere;
people read like a Western educated public: no longer aloud, but to themselves - why didn't they remove the ep?
It must be said that the first cases in which the final er was omitted arose long before the 18th century, namely, immediately after the fall of the reduced
in the 12th century.  And this was, of course, not found in books, not in some official documents, but in everyday writing, namely, in birch bark letters.
So let's say that in the tenth birch bark letter from Staraya Russa, the final ep is not written in most positions.  Well, for example:
"... in the settlements ...", "... the rogue nobles
messed up ...".
Also, even before the end of the 18th century, such a way of shortening a word as a final extended consonant was often found in manuscripts.
As a general rule, ep was not written after extended consonants;  and even if we perceived it as a sign of the end of a word, here it would be
redundant, because the extension consonant already rises above all other letters and already clearly shows where the word ends.
The first books without a final er were printed at the end of the 13th century.
For example, in several books of academic news
in 1781, a whole section of evidence of the latest works of various academies was published for the sake of experiment without era.
In the 19th century, there were already many different editions without eras and, what is remarkable, mostly
oppositional to the regime.
And in 1904, the Ministry of the Interior, even by a special circular, banned the printing of books without era.
But there was no massive rejection of the final era, even in personal documents.  It would seem, well, why not write differently: it would also be easier,
faster;  but no.  The fact is that the interests of the reader should always be
above the interests of the writer, because one person writes, but
a lot of people read.  And people who now read a lot of the old spelling
noticed that when there is ep, it is easier to read, a little even faster, because
if in modern orthography we have only one character that marks the boundary of a word, this is a space;
then in the old orthography we often encountered a sequence of characters, that is, ep + space.
That is why in general there are fewer spaces in pre-revolutionary fonts than in modern ones.  Also, the benefits of the trailing ep are clearly visible when reading
handwritten texts, because there the width of the space is different each time, sometimes it can be barely noticeable at all.
There is another explanation why the trailing ep was left for so long.  I personally do not find it convincing, but it sounds curious.  He was cited in his
1918 article by the artist Boris Nikolaevich Nikolaev.  Let's consider it:
there is a letter that, as it were, looks against the direction of reading - from right to left;
there are standing letters;  and there are those who look from left to right.
And reading the text, where most of the letters look from left to right - in the direction of reading, is the
easiest.  Compare, there are three lines: in the first, most of the letters look against the direction of reading;  in the second, most of the letters are
standing, they do not look anywhere;  and in the third, most of the letters look in the direction of reading
In Russian texts, in total, there are much fewer letters that look in the direction of reading than in texts in Latin
in European languages.  That is why the Cyrillic alphabet is in some respects a little more difficult for visual perception than the Latin alphabet.
And what happens: ep looks in the direction of reading;
because it is at the end of a word, it sets the direction for the whole word, and thus makes it easier for our eye to read.
This function of the er is very clearly visible in the books of the 18th century, where it was often written with a capital letter:
in this way it marked the end of the word even more clearly and, perhaps, reading was a little easier.
However, linguists of the early 20th century found all these nuances insignificant.
On the other hand, the reformers proceeded from statistics, according to which the final ep occupied up to 3.5 percent of the
volume of the text, and this alone prevented paper
saving.  but only the Bolshevik government
succeeded in realizing this daring undertaking.