Hello. Hello, comrades.
To the food block from the navy.
Thank you.
- To the Beastmaster. - Thank you.
- Tamer. - Greetings.
- Hello, sailor. - Lector.
- Hello! - Bosun, Bosun, candy.
Well, come on.
You do look like me.
Oh, shit, look.
Philip Savelyevich,
...how do they know you, these sailors?
Who doesn't know Shuleikin?
- Well, where did you meet them? - In a tropical port at the equator.
Oh, tell me about it.
Believe it or not ,
...believe it or not,
...but it was...
...was...
Ah, finally!
- Hello. - How do you do? - Shuleikin.
- Pleased to meet you. - Pleased to meet you.
Well, you'll soon be back home, Comrade Shuleikin.
You know, I see Odessa in my dreams.
Ah, Odessa-Odessa!
- Take the cargo right on deck. - All right.
- Here are the documents. - Thank you.
- Now let's go to the ship. - All right.
I've been waiting for you, darling.
The call came unexpectedly last night. I wasn't prepared, here and there!
If, so to speak, I had managed. What a joy, eh!
Oh, please tell me, what happened to your escort?
- Malaria. - Ah, malaria!
And tell me, what kind of cargo am I supposed to accompany?
- If it's not a secret, of course. - Tigers. - Ah, tigers!
The name of the company?
What company?! A pair of lions, ten tigers.
Like lions?
- Are you serious? - What's bothering you?
- I'm completely unfamiliar with this business. - Well, you'll get to know me.
The main thing is not to say anything unnecessary, and everything will be fine.
Look, I still want to live.
Well, live your life in good health.
- No, I can't! - You can't what?
You want to sit here until the next ship for another five months?
No, I can't! No, I can't! I just can't!
- Did you find the boy or what?! Take the papers!
No! No and no! Here are your papers.
- Follow me, please! - No, no, no, no! Please sit down!
- Please follow me. - Please sit down.
What do you mean...?
- I am not persuading you. - I forbid them to order you!
I forbid you to persuade me!
Nothing, nothing, nothing.
- Wait! Well?
- Wait! What?
- I'm afraid of what might happen. - Nothing's going to happen.
Just don't interfere. I'll take care of it myself.
- You will?! - Yes!
- Listen to me! - Well?
- I'd like to... Come on! Take it easy, take it easy.
The cargo has arrived, Comrade Captain. You can take it.
Ah-ah-ah, very good!
And I confess, I thought we were going home with incomplete cargo.
- What kind of cargo? - Deck cargo. Twelve seats.
Uh-huh.
What kind of cargo, anyway?
- So, you said 12 seats?! - Yes, yes, 12 seats.
Mm-hmm.
Come on, come on!
Come on! And one! And two!
XO!
What's that?
Excuse me!
Now he's going to say to me:
"And I'll ask you not to distract the crew during working hours."
And I ask you not to distract the team during working hours.
And I'm admonishing you.
- So we're loading? - Yes, yes, of course.
All right!
What's that on your head?
Oh, it's just a hairdo.
It's called "I'm Mama's Fool." Why?
It's a pity that the form corresponds to the content.
Now take that disgrace off!
- Well, you know what...! - Comrade barmaid,
... If you like to wear ...
... A mop on his head - wear it. Just not during office hours.
- Я!.. - And I'll ask you not to bicker.
I'm not bickering either!
I can see by your face that you're bickering.
What, you see with the back of your head, right?
Comrade barmaid, stop bickering.
- I'm not bickering yet! - And I say you're bickering!
- No, I'm not! - Silence!
Oleg Petrovich, please. The loading is about to begin.
- Keep an eye out. - All right.
My sister asked me to take you on a voyage.
I thought the sea would make a man out of you.
- Well, I... And even in the end...
...to do something seriously.
I'm sick of everything!
And your sea is disgusting and your ship is disgusting and...
...and your Oleg, uh, nasty Petrovich!
Oleg Petrovich is strict, but fair.
Lives according to the system.
He picks on me.
He does not pay attention to me at all.
Well, you contradict yourself.
I beg you, stop quarreling with him.
May this silly war between you and the senior assistant come to an end.
May there be peace and quiet in the team.
What is this?
Who authorized it?
- Oh! - What are you, Maryushka!?
Vira! (up).
What-what, what are you looking at?!
You haven't seen a tiger, have you?!
What if they find out I'm not a tamer, but a caterer?
You yourself asked to take the place of a sick attendant.
I asked, I asked because I can't in their climate.
I'm melting like a candle.
And I can't keep any more animals I've bought here.
I'm forbidden by the salesman.
They eat up all the currency.
They gobble up a horse a day for foreign currency.
And on top of that, each tiger is worth 40,000 in gold.
Are you kidding?!
Stop twirling!
The hell he knows!
I used to work quietly and peacefully in the bargain buffet.
It was the most atrocious thing I ever dealt with,
...I was cutting Amateur sausage. And all of a sudden...
Lions.
Tigers.
- You let me down, comrades. - What's the matter?!
If I knew the nature of the cargo...
Don't worry, Comrade Captain.
What do you mean, don't worry, don't worry.
Once we were carrying giraffes from Hamburg.
- And what? - Suddenly, one of them got a neck rubbing.
- A chafing? What do you mean, rubbed? - Yes, yes it did, why are you laughing?
It's a scandal! We're still reporting back.
Don't worry! Our animals' necks won't break.
- Have a good voyage, Comrade Captain. - Goodbye.
Here, meet Comrade Shuleikin.
A very experienced tamer.
A hunter.
Always works alone.
He will accompany the cargo and feed the animals.
Very nice to meet you.
It's a heroic job you do.
It'll be easier with you.
Don't worry about worrying.
This way! (This way.)
Oh, this place will zoo. (This place will be a zoo.)
Please, put bag right here and you may go home. (Put the bag right here and you may go home.)
All right. (All right.)
Our company is happy to have your affaires. (Our company is happy to have your affaires.)
...and want to do this small present. (...and wants to make this small present.)
And what is this?
Well, he says it's kind of like a bonus...
...to a wholesaler from the firm.
Good bye, sir. Good bye.
- Good bye. - Good bye.
- What's in the bag? - I don't know. I don't know.
Allow me,
...where's the bag?
Who knows!
He couldn't have gotten away by himself, could he?
- А?! - Yes, of course he couldn't!
Aaaaah!
O-o-o-o-o-o-o-o-o-o-o-o-o!
What did you take me for a tiger, Marinochka?!
What a tiger! I just saw such a thing! Such ...
...round and walks by itself!
- Round?! - Aha!
Lie more!
[Growling Tigers]
One hundred and forty-seven times three.
Ah, hell, they're gonna eat me anyway!
"Super."
Let's see what the beastly vitamin is.
Ugh, ugh.
Ugh.
That's disgusting!
Uhh! Shoo!
Uh, look, get off!
Give it back!
Be a human being! Give it back!
Ouch, you little cocksucker!
Here! Not you!
Ope!
I gave to you.
I gave it to you.
I think I gave it to you, too.
Oh, shit, they all look the same!
Split it up!
Oh, I gave it to you!
You bastard!
[Tigers growling]
Tee-tee! Tee-tee-tee! Tee-tee-tee!
[Tigers Growling]
Comrade Captain, do you have a pitchfork?
No.
Give me a fire shovel.
Please.
W-o-n there.
On the shield by the cages.
- By the cages?! - Yes.
Thank you.
Growling Tigers]
Ah, there she is!
[Humming:] Na-ni-na-na-ni-na-ni...
[Humming:] Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na...
Careful.
[Sighs] All right.
Ale-op!
Ale-oop!
[Fun and rhythmic music plays]
[Monkey squeaks]
[Monkey Squeak]
Mystique!
Who's that messing around on the ship, huh?!
I have some thoughts.
But...
Is there anyone in particular you suspect?
I can't suspect anybody in particular, but I'm just...
...thinking in character.
Oh, you think she's capable of that?
Nut.
There's also a washer.
I've got a bolt!
Give me that.
We've got a nut, too.
What a lunch!
Barmaid!
Scram!
Ouch!
Well, well, well! Well! You striped devils, get a move on!
Take that!
[Tigers growling] Oh! Here!
Why do I have to walk past you all day long?!
Oh, for you!
- What do you have for the second course? - Sausages.
And why do you speak of her in the plural?
Ah!
Comrades, eat your borscht.
- Borscht today is so delicious. - Borscht today is not edible!
There are nuts, bolts...
...and all sorts of hardware.
Call the cook!
- Clock. - It's not a clock!
What's so funny?!
Comrades, this is my personal chronometer.
Comrade Captain, what if it wasn't her fault at all?
But then who is? Who?
You don't understand anything!
Don't say a word.
But I can do whatever I want with you now.
If I want...
...I can flick you on the nose.
And if I want, I can turn your head.
Eh!
Nautical order! There!
[Monkey squeaks]
Marishka, did you bring a mop?
I didn't!
Just turned away for a second.
What are you standing there for?
I was cleaning your house.
You can't do what?!
- Let me do it. - Please.
Didn't even say thank you.
Hmm!
Very nice!
What a cleanup job!
- Well, thank you! - What's that?!
What's going on here, huh?
I didn't mean to complain.
- Bless you. - Thank you.
But my patience had run out.
Or me! Or her!
Comrades!
Comrades, of course, I'm not a healer.
Nothing! We will understand.
I am a tamer.
Comrades!
It's stuffy. It's stuffy.
Comrade, stop smoking!
Open the porthole!
And they are open.
Nobody smokes here.
Thank you.
Comrades!
Dear comrades ...
...sailors!
Shh-shh! Quiet!
I, here,
.... asked to give you a little talk.
So to speak, information about tigers.
Comrade tamer, can you tame a mouse?
There's a mouse living in the pantry. It's scary to go in there.
A mouse?!
A mouse is...so to speak, no.
A mouse I can't.
You see, comrades, a mouse is...
...a small predator.
And I work on the big horned, that is... this...
...predator: the lion, the tiger.
How did you get that kind of courage?
Courage?!
- Yes. Well, I have...
...since I was a child.
I drew you this... I drew you a tiger.
Well, of course, as best I could... in this... section.
Here, take a look.
Ooh!
- On three legs. - Three legs?! - No, the fourth one's right there.
Comrades,
...the tiger basically consists...
...three parts.
The front part.
The head.
The back part.
And this, comrades..,
...is the tail.
Can you see it?
In the middle part is the rump, the rump.
Underbreadth.
Brisket.
Lamb.
Next is the ham.
Of course,
Goulard, liver, udder.
Where?
There it is...
I see.
It's easier, so to speak,
...as they say in the people, not in the scientific - failure.
Failure, comrades.
And what does it feed on?
- Feeding?! - Yes. - Let me answer, let me answer.
I read that it feeds on human sacrifices.
[Laughter]
Why?!
Oh, well,
...it could be.
Think about it, comrades.
What can he eat when he's out of horse meat..,
... And beef, and fish oil.
That's how he eats a person.
Well, that's when he has no other products.
How come you're not afraid of them?
Tamed.
Here, believe it or not, comrades,
...tamed by me personally.
[Clapping]
The tiger leads a very, well just very...
...predatory way of life.
Excuse me.
What's wrong, uncle?
I'm not your uncle anymore!
Now I know who's been making all the trouble on the ship.
- Uncle, I didn't do anything! - You didn't do anything?!
I'm not talking to you, I'm talking to my uncle.
- I'm not your uncle anymore! - And I didn't do anything!
And who started the pogrom in Oleg Petrovich's cabin?!
- It wasn't you, was it? - It wasn't me!
- Then who did!? Tell me who, who! - I don't know!
Half-heartedly!
Let go! Ew! Let me go, damn it! Ew!
So much for the bonus from the company!
Catch and drown immediately!
A monkey on a ship is scarier than dynamite.
Where's the tamer?
Comrade Tamer, come here.
Comrade tamer, catch it.
- Who? - A macaque!
I don't deal with monkeys.
Give me a tiger, a lion, this... a leopard.
At the very least, I'll take the crocodile,
...but no macaque.
Pity!
Well, comrades, will catch organized.
According to the system - half of the team...
...with the chief mate to starboard.
I'm going port side.
- Open two hatches! - Yes, sir!
That way, strategically...
...it will inevitably go through the hatch into the hold.
Bosun and cook, get ready in the hold with the tarp.
And as soon as the macaque falls into the hold on the bales..,
...you pop it.
Right?!
- You got it? - All right! Let's go!
There she is!
Look, in my tank top.
Catch it! Catch her, catch her!
Get her! Catch her!
There she is! There! There! There!
А!
You got it!
Got her!
Hey, that's it! You got it!
He can't run now.
He can't run now!
Be quiet!
The captain will come - he'll show you how to put nuts in your borscht.
Ah-ah-ah!
And what did we catch?!
It's moving.
Open up!
- Careful, careful! - Quiet! Quiet!
Comrade Captain, is that you?
There you are!
A gift from the firm.
Do you know you've been ordered drowned?!
What am I gonna do with you, buddy?!
[Knock on door]
Be quiet!
Come in.
Oleg Petrovich,
...I keep thinking about that damned macaque.
- Where should we look for her? - There's no need to look for her anymore!
I threw it...
...and threw it over the fence. - You did? Yes!
On your orders.
Well, you're a man of iron.
I probably couldn't.
What's that?
It's a broken mirror.
Although I felt like I had some kind of weird ,
...strange expression on my face and like I wasn't shaving.
Well..,
...I came to talk about your, about your report.
Now that it's finally established ,
...that it wasn't Marianne who was on the boat at all.
So what?
I don't have to apologize to her.
Why not? She's trying very hard to be good.
I will not apologize! No way!
- It's not pedagogical. - I have my principles.
No woman would ever expect that from me.
If you must know, she's worse than a monkey to me.
Excuse me!
You're welcome.
You insensitive log!
Oooh-ooh, I'm gonna get my revenge on that guy!
Now, I keep telling you, in order not to be discovered..,
...the door must always be locked.
You open it only to me, on three knocks.
One, two, three.
On three, on three.
Do you understand me?!
Well, watch me again. Here, I run up and knock - one, two, three.
I run up - open the latch!
And get a piece of sugar.
One, two, three - try it!
Well done!
Marishka, go to the pantry - we need peppers.
- And the mouse! - Come on, come on! Come on!
Motya, be a friend and go to the pantry for some peppers.
Go by yourself. Don't be afraid.
There's no mouse in there. I've taken care of it.
Yes, there is! I saw it myself.
Mitya dear, go.
Actually, I don't have much respect for mice either.
But for you, I'm willing to do anything.
As you go in - on the left shelf. There's a yellow can like that.
The switch is on the left.
Well!
Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah!
- Ow! - Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah!
What's in there?
It's all right.
Where did the mousetraps come from?
I put them there. Only I didn't put them on Motya, I put them on the mouse.
Oh, thank you, Motya. And I'll kiss you for your bravery.
I sent a radiogram,
...to have you reinstated as captain again.
- How do you feel about that? - I look at it very negatively.
I'm sorry, what did you say?
A half-breed!
Animal tracks!
Footprints!
Maybe it's not a tiger trail?
Whose is it?! A man's?!
Or maybe it's...
Don't play dumb with me!
Who told you to let the tigers out at night, huh!
What for? Let him tell me why.
Yes, fellow sailors, I do.
Every night.
The tigers need to walk so they don't get rickets.
And at night I herd them.
I have insomnia anyway.
- That's all. - That's it?! No, that's not all!
If you let them out again..,
...I'll put you in the box where the anchor chains are kept.
Give the tamer sleeping pills, so he sleeps at night.
And you, Oleg Petrovich, a strict reprimand with a note in your personal file.
There are tigers grazing on the ship! What a jungle!
Comrade Captain,
...I'm ready to be punished.
Please put me under arrest.
Only as far as Odessa.
Arrested where?
How, Vassily Vasilyevich?!
Well, when I'm going to tame you into order!
Let me wipe my lips. Don't argue, don't argue, you filthy little thing.
Grab a spoon, grab a spoon.
Well, with your hands. That's it.
That's it. Well done!
Now be careful.
Because you eat like a pig.
Now I'll make him dance!
Can't you count to two?!
It was one knock - strangers. Sleep, sleep.
[Tamer snores]
Mm-hmm.
[Tamer snore].
Ah!
So...
Here we go!
Five. Six. Seven. Eight. Nine.
Ten.
It's all there!
Mystique!
[Fun and rhythmic music plays]
Hm-mm!
Comrade barmaid, please try to take an upright position.
Ah-ah-ah! Ow!
I did not expect this even from a woman.
Keep your distance.
It's not me, it's a jock.
Tell me, why did you do that?
Because I can't stand you.
Knight!
[Laughs]
You could throw me overboard like a monkey.
You can do it!
Ooh, sea monster! Let me go!
Ouch!
Marishka, come out to the penalty works.
Comrade Captain,
...we are a delegation from the team.
About the barmaid. We want it ... to bail her out.
- No way! - She's just fun.
What's that got to do with hanging her from a rope?
Get the prisoner out of your mind.
Aah!
- You're leaving?! - None of your business!
And because of you, I could have unwittingly suffered.
"Shall I fall, pierced by an arrow?"
"Or shall it fly by?"
"Like a fleeting vision."
What's the wooing?
Is it forty percent?
What a man!
A tamer of beasts, and he even understands cooking.
And you, teach or not.
And who approves the layout?
- Oleg Petrovich. - Serious fellow.
The captain's a bit more reticent against him.
But he was a captain. Even on this ship.
Yes, he was demoted.
What was that for? The revision?
The passenger.
He fell head over heels in love with her, and she...
...and she was messing with his head.
She was beautiful. An artist by profession.
So we're walking up to the pier.
And the passenger walks up to him on the bridge.
And she says, "Well, well, well.
It's a mistake, a mutual misunderstanding.
I forgot to tell you that I am married."
Oleg Petrovich is standing in a daze, and the ship is full speed ahead.
So we are at full throttle and cut into the pier nose.
That's how his captaincy ended.
Yes, so the man suffered for love.
What's love got to do with it?
Maybe it was just a momentary infatuation.
What have you done, you wicked thing!
Aah!
It's boiling!
Well, tell me, what good are you in life!
Nothing but harm!
Marishka,
...brought lunch.
Bring it back, I'm going on a hunger strike.
I demand the XO come here.
Until he comes, I won't eat anything!
All right.
Knysh, Knysh,
...what's the compote today?
- Peaches. - All right, let's have the compote.
And for the rest - a hunger strike!
Ah-ah-ah-ah!
Oh, mothers, help me! Aaaaah!
Found it, you little devil!
Why do you keep following me?!
Why did you call me?
I want to apologize for everything.
I always knew you were a foolish,
...meaningless, good-for-nothing girl.
But today I realize that you're willing...
...you're willing to grovel to get out of here.
Is that all you got?
Oh, you,
...the great Oleg!
Ouch!
I'm sorry.
Come on, I'll feed you, feed you...
You'll grow up big as a tiger, you'll go chew him up, you fool!...
...if he doesn't understand that I love him!...
...and I'm ruining my relationship with him!
Oh, you're stupid, buddy.
I think I'm even stupider.
Close the door behind me! Do you hear me?
Oleg Petrovich, may I see you?
No, lie down, lie down.
I came to you not as a subordinate, but as a person to a person.
I keep thinking about Marianne.
Am I being too hard on her?
True, she had a difficult childhood.
Difficult, in fact, for her parents.
I agree, I agree: bad! It's very bad that she...
...she didn't find her place in life, but...!
What does the great Pistalozzi say? Do you remember, I read you excerpts?
"The circumstances form the human being."
Work! That's what will save Marianne.
The same noble work that turned a monkey into a man.
What's that? What?!
А?!
О!
[One, two, three! One, two, three...
Bug! Give me a sample, please!
Footprints!
Ha-ha! Marishka's doing it again.
She's such a jerk! Well, you're lying. You can't buy it. You know...
Paludndra!
I'll burn! Tigers!
[African tune, drums]
Hmm...
Hmm! Strange things are happening on this ship.
Hand...
Take five right.
Oleg Petrovich, I must be unwell.
- What happened? - I was just in your cabin and it seemed to me...
- You imagined what? - No, nothing!
Everything seems to me lately.
[Oleg Petrovich!
- Mommy-mommy!
Shoo! Run to the radio operator, let him notify the crew and the tamer. Shoo!
Too late! We're surrounded!
Get out through the porthole.
[Whispers]: Oleg Petrovich...
Hey, on watch! That's a hell of a lay-up!
The old man is angry. He's gone completely mad.
I didn't understand you! Say that again!
- Orlov, run and give the alarm! - I'm far away! Get us down!
M-m-mommy!
Comrades, give me something to eat! I call off the hunger strike!
You forgot about me! Of course, you are well there!
Where are you going? Take the stove away!
Oh, you guys! Ow!
Everybody, everybody! Repeat: The animals are out of their cages!
Here you go, here you go! I haven't passed it on yet.
- Hold on, don't let go! - Push!
Get on! Spit out the cigarette, it's in your way.
You're used to throwing it on the deck.
Come on! Spit it out! Spit it out!
He's twisting!
Comrade Shuleikin, put the animals back in their cages!
[Left and right...
Ugh!
Hold it, hold it! I haven't got the message yet!
Oh, brothers! He's drooling from his fangs!
Burning! Spit, spit! Pick it up! Pick it up!
- Spit, I command you! - Ugh!
My mouth is dry! No saliva!
- Oh, I can't! - Where are you going?!
Comrades, he's coming out!
Where are you going?!
Where have you led! Get back!
Run!
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Comrades, please don't chew the ramp!
Don't you understand?! I'll fall in the water!
[Radio]: "Comrade tamer, put your animals in cages immediately!"
[Radio]: "Comrade Tamer, put your animals in cages immediately!"
[Singing]: Left and right, Two galoshes right!
Never coming together, Never coming together!
What shall I do? What should I do?!
How can I love Marusya?!
What must I do? How do I do?! How can I love Marusya?!
Coachman, don't drive... Who's that?
[Noise] Aah!
[Radio]: "Comrade Captain, I report the situation:
...the tigers have left the radio room, no human casualties,
...waiting for your instructions. I can't see anything from here."
[Radio] "Everybody, everybody! We've sent the Brigidy out of port straight from the manege...
...to assist our tamer helicopter with a local tamer.
Captain's orders: Don't hit the tigers with anything heavy.
...and don't ruin their skins. The cargo is government property...
...and must be delivered intact..."
- Rrrr! - Excuse me.
Damn you to hell!
Brothers, half-heartedly!
- There he is! Brothers! - Finally!
- Comrade tamer, help me out! - Let the tamer through!
Don't! Yes, comrades, let go! Do not!
Do not! Don't! Ah-ah-ah!
Open up! Open up, I said!
You miserable creature! You don't know what a bosun is yet.
You can't eat me like that without a dick!
Alexei Stepanovich, didn't you forget to close the door?
Comrade tamer, why are you here?
Why? Because I don't want to be a steak.
Come here!
- These are your animals, aren't they? - They're mine.
I see. Well, they're not mine.
What's wrong with you?! Are you crazy?!
Ah-ah-ah-ah!
Come on, tame it! Come on!
Let go! Open it! You can't do that! It's cruel!
Don't do it, kitty!
Ahhhh!
That tickles! Aaaaah!
Scram! Scat, you striped devils!
Scat!
Ah-m-m-m!
Uncle, what happened?!
Ouch! We're drowning, aren't we?!
Get off me! I won't do it again!
What are you doing?! Put that down!
Who let you! Don't, don't!
Ew! Scram! Ala gop!
Don't do that, don't do that, don't be naughty!
Shoo! I'll forgive you - scram!
Get the water off, damn it!
Aaah! Stop it! Aaah!
[Monkey Squeak]
Why isn't the shift going on?
Are they slaughtering a goat or something!
So you said you lived on Deribasovskaya,
...ah, comrade tamer.
Full speed ahead!
Full back!
It's coming! Hooray!
Hooray!
Hooray!!!
I am the world-famous...
...Chokolani the animal trainer.
Where there's a tiger!
I'll steal it!
Ooh la la le! Ha! Ha!
Go down to the deck...
...and cage the beasts.
No! You can't tame it!
Wild tiger! We've got to ping-pong! Gun, artillery!
Full speed ahead!
Schneller, schneller! (Hurry, hurry!)
Let's pay with currency!
Schneller! (quickly).
- You're a coward! - I'm not a coward - but I'm afraid!
Don't, Tiger! (tiger).
Let go! I'll complain!
You're not a tiger - you're a pig!
Fly, fly! Schneller! (Quickly).
Where! Where!
Tamer!
Fake!
Uncle, what happened?
Guys!
Oh, okay.
Long live freedom!
Hey, helicopter!
Hey, hey, hey!
Take it for a ride!
Ouch!
Run! Run, Marishka!
Woman, Marishka's on deck! Save her!
Save her!
I'm coming to help!
Aaaaah!
Aaaaaaaaah!
You're my striped one.
Kitty.
Pssh-pssh!
You're not scary at all.
- I don't get it! - And you won't!
Step away from the beast now.
- He'll eat you! - None of your business!
- Get out of here! Go away yourself!
Ooh, that's quite a command.
Don't argue.
You poor baby.
The XO scratched you.
Marishechka, hold this beast.
I have to go to the cabin.
Get out, get out. I'll hold him.
Well, get in, get in.
Run before they come to their senses.
I won't!
Hey, don't you dare!
Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh!
Hold the cage! I'm going!
It's deep! Everybody save me!
There's reefs right up ahead!
Somebody get to the helm.
Come on!
Stop the cage! Help me, stop the cage!
It's deep! I can't swim!
What's going on?!
I'll put a bandage on my paw and make it go away.
You're my good boy.
Don't worry, he won't hurt you again.
No.
What are you doing here?
Look how shaggy you are.
What's that on your head?
It's out of fashion these days.
Let me comb your hair.
Comrade barmaid,
...what are you doing?
Hair...
... "I'm daddy's fool."
Ask the XO for a headscarf.
You'll be tying it on duty time.
Next!
Well, big boy, will you listen to me now?
Let the XO try to growl at me.
Leave the deck now.
You're coming with me on the penalty duty, you'll be peeling potatoes.
Listen, Marishka,
...for God's sake, try to put them in cages.
I have a team to feed.
Serves you right!
You're all under arrest now.
Here.
Your captain and your second-in-command.
And I'm your boss.
Marisha,
...why don't they touch you?
Don't you understand?! They like me.
Marisha, I beg you, put them in cages.
Odessa on the horizon! Let the XO ask.
Oleg Petrovich, for God's sake, please ask you.
Comrade barmaid!
Comrade barmaid,
...put the animals in cages immediately.
And when they ask, they say please.
For me, for me, please.
Please, drive the animals into the cages.
Come on, let's go home! Forward march to the cages!
Oh, that's it, huh?! Like this?! Don't you obey?! Let's go to the cages!
Here you go! Here you go!
Ooh, ginger team! What, snapping? Snapping? Let's go!
- Marin, stop! - Well Vas!
Here, here. Well, eat. Here! Well, well!
Look out!
Ow! Aaaaah!
Drown!!! Drowning!
Guys, come here!
Drowning!
- Thank you. - Man overboard!
Hand over the left anchor!
What accuracy!
Just a second.
- They're swimming beautifully! - Who?
That group over there in the striped swimsuits.
Sergunchik, follow me!
Crazy, where?!
Where are you going, big guy? Off the roof!
It's not our car! Get off! I said get off!
What are you looking at?!
Mommy,
...I always dream of you in some exotic form.
What shall I do?
Come here! Come here! Come on!
Come on! Come on, let's go! Guys, let's go. That's my boy!
To the steamer, to the steamer. It's time for dinner. Come on, let's go.
Let's go.
Pussy!
The last ones are floating.
- Look, look! Marishka is holding on to her tail. - Quiet!
- She's not by the tail at all, she's swimming on her own. - No, by the tail, by the tail!
Fifth, sixth, seventh.
Get away from the board! Bring the last cage to the corridor exit!
Quickly! Sidorenko, get ready!
Behind the last animal, slam the door at once!
Lock it in the cage!
Roll it back to its place!
Ah, uncle! I came in handy! You did?
- Bring up the left anchor! - What's wrong with you, Marianne?!
Oleg Petrovich, please, to the infirmary her.
Raise the left anchor!
One. Two. Three. Four.
- Five. - I'm sorry, you counted me out.
And I'll have you all the way down to the pier, you crook.
What, are you gonna turn him in for a lion? There was a lion in that cage.
The lion is in the tamer's cabin!
Open up!
- You go now! Courage! - Don't shove it!
- Come on! - Open up!
- Come on, come on! - He's asleep.
Yeah. Let's go in, and he's...
- He's drunk on Luminal. He's gone crazy, poor guy. - Be quiet!
You'll wake us up.
- Tie him up, tie him up! - Quiet! Quiet!
Take it easy! Take it easy!
He's faking it, the bastard! He's waiting for us to get closer.
- Quiet. - Come on. - Valya, try to tie him like a muzzle.
- Try it yourself. - Look, he's listening! - Quiet!
Don't breathe on him. He can smell it.
- Oh, comrades! Guys, we need to change the shoulder. - Quiet! Be patient.
Shhh!...
- Hush! - Shh!...
Shh!...
Drop the gun! Be a man!
Uh-oh!
Uh-oh! Uh-oh-oh-oh!
Freeze. Where are you going?
Stand up!
- Quiet! It's occupied! - Quiet, you!
It's occupied, it's occupied!
Comrade sailors, what are you doing?!
- What about me?! - Come out already, tamer. - Well, brother, aren't you mad?
You won't bite?
- Courage! - Calm down. - Courage! - Steady.
- Don't step on the udder, it'll wake up. - Steady.
Oh, I'm glad you're feeling better.
Maybe you're able to go by yourself now, huh?
And no one asked you to drag me all over the ship!
- Goodbye, Comrade Captain. - Have a good voyage.
- Don't forget! - Happy sailing, friends.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye. - Goodbye, Comrade Captain.
So, are you sad to break up?
It's not hard for you, is it? Then let's go. Just don't lose your pants.
Yes!..
And then she sat by the cages and sobbed.
And the whole crew ,
...even the tigers, had tears in their eyes...
...tears like that.
Believe it or not.
What a sad story!
So Marianne became a tiger tamer, huh?
No, she didn't become a tamer.
And yet she found her calling.
Didn't that kind of love ever end?
I would have found it, I would have certainly found it.
Let's go.
Over there, look. See?
Excuse me, Marianna Andreyevna, you're wanted backstage.
- The artist is ill. Please. - All right.
Go home, wash the dishes, make dinner and wait for me.
Are you coming soon?
Get a doctor, quick!
Hurry, hurry. Doctor.
- Let the doctor through. Don't crowd, comrades. - Listen, how did he get out?
- They say he bit off the lock. - What lock?
- What happened. - Marianna Andreevna, Vaska tore Achilles.
Well, sick man, what are we complaining about? You won't fight another time.
Why did you bite off Vasya's tail, huh?
You got one too.
I'm bound to become something, too.
I'm going to go to technical school in the fall. Honestly, I will.
The patient needs surgery under clinical conditions. The collar!
Did you see that? I told you the whole truth.
Believe it or not.
Here it is.
The role of Marianne was played by the tiger tamer...
...Margarita Nazarova.
Directed by tamer Konstantin Konstantinovsky.