In the glorious city of Rostov, a cathedral priest in Rostov had one son.
His name was Alyosha, his father's name was Popovich.
Aliosha grew by leaps and bounds.
Aliosha was learning to read, but nothing came out of it.
And then he began to learn the warrior's trade.
-Muuuu!!! -Aya-ya-ya!!!
-That's what your Alyoshenka did! ! There!
-Hehehehe...
-Ouch!
-That's what your boy Alyosha did!...
And in those bad times, the Tugarian armies started trampling on the Russian land, and
the Russian people.
A black force came to collect a considerable tribute from the people of Rostov.
-But... what shall we do, Russians?
-Listen to me, Alyosha, son of a cathedral priest, how long will the Russians
How long will we Russians endure this evil foe? Let's protect our wives and children and stand up for our Russian land!
-The point is... -If you have something concrete to propose, then...
but if you're just talking, get off the barrel! Don't mess with people's heads.
-Quiet, my dear friend... bring our idea on paper, we'll put it to people's judgment.
-Vo!!! -We'll take the Tugarians' armies by stealth.
We'll collect their tribute in gold, we'll put that tribute in a cave under Bayun Mountain, and as soon as the Tugarian army
the Tugarian army enters it, we'll cover our trap with a stone! Hee-hee-hee-hee!!!
-And you, how will we get the gold back from the cave?
-Gold? That's... Here... -Let's wait until the Basurmans starve to death...
starve to death... -Oh!
Or weaken!
It's settled then.
-Thank you, Lord, that you've sent Alyosha a plan for our salvation!
And the people of Rostov began to collect a golden tribute. Whoever had gold and jewels,
they took it all away.
-At-two, at-two.
-Hooray!!!
-O-o-o-o! That's where we need to go.
-The tribe of the Basurman has complained!
-The black yoke... It won't be long before they feast! Now they're going to have to try their mighty strength!
-Come on.
-Yeah, have you tasted the might of a bogatyr?
-Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh!
-I don't get it... -Is that the plan?
-To stake them! -Huh? -А?
-When I look at our people, I wonder where they get so much hatred.
Is it because they're hungry, or are they soulless?
-It's the gold they're so upset about, I'm telling you.
-Yes, gold spoils people.
-So, Tikhon, as long as I don't get my gold and my good name back.
there's nothing for me to do in town. Goodbye, Tikhon.
-How can I let you go alone, Alyosha? My father will take my head off!
-You, Tikhon, go home and explain everything to your father and mother.
There's no one but me to defeat Tugarin the serpent.
-Wait... my God... how, without weapons, without money, and without comrades?!... You!
-We can't let him go alone, he'll get lost on his own.
-Where are you, our son? And Tikhon disappeared. He must have run off to help him.
-If they come back, I'll skin them both... -Wait, how do we get back as heroes?
-I won't let them get away with it. -Oh... -Oh, they came up with a plan...
-What a naughty man!.. With his bare hands, he will beat Tugarin alone!
Well, nothing, nothing, I'll intercept him behind the forest.
-And I have all sorts of dreams... Here's the girl's dream - Alyoshenka has returned,
and quietly, like a mouse into the upper room.
-Do you hear? Isn't Alyosha coming home?
-Will you hear Alyosha rustling like that?! A bird is probably nesting on the roof.
-Alyosha!... -You think it's the wind rustling.
-Are you going far, little berry?
-I can't go on like this, my heart is breaking.
-You don't give a damn about that fool, what's going to happen to him? And if he does, it's not a great loss.
I won't let him go anywhere! -Oh, yeah?! Then I'll cut off my braids and go to a monastery...
and go to a monastery. A man's. -What are you thinking? What are you thinking?
They argued as much as they could, but Lyubava insisted on her position. To tell the truth, her grandmother
her grandmother wouldn't let her go. She went with her.
-Bogatyr, buy a horse. Buy it, you won't regret it. A bogatyr horse.
-Oh, you black power, you smell your swift doom! Tremble the tribe of the Bussurman
before the Russian bogatyr!
-Ai da nada nai nai! Ai da nada nai nai! -Hurry up, you nag!
-I can't go on... I need to catch my breath.
-You, fierce fiend, try some of my bogatyr strength...
-Tikhon? Why are you here?
-You do as you like, Alyosha, but I'll go with you. The road will be easier for both of us.
-Forgive me, I didn't recognize you right away.
Why are you dressed like that? -I thought, how can a warrior without a horse, so I bought one.
-Why is his face tied up? -His muzzle? I don't know, he must be biting. Bastard.
-Yee-gee-gee-gee-gee, freedom... Finally! I almost forgot my native tongue. What are you looking at?
-Aah! A talking horse! -It's the demon inside him!
-Again... Why do you always react like that? Why are you getting so excited? Take it easy,
Take a deep breath... That's good.
Eh-uh-uh, that's too much! -You demon... !
-How's it going?! Hang in there!
-Do you hear that? -Doesn't our people get beaten up? -Do you hear that?
-What should we do? -We have to run for help!
-Wait, a girl can't get into a man's fight, they'll kill her without even noticing!
-What do you mean? -How do we... We'll hide first, and when we need help...
we'll be right here.
-Uh, excuse me...
Let's talk about this calmly. Yeah, I'm a talking horse, but that's no reason to fight.
-Don't listen to him. Chop his head off. -What are you doing, cutting off his head? My head...
...is worth 100 times more than yours. -Why is it worth more? -Why is it worth more?
-Can't you even read? -Imagine that.
-Don't be ridiculous. How many books have you read in your life?
-Okay, that's enough. Where did you come from? -He bought me from a gypsy. He also...
He also gave me a new shirt and boots. -Who, me?
-Who, me? And he also gave the gypsies his sword.
-Oh, really? -Well, yes, actually. I-I thought you could use
a bogatyr horse would come in handy. -Yeah, it's gonna be tough without a sword. And what's the name
of this bogatyr steed? -My name is Gaius Julius Caesar.
your education, you may call me Julius.
-What kind of a strange name is that? -I was named in honor of the great Roman
and emperor. Before the gypsies stole me away, I was at the temple in Novgorod.
A lot of interesting books are kept there. -So now the three of us will have to
the way is not an easy one... Well, serve me faithfully, bogatyr horse. Leave me neither
dead, nor wounded, nor gray wolves to tear, nor black crows to maul,
to my enemies to desecrate. Wherever we are, bring me home.
-There's something in the bushes. -Tikhon, come and see.
-Why me? -You go. -Because you're the oldest, most experienced one here,
You've done your time... -You want to go, you go.
-Who's hiding in the bushes? Show yourself and take up the challenge of a fair fight...
...and taste the strength of a bogatyr... -We'll throw a spear.
-Don't throw a spear!
-Lyubava? What are you doing here? -Grandma and I have been following you all the way from Rostov.
Forgive us, Alyoshenka. My heart was so worried. I couldn't help it.
-Yes, what are we going to do now? I guess we'll have to take you brothers with us. We must hurry further,
Otherwise we won't find Tugarin or the gold. Meet Julius, my horse.
-The Bogatyr's! Ah!
-What are you staring at? Haven't you ever seen a talking horse?
-And this is Lyubava... Her grandmother. -And this is Moses, my donkey.
-Yeah, really? I thought it was an Arabian horse.
-Shut up, Julius. -You shut up.
-And where shall we go, Alyosha? -To the place where the unclean are buried. That's where we have to go.
-Look, isn't there another way? And anyway, why do we have to go there...? А?.. А?.. А?
And they decided to continue the dangerous path together. All hardships and hardships to be shared equally.
-What about it, Tikhon, why don't we sing a song to cheer you up? Let's do our bogatyr song...
-Oh, eh, eh, eh, eh, eh, eh... -Ah-ah-ah... -Ah-ah-ah...
-Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, guys. I'm already in no mood, but a song like this will make you hang!
-What didn't you like about the song? -What song? -It's not a song! Give me a tear. Don't make me laugh
...my horseshoes. They don't sing that nowadays. Here, catch the rhythm... And one, one, one, two, three...
# There's tibidam tibidam tam-tam-tam-tam There's tibidam tibidam tam-pam...
-Dili-dili-dili-dili-dai-yam. Dili-dili-dili-dili-dili dai-om...
-They're all yellin'... They left the city penniless, and no matter what, they sing songs...
Come on, broads, it's a good song!
-Ugh!
-That's it. There's no bridge, we can't get to the other side.
-Wait, where? There's no way back. -Come on, I'll show you.
-Stop, you son of a bitch! I told you. -Who do you think you are? You're not the one the bogatyr
is talking to you... -Where did you get such a smart guy?!
-What's there to argue about? Let's figure out how to get to the other side.
-Here's my suggestion...
Here's a simple mechanism... We'll need some trees...
We do the math... Gravity, acceleration...
That's it.
Well, you could do that.
Is it safe?
-Safe. -Nat, it's just that you and I have to save ourselves
...or it'd be stupid to die like this.
-So, what do you suggest? -So let someone older go first,
someone with more experience...
-What? -I'm just looking out for the company's success.
-Aah!!! -Ga-ga-ga-ga!!!
-Where are you, come here...
-Wait, why does everybody think only of themselves? -What's wrong, you son of a bitch?
-Nothing for me, but what about Moses? -What's Moses got to do with it?
-You people are interesting. How can he walk on a log? He's a donkey.
-I'm afraid to walk on a log, too.
-Ugh!
-Yes! -Bab...
-Yes, what a woman!
Listen, Tikhon, look closely, why? You'll be like a stone wall! And in general, on the household.
-Thank you, Alyoshenka.
-So, Tikhon, you go now. Tikhon... Tikhon
-I'm afraid of heights.
-What are you doing up there? Hurry up! -Now, Tikhon is afraid of heights.
-And when you go, don't look down. -I can't not look down.
-Oh, I know what to do... Close your eyes. -That's right.
-Courage, go... -Courage... -You go... -Courage...
-Come on, come on, Tikhon. -You can do it.
-Silence all of you, one of you has to be in command.
Come on, come on, Tikhon, you can do it, be brave...
-You!!!
-Calm down Tikhon, they'll save you now.
-Ah-ah-ah-ah!!! -Tikhon...
-Why are you looking at me? Is anyone going to save him?
-Tikhon! -Alyoshenka!!!
-Brrr-rr!
-There's nothing to save me... I won't drown.
-There you go, and it's all Julius, Julius!
-That's where we're going. We need to find out the way from the good people.
-What if they're not kind, but quite the opposite?
-What's the point of guessing? -We need to find out. -That's right... -We need someone
...to go and do some recon...
-Maybe you'll do it yourself. -Okay, but what's the logic here?
-What logic? -What logic? -Well, darkness, everything is very simple... Alyosha the hero
He's the main hero and can't die, I'm his bogatyr horse, Lyubava is the hero's bride, they
they must get married and all that... I won't give Moses away, because I like him, so it's
so it's either you or the grandmother.
-You idiot. -You son of a bitch. Take it easy, why are you getting so worked up? All right, let Lyubava go.
-Where's Alyosha?
-Go back, or else... Go back, I'm telling you! -You're such a fool!
-Hey, come here, there's nobody here.
-Uncle, is this the house, if it isn't Svyatogor himself?
-Yes, that's right! His house. A glorious bogatyr was!
-I wonder if there's anything chewy here?
What is it? Nothing. -You just want something to eat.
-Don't look in my mouth! -You don't tell me what to do. Understand?
-Don't take me at my word. Got it? -Come on. Let's get some rest and hit the road.
-How could you do that?! А? -You're not hurt, Alyosha?
-I read in a book that fasting is considered therapeutic only after a good dinner.
Lack of food in the young body contributes to the premature death
of the brain cells, if any.
I feel as if no one could hear me. Of course, I'm just a horse.
-Okay, what do you suggest? -Oh, my God, who am I surrounded by?
You're a bogeyman, after all... Take your bow, go into the woods and kill someone.  Moses!
-А?!!! -Moses gathers wood, you build a fire...
Lubava and Granny will cook.
-I wonder what you'll be doing the whole time?
-Yes, that's it! -You're ridiculous, I'm a bogatyr horse... What if
...tomorrow's battle and I'm tired...
-Svyatogor! -Who are you? What do you want?
-Forgive us, glorious bogatyr, for our impudence.
We dropped in by chance, we're from Rostov ourselves.
We're looking for the Tugarian army. They insulted us...
-Ooh. Tugarin again... -Listen, would you take up sports or something? No, really?
-Well, I'll help you with whatever I can, as they say. -Here you go, Tugarin! We're going to take him and the two
...with two bogatyrs... -What two bogatyrs?
-That's our hero from Rostov, Alyosha Popovich.
-Yeah... Is he dumb or what? -I am, that's... Let's punish Tugarin now
...for the sneaky one, that he's near our... city... ...for taking our city's gold.
-Yes, Tugarin the serpent has gotten out of hand. Not like before, as I remember now... Back then...
I was in charge of a squad or not, I think it was a squadron...
We gave the Tugars a hard time back then...
Well, now you see, I'm old and weak. -Old? Yes, weak!
-Wait a minute, Tugarin... the gold, I've seen them...
-Really? Where?
-I'll remember now...  Well... I was standing near the forest, and the Tugar band, just
...passing by with the gold.
-I fell asleep. -Yeah, well?
-No, look at this. Well? О. Yeah. He's definitely asleep. Hey, big guy!
-What? Where? -I can't see from the village.
-Quiet, quiet, what happened? -What happened? Who are you?
-I'm Saint Luke, and this is the prophet Moses... -Julius, stop it! You told us about Tugar...
...you told us about Tugar, remember? About the gold. -Oh, yes. There was gold. I don't remember which year,
but we were coming back from the campaign and the prince rewarded us with gold gold pieces... -Ah...
I still have them!
-There!
-Ah. That's the wrong gold... Oh, trouble!
How can we find Tugarin? -Tugarin, I'll help you. I saw his army
I recently saw his army near the edge of the forest. I also know a shortcut.
And to make it easier for you, here, hold this sword.
I don't have the strength in my hands, but it will be just right for you.
-O-o-o-o-o! -Hm.
-And-a-and-a-and-a!!! -Thank you, Svyatogor, for your gift.
-Thank you, Russian bogatyr.
Show us the way to Tugarin, do us a favor!
-Well, Godspeed. You'll go to this bright star as far as the lonely rock, you'll go around it and along the trail up the
and go up the mountain, then you'll come out to the cave...
And the heroes went on the way that the glorious warrior Svyatogor indicated.
-There's the cave.
Why don't we hold hands just in case?
-Hu...
-Aah!!!
-Oops. -It's not that high.
-AH... -AH... -Aah!
-We're going that way... Let's hold hands...
-Maybe we shouldn't, Alyosha? -Why not?
-I'm afraid of the dark!
-Yulia, I'm crying.
Ya!!!
-Wow, this must have been where the Gorynych the Serpent used to live.
-Come on, b...librarians. -It's kind of cold in here.
-That's right... Grave... -Oh, look, I told you the Tugars
are out there somewhere... And their arrow. -That's quite an arrow. ! That's a whole spear!
Oh... I don't feel good. Am I going back or not... let's all go back.
-Have patience, Julius, have patience.
-Don't you think the cave is getting narrower? -It is.
-I should warn you, I'm claustrophobic.
-What? -It's a fear of enclosed spaces.
-Come on, Julius. -There's no reason to panic.
-Panic? Who said anything about panic? It's just to be on the safe side.
-Well, let's move. What are you standing up for? -I can't move, I'm pinned down by a rock.
-Oh, it looks like it's stuck. -I don't understand. -Wait a minute, are you telling me..,
I could spend the rest of my life in this dark, dank cave?
Okay, now I'll show you what real panic is!
-No need, we're going to try to get you out.
-Help me... -Help me... Somebody save the bogatyr horse!!! I don't want to die!
Moses, my friend, take care of my family. -You don't have any family, Julius. -You don't have any family.
-Oh my God! I don't even have a family... I'm still so young.
-Aah!
-You should eat less, that's what. -God, how..., how low it is to point out
to point out a man's shortcomings in a critical situation.
-Silence! Do you hear that?
YOU CAN HEAR THE MURMUR OF VOICES.
-Tugarin, that's right Tugarin. Their dialect. -Well, the hour has come, now they're going to try
of Bogatyr's strength... -Don't go, Alyosha!
-Hey... Huh?
-Wait a minute, that's...
-It can't be! -That's right, uncle, that's where he saw them.
-That's right, when they were leaving with the gold. -Don't get upset, Alyosha, maybe we'll catch up.
-I don't understand, what's the problem? Did you come back?
-What's the problem with this cave?!
-That's right. Now none of the Russian bogeymen will laugh at you.
-Wait, that's an index stone. -Really? Tikhon, read it...
-"Ke. K-t-o. It's a-right-o-o-o-o-o-o...
-What's that?
C-c-c-c-c-can't-just-get-it...
-Don't rush it, Tikhon. Concentrate. We'll break up the lagers,
...you'll be done by morning. -I'm just visually impaired... ...but I'm weak. Here.
-I see. -Then why don't you read it yourself?
-What's there to read? It says, "If you go left, you'll be rich. "To the right
"If you go right, you'll be married, and if you go straight, you'll find your death.
-Right! So that's where we're going?! Straight.
-Well, shall we go?
-Where did you get the stone, Alyosha?
-This is the place.
Let's go quickly, so we won't be late.
-What are you doing?
-Why are we running from the court, Alyosha? This is our happiness!
It's written that he'll be married. -What about Tugarin the Serpent?
What about Bogatyr's glory? -What about me? I'm already 16 years old, and I'm still
...and I'm still walking around as a maiden...
I'm going to stay an old maid. You're just afraid of a serious relationship.
-Who, me?! -Yes, you!
-What about the gold?
-By the way, the gold, it says right here.
-You'll be rich. So why should we risk it? I've heard that this
Tugarin is a serious guy. What if I die in battle or get crippled?
No, the risk is noble, of course, but nothing can undermine
of my nobility is better than expensive harnesses and gold horseshoes.
-No, Julius, you don't understand, it's not just about gold, it's about making people
believe in us, you know? To be respected.
-Hy-hy-hy, don't make my horseshoes laugh. There's nothing like a fat wallet
A fat wallet, and faith, respect, and love will come with it.
-You don't sound like a bogatyr horse, but like a peddler at a bazaar.
-Wait a minute... Everyone has the right to happiness. -What do you mean?
-That everyone gets what he wants. -You're talking nonsense, Julius!
-And you don't respect other people's opinions!
-Croo-croo-croo-pooh... -Croo-croo-pooh...
-Well... I didn't think we'd have to part, but I guess that's our fate. Let's go.
Tikhon, we'll manage on our own.
-And don't look for me, okay, I'll marry someone else and I'll have five... Not five, but ten
children. And there will be a household and a clever husband, such that woo! And he will love me and we will
live happily ever after and die on the same day... No, we'll never die! Here... Let's go to .
Grandma, let's find a real groom, not like this one.
-Where has it ever been seen that a woman is an order to a man?
-You've got the fashion to go against my word! -That's right.
-I'm afraid of a serious relationship... Ho-ho, I don't smile in the mirror because I'm...
¶ I'm not smiling at myself in the mirror ¶ -So what?
-I'll find so many other brides... !
-Why do you keep nodding off? -I'm not giving in.
-So go ahead and say it. -You can't let a woman get away with this!
-You can't go against a man's word. -You can't go against a man's word. -That's right.
-You don't smile at yourself when you go to the mirror.
-Don't you have an opinion? Don't you have an opinion? Yes, I do.
-I don't think you're a couple. -That's right.
So what if she's the best-looking girl in Rostov?
-So what if she's the smartest girl in Rostov? -Yes...
-So what if you love her to death? Mm-hmm.
-So you'll marry someone else and be happy with her for the rest of your life. So what?
-You'll get by somehow.
-Uncle, I feel bad without her, I can't live without her! I love her!
-When I get rich, I'll get married and settle down. I've had enough of these bogatyr adventures! I'm tired. I'll buy
a palace with big stables... or two...
So... where to next? Uh-oh, don't you know where the riches are?
-You want to get rich, stranger? -Who's there?
-Only today and only here is the biggest prize-two half-kingdoms, take a chance and feel the luck.
Well, do you want to play? -Yeah!
-Huh? ...On horseshoes!!! -Horseshoes, then horseshoes!
Put the horseshoes here and guess a number from one to ten. Just, I guess, you guess...
So, your number is... -Uh, three...
-That's right! Your winnings are ten points. Try again?!
-Of course, it's so easy! -And so... Place your bets.
-Hmm... another horseshoe? Well, it's settled... Your number... -Five...
-Right again! Yes! Ten more points! You're a lucky guy.
-Hee-hee. Lucky. Luck is my middle name. Give me another one.
-So, place your bet. -Hey, I'll bet anything.
-Recognized. -And... the number? -Two.
-I like this guy, he won again!
-Guys, it's not your day!
-He thinks I'm weak-willed. -He probably is. -I'm gonna find a hundred more like him...
...just like him. -Okay.
-Even better! -That's right.
-Nobody tells me what to do. -It's a fact.
-Do you agree with me on everything? -Yeah. -So what do you say to me?
-Alyoschka, the naughty one... -That's right!
-That's right, ba... -You'll marry the first guy you meet...
and live with him... -I will!
You'll cry into your pillow at night, remembering Alyosha.
-I won't!
I need him, I can't live without him! I love him!
-Yee-tya, yee-tya, yee-tya, yee-tya... 40 points, 40 points! -It's time to play the super game!
And win two half-kings! -Yes, it's time, come on, come on!!!
-So, the bet is 100 points. -Yes, 100 points... Э.. But I only have 40?!
-Hmm... -Let me see...
Okay, 40 points and your hide. -My hide?
-Your two half-kingdoms.
-Agreed, it's a deal. -So, what's your number?
-Okay, five was, three was, seven and nine were, so according to probability theory... -eight... -Yes..,
that's right, eight!
-I'm sorry... but you lose... Hey, guys, skin him...
-Wait a minute, I'm asking for a continuance. I need a loan. I have a lot of connections.
I've got the scales of Novgorod behind me.
-Oh... the trail has gone sideways, I guess we'll hit their road just right.
-Hurry, Tikhon, follow me. -Oh...
-Lyubava? -Alyosha!
-I have to tell you something. -No, it's me who should tell you.
-Don't argue with me. -Don't interrupt me.
-Good to see you guys... -I realized our strength is in unity, only together will we reach
our high purpose... Friendship is our real wealth!
Tremble, Tugarian army, the Bogatyr's horse is coming...
Well, let's not waste a minute, or someone else will take the gold...
I mean... someone else will take Tugarin's gold.
In short, let's go, friends... to the feat... !
-Hey!!! -hey-hey-hey...
-Hey, hey...
-Hey!
Peek-a-boo... Peek-a-boo...
-Alyosha the Fool!
Whether long or short, our heroes walked their difficult road, but in the evening
they reached the Tugarian camp and began to think about how to defeat Tugarin
and return the gold from Rostov to their homes.
-Well, it's time for the enemy to taste my heroic strength...
-Wait a minute, buddy, can you do that without a plan? -That's right! You can't do it without a plan!
-I'm surprised at you, have you ever heard of tactics, of strategy?
The main thing for us is observation and stamina...
-What's there to watch and see? It's all clear.
We go in from four sides and...
-Whoa! -Wait, I think everyone in this situation
should have a say in this situation. -What are you talking about?
-Moses and I, Moses and I believe that the best battle is the one that never happened.
-Oops. What? -It's all about diplomacy in the world these days. Maybe
Maybe we should talk to these guys, get to their heartstrings, play on their feelings.
-All right, then you go. -No. -No, Moses and
Tikhon... Moses isn't as hot-tempered as me, and Tikhon isn't sorry.
Just kidding... You have to admit, you can't look at him without tears! I mean, who'd want to be seen with such a man...
who'd have the guts to kill someone like that? -That's enough, I'm fed up. Tonight we'll sneak into their
We'll sneak into their camps at night and take the gold...
-That's my kind of thing. -That's my kind of thing. You can do it at night without me. -Crrrrr!
-Hoo... Hoo-hoo!
-Yum, yum, yum! -Tsk-tsk-tsk!
-Igo-go, how... -Hush, you wretched man!!!
-Shoosh, guys, let me go... I've got myself under control.
-What the hell did he do with the gold?! -What's wrong?
-How can we look people in the eye? -What's the matter?
-Is that any way to treat other people's goods? -Will somebody explain to me what's going on here?
what's going on here? -Gold is gold. So they melted it down,
so what's the big deal?
-And how can I find my tooth now?
-What are you making noise for?!
-I can't do this... are we thieves or what? We've come for our own!
Come on, you Basurmans, fight fair and brave... !
-Oh, you fool... !!
-Eh?!
-Alyosha...
-Is there room? -No. No. No!
-Didn't fall. -Didn't fall.
-Uh... ! -Ugh, I think we got away!
-Help me!
-Find me at the old oak tree.
If you bring me the gold, I'll bring back the girl.
-So, Tikhon, Grandma, take Moses and take the gold home to Rostov.
and I'll go with Julius to rescue Lyubava... -No, I'll go with you to get Lyubava too...
-Understand, grandma, you'll only be a burden to us, and there's no time to lose.
-Wait, wait, wait, you mean we're just going to trust these guys with the gold?
-What guys? -I'm surprised at you, you have no
You don't know anything about people... Look at them closely... It's like...
a real gang, a gang of criminals... The three of them are scarier than Tugarin! They'll take the gold and...
-I don't get it! -What's there to understand... If you take that money...
...and divide it among the five... among the four...
No... for three... Tikhon and Grandma have enough for one share.
Why, they've got less to live for...
-What about the people of Rostov? -Ha-ha, don't be ridiculous... um...
What people? The people, if I'm not mistaken, wanted to stake you!.. Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh...
-Listen, if you don't shut up now, I'll turn you over to the varmints and they'll make a sausage out of you
...and they'll make a sausage out of you in no time.
-А.. That's why I love him. He didn't give in to the provocation.
-What are you standing around for? Come on, let's go. People in Rostov are getting too greedy... Oh... they're waiting!
-We don't want to leave you alone... -What do I mean? Everyone has to go together.
-No, we won't pamper you with human gold a second time. I think so. Let's go.
-It wasn't right to let them go alone, after all.
-Yes, they can hardly manage on their own... -What are we going to do? -What are we going to do?
-I think we'll leave the gold to the Prince of Kiev,
and we ourselves will go to help Alesha...
-You know, I wanted to ask you... About your phrase...
-What line? -The one about the vultures. Could you really...
to hand me over to the vultures?
-Well, you know... -Wait, wait, wait, I just want to hear...
Yes or no? -Well... No..
-I almost believed you, and your eyes were so natural.
-Listen, could you walk, my back's hurting so bad.
-Yeah, we've had a tough time... -Not everyone can take it.
-But that's all right, at least the people of Rostov will be happy.
-Well, here we are.
-To cut off their heads!
-I wonder how Tikhon and Moses got there.
-Oh, I'm worried myself. They trusted them with the gold, and it's human, no, but I'm sure in Moses,
I'm sure he's a normal guy, but Tikhon...
-Remember Julius, I trust Tikhon like I trust myself.
-He's like a brother to me.
They're just so defenseless.
-Don't execute him, Prince. Say your prayers.
-Come on, what have you got there?
-We've come to you from the people of Rostov, Grand Duke of Kiev...
-And what need brought you here?
And Tikhon told the Prince of Kiev the story that there are still heroes in Russia.
but until Tikhon finishes the job he started, Tugarin won't punish the evil one, and Alyosha and Lyubava
and Lyubava, there's no one to look after the gold, so Tikhon beats an oath.
-Yeah, that's an interesting story.
Look at this thing...
-Hmm..., yes..., the ball is curious, I would say, original...
So, what did you say your name was?
-We should have a squad of men, and leave the gold with you, prince, for safekeeping.
-I can't give you men, you know, the time is not calm, and I have every druzhinnik in the account.
And leave the gold, as it is. If not to the Prince of Kiev, then to whom is the faith?
It's such a thing, that a constant guard is needed...
-Thank you, Prince. -Go with God.
-I wonder where in Rostov we get so much gold.
-Where is that oak tree? -I'm sorry, but I can't see it from here, and anyway,
are you sure this is a good plan? -No, but it's the only one I got.
-So here's the deal... Tugarin gives you Lyubava, and you give him the bag of gold...
there's no gold in the sack, it's me in the sack! And you're giving me to Tugarin?
Well, stop, let me out! -I'll be all right.
-No, let me out now, or I'll get hysterical!!!
-I said I'm not leaving you!
-Where is my gold?
-Where is the gold, I know, but first I would like to know my share.
-Gotcha!!! -I know. Gold must be shared.
-Oh, and he says something about gold.
-How about..., you're 40 and I'm 60, what do you think?
All right, all right... in half!
-Hey, that's our horse!
-Lubawa. ! -Alyosha!
-Alyosha!
-Excuse me, Luba, I have to help Julia.
-Who are you? А?
-It doesn't matter, he's our horse!
-I am Tugarin the Serpent, have you ever heard of him?
-We've heard of him, but he's our horse, he owes us money...
-What? That horse is mine! He knows where my gold is hidden!
-Guys, that's my horse!
-Who are you? -I'm a warrior from Rostov, Alyosha Popovich,
I've come to keep my word.
-A bogatyr...
-Where's my gold? -It's not yours!
-That's right, the gold is ours! -Alyosha...
-Alyosha! -No, I didn't.
-Huh? -Hu-hu-hu-hu!
-Fall!
-Alyosha! -Ah... Ah... Oh...
Did I do that to him? -Yes, you, Alyosha!
-I don't remember anything. -No wonder...
-Quiet, you're here, Grandma, how did you end up here?
-Don't worry, we did everything you told us to do.
We left the gold to the Prince of Kiev for safekeeping, and we decided to help you.
-And we got there just in time... -Gee-goo...
-We should tie him up before he wakes up.
-Wake up...? Ha! He's safe for now!
-Pardon me... !
Well, how are you? -Huh?
-Well, now we'll take the gold and go home.
-And let the people of Kiev admire Tugarin. Mm-hmm!
-Oh... Ya... Ya... Y-a...
-Hello, Prince of Kiev!
-Hello, hello, hello, hero of Rostov!
Come, sit down... Come to the table, be my guest!
-Don't take it as an impudence, Prince, but I have no time to feast,
The people of Rostov are waiting for me. They're waiting with their belongings, taken away by Tugarin...
-Oh?!
-Well, as you know, it's necessary, so it's necessary.
Go with God...
So what did you say happened next?
-Don't be angry, Grand Duke, but you must have forgotten that you have Rostov's gold...
in your custody?
-Huh? Ah! Yes, yes, I remember...
Hey, there... bring the bogatyr his gold...
-Aah!!!
-It is not good, Prince, to offend simple people. ! -How did I offend anyone?
I only took my share for keeping it.
-Well, prince, you've amused yourself enough with me...
It's my turn to make jokes. Try some of this bogatyr's strength...
-А!!! Wait, wait, Rostov bogatyr, don't get excited...
I can see how tough you are... I'm just the kind of vigilantes I need!
Stay here, Alyosha. You'll be fed, clothed, and endowed with the prince's affection!
-Don't be angry, Prince of Kiev, but they're waiting for us at home, in Rostov,
and without gold there's no way back for us.
And so it was agreed. And the prince returned the gold,
Tugarin Alyosha left the Prince of Kiev as a gift, the Prince
put him in a cage to please the people of Kiev, the people like to be amused.
-And, I wonder, for our exploits we don't get a share of the gold, by any chance?
Or a title of some kind?
-Well, hello, our father Rostov! We've brought back the gold of the people!
-Aah!!! God has heard us!
-Oh, look at that! The bad guy's back!
-Yeah. -Yeah. You're respected here.
-Oh, look, it's my ring! -It's not yours, it's ours!
-You've never had gold in your life!
-Let go of my father, let go of my father! -We're good, aren't we?
Well... I helped you, help me too...
One tree there owes me four horseshoes...