Climate change is very much the same.
There's never any good news,
just graphics that get more and more red and angry.
Almost every year it breaks some terrible record,
from the most intense heat waves to the fastest melting glaciers.
It doesn't end, and it has no mercy.
We have known for decades that rapid climate change is being caused by the emission of greenhouse gases.
But instead of reducing emissions, in 2019 the world was emitting 50% more CO2 than the year before.
And emissions are still growing.
I wonder why?
Why is it so difficult to stop emitting these gases?
*Opening Theme*
~ Kurzgesagt: In a Nutshell ~
Our collective CO2 emissions can be expressed as a product of 4 factors, and their relationships with each other:
Two of them explain why the world's emissions are still growing,
and two  tell me how to stop it.
Population size,
economic growth,
energy intensity,
and emissions per unit of energy produced.
Number one: population growth.
People need food, a house, clothes,
and they demand luxury goods -
from I-phones to $1 cheeseburgers.
More people, higher CO2 emissions.  It's a very simple equation.
The global population is growing and, according to the UN,
it will settle to around 11 billion by 2100
, which is 40% more than today.
The only way to slow this growth is through investments in public health,
access to contraceptives and education in developing countries.
But even with large investments, it would take a few decades
for the effects of lower fertility rates to manifest.
So the population will continue to increase for the foreseeable future
and, as a consequence, global CO2 emissions
will increase over the next few decades.
Number two: Growth, or getting richer.
But it's not just about our numbers;
the richer and more developed we are, the more emissions our lifestyle produces.
A programmer in the US has a larger CO2 footprint than 50 Ugandan farmers.
The wealth of the world grows almost everywhere.
And, despite being far from a fair distribution,
economic growth has led to the highest standards of living
and the greatest reduction in extreme poverty in human history.
"Growth" has become the dominant mantra of the world's economies,
whatever political system they have.
Rich countries are unlikely to give up the concept of growth anytime soon;
but even if they gave up, developing countries want to get rich too.
For billions of people, ending growth would likely mean staying poor,
so developing countries are not willing to stop growing their economies.
Overall, we can be sure that growth as a guiding economic ideology is
not going to leave us anytime soon.
More countries and citizens around the world will grow and become richer,
while rich economies will continue to grow their wealth.
There are some signs that growth can be decoupled from CO2 emissions,
but we're not close to that yet.
As a consequence of this growth, CO2 emissions will rise.
OK.  So far, we've learned that
because of population and economic growth,
humanity's CO2 emissions will increase -
the opposite of what should be happening.
We need to slow down, peak, and then reduce annual emissions.
The next two factors describe how we can actually do this:
Number three: Energy intensity.
Energy intensity describes how efficiently we use energy.
A street griller in rural Brazil can burn charcoal for roasting,
while a street vendor in France can use an induction oven charged with nuclear energy.
The latter is much more efficient ¯\_(ツ)_/¯
The more efficient the item, the less energy it takes to accomplish something -
whether it's supplying a metropolitan area, or grilling kebab.
So making our technology efficient and finding more efficient ways to organize our societies
is one of the most important ways to reduce the modern world's dependence on CO2.
This can have many meanings, from reducing energy consumption with artificial intelligence,
to electrifying the transport and industrial sectors,
or to sustainable concrete production.
Opportunities for improvement are almost limitless,
and human ingenuity can run wild.
But we know that increasing efficiency alone will not be enough
, mostly for three reasons:
1/3 - Direct Repercussion Effects.
This means that as soon as something becomes more efficient,
that "something" is used more so, in general,
the greater efficiency does not generate as significant a reduction as thought.
Or worse: sometimes, more efficiency doesn't make humans use less of this resource, but more of it.
As planes became more fuel efficient, ticket prices dropped
and more people traveled by plane.
So making things more efficient doesn't automatically mean less energy expenditure in total.
It can even have the opposite effect.
2/3 - Indirect Repercussion Effects.
Sometimes, when you save money using something efficient, you can spend it on something else.
For example, if you buy a fuel-efficient car,
you save on fuel costs and end up with more savings in your bank account,
which you might spend on an airplane vacation.
So, in the end, you could end up emitting more CO2,
even though you have a more efficient car.
3/3 - Lower Return on Investment
Finally, the
more you invest in efficiency, the
harder and more expensive it becomes to become even more efficient.
So, over time, the return on investment goes down –
and with many technologies, we are already very efficient.
But no matter how efficient we make our savings,
as long as we need some energy, we will have emissions.
Efficiency alone will not create a carbon-free world.
This brings us to our last factor:
Number four: CO2 emissions per unit of energy consumed, or our global carbon footprint.
Humanity's global carbon footprint
is the amount of CO2 released per unit of energy generated.
For example, coal plants release much, much more CO2 than solar energy per unit of energy.
This relationship is crystal clear;
the more fossil fuels we burn, the greater our amount of CO2.
Fossil fuels are the biggest lever humanity has at the moment.
Of course, it is impossible to turn off coal and oil overnight
without throwing humanity into chaos.
But the reality is, what we do is not close enough to keep fossil fuels in the ground
and utilize low CO2 alternatives.
We need to do two things for this transition away from fossil fuels.
First, we need to use the levers we have today with current technology.
There are many things we can do very quickly:
we can keep nuclear plants online longer;
we can cut subsidies from the fossil fuel industry and target renewables;
we can charge more for CO2 emissions, and raise the price each year,
to encourage the world's industries to transition;
we can enforce strict standards for energy efficiency, and for any type of new construction;
we can abandon vehicles to alcohol/gasoline.
Then we also need to invent new and better technologies.
Without new technologies and innovation, it would be impossible to achieve a world free of carbon emissions,
whether through technologies such as carbon capture, or a new generation of nuclear power plants,
to batteries that would revolutionize the storage of energy from renewables.
But innovation takes time;  years, and decades.
And we don't have that time.
Each year, we continue to add more carbon to the atmosphere.
This means that we cannot continue to rely on innovation alone.
We need to find ways to reduce emissions now,
while inventing what we will need in the future.
The less fossil fuel we burn over the next few years, the
more time we will give innovation to catch up.
The more low-carbon energy infrastructure we build today, the
more we can compensate for the economic growth and people born today.
The more coal plants under construction we prevent from being completed, the
more CO2 we "save".
Neither innovation nor the alternatives we use today alone can solve rapid climate change.
But innovation, coupled with a decisive move away from fossil fuels as much as possible today,
can do it.
Solving climate change will be tricky.
We have to consider the needs of billions of people and the reality that, at the moment
, society runs mainly on fossil fuels.
This will not change overnight, but it needs to change as soon as possible.
And it's still absolutely possible.
We'll look at different aspects of climate change, and how to tackle it, in other videos.  Let
us know what kinds of things you want to know more about -
here on Youtube, or join us on our subreddit.
This video is part of a series on climate change supported by Breakthrough Energy -
a coalition founded by Bill Gates that works to expand investments in clean energy
and support innovations that will move the world to near-zero carbon emissions.
We also especially thank the Our World in Data team for helping us with data and research.
*Closing theme*
~ Subtitles: Portuguese (Brazil) - by StipulateVenus ~