So, dear fellow radio listeners,
I'm reporting from our seaport!
In a few minutes, this snow-white beauty of a liner
will embark on yet another cruise,
taking away in her comfortable cabins...
a large group of Soviet tourists on a fascinating voyage.
Excuse me, please...
- Hello ... - Hello.
- Э... please tell me your patronymic name... - Semyon Semyonovich Gorbunkov!
Where do you work?
Senior economist at "Giprorib".
Nice to meet you...
Semyon Semyonovich,
what would you like to say to our dear fellow radio listeners?
э... before embarking on this fascinating journey.
Actually, to tell you the truth,
I didn't want to go.
I was thinking of buying my wife a fur coat.
- Uh-uh-uh-uh... No, the fur coat can wait.
I think the main thing is to see the world!
It really works, it really works...
The coat can wait.
Mm-hmm. So you've never been...
Of course I haven't...
We've never been further than Dubrovka. - Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha...
But you're going abroad for the first time, too?
No, I'm not going anywhere.
We're seeing Dad off!
- Oh! Well, what is it... - I can't believe it.
Fries Street, Fish Street,
- Chikanuk Pharmacy... - Lelik, I remember everything perfectly!
Everything must be authentic: I fell down, I swore...
Holy crap! Uh, sorry, "Damn it!"
Look, don't get it wrong!
Trauma, it's realistic.
As our dear boss says, it's realism that counts in our business!
Ха-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га!
Well...
It's time, tourist!
Nynado...
Go...
Good afternoon!
Good afternoon.
Is this cabin sixteen, or, pardon me, am I mistaken?
Sixteenth. Are you going here too?
Yes, let's meet. Gennady Petrovich Kozadoyev...
Pleased to meet you. Semyon Semyonovich Gorbunkov...
Pleased to meet you...
I hope we'll become friends.
Of course...
Do you take any souvenirs with you?
No, no, no, no, no!
I brought...
Vodka?
Ha-ha, ha-ha-ha-ha!
I like the song about the bunnies.
Who?
The rabbits.
Senya, about the rabbits...
That's not relevant!
"Island of Bad Luck"!
All covered with greenery, absolutely all of it,
There's an island of bad luck in the ocean
There's an island of bad luck in the ocean,
All covered with green, absolutely all of it!
There live the unhappy wild men,
♪ Horrible on the face, kind on the inside ♪
♪ Horrible on their face, good on the inside ♪
There's a miserable bunch of savages There's a miserable bunch of savages
What they do, they can't do, they can't do, they can't do!
Their mother must have given birth to them on Monday.
They must have been born on a Monday,
They can't catch a crocodile, they can't catch a crocodile
No crocodile, no coconut to catch, no coconut to grow,
Crying, praying to God, not sparing their tears,
Crying, praying to God, not sparing their tears...
No crocodile, no coconut grows...
It's not like they're slackers, and they could live,
They should take Mondays and abolish them,
They should take Mondays and cancel them,
They're not slackers, they could live!
The island has no calendar, as luck would have it,
Kids and grown-ups go to waste,
♪ Kids and grown-ups go to waste ♪
There's no calendar on the damned island!
On such an occasion, from night to dawn
The unlucky wild men weep
And weep for the poor, and curse their misfortune,
On what day - no one knows, no year!...
Wa-ba-ba-ba-pfa-ba-ba-ba-badum,
Sebo-zaba-zaba-zaba-zaba-zabazo.
O es, bi man, l'ai... uye...
So, gentlemen, here we are in what is known as the Old City.
During the reign of Emperor Shimudshin Shah the Third.
here on these hills was located
the most magnificent ensemble,
including a palace...
...a mosque with two minarets...
a harem...
О! Ayb yoh annabaden. Thomas caro romal. Yom rado liko salem jarip pogorello.
Lunda hanamarun, zigel, zigel, zigel, ai lulu... Luce paron, ai lulu, ai lulu...
You!
Are you out of your mind?
She wants to tell me something happened...
О! Rubiyo-tubiyo, lundo ehsho anabaran. Zigel-zigel, ai lulu!
"Ai-lulu" later. Noo! Niht! No! Absolutely not!
Why, does she want something?
I'll tell you what she wants later...
You know, Signora, Frau, Miss, unfortunately it's not going to work!
Rousseau touristo...
Oblico morale... fair enough?
Come on, quick, let's go!
A hack! Parteronne!
Ero vas trouhala robusta!
Allow me to thank you, Nikolai Ivanovich,
for your interesting, very interesting tour, thank you!
Comrades, attention!
Now you have free time.
You can walk around the city,
but be warned,
at exactly 5:00 p.m.
everyone must be on the boat!
No tardiness!
Do you understand?
That's it!
Gesha!
Why did you leave me...?
But who left you... Waiting...
Over there!
Inkes... tiora pan?
[But where is he?]
Morborit te, ne sobko.
[Calm down! Must come!]
Purgen last "damn it"?
[The password is old - "Damn it!"]
[Damn it!]
Damn it...
Kemeden raine, jesus swi mi Mikhail Svetlov?
[Is he really from the Mikhail Svetlov ship?]
[We were told so...]
Chiedias brak moment trazi [The boat will leave in an hour...]
Tup litek tu pado, isintes tak! Mok pintu! Pastu jurnek, nem tuulai, nik cha cha cha, zurkadelo pic!
[Shut up!]
Bor! Hu madonna dium bais! Döp peirin bako gaskara timyen branno chima ranchez särveis dins haem durälä!
[Sorry, I overreacted...]
You know... Ah! Ah!
Gesha...
Gesha!
Citizen...
А...
Aah!
Goddamn it!
- Goddamn it, goddamn it, goddamn it! - Aah!
A hap ta kapti, bupti ho!
Rousseau?
Aha!...
Mikhail Svetloff?
Yes, yes!
Sichi komas!
А... Fucking hell!
Goddamn it!
Goddamn it...?
Aah!
Quet numero uno? [What's wrong with him?]
Engom svara posva, [Really strong dislocation,].
[I've got a plaster with a srach nibedu...] [even lost consciousness...]
Könem margae. [Let's begin.]
Könem.
Berezi no kamonit.
Ecu.
Damn it,
Goddamn it!
Mikhail Svetloff...
Mikhail Svetloff, oooo!!!
Ziegel, ziegel, ziegel, ziegel...
Ziegel! Ha-ha-ha!
- Zigel! Ziegel... - Damn it!
Damn...
Ziegel, ziegel, ziegel!
Goddamn it!
Up tun!
Yippee!
Yee-hae-hae-hae-hae-hae-hae-hae-hae, eee-hae-hae-hae-hae-hae-hae-hae!
Goddamn it!
Uot kals man?
Un blancin gowf...
- Rousseau? - Russo, Russo, Russo!
- Mikhail Svetloff? - Mikhail Svetlov! It's me, me, me!
Detsi ein schmatsi? [Where were you looking, you old donkey?]
Veserra mod... [But that one also said the password "Damn it!"]
Damn it, damn it, damn it! Herrock eskusto ben slag morduk!
[Garoque escusse modiuc, ich nach!]
[What follows is an untranslatable play on words,
using local idiomatic expressions.]
- ...eledias, eledias... - ...quah tus smaitis supadois, dimkos fear.
- Mak grede manjer... - ...dyinzim sxah, tsigel tsigel, ay-lu-lu
Comrade, comrade, comrade, good ay-lu-lu, zigel, zigel - time, comrade!
These morons assured me that he was unconscious...
So this sucker doesn't know anything.
Well...
Well? What? What is it?
It's nothing. It's just smuggling.
- How? - Contra-ban-da!
Aah!
Come on, Semyon Semyonovich...
Take it easy...
Have a drink!
I don't drink...
We read in "The Week", the section for, at home for the family...
Doctors recommend it:
It calms the nervous system, dilates blood vessels...
Drink it.
Drink, drink...
- Comrade Captain, - Yes.
But what should I do now?
Nothing! Rest, dance, have fun...
But please, don't say a word about the smuggling to anyone!
I... They'll ask me what happened to my hand.
And you say:
I slipped, I fell...
closed fracture...
Lost consciousness, woke up.
a cast!
Slipped...
- Fell. Fell.
Closed fracture...
Passed out, woke up, cast.
That's right.
And about that...
I'll let you know where to go...
Thank you!
Don't you remember anything?
- Careful! - Careful...
Why, I remember...
Remember what?
I slipped...
Okay...
Fainted...
Okay.
Woke up, cast...
That's it?
That's it!
I wish I'd fallen instead of you!
What are you, Gesha... Thank you.
Take care of your hand, Senya, take care of it!
Nadya will be upset...
What to do...
That's "c'est la vie", as they say...
- Aah! -Aah!
Sorry, friend!
Comrade, should I go already?
Come in, comrade, don't hold me up.
- At all? - Yes!
Didn't the captain warn them?
What to do?
But! There he is!
It's all right, the goods are in the safe!
- And the key? - What?
As our beloved chief says,
if a man is an idiot.
then it's for a long time.
Lelik, I don't know what you're talking about?
Now you'll understand!
To the chief!
No hands!
Where are we going?
Home.
So you've been abroad?
Yes, I have!
What should I do now?
Where should I go, to the police? Or maybe go home?
So I'm going home...
Ah!
I didn't tell him the address,
where he's taking me?
There's only one way into town!
Please, Morskaya 21, apartment 9,
Third floor...
What's wrong with your hand?
Why does he want to know?
What is this mere curiosity?
Suspicious type...
Slipped, fell...
Closed fracture...
Lost consciousness, woke up with a cast.
Are you an amateur performer?
I do.
Why did I lie, I'm not involved?
Why did he ask?
He's talking...
A very suspicious guy!
Why did he swerve?
The road is straight!
And there's a repair...
A detour...
Stop, we'll take it!
Not allowed, the instruction!
If you don't hitchhike, you're not a cab driver!
Bandit!
Why didn't you introduce yourself right away?
I wanted to take a closer look first,
to see if he'd be a good match for us...
Well, did you check?
I checked, Comrade Colonel.
he'll fit.
I didn't expect him to...
with a plaster...
That's right, Comrade Colonel.
Perhaps I should...
Don't!
- Did he agree? - He agreed!
Now here's a suggestion, what if...
- You shouldn't! - I see.
Then maybe we should...
- Don't! - I see...
- Let me at least... Try this one!
You're in charge of this operation, so do it!
Report what's next!
Yes, Comrade Colonel!
When he and I were thus acquainted,
I laid out our plan.
What should I do now?
Nothing,
live your life, they'll take the bait themselves.
They will follow you, and we will follow them.
And as soon as they try to take it off.
we'll get them!
Yeah, like a bait,
I understand... a fisherman himself!
They'll offer a big ransom, of course,
and I'll haggle some more.
I don't think so,
why would they give themselves away?
They're sure you don't know anything,
They'll try to get their merchandise for free
and without your knowledge...
How do you cut off a man's cast
without being noticed?
You can...
I really don't know how they would do it...
But you can...
get them drunk,
put him to sleep,
stun them,
Well, well, from an emotionless body;
finally from a corpse...
Uh-huh...
Whose corpse?
Well... I'm sure it won't come to that...
Michal Ivanovich,
Couldn't someone else wear this cast instead of me?
to be worn by someone else instead of me?
Ah... Yes.
You can refuse, of course,
No, I'm not a coward,
but I'm afraid...
I'm afraid if I can, if I'm capable.
I think, Semyon Semyonych,
every man is capable of many things.
But, unfortunately,
not everyone knows what they are capable of.
Yes, yes, it happens...
Now let's talk about communication...
Come on, Semyon Semyonovich...
Ah... Ah!
Just a moment.
We'll keep in touch like this:
Uh-huh...
If we need you...
You'll come to me.
If you need us...
I'm calling a cab in my name.
It'll be me or my assistant, okay?
Mm-hmm.
Here you go!
Uh... Aye...
Thank you very much,
I'm sorry I...
It's all right, we've had worse...
Why don't we come over to our place?
I'll introduce you to my wife...
Semyon Semyonovich!
We agreed with you:
No one must know!
And Nadya?
No one!
I see...
Semyon Semyonovich, and the things?
Senya, open up!
Welcome, Semyon Semyonovich!
Thank you!
I'm sorry it's so late...
You know yourself...
Public business comes first!
What's wrong with your hand?
Yes...
Semyon Semyonovich...
We have your lecture in the Red Corner on Wednesday.
It's already advertised.
What lecture?
Well, of course,
except for you
no one from the housing cooperative has been there.
The theme of the lecture: "New York, the City of Contrasts."
I haven't been to New York!
Where have you been?
I've been to Istanbul, to Marseille...
Please, Istanbul is a city of contrasts, what's the difference,
Let's rewrite the ad! What happened to your arm?
Closed fracture,
lost consciousness,
woke up with a cast...
Great, great,
modest, but tasteful...
Ahhhh!
That's nice!
Aah!
F-f-f-f!
Ahhh! Heh-heh...
What a beauty!
What happened to your hand, you say, Semyon Semyonovich?
This is for you! A souvenir...
What are you...
Thank you.
Thank you, Semyon Semyonovich...
Press the button.
Yes?!
Ah-ah-ah-ah!
Ha-ha-ha-ha, ha-ha-ha-ha!
Ha-ha-ha...
Funny, huh?
Very funny.
Thank you.
Senya...
А...
Have you seen Sophia Loren?
No...
Have you been drinking Coke?
Uh-huh.
How was it?
K-k... [bleep]
Uh...
Sleep, sleep...
Sleep.
Doctors recommend...
Sleeping pills...
In the week...
for home, for family...
Sit down...
Tell me, what happened to your arm?
I slipped, fell...
Closed fracture...
Lost consciousness, woke up with a cast.
I've heard that before. Don't spare me,
I don't care if it's the worst, but it's the truth.
Tell me, what happened to your arm?
So I say,
I was walking down the street, I slipped, I...
um...
well, that's...
You can't lie, Senya!
I know what you have there.
Who told you that?
It's not a closed fracture,
but what do you have in there?
Gold, diamonds!
Don't make jokes,
You don't have a closed fracture in there,
It's an open fracture!
Let's go to bed.
Mea-ow!
You should kill for that!
Lelik only without hands, I'll fix it...
I wish you were dead!
I wish I could see you in your coffin,
in white slippers!
I wish you lived
on one
your paycheck!
Victor Nikolayevich,
Can't you read?
А?
H-h-h-h...
Mama, look how I can... Hee...
You can't do that...
- You can't. - Wait a minute...
There, like that...
And I'm telling you, our yards aren't planned for walks.
What are they for?
For aesthetics.
And where would he walk?
You have a separate apartment.
- Yes. - There and walk!
And where would he...?
Well, why so, why...
Good morning!
How do you do?
I, Varvara Sergeyevna, have been to London,
and there dogs walk everywhere...
The dog is man's friend!
I don't know what it's like in London...
I have not been ...
Maybe there a dog is a friend of man!
But here...
The supervisor is a friend of man!
Hello!
Pops,
do you have a light?
Huh?
Ah, ah, ah...
Are you deaf or something?
Yes...
I see...
There he is!
Lopus...
We'll take him without a fuss!
Go on, take him fishing,
to the black rocks, as agreed.
Invite him overnight...
Don't make a fuss:
Ice cream for the kids,
and flowers for his woman.
Don't get it wrong.
Kutuzov!
Ah-ha!
Gyo-e!
Idiot!
Ice cream for the kids!
Uh-oh!
The eye is nothing, it'll pass!
Senya, how's your arm?
It's nothing.
- It doesn't hurt? - Nope.
Well, wiggle your fingers...
No, not those, those...
Yeah...
There, that's all right.
It'll do.
Gennady Petrovich,
you, as Senin's friend, should influence him.
He's taking it too lightly.
You know, he wanted to trick me...
That's not at all what Daddy tells everyone, hee-hee...
Why?
After all, it's not a closed fracture,
It's an open fracture!
Heh-heh-heh-heh...
Zing...
Come to Mama!
Senya, let's go fishing, huh?
Let's go to the Black Rocks,
take a boat, sleep overnight,
we'll sit out the evening dawn.
Sen?
- Well? No,
I'm not going on an overnight trip,
I'm afraid of getting a cold.
How about first thing in the morning?
That's it!
Let's do it in the morning,
what do you mean in the morning?!
- In the morning! - That's it!
Па-ба-ба-ба-ба-ба-ба-ба!
Oh, es bi man...
Maxim...
What are you doing?
How can you do that?
Apologize to your uncle right now!
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Good boy...
Eh...
Author's team:
artist - Margarita Semyonova,
architect - Rogal Levitskaya,
chief designer - Albert Mudrik.
Summer Combination Suit
"Universal-69".
Incentive award
at the interregional forum of modern clothes
in Zhitomir.
Original constructive solution
allows you to easily turn a jacket...
into a jacket!
But that's not all!
With a slight movement of the hand...
the pants turn...
The pants turn...
turn your pants...
into elegant shorts!
Sorry, a little technicality...
And last but not least...
the Mini Bikini 69 beach ensemble!
What happened,
why is the chief here?
Things are changing,
We're going to do the operation at White Rock...
Why not at the Black Rocks?
It's too crowded during the day...
But there's no nibble at White Rock...
Nibble!
There'll be a nibble, I'll take care of that.
There'll be so much nibbling..,
that the customer will forget all about it!
Everything goes according to plan?
It's just as we agreed.
You stun him a little...
There you go!
Lelik,
But it's not aesthetically pleasing...
But it's cheap, reliable and practical!
Quickly remove the plaster,
and wash it off!
And my alibi?
Oh yes, you're left with signs of violence on your face...
Just like the victim of an attack by unknown assailants...
Lolek! Only I ask you to...
Don't worry, Kozodoev...
Kozadoyev!
Kozlodoyev!
I'll hit it gently,
but hard!
Ха-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га!
Good evening, Marya Nikolayevna.
Good evening, Semyon Semyonovich.
Where are you off to in the middle of the night?
Early in the morning we went fishing,
and we missed it, and there was no bread...
Now we're going to the avenue to the duty lady,
It's a long way, but I have to...
Yes, yes, yes...
Ahhhh!
Yes...
Poor guy...
Guys,
it should be me.
If you're drunk, you will be!
- Let's load it up! - Come on, pick it up!
Waaaayyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyy!
Heavy... Oops! Into the baby carriage... That's it...
Shit! Come on... let's go.
Good evening, Semyon Semyonovich!
Good evening.
But I don't know you...
Volodya.
Senya.
My regards to you from Michal Ivanovich!
Ah...
Thank you!
He wanted to see you very much.
When?
Any time now!
А... I'll be late for the bread...
Don't worry, I have my car,
Let's go...
Well, Volodya,
thank you very much!
- You shouldn't. - Have a good time.
Have a good time,
and have a great time!
So you'll definitely be at the Black Rocks?
Yes, yes, the Black Rocks.
Well, break a leg!
To hell, to hell!
Good night, Semyon.
Good night, Semyon Semyonovich!
Yes...
Our people
don't take cabs to the bakery!
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
It seems to be here...
Or maybe...
We shouldn't have come here,
The Black Rocks are closer and the bite is better there.
If I'm not mistaken,
there'll be so much nibbling, you'll forget all about it.
Get out of here!
Help!!!
SOS...
Help!
Lyolik!
Idiot!
Ugh!
Mommy!
Lelik!!!
Help!!!
Mommy!!!
Why are you shouting?
Go away boy, don't interfere...
Mom...
Mm...
Ahh... ah... ah... ah...
Let us pray to God...
Lord have mercy...
Holy God, we give glory to you,
Father and son and holy spirit, now and ever, and forever and ever...
Have mercy...
Get out of the way, you little puppy!
Get out of here!
Flying ducks...
Flying ducks... ducks...
and-and two geese...
Yes... м...
The chief is giving us an opportunity to rehabilitate...
The location of the operation, code-named "The Game."
What?
A game!
He's designated the Weeping Willow summer restaurant
Strictly north,
about...
50 meters,
there's a restroom,
like a latrine,
indicated in the diagram by the letters "Mae" and "Jo.
The asphalt path leading to the toilet goes past the puff,
where I will be located.
This is our disposition...
Now your task...
You bring the customer into the restaurant,
you get him to the right state of mind,
and take them out quickly to freshen up...
After making sure the customer is following the direction you want him to go..,
with the words "Senya, I'm waiting for you at the table"
you quickly return to your original position...
Your alibi is secured.
The client, passing by the fir tree, falls into my hands...
And the rest is a matter of technique.
- You got it?! - Yum, yum...
Ah, Lyolik, I'm just afraid, how to bring him to the point?
He's a low drinker.
As our dear boss says,
even teetotalers drink at other people's expense
and sober men.
Ха-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га!
Hmm, you can't get a cab on one paycheck...
A hundred grand in a row, please.
О!
Whoever gets a stack of tickets gets...
Water bottle!
Drop your stupid campaigning,
I'm not buying tickets to win!
What are you buying tickets for?
You should read the papers!
Why?
Hmm...
Distribute it among the tenants of our building!
- And if...? А... - And if they don't take it, we'll cut off the gas!
Well, everything is clear...
Go to the thrift shops,
and look at the market,
Sit in a restaurant...
You can go to the train station...
Go in.
In a word, be more visible!
Yes...
Naturally, you'll have expenses...
Here, take it.
No, no, that's all right, I'll do it myself...
Semyon Semyonovich,
let's not do anything amateurish!
Here's 500 rubles...
With new ones?
Ouch...
What's wrong with your head?
Money!
Semyon Semyonovich...
Got it!
Here...
What for?
Well, as they say, just in case of emergency,
take it!
I haven't held a combat weapon since the war...
But it's not a combat weapon, it's more of a psychological one...
You can scare them off if you need to,
give a signal...
It's loaded with blanks.
Give me a live one!
What for?
Just in case...
Don't!
I see...
- Semyon Semyonovich, what are you... Ah!... Oooh...
Uh...?
Uh... ah...?
А?
That's the way to do it!
Uh-huh...
Fedenka...
and it would be good...
a game.
Let's do...
What shall we drink, vodka, cognac?
I'd like a beer...
All right, we'll start with a bottle of vodka
and a bottle of cognac...
A couple of beers!
Yes, sir.
Oh, I have to call my mother...
- I'll be right... - Yeah.
Good evening, Boris Savelyevich,
I've ordered a Fede game...
I beg you very much...
Lelik, I'm waiting,
the client will be all right...
The chief himself is here,
waiting...
Available?
Occupied!
This is it...
Here we go...
Just take it easy,
we have to act...
Can you tell me, please,
where's the phone?
Thank you...
Cab?
This is Semyon Semyonovich Gorbunkov.
Gorbunkov.
Yes, yes, Gorbunkov.
Send a cab to the Weeping Willow Restaurant.
It's urgent.
Thank you.
Well, let's get started, shall we?
No, no, no, I'll have a beer...
No, no...
Yeah, he does,
Let him see me drinking.
Coo-coo...
Here's to your bonus.
God forbid it's not your last.
You don't eat after the first one!
Vodka...
Here's to your health...
Come on!
Peek-a-boo!
Drink...
I am convinced
that each and every one of you,
when they find the treasure,
will do exactly the same as me!
What will you do with the bonus?
With my legal bonus, I,
on the advice of my friends,
I decided to buy
a Moskvich car.
A new model...
I'll be right there!
The client is ripening, be ready!
Always ready!
Idiot...
Pardon...
Ха-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га!
Who are you here to see?
You!
But?
Don't you recognize me?
I don't recognize you...
How about a drink?
A drink!
I didn't recognize you right away either...
- Yeah? Mm-hmm.
Why did you shave off your mustache?
What?
I said, why did you shave off your mustache, stupid?
Who?
Excuse me, with whom do I have the honor?
Ladyzhensky, Yevgeny Nikolayevich,
this fool's school friend!
Do you know why Volodya shaved off his mustache?
A mustache?...
Senya,
Quickly, explain to the comrade,
why Volodya shaved off his mustache.
We don't have much time. Drink!
Senya?
Heh heh heh, heh heh heh!
I'm sorry, I was mistaken...
Here's your mustache...
Just like Volodya Trynkin!
Just like him!
Comrade, when is your plane?
Yes...
It's time...
Well, if you come to Kolyma...
If you come to Kolyma, you're welcome.
No, you'd better come with us.
Goodbye...
Good thing he's not a smuggler,
A handsome man...
Why did I get so drunk?
Senya,
Have you come to the point yet?
- To what? - The right one!
No...
- One more drink, then! - No, no, no, no, no more... No more!
- I have to! - That's it!
Senya...
Do you respect me?
I do, but I won't drink!
Then I'll bite you!
Bite me!
A-gy-gy...
Gesha... Gesha... Gesha... Gesha... Gesha...
There are people everywhere!
Gesha!
Do you want some game?
With game - I will!
Fedya, game!
A game!
Shh...
Is this a game?
It's game!
- You don't drink vodka with game! - Why?
You drink this... Shh, shh, shh...!
Got it, got it... Fedya! Another 150 champagne, and that's it!
Yes...
- Cheers! - Thank you.
I think it's time for you to freshen up...
Senya, it's time to freshen up.
Come on, let's go.
- And the game? - Let's go.
The game won't fly away, it's fried.
Quickly!
Senya, don't mess around, quick!
Strictly to the north, about 50 meters ...
Hurry up!
Well?
Senya!
A song about hares!
In the dark blue forest,
Where the aspens tremble,
Where the witch hazel oaks
The leaves are falling away.
In the glade the grass
The hares were mowing at midnight
And they sang
Strange words.
We don't care, we don't care,
We're afraid of the wolf and the owl.
We have things to do,
♪ In our darkest hour ♪
♪ We're doing the magic ♪
We mow the grass.
And the witch hazel oaks
Something whispers in the fog.
The shadows of the marshes are rising.
The hares are mowing the grass,
The grass on the meadow
And they sing faster and faster out of fear.
We don't care, we don't care,
Even if we're afraid of the wolf and the owl.
We have things to do,
At the most dreadful hour
We're mowing the magic weed.
We don't care, we don't care,
♪ We believe in the old saying ♪
The brave one is the one who three times a year,
At the most dreadful hour he mows the weed.
We don't care, we don't care,
We'll be braver than two times two,
Let us stand for once in our darkest hour,
We'll be in trouble and we'll be in trouble.
And we don't care, and we don't care,
We'll be braver than two times two,
We'll stand our ground in the darkest hour,
We'll be a darned sight better than a darned sight.
Well...
We'll have to take action, but what can we do?
Fight drunkenness!
But... You know Varvara Sergeyevna...
I know everything more than you do, my dear!
Where did he get the money?
His comrade invited him, he got a bonus.
And according to the protocol,
your husband paid 97 rubles 18 kopecks for one broken mirror window!
Where did he get that kind of money?
After returning from there...
Your husband is different!
The corrupting influence of the West...
These toys are idiotic!
And that strange phrase:
"The dog is man's friend"...
Weird, to say the least...
And these are...
Elements of the sweet life...
And you know, I wouldn't be surprised
if tomorrow it turns out
that your husband
is secretly visiting his mistress!
What?
Is this yours?
It's mine...
Where's it from?
From there...
They took it!
But how could he?
Ah, he's so trusting...
Aaah!... hand...
He was tortured! How could I not have guessed before?
My goodness!
We don't care...
What should we do?
And the children?
What will happen to them?
Ah-ah! What a shame!
Ah-ah... There's only one way out...
Only one.
That's enough...
That's enough!
Champagne in the morning
or aristocrats or degenerates!
Aah!
Meow, meow, meow!
Let's go see the chief.
Dressed like that...
I can't.
I have to... first...
take a bath,
Have a cup of coffee...
You'll have a va-anna,
There'll be coffee,
♪ There'll be a caca and a tea... ♪
Let's go!
Aah!
Meow!
Let's go...
Gesha...
Aaah!
Boo!
А?
Nadia!
- Senya... - Nadia!
Senya...
Calm down, calm down!
You have, you have a way out.
Yes...
You have to go and confess yourself!
You!
To what?
The adultery!
How could you think such a thing,
you, my wife, the mother of my children!
Oh, God! Oh, woe is me!
Why, what was I supposed to think?
Anything but that!
Oh, woe is me!
Oh, woe to me!
Where did you get the gun and the money?
Shut up, you wretched woman!
Shut up!
Senya!
Tell me, where did you get the gun and the money?
I'm begging you, Senya, tell me!
All right...
I'll tell you, but not a word to anyone!
I swear!
This is a state secret...
The gun and the money
I received for a responsible special mission...
Ah-ah-ah!... Which one?
I can't tell you that!
- Aah! - Bye...
When the time comes, you'll find out...
Maybe I'll even...
...rewarded...
posthumously...
That's a great plan, chief.
It'll be ready by 12:00.
Genius!
Good afternoon!
F-f! Uge-ga-ga-ga-ga-ga-ga!
Bonjour!
Bonjour, madame...
- Pardon. - Meow!
I am happy to welcome you to this humble, cozy...
Hello, boy!
I'm from the chief.
It's all set...
Your credentials?
Passport...
ready!
Where?
Hotel Atlantic.
Two-bedroom suite... paid for!
Customer?
Mm... Face...
Profile...
Fee?
Oh...
For now, a down payment.
Mhyahu-yah!
One pill is enough.
Tell me, please,
Do you have one without wings?
Unfortunately, no...
- No, do you? - No.
We'll look for it...
Don't you have one just like it but
with mother-of-pearl buttons?
Unfortunately, no...
No, yes... we'll look for it...
- Are you me? - Yes!
I'm sorry...
I heard...
I happen to have what you're looking for...
And it's the one with the mother-of-pearl buttons!
Only it's at my hotel...
- Do you really need it? - Yes!
Then I'll give you the address.
I live at the Hotel Atlantic.
It's not far from here.
Hello...
Is nine o'clock okay with you?
- Yeah. - That's fine!
You're welcome.
I'll be waiting for you.
At nine o'clock, at nine o'clock sharp,
Atlantic Hotel, room 327, Anna Sergeyevna...
Nine o'clock, nine o'clock sharp...
I smell a real fish in my liver.
What does she look like?
- Does it? - Yes.
Oh...
I see...
Be careful not to repeat yesterday's mistake!
Ahh... Eh! I don't drink at all.
A friend invited me.
By the way, how's he doing after last night?
I don't know, he hasn't called yet.
- He's a good man... - You think so?
All right, go to the hotel, act as you see fit.
Possible accomplices, check it out!
Do you have a weapon on you?
Mental...
They'll hear you.
Give me a note!
French, Chanel, Number Five...
Let's go!
Ah! ah...
Ta-da-ri, ta-da-ri,
# Ta-da-ri, rah-rah-ri-ram #
Where are you going?
А.. Special mission?
Be careful, you hear!
Don't worry, you'll be fine!
Sen!
Ahhh!
F-f-f-f!
Go!
Cleanth has arrived!
Dobro.
Ahhhhhhhhhh!
Five, five, he's in,
over!
Roger, Roger, Roger!
Hotel... 327,
Anna Sergeyevna...
Nine-zero-zero...
Haha!
Yes, yes, come in!
Ah, here we are...
- Good evening! Good evening!
Please sit down, I'll be right with you...
What's wrong with you?
What's the matter with you?!
It's just...
The cufflink rolled up...
Here...
I'm kicking myself!
Oh, you scared me!
Let me help you...
I thought something was wrong...
Listen to my heartbeat...
Is it beating?
S-beat.
Follow the signal,
as soon as he falls asleep, she'll turn out the lights...
Lelik, what if he leaves now?
Gesha, would you leave a woman like that?
I wouldn't, but he's a faithful husband!
Ooh! As our dear chief says, there is no husband
who, even for an hour, wouldn't dream of being a bachelor!
- Ха-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га! - Hee-hee, hee-hee... Hee-hee, hee-hee...
Watch the signal!
We'd like to talk about... the robe...
Oh, I didn't tell you,
a friend should be bringing it over any minute.
Are you in a hurry?
No, I'm in no hurry...
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
How about a glass of wine in the meantime?
I'd like a...
A beer...
Hm-m-m-m-m... No, just wine!
The words of love you spoke to me in the city of stone,
And lanterns with yellow eyes guided us through the fog.
I have never been able to love so fiercely, so ardently.
In my soul you have inadvertently awakened a volcano.
Help me, help me
...for our chance acquaintance...
...call the yellow-eyed night.
Drink, drink!
Drink...
Ff...
See the heart perish, ah, perish
In the fiery lava of love.
Where's the girl? # Maybe tomorrow I'll...
What's the use of a girlfriend?
My robe is almost like that one...
Mm-hmm...
Take a look!
...drinking and waiting for news.
You called me a clever girl, a sweet girl,
But could not understand that you were joking with a volcano of passions.
Help me, help me, help me,
Yellow-eyed night call.
See, ah, the heart is dying, ah, dying
In the fire-breathing lava of love.
In the fire-breathing lava of love. Woof!
The twilight smells of Jamaican rum, blue and long.
And the city of stone still drinks and waits for news.
The sunset has once more painted the street with colors that are marvelous.
...swirling over the volcano of passions.
Help me, help me, help me,
Yellow-eyed night call.
See, ah, the heart perishes, ah, the heart perishes.
In the fiery lava of love.
It's not my fault! He came of his own accord!
I saw your "special assignment."
After such a monstrous lie, I don't want to be with you and I can't be with you!
I'm sure my children, when they grow up, will understand.
I'll file for divorce myself. Goodbye!
Good morning, Semyon Semyonovich!
No, I have to go to Dubrovka immediately.
That's right, but not now.
We'll send you a car tomorrow morning,
the usual cab.
8 a.m. Is that convenient for you?
Why not today?
I have a favor to ask of you today.
What is it?
You must meet your friend.
What friend?
Well, the one you were with...
on a fishing trip, in a restaurant...
Ah... Gennady Petrovich...
Uh-huh. You'll meet him,
and casually tell him that tomorrow
You're leaving for Dubrovka at eight in the morning.
Uh-huh...
And most importantly, tell him,
also casually, by the way,
that the day after tomorrow you'll have your cast off.
Gena?
Yes!
And why didn't you...
So as not to scare away bigger fish!
Pardon...
And the town was drinking spicy cocktails,
and drank and waited for news.
- Help me... - You sing well!
Mm-hmm. Oh, come on... Mhh-ha-ha-ha...
Please tell me, have you known citizen Gorbunkov S... С.?
Yes, unfortunately, ten years!
And what, all these ten years he was drinking, debauched, and, so to say, morally degraded?
Well, no, you know,
all that time he's been cleverly disguising himself as a decent man.
I don't believe him!
But if you know a man well, you should always believe him.
Oh, no,
I think a man should only be trusted as a last resort.
- You think so? - I do.
Ooh!
By the way... Who are you?
Well, I know him from work, let's say, a colleague...
Right - a drinking buddy!
Get out of here,
Misha!
As you say there, go to the house. Go, go!
All right, all right, I'll leave now, just one question:
Tell me, did you fasten it well?
Don't worry, drunkard, you won't break it!
Now take it off!
Chief, it's all gone. It's all gone.
The cast comes off, the customer leaves.
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha! Blech, blech...
I'm gonna kill him! I'll wo... м... м... м... м...
- Uhh! Uhh! Uhh! Aah!
Uhh! Uhh! Uhh! Uhh! Uhh!
Good morning, Semyon Semyonovich!
Where are you going so early?
To my place, to Dubrovka.
Ah...
Who ordered a cab to Dubrovka?
Я!
Uh... Get in!
- I'm off. - Goodbye!
I met you and all the old things
In my dead heart came alive...
- I remembered the time... - Couldn't Mikhail Ivanovich come?
- Golden... - And Volodya?
- And my heart... - Busy...
- And my heart is... - What's your rank?
What's your rank?
Like Volodya, Lieutenant of the Militia?
Laitinant.
I'm the senior lieutenant... yeah...
Comrade Senior Lieutenant,
may I call you by your rank in front of your wife
"Comrade Senior Lieutenant"?
- Yes... - For the sake of respectability, may I?
Yes... I'll allow it!
Thank you!
Make sure you tell her that I did your special assignment
at the restaurant... and more importantly, in the hotel!
- Yeah... - So she won't worry,
- Tomorrow they'll take it off anyway... - Yeah...
You don't tell her anything about smugglers,
gold, diamonds...
No, I can't do that!
- Comrade Chief... No, I have to consult with the chief!
With the bosses...
- Michal Ivanovich? - Gee!... with Mikhal Ivanovich.
Michal...
Hello Michal Ivanovich!
Hello, hello, chief, it's me...
Hello, chief, it's me - Lyolik.
Lyolik!
He left for Dubrovka, about 20 minutes ago,
in a cab, a beige Volga.
28-70 OGO
Uh-huh...
I got it, I got it.
The gent on verst 19...
So, without him...
А... Got it...
I begin to act, without noise and dust, according to the newly approved plan...
Everything
- How was it? - Greetings from Michal Ivanovich!
- Thank you. - Heh-heh-heh-heh...
- Well? - Everything will be all right,
even better,
you'll come back to your wife like a cucumber,
no cast, no dust, no noise.
- Michal Ivanovich allowed to take the cast off today. - Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
- Did you get it? - Got him!
- And who is he? - A lout!
- Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha! - Aha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
Why go back,
let's not waste time...
We've got a point on the highway, we'll get the cast off there.
As our dear chief, Mikhal Ivanovich, says:
"Make the iron, without leaving the box office!
- Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha! - Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
Quickly remove the cast, disembowel him, and we'll be all right...
Comrade Senior Lieutenant,
I just ask you to take all the valuables according to the inventory!
What are you talking about? In the proper form:
inventory, protocol, handed over, accepted, fingerprints...
Ха-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га-га!
The whole operation will take no more than 15 minutes.
Let it soak,
while I gather up
the stuff.
Business...
It's a nice setup you got here.
Yeah, I got to get my claws into it,
because the brass at
ordered a change of location,
to relocate,
so...
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha...
Your... Your mustache has come off...
Thank you...
Hands up!
Seven, seven, what do you see on the track?
Report.
I'm seven, reporting:
there's a Moloko tanker heading towards town;
no cab detected,
continuing survey, over...
Seven, seven, no beige cab entered Dubrovka,
check the 45th square!
Stop!
Wait a minute!
- Please, take me to town! - What happened?
It's a matter of national importance! There may be a chase...
- I'll take you, I'll take you, all right. - Hurry up!
Hurry up!
I'm still just learning...
Come on, time!
Time is money!
As they say, when you see money, don't waste time.
Make the iron, don't move away from the cash register!
Hands... uver!
Wallpaper! I'll kill you!
Ha, ha, ha! You shouldn't have tried... there are no diamonds!
- What do you mean? - No, that's all!
And how do you know they were there?
And the one with the glued mustache thought they were there too...
They've been with the police for a long time... Chief!
Stop!
Stop, you idiots!
As an acquaintance of mine used to say,
a dead man:
I knew too much...
Hm-hm-hm...
Five, I'm seven, report:
On a forest road, at high speed, in the direction of the state border,
a cherry-colored Moskvich is moving,
Over!
Seven, seven, listen to my command!
Mama!
Lelik, stop it, Lelik! Aah! Lelik!
Calm down, Kozladoev, let's sit down all!
I met you and all the past...