The 25th Amendment
Section 1
In case of the removal of the President
from office or of his death or resignation,
the Vice President shall become President.
Section 2
Whenever there is a vacancy
in the office of the Vice President,
the President shall nominate a Vice President
who shall take office upon confirmation
by a majority vote of both Houses of Congress.
Section 3
Whenever the President transmits
to the President pro tempore of the Senate
and the Speaker of the House of Representatives
his written declaration that he is unable
to discharge the powers and duties of his office,
and until he transmits to them
a written declaration to the contrary,
such powers and duties shall be discharged
by the Vice President as Acting President.
Section 4
Whenever the Vice President and a majority of either
the principal officers of the executive departments
or of such other body as Congress may by law provide,
transmit to the President pro tempore of the Senate
and the Speaker of the House of Representatives
their written declaration that the President
is unable to discharge the powers and duties of his office,
the Vice President shall immediately assume
the powers and duties of the office as Acting President.
Thereafter, when the President transmits
to the President pro tempore of the Senate
and the Speaker of the House of Representatives
his written declaration that no inability exists,
he shall resume the powers and duties of his office
unless the Vice President and a majority
of either the principal officers of the executive department
or of such other body as Congress may by law provide,
transmit within four days
to the President pro tempore of the Senate
and the Speaker of the House of Representatives
their written declaration that the President is
unable to discharge the powers and duties of his office.
Thereupon Congress shall decide the issue,
assembling within forty-eight hours
for that purpose if not in session.
If the Congress, within twenty-one days
after receipt of the latter written declaration,
or, if Congress is not in session,
within twenty-one days after Congress is required to assemble,
determines by two-thirds vote of both Houses
that the President is unable
to discharge the powers and duties of his office,
the Vice President shall continue
to discharge the same as Acting President;
otherwise, the President shall resume
the powers and duties of his office.