Hello, Internet.
Each final, finished, precisely polished video you see
stands atop a mountain of material you don't.
Books and papers,
and sometimes investigative travels,
time lost and confused
in the infinite diverging paths
of The Forest of All Knowledge.
Writing a script to try to light the way.
The final video takes hundreds of human hours to carefully craft.
The whole mountain couldn't possibly fit in
otherwise there would never be a video.
But what has to be left out is sometimes heartbreaking!
Not to mention the Easter eggs
and little details that are put in
but can easily go unnoticed.
So, I'm going to talk about some of
the behind-the-scenes in a more casual,
force-myself-not-to-prepare-too-much-otherwise-it'll-never-happen
Director’s Commentary for crowdfunders
who make all of this possible in the first place.
If when you clicked this video,
the thumbnail said 'LIVE' then, it's live right now.
I'm Director Commenting and you can join
the chat to ask questions about the newest video.
If there was no ‘LIVE’
then you can watch the archive of previous ones.
So, if you're interested, please click here to sign up
and check out the commentaries.
I hope you like them, and thank you.
(soft playful electronic music fades out)