The Chris Columbus movie
Cast: Mkali Kalki
Joe Peskey
Daniel Stern
John Heard
Kathryn O'Hara
Home alone 2
Get lost in New York
Also starring Eddie Bracken
Devin Rattray
Kieran Culkin, Jerry Bemman
Rob Schneider, Dena Ivey, Hilary Wolff
Tim Curry
Brenda Fricker, and others.
Composer: John Williams
Directed by Chris Columbus
Nobody knows how to play
Where are the golf balls?
Has anyone seen my sun cream?
What's the point of going to Florida if you have to put the sun cream?
I don't care if I use a whole suitcase, I'm getting sick
Choose now you'll just be crying with darker skin
Bass is just jealous because it doesn't turn black. freckles just join together
Hey-hey, don't drink too much.
We have already collected rubber sheets
And let's see what it will open
two hundred points is fine
That gives you four thousand seven hundred points
Two hundred points is good.
Honey, have you gathered yet?
Yes. Yes.
What did I put?
Yes!
Oh, and did you see what Grandma Penelope sent for your trip?
I will try to wear it. Slippers with donald?
Quite close
An inflatable clown to play with in the pool
Don't let my heart burst with joy
Why are we going to Florida? There is no Christmas tree in Florida
Kevin why do you stick to Christmas trees?
After all, how can you celebrate Christmas without a Christmas tree, Mom?
We will buy a good silver artificial one. Or we will decorate a palm tree
Yesterday, new star Bin Dentong was hosted at the world famous Plaza Hotel
To book a room at New York's finest hotel, call the following toll-free number: one, eight hundred, seven hundred and fifty nine, three thousand...
Honey do you know where the batteries are for this?
I put it to charge
How is this?
This one is better
Hey Kevin, you better go tie your tie
Shouldn't we be late for the holiday performance?
My tie is in the bathroom, I can't get in - uncle is showering
He said that if I come in and see him naked, I won't feel like a real man when I grow up
I didn't understand what he wanted to say
He was definitely joking
Just go in, grab your tie, get out, and don't look left or right
Pull a rud, you degenarate puppy, or you'll eat tadpoles
Now it's Kevin's solo, tell Leslie
Kevin's solo is coming, tell Frank
It was. Frank. Frank.
End it! End it!
Kevin!
Ladies and gentlemen, members of the jury
I apologize to my family for the inconvenience I caused
What?
My joke was childish and inappropriate
Childish, not childish, I died of snoring
I would also like to apologize to my brother
Kevin, I'm sorry
Oh Bass!
good job
Kevin, don't you have anything to say?
can you please?
I'm not asking for forgiveness, I did the right thing, Bas humiliated me and always
comes out from under it. It's not, but because you're so stupid as to believe it
its lies, i don't care if your stupid trip to florida is successful or not
And in general, what sane person celebrates Christmas in the heat?
Kevin, if you leave the room now, you're going to sleep on the third floor
Here's what it is
What else can you say?
You better not ruin my trip, you grumpy, your father spent a lot of money
Oh, I wouldn't want to spoil your fun, Mr. Pathetic Line
What a troubled young man!
It's a collection of idiots
Hey!
You know Kevin, last time we wanted to go on vacation we had the exact same problem
Uh, spilling all the crap on my head
I don't care about your choice of words
It wasn't like that last time and it's not like that now
Baz apologized to you
Yes, how? Then he called me an elephant, and he was not sincere at all
It was all about you
It would be good if you stay here and think a little about what has happened, and when you are ready
to apologize to Buzz and the family, you can come down
I'd rather flush the toilet than apologize to Buzz
Then you'll stay here all night
Great, I don't want to go downstairs anyway
None of you can be trusted. And you know what, if you are money?
If I had, I would go on a separate trip
Alone, without anyone, and I would spend the best days of my life
Well, last year your wish came true, maybe this year too?
I hope
>
More of the same?
OK, our McCallisters drive the car on the right, the other McCallisters drive the car on the left
I know I shouldn't complain, after all I'm traveling for free, but you guys
Are you the world's worst alarm clock?
Frank, what about the tickets?
They are near me. these are your family's, these are mine
How many do you have? - Seven
Seven more to me
Fourteen.
Seven, eight, nine, ten. - Why don't we sit together?
I'll be lucky if we end up on the same plane
Eleven, twelve, thirteen
where is kevin
Fourteen
I'd better keep my ticket with me, see you again
do you want to forget me again?
- Come on Kevin
- Dad I need batteries
- I have them in my bag, I will give them on the plane
There are both
Now give me another one, I'll take it
Not now. What is our gate?
Uh, seventeen, sir
thank you
which gate was it?
Seventeen, Bass. We went to Kevin
Will you take my bag?
Come come
American Airlines flight number "two, two, six" is preparing to take off to New York
Well, well, soon!
Dad, wait!
wait
let's go, let's go, quickly
dad wait
here we are, here we are
We made it
Are you all here?
Madam, please come in, the plane is about to take off
Let me see, is that all?
We'll let everyone in
Merry Christmas
- Have a nice flight
- success
Wait, people, wait for me!
You barely made it
Really?
- Merry Christmas
- Merry Christmas!
Wait! wait!
Wait!
I apologize
Nothing, nothing. Is this your missile?
Yes, I am with my family, they are already on the plane, I don't want to stay here either
Do you have a ticket?
Somewhere here...
They are already ready for flight
Tell him not to fly. The same thing happened last year, my Christmas was ruined
Are you sure your family is on this plane?
Yes, my dad walked in just as we collided
Okay, put him on the plane, but make sure he finds his family
It was, come on
Well, where is your family?
Uh, it's my dad
Very well, go find a free place. Merry Christmas
Yours too
Ladies and gentlemen, in order to prepare for take off, all passengers need to be seated and fasten their seat belts.
Have you ever been to Florida?
Welcome to American Airlines
Flight number one, seven, six to New York, non-stop
It seemed to me that we would not make it
What's the matter, my dear?
I kind of am
Did we forget something?
No, I don't think we've forgotten, but you kind of have a premonition.
Just bad memories
We have done everything, we have brought everything, everyone is here
Nothing to worry about
Ha, ha, you're right, you're right, everything is fine
Mom?
Dad?
Frank?
Baz?
(the film was recorded for the moviesinarm.ru website. Watch all movies in HD quality on the moviesinarm.ru website)
We were the last
Where are they?
Is it Megan's? Brooke: Give it to Brooke. This is Kevin
- Give it to Kevin
Take it, Kevin!
- Kevin is not here
What?
Kevin!
Sorry, it's an emergency
Yes, sir?
- What city is this
- New York, sir?
I did the same thing again
Is something wrong sir?
It will be good
Oh, come on. My family is in Florida and I'm in New York
My family is in Florida.
i new york?
What is the baby's name?
Kevin.
When was the last time you saw it?
In the car?
No, he was at the doors, he was with us at the airport
Most people lose each other during the inspection. Did everyone pass the inspection?
I don't know, Peter?
We were in a hurry, we ran towards the goal all the time
When did you notice Kevin was gone?
When we were already receiving luggage
- Has your son ever run away from home
- No
Has he ever been left alone?
In fact, something like this has happened before
This is already becoming a McCallister camping tradition
It's funny that we never lose our suitcases
We left it at home last year, by accident
Yes, that's what my wife meant by family tradition
We will call Chicago and
we will inform about the situation, it is possible that it will be there
We are grateful
Unlikely to be anywhere else
Be careful, boy!
Where is your card?
This is New York, Marv, the land of opportunity
Can you smell it?
Yes՜
You know what?
- Fish
- Freedom
No, it's a fish
It's freedom and money
Okay, okay, it's freedom
Okay, let's go before we get caught
But it is the fish.
It's easy and fast
Then we take fake passports and go to distant countries
Arizona?
That was very cute, Marv. We escaped from prison. to steal fourteen cents from Santa Claus?
Well, "grinder" is always a benefit, taste too
we got a new nickname: we will be "sticky bandits".
"Sticky Bandits" at the Plaza Hotel, New York's coolest hotel
Mental
What happened
I saw something, as if
>
It was the place, move, go!
Like I liked it
- Excuse me, where is the hall?
- Down the corridor to the left
- Thank you
Yesterday, new star Ding Dang Dong was hosted at the world famous Plaza Hotel
In the most wonderful hotel in New York. To book a room, call the following toll-free number
one, eight hundred, seven hundred and fifty nine, three thousand
But I won't call
Greetings, Peter McCallister's father speaking
I need a room with a big bed, a TV and a small fridge that can be locked with a key
Credit card now?
Plaza reservation department: how can I help you
Greetings, Peter McCallister's father speaking
I need a room
Sex, of course
With a large bed, TV
and with a small refrigerator, closed with a key
You must have a major credit card
Credit card now?
Thank you, happy holiday.
Two on eight, Henry, Mr. Yamamoto
One credit
I will call you
Hello to you
- May I help
- booking under McCallister's name?
Booking under your name?
Madam, my feet barely reach the ground, I can barely see you too, how?
can i book a room
Think, the child enters the hotel and makes a reservation?
I do not think
Sorry, I got confused
I am traveling with my father, now he has work, he has a meeting
I can't stand meetings
They don't let you in, you have to sit and wait. It's borring.
That's why my father brought me down here. Gave credit
the card and told me to register and go to the room so as not to do anything stupid
Let me tell you, I do stupid things once in a while
We all do
Congratulations to you too.
No trace
- Yes, we should stay in touch. Do you have a hotel
- Yes
Do you have any recent photos?
I have one in my wallet
My wallet is missing
It was in my bag.
Kevin rummaged through my bag at the airport, looking for people.
- My wallet is with him.
- Did you have a credit card in your wallet?
- Both card and money.
You should urgently inform the bank if your son
has a card, then the location will be fixed when using it
You know, I don't think so. whether he knows how to use it
It worked
- Cedric
- Yes
? - They don't count tips in a public place
- I 'm sorry
- And find out everything about that young man !
Please here
I wish you a pleasant pastime. Please don't forget
to tell your father when he comes that he must come down
and sign a couple of things
Thank you for being so kind.
- Can I take your bag?
From the left please
- You know, Herbert Hoover once stayed on this floor
- The vacuum cleaner manufacturer?
- No, the president
This is one of our best numbers
Excellent
A big bed just for me
Luxurious and classy
Whatever they thought
Hey
- Do you want me to put the key in the bag or hang it on it
- I will hang it
Is everything alright sir? Is the temperature okay?
It `s good
Do you know how to turn on the TV?
I am ten years old, TV is my life.
OK
Oh, sorry!
And I still have a lot of them
Thank you.
Do you mind if I work on my jump a bit?
No
Thank you
This is how vacations happen
- Don't come forward
- It's me, Johnny
- I knew it was you. I still smelled you from the elevator.
Two balls?
Two... put three, I'm not driving
- It's a flower, Johnny, your favorite
Thank you
- You were here last night too, weren't you?
- I used to sing in a cabaret in the evening.
He's lying, he was doing syllabary with your brother
- You were here, you were doing syllabary with my brother
You saw
Well, cut it out, you're doing syllabic with all of them: Staffy, Heli, Leo, To Balmo, Chicky
Bobby's, Griffey's... Shall I continue, life?
- You misunderstood
- Okay, okay, I believe, my machine doesn't believe.
- Johnny!
- You are the only inhabitant of my heart
- Kiss my face and tell me you love me
- My dear, I adore you.
- Was your imagination that big?
- If love were an ocean, you'd need two planes to cross it
- Maybe I'm too soft, but believe me, okay.
- That's why I'll let you go.
I'm counting to three
disgusting, lying, vile
"You don't want to be naked" from here
Pulled
- One
- Two
- Three
- Happy New Year, dirty animal!
and Christmas.
Maintenance
Pull a rud, you degenerate puppy, or you'll be a tadpole
Our honeymoon isn't too bad, is it my dear?
Hey, Uncle Rob lives here too!
If they come from Paris, you can go see them, they usually give good gifts
Good night mom
Good night Kevin
Your clothes, sir
Wow, don't show these to the whole world, are there any girls?
I was very careful, dance
Care should always be taken with underwear
I see
Excuse me, would you like some tea?
No need, really, there's still a balance
You don't want to, okay?
No, no, no, no, wait a minute
The concierge will be happy to hail a taxi for you
Mr. McCallister!
Sorry
How are you feeling this morning?
I'm fine, is my car here?
It's in front of the door, sir. Limousine and pizza courtesy of our hotel.
I hope your father
realizes I was just checking last night to make sure everything was okay
Oh well pissed off!
Really?
He said he didn't come here to have his bare ass watched
Of course no. Will it drop soon?
Already gone
I would like to personally apologize
If a man caught you in the bathroom, would you want it?
ever see him
- I think not
I don't think you'll ever see him
Well, I understand
Goodbye
Have a nice day
McCallister
- Good afternoon, Mr. McCallister
- Hello
Mr. McCallister, your "custom" cheese pizza, please.
- Hello?
- Yes
? - Do you know a good toy store?
- Of course, sex
>
bingo
I was rad. Get lost from here, run away. Well, who am I talking to?
Hey, Marv, come here, there's something to talk about.
- Does he want a scarf?
- Maybe leave that scarf, I'm saying something
Look, we don't have tools.
to do big things: a bank, a jewelry store.
We don't need them. We need cash, and now."
Hotels, huh?
- People spend a lot of money
- No confidence, I have a better idea
Stores don't take money to the bank on Christmas Eve
- And those stores that sell average price products will have money - That
's right
So, which stores are going to have the most money today?
and no one is going to rob
Candy shops
Nine year olds steal candy
See what I mean
Brilliant, Harry, brilliant!
there are no other idiots
Ugh, no more idiots to rob a toy store on Christmas Day
No, there definitely are
Here, sir, is Duncan's chest."
Merry Christmas, Kevin!
This is the best accident of my life
- Marv, Marv
- I hear it's a cabin, it's a pity, it doesn't have a toilet
Huh, what's your plan?
Now everyone will go home
and we leave the cabin
Here, what then?
We take the money, and come on!
It's an emergency, Harry
Well, thanks, and Merry Christmas
- Cheers to the family
- Let me see
Do you trade alone?
- In New York, sex, I'm afraid of my own skin
- Well, I was just checking
- You are very attentive
- Yes, thank you
- Please
Twenty-three dollars and seventy-five cents, please
Look, look, look, where did you get so much money?
Oh, I have a lot of grandmothers
Ha, well that explains a lot
It is a wonderful store. Probably the best I've ever seen or been
Thank you
Mr. Duncan must be a very good man to let the children come to play
Other places are prohibited
- Really
? - Yes
Well, he loves children very much.
And you know all the money you made today?
Mr. Duncan will donate to Children's Hospital
And on Christmas morning we'll empty the cash registers, and
Mr. Duncan will take you straight to the hospital
That is a great generosity
Oh, the children bring him joy
Like anyone who appreciates them
I probably shouldn't spend this, but I've got twenty dollars in my stash,
that my brother will not find. Then I will return it.
So give this please to Mr. Duncan, more at the hospital
need more than me.
I, on the other hand, will spend on something that will ruin my teeth
You are very kind, very kind
OK, do you see this tree?
Yes
In appreciation of your generosity, I allow you something from this tree
pick and take home
- Unsuccessful?
Do you want me to make a suggestion?
OK
Take the pigeons
Both of them
Yes, both
Tell me, what can you do?
Keep one for yourself and give the other to someone very dear to you.
You know, pigeons are a sign of friendship and love
As long as you both have your pigeon,
you will remain friends forever
Oh!
What! I also thought they were song lyrics.
It is so, and precisely because of that.
Thank you
- Merry Christmas
Dress warmly before going out, it's very cold.
I will do the same.
Where now?
You promised to take me to the Central Park Zoo.
Hey, look who it is.
Let's get to it
Hey!
What's New.
Run!
hey
Hey, take it easy!
Buy now and avoid the queues
Two five bucks, two five bucks, four ten bucks
It's cool, it's cool, it's running
- Live!
- Thank you
- Congratulations, my brother.
- It was a very good offer
- Good luck, madam.
Help, two people have fallen behind me
What's wrong, the store won't accept it?
Your stolen card
Let's see what the police say
Come back you thieving puppy!
Stop it
Hold on
You dirt!
In fact, I committed fraud
Call security
Gotta stop the scammer
Let's go, Cedric
This vacation was enough, I went home.
- Don't come forward
- It's the doorman, sex
- I knew it was you. I still smelled you from the elevator.
You were here last night, weren't you?
- Yes, sex, I was here
- you were here, here. You used to play syllabary with my brother.
- Did you mix something up?
- Well, you're doing syllabic with everyone.
Snuffy, Haley, Leo, Tobalmo, Chicky
Bonnie Bobby, Cliffy...
- False
- Shall I continue, life?
- Sorry, gender, but... but I'm afraid you're wrong
We are looking for a young person
- Well, well, I believe. He doesn't believe automatically.
- Chalk my face and say you love me
- Kneel, then, huh?
- I love
- Was your imagination that big?
Maybe I'm too soft, but believe me, okay.
That's why I'll let you go
On the count of three you disgusting!
liar, mean, lousy
get the hell out of here
- One
- Do it quickly, do it quickly
Two
Three
- Happy New Year, dirty animal!
and Christmas.
Stay in the rooms, it's an emergency.
One of the guests is mad and armed.
Come to papa
- Return ticket to Miami - Did
you get on the wrong plane?
You won't need this either
You're not going to fly to the promised land, are you?
- We went
For nine months in prison, we thought that there was no one unluckier than us in the world
We were wrong, aperik
- So
we ran away and we feel very good. Even better, because now a toy
we rob shops, not houses
At midnight we go to Duncan's chest, five stories of money
After that we get fake passports
call Rio
- Marv, Marv
maybe you'll cut your hair, huh
? - What's the difference, one?
no one will see it except the fish
or from a hole digger
- Let's take it to a subway tunnel
I'll feel a lot better when we get him locked up
- Look, there is a weapon in my pocket. If you open your mouth, I will remove the chewing gum from your forehead
Greetings
It was himself
What
Thank you
- Got up
- Went to the park
- What did your lover catch?
Over there
- Hey, come on. I caught it
- I 'll see
This is not him, take him down, he is not.
Must die, as many chances as possible
I don't want to start any business
because it is free
- What should it do?
It's a child, children are helpless
- This is not one
But this time he has no home, full of dangerous things
In a park, alone, kids are afraid of parks
Hey, big people come to the park and don't come back alive
Try your luck
I want a house
Where are you, mom?
Turn off the sound
-
Hello? - Kate McCulster?
- Yes
? - We found your son
- Oh my God
- What?
- Do they know where Kevin
is - Where?
- In New York
- New York?
- What?
- He's definitely scared, he can't create problems
- What, what?
- One second, please
- What?
- Your credit card was registered at the Plaza Hotel
- And is it there now?
- Is it there?
- No, they are still looking for
- Take the writer
- Come to New York
- On the next flight, thank you
We're going to New York, move!
- Yes!
He ran away from the hotel when he was caught. Perhaps he is terrified.
Maybe he will go to my brother's house
isn't it in paris
Maybe there is someone watching at home
But wasn't it a repair?
Hey!
Uncle Rob!
Aunt Georgette! is there anyone at home
Hey!
Is there anyone at home? Kevin is your favorite cousin
Uncle Rob!
Aunt Georgette!
No, no... A... yes, yes... no, no...
Be careful, boy
Hey, looking for someone to tell you a bedtime story?
Taxi
It's going to be scary outside
There is nothing here either, brother
That's it, I don't want such holidays
Where did you come from, there won't be enough of you all?
How hungry are you?
That's it, you ate all my food
Sorry for yelling in your face. You were trying to help me, weren't you?
My name is Kevin McCallister
You have very nice birds
I saw you again
you were completely covered in pigeons
You'd be a little scared at first, but now that I think about it, it's not so bad
They definitely love you that they surrounded you like that
Am I disturbing you?
can i go
No
Well, it's good. Aren't I disgusted?
And do the pigeons return by themselves or do you have to call them?
Give me your hand
They listen
It is wonderful
It's cold, isn't it? I would drink hot chocolate if I was lucky
And you
I treat you
I wouldn't want to spend Christmas Eve in a park like that. Shall we go somewhere warm?
Yes, I know where
What good music!
Wonderful place
I listen to the best music in the world in this room
Ella Fitzgerald, Caruso
Frank Sinatra
Luciano Pavarotti
Well, aren't you bringing your friends here?
I don't have many friends
Sorry
I am like the birds I take care of
People avoid me, they see me and ignore me
Maybe they'd rather I wasn't part of their town
Yes, something like that runs in my family
I am also the pigeon of our house, just because I am small
Everyone's fighting for a place
People want to be noticed and heard
yes maybe but
Yes, maybe. But I was well seen and heard. And basically sent to my room
I haven't always been like this
Oh, and how have you been?
I had a job
family
Children?
I didn't have it
But I wanted to
And the one I loved
stop loving me
My heart broke
And when there was an opportunity to be loved again, I avoided it
I stopped trusting people
No offense, but I think you did something wrong
I was afraid that my heart would be broken again
Sometimes you trust a person, and then when something goes wrong,
they forget you
And maybe they are too busy, maybe
they don't forget you, but they forget to remember you
People don't want to forget, it just happens that way. My grandfather says if
if my head wasn't stuck I would have forgotten on the school bus
If I trust someone, my heart will be broken again
I see. I had a lot of cute licks.
but I was so afraid of breaking it that I kept it in a box
Do you know what happened? They got smaller.
Don't wear it outside anyway, only in my room
Several times
The human heart and emotions are different from the Glicks
It's about the same
If you don't use your heart, who cares if it gets broken?
If you keep only yourself, it will look like my licks
If you decide to try one more day, it won't work
It is necessary to use the opportunity. There is nothing to lose.
There is truth in what you say
I think yes. A heart can be broken
but still there.
If it wasn't, you wouldn't be so kind.
Thank you. You know, I haven't talked to anyone in a few years.
no one.
It's okay, it works out well.
You are not boring. You don't mutter or spit. Try more often.
Just dress so that your clothes don't look old.
It turns out that I worked to keep people away, huh?
- I always thought that
I will spend more pleasant time alone
but when I am alone, it is not happy at all.
No matter how many
disgusts me, I'd rather be with a friend than alone.
Then what are you doing alone on the streets on Christmas night? Do you have a problem?
- Yes
- Did you do something wrong?
Full thing
Do you know that good deeds wash away bad deeds?
It is already a little late.
There is no time to do enough good work to clean up all the bad ones.
It's Christmas, good deeds are worth more today.
- Really?
Of course. Think about what important thing you can do for others.
and do.
Follow the star in your heart.
Very good.
It's already late, maybe I should go.
If I don't see you again, I hope everything will be fine.
Thank you.
Say goodbye to the pigeons from me
- I will
- Merry Christmas
- Merry Christmas!
If you need someone to confide in:
I can be that one. I will not forget to remember you.
Do not promise what you cannot do.
Mr. Duncan will donate all money earned today to the children's hospital
We're going to loot Duncan's chest at midnight
You can spoil anything, but not the children's Christmas
We can offer you a nice room on the top floor:
With a view of a park in New York.
I think you will like it.
The Countess of Wales has just released it.
Which hotel registers a child alone?
The boy made up a very believable story.
And what kind of idiots work here.
- The best in New York.
Well, when you discover that your credit card has been stolen...
- I was the discoverer
How did you let him get away?
When we tried to stop him, he ran away
- Because you scared him
It's Christmas night, and because of you, our child is lost in one of the biggest cities in the world.
Please escort my family to the room.
- Yes, sex
- Move over, Cedric
I'll go to the police to make sure they're doing everything they can to find Kevin. Please stay with Franken.
No, I'm going to look for my son
- What?
With all due respect, ma'am, but a child is missing in one of the world's greatest cities
- Will you not interfere
? - Of course
Thank you.
I don't think it's a good idea to run around New York alone
If Kevin can do it, so can I
- Kate
Nothing will happen to me. From my appearance, no thief or robber would dare to approach me
Well, ma'am, there are hundreds of porters out there, armed with a...
Dress up, it's very cold outside.
Marv, Marv, let's go!
Marv?
Cheers!
Merry Christmas
- Come on!
Happy Hanukkah, Marv!
There's more money here than I can count
Now I think, what business were we robbing houses?
The surprising thing is that we ran away from the law up to our elbows in money.
and no one even knows about it
It's back
He drew
How did I look?
That's it, no step back.
Another Christmas in the trenches.
"...don't leave them, don't take money,
շուտ․․․"
I am coming
right?
Harry, it was excellent.
Where is that?
Twisted my leg huh?
Hey guys, smile!
Get up, help, let's go
- I caught it, I caught it
Taxi!
Town Square
Where did he go?
Hey guys, smile!
Let's kill!
Wait, you brainless. We got caught that time because we underestimated
that pitiful puppy
- Not like that now. This is not his house.
Now he runs away scared, he has no plans
Will you please let me be the thinker?
Thank you
Boy
- I'm listening
Nothing would give me more pleasure than
killing you.
Some puppy
it's not a big deal for me to get drunk, you know
- Uh ?
But, since we are late, we want to make an appointment
with you.
You drop the camera, so do we
we are not harming you. you won't hear about us either.
- Okay
? - Do you promise?
I cross my heart. Am I going to die or am I lying?
Alright.
All right, kid, throw it away
At the destination
How many fingers am I pointing at, Marv?
Eight
Oh that's right, puppy!
Do you want to throw a stone? Well, throw it away, soon.
- No, no, don't do it, no.
If you don't have anything from that, you're definitely done
Harry, no!
Do you have any more?
Get up, he doesn't have it either. That's it. It's dirty.
What?
You are finished. Whoever throws a stone at him will not live.
Get up. You on this side, I on the back.
Harry? Harry! Harry!
Huh?
I'll kill you, huh!
Well, now you will see what I will do.
A minute, a minute.
Look what I have to do to you. "Ab right in my mouth" Marv.
Harry, I'm mad.
Well, look, well, look at what I'm going to do. Now you will see what I will do to you.
Well, look, well, look. I'm going to finish you now, look.
I'll kill you, puppy
Wow! You are a ruin
Harry
I'm going up
I'm going to slaughter that puppy
yes
Don't you know that a child can always be defeated by two tricks?
- Harry, he is going to the hall
Climbs the stairs
I'm coming, Harry
I came
Harry!
Hey, you haven't lost any teeth, see
Hey, don't you want the stairs?
Come on, go to the second floor
A minute, a minute.
Don't you remember last year?
No
Well, look
Let's go catch it
- Oh, right in my mouth. Ah!
This one.
"Don't worry, Harry, I'll catch you."
Straight nose to nose
This is two. Here we go now.
Three more.
Not again!
This is four.
Come on, Harry!
- Are you sure it's safe?
- Ha, ha. We will see now.
Solid as a rock
- Like a rock, huh
?
When?
- It would be good to say all the prayers
you know - Your parents would also do well to slowly start ordering your tombstone
Where did he go?
I'm upstairs. I'm scared.
What's the sound?
It was the sound of the toolbox rolling down the stairs -
Ha!
yes
Over there
I will kill you even if I get an electric shock
Give it up, boy!
Gone
- I'm down you fools
" in decay
Well eat it, puppy!
- Come on, Marv
- I don't know
I said come on
Come on you coward!
Harry?
- Do you sprinkle perfume -
No perfume, it's kerosene, the rope is impregnated with it
But who needed to soak the rope in kerosene?
Merry Christmas
Up, up, soon!
Up
Get up
Bring the bag
Hello to you. The two that robbed Duncan's trunk are in Central Park, West Side, Ninety-fifth Street.
Come to the fireworks.
Hey, I'm here. You will do well to catch me, how many times have I called the police?
See how elusive luck is
"Do you like it?
Let's go to the park for a while
Give me the bag. Give me.
Hey, whatever will look good on the album
You won the battle, but you got carried away in the war, aperik
They don't fall with us, dear boy. We are dangerous.
- Harry
? - Your voice?
- Yours. Let me enjoy this moment
There is one thing. Let's fly from here.
I say your voice.
I didn't even go to the sixth grade. Maybe you won't go either.
Let the boy.
Kevin, run!
Shoot him. Shoot this.
- Shoot
- I'm trying, idiot
Goodbye! Thank you.
- Oh, something like Independence Day
- Quick, quick
- We are a bridge, you are a tunnel
- Well, get up, walk
Oh my God.
Stop, quick!
Hey guys, you should start early. The prisoners have already received the gifts.
Are we late for the gifts? He forced us to hide in the store and steal the children's money
Your voice, Marv.
You have the right to remain silent, don't you know?
- It's a bit annoying. We just escaped from prison, huh
! - Your voice, Marv
Take these
- If you write about this, remember: we are not the wet bandits anymore, we are the sticky bandits
- Your Voice
- You remember, don't you? K P... Sticky. No.
Well, Mr. Danken, we are done. We found the bandits and returned your money.
I want to take that money to the children's hospital as soon as possible
- I'll take care of that
- Yeah, thanks
- Sorry, Mr. Duncan
- Yes?
I found a new note, as if a child broke the window
Dear Mr. Danken, I broke your window to catch the criminals. Are you insured?
If not, I will send the money for it if I ever get to Chicago.
Merry Christmas.
Kevin McCallister.
Postscript: greetings for pigeons.
Pigeons.
Excuse me, I'm looking for my son, in this picture...
Please, help, please.
Do you know the guy in the picture?
I am looking for my son. It's gone for two days
- Did you leave a message
- Yes, of course
So trust us. We will deal with that issue.
- I am the boy's mother
- I understood that, madam, but there is no point in looking for a needle in the haystack.
- Do you have children
- Yes, ma'am
- What would you do if one was lost?
- Probably the same as you now
- Thank you
- Look, imagine yourself in his place. What would you do? Where would you go?
- Me? I would probably have fallen in one of the streams, I would have died.
But not Kevin. He is much stronger and braver than me.
And I know that now it is good. Just still alone in the giant city
He doesn't deserve it
He should be at home, with his family, near the Christmas tree. Do you understand?
oh my God
I seem to know where it is
Gotta go to Rockwell Center
- Get in the car
Thank you
I know I don't deserve Christmas even if I did a good job
I don't want gifts. Instead, I want to take back all the words I said to my family.
Even if they don't do the same, I love them all. Including Baz.
If I can't see them, can I at least see my mother?
I will never want anything again. I only want my mother.
I know, it won't happen like this. But promise that I will see you again. One day. Any day. At least once. At least for a few minutes.
I apologize
How much?
Mom?
That fast?
Oh Kevin!
Mom, I'm sorry
You will forgive me too
- Merry Christmas, Mom
- Merry Christmas, my dear
Thank you
Let's go
- How did you know that I am here?
- I know the connection between you and the Christmas tree, and this is the biggest one
- Where are the rest
? - In the hotel. They didn't like the palm trees either
Oh, you wonder! It is already morning.
It's Christmas morning
- Fuller, don't get your hopes up
- Huh?
- I don't think Santa enters hotels
- Are you smart? He is everywhere and goes everywhere
Get up, it's Christmas!
Mom, Dad, it's Christmas
- Where did all this come from?
- Hey, dad, you have to see this
A miracle to you, Pitt?
Are we in the right room?
Don't open mine, I'm serious
Who is Mr. Duncan
- Duncan? I don't know
Everyone calm down, shut up, I say, eh, eh
Okay, now. If Kevin hadn't lost his taste, we wouldn't be in this extraordinary and huge number again.
a wagon full of freebies
So I think it's only fair if Kevin opens first
Then me. Then all of them.
Merry Christmas, Kev!
Merry Christmas, Buzz!
Merry Christmas, Kevin!
Hey Kevin, cool, congrats!
Well, enough of feelings.
Let's see what is there.
People, keep the papers, we will use them next year. The threads too.
Merry Christmas
Merry Christmas Kevin!
I have something for you
What is this
Pigeon
I have one, you have one
As long as they are with us, we will be friends forever
Oh, Kevin!
Thank you
I will not forget you, be sure.
Fee for Mr. McCallister's services
Merry Christmas
Ha, um, ha...
What a nice family
Whew. Merry Christmas....
Dad!
Kevin, did you spend nine hundred and sixty seven dollars on services alone?