The language frontier
Yes, I falled for him! He tried very hard,
but I remained dedicated to what I'm obliged to.
This scandalous situation is just a fuss.
A fortunate liaison is appreciated more than diplomatic successes or military victories in beau monde.
Natalie remained cold-hearted even towards the Emperor.
Let the audience think that only I was able to cuckold the curly-haired one!
That scoundrel has been following Natalie for a long time
I believe that she is faithful to me but how do I make the beau monde believe it?! Only by hazarding my life!
So it's the duel and as soon as possible!
In 1880 Ivan Turgenev on the occasion of opening Pushkin's monument said:
"There's no doubt that he had created our poetic, our literary language.
And he alone had been carrying the burden of the two missions, which were separated by hundreds of years in other countries.
That is to say: to establish the language and to create the literature.
What a great man he was!
And died...like a hare.
Are you ready?
Come!
How did Pushkin change the Russian language?
For hundreds of years the Russian language has been pushed down by the Church-Slavonic
Peter the Great tried to reform the language but he didn't achieve any success.
And we must notice that he was the one who swoll the language by bringing too much foreign barocco words.
Not to tell it in front of the ladies, like some sort of an old galjoen (_the head of a ship where the toiled was placed_)
The language could've stayed polluted... But then Pushkin showed up.
Gifted by superb genius, like a divine plunger it was, he cleaned the language and got rid of many ramshackle and bad-sounding words
Pushkin himself was using a clear language, easily-comprehended by anyone.
That's why he is widely regarded as our language's reformer.
But is that really so?
Let's find out!
Is Pushkin the creator of modern Russian literary language?
The more years pass since some great person's death, the easier it becomes to turn his life into a myth and exaggerate his achievments.
It started when Pushkin was still alive and reached its peak after 100 years since his death.
There was no Russian author who has been honoured as much as Pushkin has during the Soviet era.
Pushkin was not only "the voice of the most avant-garde revolutionary minds of his time",
but also the creator of the Russian literary language.
Although, when reading the works of  Pushkin's contemporaries,
it's difficult to see why his language is called unique, what peculiarities his style has, why he is honoured so much.
An inexperienced reader won't notice any difference,
even a professional linguist has to make an effort to catch peculiarities of the Pushkin's style.
It's kind of weird when speaking about the one who "had established the language and created the literature", isn't it?
text: "What did Pushkin NOT do?"; voice: First of all, let's talk about what Pushkin certainly didn't do, but what he is believed to have done.
Pushkin didn't reform nor standardize the language (grammar)
It was unnecessary in Pushkin's times to standardize the language.
Of course, there still were some linguistic variations, but they are present even now.
But in Pushkin's times there was no chance of encountering such things in a text that were widespread in the beginning-mid. 18th cen.
That is to say: mixing colloquial speech, Church-Slavonic, formal language and new European words and calques.
Here's an example taken from a Peter the First's times romance adventure novel:
Red are the words that were no longer used in everyday life, those were the Church-Slavonic ones.
Dark-blue is the formal style's word, yellow are the new European words
"At ye same timeth (red) they marched  (yellow) them and told them to bring more joung sailors (y) to Holland
for the sake of arithmetic (y) science and various languages;
not enwheeling (r) this very (dark-blue) Vasily, who wasn't set up as a commander (y) above the sailiors, but wast hath left (r) in Kronstadt"
Such mixings step by step disappeared to the middle of the 18th cen.
Lomonosov put an end to these frivolousnesses.
His "Russian grammar" (1755) is a guide to what forms to use and what not to.
This means that in Pushkin's times there was no question of standardizing the grammar of the literary language anymore.
It has already been structured and there aren't  even much differences compared to the modern one.
During Pushkin's youth there were the same Russian grammar standards in all the secular educational institutions.
The grammar of Pushkin's writings is no different from his contemporaries'.
We have to keep in mind that Pushkin wasn't a linguist
He didn't publish any grammar books,  dictionaries, vade mecums nor grammar-guides.
Indeed, Pushkin took part in the language discussions, but his remarks were rather vague and unspecified.
We'll have a look at them later.
Pushkin didn't change Russian syntax
A peculiarity of the 18th century's texts is that their word order is very unusual to a modern reader
Church-Slavonic, Latin, Greek, German, French influences are all mixed together there.
And the tendency to make the prose more poetic and sophisticated in barocco style.
Let's look at this piece of Tredyakovsky's text
From the bottom of my heart I wish this, even though it's not the main aim and need now, but as it has firmly and loudly plenties and plenties of nations, and stronger than any other thing, as I suppose, and it's hard to believe otherwise,
because if the palm branch, received for noble deeds, ...
has been praising them [the deeds] for centuries, then this exalting science shall bloom there as a magnifying epic horn, as some strings that have already been blooming with the clangs
*I've chosen a very bright example on purpose
(the texts weren't usually so hard)
So, Sasha, tell me what do you think of this quatation's tongue and how do you understand it?
...though it's not the main aim and need now...
What is it? What is he talking about?
Seems like the epithets are overused there... A bit of too much.
Nah, it's insane.
I don't get it at all, which parts of it are connected.
Even Latin poems are easier to comprehend than this nonsense.
What was in his brains... It's like he's making a wedding speech.
As you can see, it's impossible to understand such things when reading it for the first time
To speak in such a manner, e.g. reading a lecture, is just unreal because it sounds like rubbish.
And it's not the age of this text that makes it hard -- the contemporaries struggled to understand it, too.
In those times the form and beauty of the text were more important than its clear meaning.
A confusing word order was regarded as very solemn and beautiful.
Lots of people have been crying over it...
but they didn't stop using this manner until the end of the 18th cen.
Even Lomonosov couldn't help making the syntax easier
On the opposite, he recommends to use this style when writing something highly poetic
And the word order in his writings is way not that easy, too.
Karamzin totally changed the situation.
He paid no attention to Lomonosov's rules and created his own.
On the one hand, he used French phrasing as a model because it had direct word order, logical way of expressing a thought and it was quite short.
On the other, there was a Russian colloquial model.
Therefore Pushkin and the others used the syntax that Karamzin had brought into life
N.M. Karamzin (1766-1826) a writer, historian
Pushkin admitted that he was Karamzin's successor and considered Karamzin to be the main reformer of the Russian language.
An example from Karamzin's text.
You'll see that the sentences are short enough and the subordinate clauses aren't very long.
The meaning is easily understood even without looking at the text.
It was also important to Karamzin that beau monde ladies would understand his tongue.
Because the casuistic way of speaking could've abolished their desire to read anymore.
Liza's father was a rather well-to-do settler, for he loved
work, tilled the land well, and always led a sober life. But soon after his death, his wife and daughter grew poor...
The lazy hand of a hired man worked the land poorly, and the grain ceased to thrive. They were forced to rent out their land, and for a pittance of a sum
There was a poet Ivan Semyonovich Barkov
And his relationships with Pushkin were, so to say, pretty cold.
An anecdote
Once upon a time Pushkin had been writing some poems and suddenly he saw Ivan Semyonovich walking  outside
Pushkin thought, 'Now I'll make it hot for Barkov. I'll take a 5 ruble coin, heat it up, drop it at Barkov's feet, he'll try to catch it and get his hands burned. What an unspleasant situation!
And then, when the coin is cold again, I'll take it'.
Please keep in mind, that 5 rubles was a huge sum back in the days.
And so Pushkin did what he had planned.
He took a 5 ruble coin, heated it up,  dropped it at Barkov's feet and Barkov had almost caught it,
but he felt that the coin was very hot, and if he cathes it, he'll burn his hands, drop the coin and it'll be an unpleasant situation, ideed.
Barkov looked up and saw smiling Pushkin in the window.
Barkov thought, 'Now I'll make it hot for Pushkin.
I'll cool the coin down with my "jet", naturally I won't take it and just go on walking.
I won't lose a thing, I'll give Pushkin what for, plus he'll lose some money "
because he won't risk his "aristocracies' honour" by taking a peed coin
And so Barkov did what he had planned.
He unzipped his pants, peed on the coin and went on walking.
That's the story how Barkov didn't let Pushkin mock him and made Pushkin lose money instead.
Pushkin didn't get rid of Church-Slavonic words in Russian language
Church-Slavonic language had a huge impact on Russian language ever since the Christianization
We have a video about it.
Just in case you forgot: "Church-Slavism" and "Slavism" are the same categories.
We'll use the second one just because it's shorter.
Archaic elements of grammar and syntax like "пpиимаша"(taketh), "погребох" (inurn),
"похотел бысть" (did want to), "едущу ему" (traveleth to that gent) etc.
weren't used anymore in written language up to the mid. 18th century.
Lomonosov's grammar was the cherry on the cake in fighting this shabby tongue.
But until Pushkin's times there was an argue going on about Church-Slavonic lexis
The written language of those times was even called "Slavonic-Russian".
Because he included so many slavisms.
Many words were written in texts in two ways: in Russian and in Slavonic.
It's easy to demonstrate slavisms by naming body parts
And the first group is those words that aren't like the Russian ones.
"очи" (eyes), "рамена" (shoulders),
"персты" (fingers),
"ланиты" (cheeks), "чресла" (loins),
"выя" (neck),
"перси" (bosom),
"чело" (forehead),
The second group is slavisms that have the same-root Russian words
"голова -- глава" (head),
"борода -- брада" (beard),
"волосы -- власы" (hair),
"длань -- долонь -- i.e. ладонь" (palm)
Up to Pushkin's times there were two types of slavisms:
'Marked', regarded by everyone as ecclesiastical
in vain, how much/many, night, to crave, gold, nowadays, to speak, trees, and so on.
'Unmarked', etymologically Slavonic words that have been used in everyday speech for many years
younger, guard,
to congratulate, seeing, and so on.
During Pushkin's youth there were two huge literary societies: Shishkovist and Karamzinist.
Their dispute was based on totally different ways of looking at the Church-Slavonic inheritance.
Young Karamzin regarded slavisms as alien elements,
pathological mixing of uncombinable things,
a dump, macédoine
A.S. Shishkov (1754-1841) an admiral, writer
Shishkov thought that Russian and Church-Slavonic are basically the same language, they just differ in styles
And the so-called slavisms are the main treasure of the language, they are more beautiful and have deeper meaning.
I have to say that those views were mostly declarative (=those authors didn't strictly follow them)
And the vocabularies of both authors are almost equal.
Yes!
You may notice that Shishkov tends to use literary words more often,
but they are still used in modern language and easily comprehended by everyone.
There were some funny situations, e.g. it's said that Shishkov was pathologically afraid of foreign words and he invented the word "мокроступы" in order to avoid using "galoche".
But it's just an overforced pearl of his,
Actually Shishkov's tongue was of no diffecence to the other authors of the late 18-19th centuries.
He didn't use old grammar models
nor archaic and confusing slavisms that would've been hard to understand
and hard not only to his contemporaries, but to us, too.
and we still read his works easily.
Karamzin's tongue seems easier than Shishkov's,
but he also used a lot of slavisms,
but there are such sentences in his texts, that you'll have to read twice to understand.
Besides, late Karamzin isn't that enthusiastic about the reformation of the language anymore,
and he started using the slavisms that he used to avoid when he was younger,
and correcting his earlier works.
He wrote 'History of the Russian State'
(the main and his most long work), where it was appropriate to use slavisms for the atmosphere of the old times.
Technically, Pushkin didn't belong to any of the literary societies,
but, of course, he is closer to the late-Karamzin style.
Sasha, you've told me that you like the works of Chekhov, Gogol, Goncharov, Chernyshevsky
Tell me now, who would you prefer as a man out of Russian authors?
Oh, that's a good question,
to be honest, I can definitely say that it's not Tolstoy,
our views differ too much, and that idée fixe of his about the morality...
well... definitely not Lermontov
he's acting like an "eternal martyr" and is a whiny
not my type of man...
But... maybe Pushkin. He is such an open person, you know,
he's simple,
has sense of humour and, judging by his works and correspondence, I feel like he's a sunshine person.
Pushkin's main principle
"The true taste is not to thoughtlessly reject some word, some phrase, but to use everything appropriately, not too much nor too little" A. Pushkin
Pushkin avoided any kids of overusages or radical ideas when speaking about the language
He was like the ancient wisemen, who considered temperance to be the greatest virtue
He is against using too many foreign words,
but he criticizes those who want to get rid of all of them
He doesn't deny the Church-Slavonic literary inheritance,
but he also uses colloquialisms.
He can describe some miserable things using highly poetic style,
and he can describe some "higher matters" (i.e. moral, heroic etc.) using everyday speech.
Pushkin doesn't strictly follow all the grammar rules and dictionaries' commandments,
but he criticizes those who use vulgar argot, dialectisms, misuse grammar rules and write in an unnatural manner.
Pushkin relies on his taste and feeling of the language
We can look at any of his texts, at any expression,
but firstly we have to think, how suitable it is in this particular work,
how it looks in this particular context.
What have Pushkin done?
During his times there were the following linguistic debates going on:
What do we do with slavisms?
Joung Pushkin tended to reject the poetic Slavonic style,
'a source of dark barbarianism'.
In his poetry he used Russian and Slavonic words interchangeably according to the rhyme and syllabo-tonic needs.
Not only he did so.
Most of the poets did the same thing in those times.
But approximately during his 25's, he changed his mind about the Slavonic style
and had a special opinion on slavisms,
now we'll look at it.
Pushkin wasn't a linguist, therefore he made no difference between Russian and Slavonic words.
Lunguists were able to deduce the origin of a word in those times,
but some scientifical reasonings were of no use to Pushkin.
Pushkin had a different point of view on lexis.
Etimologically 'unmarked' words Pushkin regarded as inevitable archaisms.
You can't correct them, but anyways you don't need to,
because only a maniac would state that one has to use 'охлажать' instead of 'охлаждать' (to cool down),
and 'здоровствуйте' instead of 'здравствуйте' (hello).
'Marked' slavisms Pushkin was using in such a semantic styling
that these words received during the past decades.
He used cautiously only such slavisms
that were strictly associated with church or Bible.
All the other slavisms seemed totally fine to him,
he used them depending on the stylistic requirements of a particular text.
Slavisms had one stubborn function in poetry by that time,
they made the atmosphere of a text highly poetic,
as Lomonosov had bequeathed.
The 18th and 19th centuries had the following difference:
in the 18th cen. slavisms were a must-have when speaking about something serious, some "higher matters", it was impossible not to use them
Pushkin wanted to distract the audience from the idea
that if the text contains slavisms, it's automatically about a serious subject. And vice versa.
Pushkin regarded slavisms as a literary instrument which you can apply -- and can not apply.
An example of a "higher matters" speech (Tzar's monologue) where 'marked' slavisms (red) are used
alongside with Russian colloquialisms (blue).
Even so 'in youth' (blue)
We 'greedily desire' (red) the joys of love,
But 'only' (blue) quell 'the hunger' (red) of the heart
With momentary possession. We 'grow cold' (red),
Grow weary and oppressed!
God sent 'a famine' (red); perishing in torments
The people 'uttered moan' (blue).
The granaries
I made them 'free of' (red), scattered 'gold' (red) among them,
Found labour for them;
all things 'revolt' (blue) me,
And my 'head' (blue) whirls, and in my 'eyes' (blue) are children
Dripping with blood;
The contemporaries often criticized Pushkin for such 'mashups'.
E.g.: a "Vestnik Evropy"'s ("Herald of Europe", a magazine) critic wrote in 1821,
"the throne is mined" and "the dropped altar" insted of "subverted" or "shattered" «...»
What a weird word usage -- to talk about such awe-inspiring higher matters using these miserable words.
Many critics attacked Pushkin because of a line from 'Ruslan and Lyudmila': 'screwing my eyes up in disgust' ("от ужаса зажмуря очи")
One more example
"The words 'moustache', 'to scream', 'Mazepa', 'ogo' (an exclamation), 'it's about time' seemed vulgar, burlak-like to the critics. What shall I do?!"
Even though critics were spitting and squealing like pigs,
it was the Pushkin's way of treating slavisms that eventually "won the literary contest" and became essential in the 19th cen.
How do we deal with colloquialisms, dialects and vulgar words?
It's often believed and attributed to Pushkin's merits that he has brought the written language and the everyday speech close together.
In a way it's true .
Let's look at what Pushkin himself said about it:
"The everyday speech of those simple people who don't read foreign books
and, thanks be to God, don't speak out in French, as we do,
is also worth of deeper researches".
"Ye young writers, listen to the vulgar speech -- you'll learn a lot, you won't find such things in our journals".
"The study of old songs, faitytales etc. is necessary if you want to know the Russian language and its features.
It's a great omission that our critics manquer it".
But Pushkin didn't bring his idea to a logical conclusion.
Pushkin isn't a language revolutionary.
He didn't want to throw away all the old traditions and build up a new literary language,
this was the thing that some of the bolsheviks in the 20's wanted to do, for example.
"The written language comes alive every time some phrases, that had been born in a conversation, are used,
but it also shouldn't leave out the things, that had been gained during the previous centuries".
Pushkin wasn't trying to write in a vernacular manner on purpose
he used peasants' and bourgeois' way of speaking just as a matter of stylization.
It was appropriate in some contexts, but in the others it was not.
And yes, or at least he said so, Pushkin appreciated vernacular language more
than that of an upper class
or forein languages, and that was the difference between Pushkin and Karamzin.
Karamzin, as we've already mentioned, kept beau monde ladies in mind,
and they could've uttered their subtle "ugh!",
when hearing a harsh peasant word.
Don't you agree, that it's quite offensive, if the whole text is written in an elegant, sophisticated manner,
and then, 'OOPS! Here comes a naughty vulgar word',
and you've spoilt it all! (literally: you've dipped the raspberry in shit!)
During the Soviet era they attributed Pushkin's vernacular word usage to his special love to the lower classes
But actually it was because of the zeitgeist.
It was one of the romanticism's traits -- which was at its peak during Pushkin's youth --
to pay special attention to the so-called 'national spirit', der Volksgeist.
We have a video where we are talking about this idea's influence. There's a link in the description.
Johann Herder, a German philosopher, came up with this idea at first.
And then Friedrich Hegel, who was popular in Russia, developed and spread it.
The 'Volksgeist' idea is that every nation has its own unique spirit
and, inter alia, it is present in this nation's  language.
But it's a metaphysical category,
one can't perceive it with eyes nor rationally understand.
So. Pushkin didn't use all the vulgar words, but chose them cautiously.
He didn't use harsh vulgarisms: 'to get drunk', 'to souse' (=to get drunk), 'to bang' (=to have sex), 'to fress', 'lofty', 'snout';
and the words that had already been regarded as vernacularism: 'in the meantime', 'let sth be', 'slippery', 'to be afraid';
and dialectisms: 'beauty',  'cockerel', 'beet', '?', 'an insect', 'fall' (rope)
When using dialectisms, Pushkin chose such words, which were understood throughout the country:
'wherefore', 'to rustle', 'to start', 'yesterday'.
An example from 'Mistress into Maid':
Pushkin changed dialectical pronunciation in the final version of the text: 'You even call your dog in French' (standard variant: по-французски) > 'You even call your dog in a foreign tongue'.
'And wha do you think?' > 'And whut do you think?' > ''And what do you think?'
And here's the example of how Pushkin made a poem's line simpler:
'and chestnut horse, whilst feeling it' > 'and gaunt horse, whilst feeling it' > 'a horse of his, while feeling snow'
You could use vernacular language not only when writing about folklore, rural life and so on,
but also when writing a review, in author's speech.
If the phrase is emotional and full of ardour -- why not?
"Firsly, they told me, that 'no one have ever heard such a thing' (red) that a woman could fall in love with an old man'.
Of course, vernacular language have been used in literature before,
and not only in entertaining contexts, but in serious ones, too.
But, firstly,
after Pushkin it blew up, you know, because of the romanticism influence.
Secondly, Pushkin showed in his texts that it's totally normal to use vernacular language in author's speech,
when talking about something serious or even the 'higher matters'.
And if such a great poet as Pushkin himself does so,
then the others can do it freely, too.
Thirdly, Pushkin often replied to critics
and gave reasons for his literary methods.
Thus, in Pushkin's time mixing styles wasn't regarded as burlesque,
as a macedoine used for comical effect,
but as a reasonable literary styling.
Pushkin!
This freedom-loving hero who mocked tsarism,
this intransigent fighter against serfdom,
it was impossible for him not to anchor in memoria populi.
Songs, legends, tales and fables about the greatest poet have been luring folklorist for a long time.
A lively source of a national legend about Pushkin
is discovered in Ivanovo Oblast during the eve of the dramatic loss of the poet.
It will now be presented to you by the sovkhoz's ensemble "The Krasny Khleborob" ("the Red Cultivator").
Lots and lots of those books had // Our lil' Marfusha.
There was once a great poet // And his name was Pushkin.
From Ivanovo they sent // Poems with no doubt.
My beloved and I have read // Pushkin all throughout.
We would like to tell you guys, // Who has love and feelings
Love would be a paradise // if you're Pushkin reading.
How do we deal with foreign words?
Pushkin's first language was French.
Aristocracies spoke French way more often than Russian.
Pushkin's correspondence with his friend and family was written in French.
Pushkin wrote poems in French.
Pushkin read French literature in the original.
When he had grown old, he learned English and some other languages.
You can encounter French calques in his works.
For instance, this is definitely not Russian word odred:
"But instead Nikolay and Alexander Raevsky and I, we had a pleasure laughing at him"
Look closer, and you'll undoubtedly hear this:
Puskin didn't like meaningless language puritanism.
He certainly made fun of those 'purga lingua' warriors.
His most famous quotation about it was:
She seems the image, to excess,
Of comme il faut… (Shiskov, forgive:
I can’t translate that, as I live!)
Pushkin thought that if you can't thanslate the word, you can easily borrow it as it is.
Frac, gilet, pantalon, tricot -- how do you thanslate these?
No way!
Pushkin understood that there were life spheres which were developed in Europe way more than in Russia.
Namely science, politics, philosophy, economics, technology, fashion.
And Pushkin saw nothing wrong with borrowing words from those spheres.
It was better to borrow some of the scientific terminology,
than to admit that they didn't talk about it in Russian
and to switch to German in order to continue the discussion instead.
But if the Russian word had already been existing, one mustn't use a foreign one instead.
"Avoid the scientific terminology; try to translate it, to paraphrase: this would be a ignoramus' pleasure and our young language's profit".
What is more important: to write elegantly or to write short and straight to the point?
"The beauty of simplicity is too complicated to us for now, and even in prose we are still trying to add lots of shabby literary decorations..."
"Certainty and conciseness are the most important qualities of prose. It requires thoughts and thoughts, and without them the fanciest decorations would be of no use".
We've alredy mentioned that in the 18th cen. it was widely believed
that the beauty of a text is more important than its comprehension.
Some people still had this opinion in the beginning of the 19th. cen.
The great advantage of Karamzin's prose was  that its word order was quite easy to understand.
But the disadvantage was that Karamzin overused various decorations in the text,
and those decorations often made the meaning obscure.
The moon is shining -- "Pale Hecate is reflecting dim gleams".
Windows were covered with frost -- "A furious aged woman covered windows with drawings"
Karamzin understood it himself and ironised it.
"A north wind blew hard upon a tender bust of a gentle mother, and the genius of her life extinguished its torch!
Yes, my dear gentle reader, she fell ill".
Pushkin couldn't stand such decorations
und used them only when it was inevitably necessary.
"I'm reading a show report by some theatregoer,
'This juvenile foster daughter of Thalia and Melpomene,
generously gifted by Apol...'
Oh my God! Couldn't you just say, 'this young great actress', and go on.
I assure you, no one will notice your exalted remarks, no one will thank you for it".
"These people would never say 'friendship' without adding
'this holy feeling, which noble fire...' etc.
One should've said 'early in the morning',
but they write 'as soon as first beams of the rising sun illuminated the eastern edge of the cerulean sky'
Oh my, it's so new and fresh! Does it seem better just because it's longer?'
Pushkin tried to avoid using such language constructions, which made comprehension of the text  more difficult.
Long sentences, inversions (anastrophes),  complicated metaphors, etc.
It is also known, that lots of adjectives and other modifiers
make a narrative slower.
From the other hand, lots of verbs, hence more actions,
make the narrative more dynamic, and the plot is easily imagined.
Pushkin knew it.
Here's a good example,
'The door was locked; he rang, and a few seconds of painful anticipation followed.
The clanking of a key could be heard, and the door opened.
"Does Avdotia Samsonovna live here?" he asked.
"Yes, she does," answered the young maidservant. "What do you want with her?"
The stationmaster went through to the hall without answering.
"You can't, you mustn't!" shouted the maid after him. "Avdotia Samsonovna has visitors."
Pushkin was trying to use short sentences and straight word order (SVO).
But Karamzin advised to do the very same thing.
The difference was that Pushkin reduced the amount of modifiers,
metaphors and other decorations.
So Pushkin among his contemporary writers was sort of Dovlatov
The narrative was cool and lively, it was easy and fast to read, everything was clear.
I suppose, my dear audience, that there are no fools among you.
And that all of you are people of intellect, not blind faith.
Then here's a question for you,
Who is our authority in the field of so-called social norms?
You'd say, 'Literate people'.
But who are those literate people? Pushkin? Tolstoy?
Or maybe even Vinogradov himself and K.G. Paustovsky?
Only we, the face of our time, are!
The horn of our time enunciates us as the modern literature
The past is narrow! Academics, Pushkin are as vague as hieroglyphs!
Throw Pushkin, Tolstoy, Dostoevsky off the steamer of modernity!
The one who won't forget his first love, won't taste the last one!
How will the Russian language be split into different styles?
The most common opinion is that before Pushkin, using Lomonosov's system,
Russian language had had three styles:
high, middle and low.
And Pushkin just took the 'middle' style and extended the range of its literary devices.
That's how modern Russian literary language was born,
other modern styles are based on it:
scientific, journalistic, officialese, etc.
This opinion is only partially true.
The truth is that Pushkin and many of his contemporaries really thought that there were three styles
The falsehood is that in real life it was way not so.
It was just a theoretical construction of Lomonosov,
even though, yes, important to the culture and people of its time.
Almost immediately after the Lomonosov's theory had emerged it was obvious that...well...
there are almost no works with 'pure' style.
Moreover, there were no stylistic dictionaries nor manuals.
Lomonosov gave some references, mostly about grammar.
But there were no strict borderlines.
It was up to every author's own understanding.
And the 'middle style' is a total fiction,
because it just contains the words that weren't regarded as 'high' nor 'low',
so it wasn't something that the 18th cen. linguists defined as the 'middle style',
those were the leftovers that the linguists ignored while developing 'high' and 'low' styles.
In the 18th cen. fiction the 'middle style' was scarcely used.
The 'middle style' back then was used in journalism, scientifical writing and so on.
The 'middle style' authors didn't have to use some special words,
they didn't care about the styles nor deliberate tongue.
In the history, as a rule, the fiction's language is the one
which influences so-called 'middle style' texts,
I mean, the tongue of non-fictional texts.
Not vice versa.
Significantly 'high' or 'low' words,
while being used often, become more neutral.
E.g., words 'gritting', 'ghost', 'to imagine', 'to dare', 'to hope for'
used to be of the same category as 'in vain', 'inasmuch as', 'the dearest' (archaic)
However in the 'Dictionary of the Russian Academy' (1794)
the following words were marked as 'colloqialisms':
'a pauper', 'routine', 'greedy', 'persistent', 'to allude', 'haughty', 'youth', 'luck', 'to dirty', 'to judge', 'that'
Pushkin opens the realism in Russian literature.
Realism's goal is to depict reality as it is.
In realistic literature a peasant, a servant, a lackey, a criminal
cannot speak by using Church-Slavonic words
and use antique metaphors
just because this writing's style is supposed to be 'high'
and an author is speaking about some 'higher matters' in the text,
for example, if the author desribes a conflict between landlord's feelings and duties.
Therefore every poetic device is good as long as it helps to depict reality better.
An root of a word didn't matter to Pushkin,
was it borrowed from foreign languages,
from church books, from dialects,
from argot of Petersburg's nobility.
He broke a strict connection 'colloquial -- low style',
'Chuch-Slavonic -- high style',
and used any word if needed.
He relied partially on his own language sense,
partially on previous literature's stylistic norms.
Therefore Pushkin didn't think that a literary work mustn't be split in styles.
Because almost in every case a long narration would include
something serious, 'high' and funny, 'low'.
And the most of the text would be neutral.
Pushkin avoided using two distinctly dissonating words together
E.g. "очи (arch.) разуй (colloquial)" (open your eyes),
"ея чресла (arch) лапать (derogatory)" (to touch her loins) or "девка теребила (coll.) перстами златыe власы (arch.)" (a girl played with her golden hair with her fingers).
It creates a humorous effect.
There are exceptions like, 'I squeezed my eyes shut, for, you see,  // I could not bear it any longer, // And broke away....', but it's a rare thing.
However, separating large pieces of a text into smaller ones is easy.
Pushkin's works are easily separated into small texts,
and each of them has its own stylistic unity.
A good example of Pushkin's poetry where the poem is separated into three equal pieces:
A solemn Church-Slavonic beginning,
Karamzin-style French midst
and folk-colloquial ending.
(this is my literal translation)
This sandy and deserted land // Is sacred for a poet's soul, // Derzhavin praised it very high, // With Russian glory is it full.
Up to this time the Naso's shadow // Is haunting Dunay's greatest shore // It is allured by heav'nly singing // Of Muses' children [poets] and Apollo.
With it I often under moon // Wander around the riverbank, // But, dear fellow, I would rather // Enfold you as my living Ovid
Is the Russian language applicable for every purpose?
In 1825 Pushkin wrote,
'Science, politics and philosophy have never spoken Russian;
there's no such thing as metaphysical vocabulary in Russian.
Our prose is so undeveloped that in a regular correspondence we are forced to invent new idioms
to explain most usual things; so our idleness prefers to speak foreign languages, where all the phrases and words are developed and known'.
The main trait of a developed language is that you can describe everything in it
You can write articles on science or politics in it,
with its tongue you can create an atmosphere of older times and express the national spirit,
you can write an amorous poem in it,
you can curse harshly in it, you can tell a tale to a child in it
or discuss yesterday's party with friends.
It is obvious that if some nationality had never had a need to discuss some topics,
then it won't be able to do it impromptu.
Creating a scientific, political, philosophical vocabulary takes a lot of work and time.
Usually this process takes place in later historical period and is quite clear.
For example, it is known that Russian philosophical vocabulary
was based on German and was developed in the beginning-middle 19th cen.
During Pushkin's time lots of words were absent,
so no wonder he and his contemporaries often had to speak in French.
They just didn't know how to explain it in Russian.
This situation is well-known to anyone who knows a foreign language well
and have read about some subject in this foreign language.
And when you're trying to discuss it in Russian with your friend
you are confused about the word usage because there are only foreign categories in your head.
Of course, Pushkin was convinced that Russian language should be used
in all literary genres and in every field of life.
Maybe one of the answers to a question, 'Why is Pushkin considered to be the greatest Russian writer', is
Pushkin left his marks everywhere:
poetry of all genres,
poems, tales, novels, narrations, dramas, memoirs, diaries, opinion journalism,
critiques, works about history:
his correspondence is published. And for all this he is famous.
Summing up
Approximately up to 23-25 years old Pushkin was experimenting with styles and genres.
As a hard-working bee he took notice of different authors' advantages
and rejected everything he disliked.
Pushkin wrote well, better than many others, but actually he wasn't outstanding.
Howeever, when he became older, he cerated nothing more than his own recognizable style.
Every great writer has it.
And it's nothing like the creation,
the reformation, the thansformation of the Russian literary language.
These phrases about Pushkin are nothing but praising mumble.
Pushkin developed his own opinion on slavisms, dialectisms,
on using various literary devices.
But Pushkin didn't write a book where he'd sum up his opinion on the evolution of the Russian language.
He only made some common statements,
sometimes contradictory, in various articles, personal letters,
replies to critics or critique of other authors' works.
Because of Pushkin's texts some words have changed their meaning or stylistic category,
but Pushkin didn't reform the stylistics, too.
He was rather just fighting with stereotypes,
because there hadn't actually been any 'system of three styles' before Pushkin.
He was only very well-read and had good sense of language,
that's the secret of his tongue.
Pushkin stood on the shoulders of titans:
Karamzin, Fonvizin, Radishchev and many others, who used to write as original as Pushkin in their times,
but who weren't crowned with laurels and called 'the creators of the modern Russian literary language'.
Pushkin just wrote a lot, he tackled every genre,
and his style is actually pleasing.
In my opinion, the most important thing is that Pushkin became a legend while being alive.
He was a real superstar of his time.
He was born to a famous noble family,
he was the first Russian author who managed to gain money for his writings,
an emperor's сonfidant, a friend of many other famous writers,
he was loved by journalists: lots of amorous liaisons, duels, scandals, exiles.
Sometime he told something good about Russian nation,
something bad about serfdom,
that was the reason bolsheviks adored him, and, of course, a tragic death in a duel.
Perished, so to say, because of the woman he loved, died so young...
These things created the cult of an author.
(Bulat Okudzava's song "А всё-таки жаль...") (my literal translation) 'One cannot turn time widdershins and mustn't mourn over the past,
Every epoch has its own sprouting branch.
But it's still a pity that Alexander Sergeich and I can't just
drop in the 'Yar' and have there a fast lunch'.
the end