# The Yellow Wallpaper,
by Charlotte Perkins Gilman
It is very seldom that mere ordinary people
like John and myself secure ancestral halls
for the summer.
A colonial mansion, a hereditary estate, I
would say a haunted house, and reach the height
of romantic felicity—but that would be asking
too much of fate!
Still I will proudly declare that there is
something queer about it.
Else, why should it be let so cheaply?
And why have stood so long untenanted?
John laughs at me, of course, but one expects
that in marriage.
John is practical in the extreme.
He has no patience with faith, an intense
horror of superstition, and he scoffs openly
at any talk of things not to be felt and seen
and put down in figures.
John is a physician, and perhaps—(I would
not say it to a living soul, of course, but
this is dead paper and a great relief to my
mind)—perhaps that is one reason I do not
get well faster.
You see, he does not believe I am sick!
And what can one do?
If a physician of high standing, and one’s
own husband, assures friends and relatives
that there is really nothing the matter with
one but temporary nervous depression—a slight
hysterical tendency—what is one to do?
My brother is also a physician, and also of
high standing, and he says the same thing.
So I take phosphates or phosphites—whichever
it is, and tonics, and journeys, and air,
and exercise, and am absolutely forbidden
to “work” until I am well again.
Personally, I disagree with their ideas.
Personally, I believe that congenial work,
with excitement and change, would do me good.
But what is one to do?
I did write for a while in spite of them;
but it does exhaust me a good deal—having
to be so sly about it, or else meet with heavy
opposition.
I sometimes fancy that in my condition if
I had less opposition and more society and
stimulus—but John says the very worst thing
I can do is to think about my condition, and
I confess it always makes me feel bad.
So I will let it alone and talk about the
house.
The most beautiful place!
It is quite alone, standing well back from
the road, quite three miles from the village.
It makes me think of English places that you
read about, for there are hedges and walls
and gates that lock, and lots of separate
little houses for the gardeners and people.
There is a delicious garden!
I never saw such a garden—large and shady,
full of box-bordered paths, and lined with
long grape-covered arbors with seats under
them.
There were greenhouses, too, but they are
all broken now.
There was some legal trouble, I believe, something
about the heirs and co-heirs; anyhow, the
place has been empty for years.
That spoils my ghostliness, I am afraid; but
I don’t care—there is something strange
about the house—I can feel it.
I even said so to John one moonlight evening,
but he said what I felt was a draught, and
shut the window.
I get unreasonably angry with John sometimes.
I’m sure I never used to be so sensitive.
I think it is due to this nervous condition.
But John says if I feel so I shall neglect
proper self-control; so I take pains to control
myself,—before him, at least,—and that
makes me very tired.
I don’t like our room a bit.
I wanted one downstairs that opened on the
piazza and had roses all over the window,
and such pretty old-fashioned chintz hangings!
but John would not hear of it.
He said there was only one window and not
room for two beds, and no near room for him
if he took another.
He is very careful and loving, and hardly
lets me stir without special direction.
I have a schedule prescription for each hour
in the day; he takes all care from me, and
so I feel basely ungrateful not to value it
more.
He said we came here solely on my account,
that I was to have perfect rest and all the
air I could get.
“Your exercise depends on your strength,
my dear,” said he, “and your food somewhat
on your appetite; but air you can absorb all
the time.”
So we took the nursery, at the top of the
house.
It is a big, airy room, the whole floor nearly,
with windows that look all ways, and air and
sunshine galore.
It was nursery first and then playground and
gymnasium, I should judge; for the windows
are barred for little children, and there
are rings and things in the walls.
The paint and paper look as if a boys’ school
had used it.
It is stripped off—the paper—in great
patches all around the head of my bed, about
as far as I can reach, and in a great place
on the other side of the room low down.
I never saw a worse paper in my life.
One of those sprawling flamboyant patterns
committing every artistic sin.
It is dull enough to confuse the eye in following,
pronounced enough to constantly irritate,
and provoke study, and when you follow the
lame, uncertain curves for a little distance
they suddenly commit suicide—plunge off
at outrageous angles, destroy themselves in
unheard-of contradictions.
The color is repellant, almost revolting;
a smouldering, unclean yellow, strangely faded
by the slow-turning sunlight.
It is a dull yet lurid orange in some places,
a sickly sulphur tint in others.
No wonder the children hated it!
I should hate it myself if I had to live in
this room long.
There comes John, and I must put this away,—he
hates to have me write a word.
## ---
We have been here two weeks, and I haven’t
felt like writing before, since that first
day.
I am sitting by the window now, up in this
atrocious nursery, and there is nothing to
hinder my writing as much as I please, save
lack of strength.
John is away all day, and even some nights
when his cases are serious.
I am glad my case is not serious!
But these nervous troubles are dreadfully
depressing.
John does not know how much I really suffer.
He knows there is no reason to suffer, and
that satisfies him.
Of course it is only nervousness.
It does weigh on me so not to do my duty in
any way!
I meant to be such a help to John, such a
real rest and comfort, and here I am a comparative
burden already!
Nobody would believe what an effort it is
to do what little I am able—to dress and
entertain, and order things.
It is fortunate Mary is so good with the baby.
Such a dear baby!
And yet I cannot be with him, it makes me
so nervous.
I suppose John never was nervous in his life.
He laughs at me so about this wallpaper!
At first he meant to repaper the room, but
afterwards he said that I was letting it get
the better of me, and that nothing was worse
for a nervous patient than to give way to
such fancies.
He said that after the wallpaper was changed
it would be the heavy bedstead, and then the
barred windows, and then that gate at the
head of the stairs, and so on.
“You know the place is doing you good,”
he said, “and really, dear, I don’t care
to renovate the house just for a three months’
rental.”
“Then do let us go downstairs,” I said,
“there are such pretty rooms there.”
Then he took me in his arms and called me
a blessed little goose, and said he would
go down cellar if I wished, and have it whitewashed
into the bargain.
But he is right enough about the beds and
windows and things.
It is as airy and comfortable a room as any
one need wish, and, of course, I would not
be so silly as to make him uncomfortable just
for a whim.
I’m really getting quite fond of the big
room, all but that horrid paper.
Out of one window I can see the garden, those
mysterious deep-shaded arbors, the riotous
old-fashioned flowers, and bushes and gnarly
trees.
Out of another I get a lovely view of the
bay and a little private wharf belonging to
the estate.
There is a beautiful shaded lane that runs
down there from the house.
I always fancy I see people walking in these
numerous paths and arbors, but John has cautioned
me not to give way to fancy in the least.
He says that with my imaginative power and
habit of story-making a nervous weakness like
mine is sure to lead to all manner of excited
fancies, and that I ought to use my will and
good sense to check the tendency.
So I try.
I think sometimes that if I were only well
enough to write a little it would relieve
the press of ideas and rest me.
But I find I get pretty tired when I try.
It is so discouraging not to have any advice
and companionship about my work.
When I get really well John says we will ask
Cousin Henry and Julia down for a long visit;
but he says he would as soon put fire-works
in my pillow-case as to let me have those
stimulating people about now.
I wish I could get well faster.
But I must not think about that.
This paper looks to me as if it knew what
a vicious influence it had!
There is a recurrent spot where the pattern
lolls like a broken neck and two bulbous eyes
stare at you upside-down.
I get positively angry with the impertinence
of it and the everlastingness.
Up and down and sideways they crawl, and those
absurd, unblinking eyes are everywhere.
There is one place where two breadths didn’t
match, and the eyes go all up and down the
line, one a little higher than the other.
I never saw so much expression in an inanimate
thing before, and we all know how much expression
they have!
I used to lie awake as a child and get more
entertainment and terror out of blank walls
and plain furniture than most children could
find in a toy-store.
I remember what a kindly wink the knobs of
our big old bureau used to have, and there
was one chair that always seemed like a strong
friend.
I used to feel that if any of the other things
looked too fierce I could always hop into
that chair and be safe.
The furniture in this room is no worse than
inharmonious, however, for we had to bring
it all from downstairs.
I suppose when this was used as a playroom
they had to take the nursery things out, and
no wonder!
I never saw such ravages as the children have
made here.
The wallpaper, as I said before, is torn off
in spots, and it sticketh closer than a brother—they
must have had perseverance as well as hatred.
Then the floor is scratched and gouged and
splintered, the plaster itself is dug out
here and there, and this great heavy bed,
which is all we found in the room, looks as
if it had been through the wars.
But I don’t mind it a bit—only the paper.
There comes John’s sister.
Such a dear girl as she is, and so careful
of me!
I must not let her find me writing.
She is a perfect, and enthusiastic housekeeper,
and hopes for no better profession.
I verily believe she thinks it is the writing
which made me sick!
But I can write when she is out, and see her
a long way off from these windows.
There is one that commands the road, a lovely,
shaded, winding road, and one that just looks
off over the country.
A lovely country, too, full of great elms
and velvet meadows.
This wallpaper has a kind of sub-pattern in
a different shade, a particularly irritating
one, for you can only see it in certain lights,
and not clearly then.
But in the places where it isn’t faded,
and where the sun is just so, I can see a
strange, provoking, formless sort of figure,
that seems to sulk about behind that silly
and conspicuous front design.
There’s sister on the stairs!
## ---
Well, the Fourth of July is over!
The people are gone and I am tired out.
John thought it might do me good to see a
little company, so we just had mother and
Nellie and the children down for a week.
Of course I didn’t do a thing.
Jennie sees to everything now.
But it tired me all the same.
John says if I don’t pick up faster he shall
send me to Weir Mitchell in the fall.
But I don’t want to go there at all.
I had a friend who was in his hands once,
and she says he is just like John and my brother,
only more so!
Besides, it is such an undertaking to go so
far.
I don’t feel as if it was worth while to
turn my hand over for anything, and I’m
getting dreadfully fretful and querulous.
I cry at nothing, and cry most of the time.
Of course I don’t when John is here, or
anybody else, but when I am alone.
And I am alone a good deal just now.
John is kept in town very often by serious
cases, and Jennie is good and lets me alone
when I want her to.
So I walk a little in the garden or down that
lovely lane, sit on the porch under the roses,
and lie down up here a good deal.
I’m getting really fond of the room in spite
of the wallpaper.
Perhaps because of the wallpaper.
It dwells in my mind so!
I lie here on this great immovable bed—it
is nailed down, I believe—and follow that
pattern about by the hour.
It is as good as gymnastics, I assure you.
I start, we’ll say, at the bottom, down
in the corner over there where it has not
been touched, and I determine for the thousandth
time that I will follow that pointless pattern
to some sort of a conclusion.
I know a little of the principle of design,
and I know this thing was not arranged on
any laws of radiation, or alternation, or
repetition, or symmetry, or anything else
that I ever heard of.
It is repeated, of course, by the breadths,
but not otherwise.
Looked at in one way each breadth stands alone,
the bloated curves and flourishes—a kind
of “debased Romanesque” with delirium
tremens—go waddling up and down in isolated
columns of fatuity.
But, on the other hand, they connect diagonally,
and the sprawling outlines run off in great
slanting waves of optic horror, like a lot
of wallowing seaweeds in full chase.
The whole thing goes horizontally, too, at
least it seems so, and I exhaust myself in
trying to distinguish the order of its going
in that direction.
They have used a horizontal breadth for a
frieze, and that adds wonderfully to the confusion.
There is one end of the room where it is almost
intact, and there, when the cross-lights fade
and the low sun shines directly upon it, I
can almost fancy radiation after all,—the
interminable grotesques seem to form around
a common centre and rush off in headlong plunges
of equal distraction.
It makes me tired to follow it.
I will take a nap, I guess.
## ---
I don’t know why I should write this.
I don’t want to.
I don’t feel able.
And I know John would think it absurd.
But I must say what I feel and think in some
way—it is such a relief!
But the effort is getting to be greater than
the relief.
Half the time now I am awfully lazy, and lie
down ever so much.
John says I musn’t lose my strength, and
has me take cod-liver oil and lots of tonics
and things, to say nothing of ale and wine
and rare meat.
Dear John!
He loves me very dearly, and hates to have
me sick.
I tried to have a real earnest reasonable
talk with him the other day, and tell him
how I wish he would let me go and make a visit
to Cousin Henry and Julia.
But he said I wasn’t able to go, nor able
to stand it after I got there; and I did not
make out a very good case for myself, for
I was crying before I had finished.
It is getting to be a great effort for me
to think straight.
Just this nervous weakness, I suppose.
And dear John gathered me up in his arms,
and just carried me upstairs and laid me on
the bed, and sat by me and read to me till
it tired my head.
He said I was his darling and his comfort
and all he had, and that I must take care
of myself for his sake, and keep well.
He says no one but myself can help me out
of it, that I must use my will and self-control
and not let any silly fancies run away with
me.
There’s one comfort, the baby is well and
happy, and does not have to occupy this nursery
with the horrid wallpaper.
If we had not used it that blessed child would
have!
What a fortunate escape!
Why, I wouldn’t have a child of mine, an
impressionable little thing, live in such
a room for worlds.
I never thought of it before, but it is lucky
that John kept me here after all.
I can stand it so much easier than a baby,
you see.
Of course I never mention it to them any more,—I
am too wise,—but I keep watch of it all
the same.
There are things in that paper that nobody
knows but me, or ever will.
Behind that outside pattern the dim shapes
get clearer every day.
It is always the same shape, only very numerous.
And it is like a woman stooping down and creeping
about behind that pattern.
I don’t like it a bit.
I wonder—I begin to think—I wish John
would take me away from here!
## ---
It is so hard to talk with John about my case,
because he is so wise, and because he loves
me so.
But I tried it last night.
It was moonlight.
The moon shines in all around, just as the
sun does.
I hate to see it sometimes, it creeps so slowly,
and always comes in by one window or another.
John was asleep and I hated to waken him,
so I kept still and watched the moonlight
on that undulating wallpaper till I felt creepy.
The faint figure behind seemed to shake the
pattern, just as if she wanted to get out.
I got up softly and went to feel and see if
the paper did move, and when I came back John
was awake.
“What is it, little girl?” he said.
“Don’t go walking about like that—you’ll
get cold.”
I thought it was a good time to talk, so I
told him that I really was not gaining here,
and that I wished he would take me away.
“Why darling!” said he, “our lease will
be up in three weeks, and I can’t see how
to leave before.
“The repairs are not done at home, and I
cannot possibly leave town just now.
Of course if you were in any danger I could
and would, but you really are better, dear,
whether you can see it or not.
I am a doctor, dear, and I know.
You are gaining flesh and color, your appetite
is better.
I feel really much easier about you.”
“I don’t weigh a bit more,” said I,
“nor as much; and my appetite may be better
in the evening, when you are here, but it
is worse in the morning when you are away.”
“Bless her little heart!” said he with
a big hug; “she shall be as sick as she
pleases!
But now let’s improve the shining hours
by going to sleep, and talk about it in the
morning!”
“And you won’t go away?”
I asked gloomily.
“Why, how can I, dear?
It is only three weeks more and then we will
take a nice little trip of a few days while
Jennie is getting the house ready.
Really, dear, you are better!”
“Better in body perhaps”—I began, and
stopped short, for he sat up straight and
looked at me with such a stern, reproachful
look that I could not say another word.
“My darling,” said he, “I beg of you,
for my sake and for our child’s sake, as
well as for your own, that you will never
for one instant let that idea enter your mind!
There is nothing so dangerous, so fascinating,
to a temperament like yours.
It is a false and foolish fancy.
Can you not trust me as a physician when I
tell you so?”
So of course I said no more on that score,
and we went to sleep before long.
He thought I was asleep first, but I wasn’t,—I
lay there for hours trying to decide whether
that front pattern and the back pattern really
did move together or separately.
On a pattern like this, by daylight, there
is a lack of sequence, a defiance of law,
that is a constant irritant to a normal mind.
The color is hideous enough, and unreliable
enough, and infuriating enough, but the pattern
is torturing.
You think you have mastered it, but just as
you get well under way in following, it turns
a back somersault and there you are.
It slaps you in the face, knocks you down,
and tramples upon you.
It is like a bad dream.
The outside pattern is a florid arabesque,
reminding one of a fungus.
If you can imagine a toadstool in joints,
an interminable string of toadstools, budding
and sprouting in endless convolutions,—why,
that is something like it.
That is, sometimes!
There is one marked peculiarity about this
paper, a thing nobody seems to notice but
myself, and that is that it changes as the
light changes.
When the sun shoots in through the east window—I
always watch for that first long, straight
ray—it changes so quickly that I never can
quite believe it.
That is why I watch it always.
By moonlight—the moon shines in all night
when there is a moon—I wouldn’t know it
was the same paper.
At night in any kind of light, in twilight,
candlelight, lamplight, and worst of all by
moonlight, it becomes bars!
The outside pattern I mean, and the woman
behind it is as plain as can be.
I didn’t realize for a long time what the
thing was that showed behind,—that dim sub-pattern,—but
now I am quite sure it is a woman.
By daylight she is subdued, quiet.
I fancy it is the pattern that keeps her so
still.
It is so puzzling.
It keeps me quiet by the hour.
I lie down ever so much now.
John says it is good for me, and to sleep
all I can.
Indeed, he started the habit by making me
lie down for an hour after each meal.
It is a very bad habit, I am convinced, for,
you see, I don’t sleep.
And that cultivates deceit, for I don’t
tell them I’m awake,—oh, no!
The fact is, I am getting a little afraid
of John.
He seems very queer sometimes, and even Jennie
has an inexplicable look.
It strikes me occasionally, just as a scientific
hypothesis, that perhaps it is the paper!
I have watched John when he did not know I
was looking, and come into the room suddenly
on the most innocent excuses, and I’ve caught
him several times looking at the paper!
And Jennie too.
I caught Jennie with her hand on it once.
She didn’t know I was in the room, and when
I asked her in a quiet, a very quiet voice,
with the most restrained manner possible,
what she was doing with the paper she turned
around as if she had been caught stealing,
and looked quite angry—asked me why I should
frighten her so!
Then she said that the paper stained everything
it touched, that she had found yellow smooches
on all my clothes and John’s, and she wished
we would be more careful!
Did not that sound innocent?
But I know she was studying that pattern,
and I am determined that nobody shall find
it out but myself!
## ---
Life is very much more exciting now than it
used to be.
You see I have something more to expect, to
look forward to, to watch.
I really do eat better, and am more quiet
than I was.
John is so pleased to see me improve!
He laughed a little the other day, and said
I seemed to be flourishing in spite of my
wallpaper.
I turned it off with a laugh.
I had no intention of telling him it was because
of the wallpaper—he would make fun of me.
He might even want to take me away.
I don’t want to leave now until I have found
it out.
There is a week more, and I think that will
be enough.
## ---
I’m feeling ever so much better!
I don’t sleep much at night, for it is so
interesting to watch developments; but I sleep
a good deal in the daytime.
In the daytime it is tiresome and perplexing.
There are always new shoots on the fungus,
and new shades of yellow all over it.
I cannot keep count of them, though I have
tried conscientiously.
It is the strangest yellow, that wallpaper!
It makes me think of all the yellow things
I ever saw—not beautiful ones like buttercups,
but old foul, bad yellow things.
But there is something else about that paper—the
smell!
I noticed it the moment we came into the room,
but with so much air and sun it was not bad.
Now we have had a week of fog and rain, and
whether the windows are open or not, the smell
is here.
It creeps all over the house.
I find it hovering in the dining-room, skulking
in the parlor, hiding in the hall, lying in
wait for me on the stairs.
It gets into my hair.
Even when I go to ride, if I turn my head
suddenly and surprise it—there is that smell!
Such a peculiar odor, too!
I have spent hours in trying to analyze it,
to find what it smelled like.
It is not bad—at first, and very gentle,
but quite the subtlest, most enduring odor
I ever met.
In this damp weather it is awful.
I wake up in the night and find it hanging
over me.
It used to disturb me at first.
I thought seriously of burning the house—to
reach the smell.
But now I am used to it.
The only thing I can think of that it is like
is the color of the paper!
A yellow smell.
There is a very funny mark on this wall, low
down, near the mopboard.
A streak that runs round the room.
It goes behind every piece of furniture, except
the bed, a long, straight, even smooch, as
if it had been rubbed over and over.
I wonder how it was done and who did it, and
what they did it for.
Round and round and round—round and round
and round—it makes me dizzy!
## ---
I really have discovered something at last.
Through watching so much at night, when it
changes so, I have finally found out.
The front pattern does move—and no wonder!
The woman behind shakes it!
Sometimes I think there are a great many women
behind, and sometimes only one, and she crawls
around fast, and her crawling shakes it all
over.
Then in the very bright spots she keeps still,
and in the very shady spots she just takes
hold of the bars and shakes them hard.
And she is all the time trying to climb through.
But nobody could climb through that pattern—it
strangles so; I think that is why it has so
many heads.
They get through, and then the pattern strangles
them off and turns them upside-down, and makes
their eyes white!
If those heads were covered or taken off it
would not be half so bad.
## ---
I think that woman gets out in the daytime!
And I’ll tell you why—privately—I’ve
seen her!
I can see her out of every one of my windows!
It is the same woman, I know, for she is always
creeping, and most women do not creep by daylight.
I see her on that long shaded lane, creeping
up and down.
I see her in those dark grape arbors, creeping
all around the garden.
I see her on that long road under the trees,
creeping along, and when a carriage comes
she hides under the blackberry vines.
I don’t blame her a bit.
It must be very humiliating to be caught creeping
by daylight!
I always lock the door when I creep by daylight.
I can’t do it at night, for I know John
would suspect something at once.
And John is so queer now, that I don’t want
to irritate him.
I wish he would take another room!
Besides, I don’t want anybody to get that
woman out at night but myself.
I often wonder if I could see her out of all
the windows at once.
But, turn as fast as I can, I can only see
out of one at one time.
And though I always see her she may be able
to creep faster than I can turn!
I have watched her sometimes away off in the
open country, creeping as fast as a cloud
shadow in a high wind.
## ---
If only that top pattern could be gotten off
from the under one!
I mean to try it, little by little.
I have found out another funny thing, but
I shan’t tell it this time!
It does not do to trust people too much.
There are only two more days to get this paper
off, and I believe John is beginning to notice.
I don’t like the look in his eyes.
And I heard him ask Jennie a lot of professional
questions about me.
She had a very good report to give.
She said I slept a good deal in the daytime.
John knows I don’t sleep very well at night,
for all I’m so quiet!
He asked me all sorts of questions, too, and
pretended to be very loving and kind.
As if I couldn’t see through him!
Still, I don’t wonder he acts so, sleeping
under this paper for three months.
It only interests me, but I feel sure John
and Jennie are secretly affected by it.
## ---
Hurrah!
This is the last day, but it is enough.
John is to stay in town over night, and won’t
be out until this evening.
Jennie wanted to sleep with me—the sly thing!
but I told her I should undoubtedly rest better
for a night all alone.
That was clever, for really I wasn’t alone
a bit!
As soon as it was moonlight, and that poor
thing began to crawl and shake the pattern,
I got up and ran to help her.
I pulled and she shook, I shook and she pulled,
and before morning we had peeled off yards
of that paper.
A strip about as high as my head and half
around the room.
And then when the sun came and that awful
pattern began to laugh at me I declared I
would finish it to-day!
We go away to-morrow, and they are moving
all my furniture down again to leave things
as they were before.
Jennie looked at the wall in amazement, but
I told her merrily that I did it out of pure
spite at the vicious thing.
She laughed and said she wouldn’t mind doing
it herself, but I must not get tired.
How she betrayed herself that time!
But I am here, and no person touches this
paper but me—not alive!
She tried to get me out of the room—it was
too patent!
But I said it was so quiet and empty and clean
now that I believed I would lie down again
and sleep all I could; and not to wake me
even for dinner—I would call when I woke.
So now she is gone, and the servants are gone,
and the things are gone, and there is nothing
left but that great bedstead nailed down,
with the canvas mattress we found on it.
We shall sleep downstairs to-night, and take
the boat home to-morrow.
I quite enjoy the room, now it is bare again.
How those children did tear about here!
This bedstead is fairly gnawed!
But I must get to work.
I have locked the door and thrown the key
down into the front path.
I don’t want to go out, and I don’t want
to have anybody come in, till John comes.
I want to astonish him.
I’ve got a rope up here that even Jennie
did not find.
If that woman does get out, and tries to get
away, I can tie her!
But I forgot I could not reach far without
anything to stand on!
This bed will not move!
I tried to lift and push it until I was lame,
and then I got so angry I bit off a little
piece at one corner—but it hurt my teeth.
Then I peeled off all the paper I could reach
standing on the floor.
It sticks horribly and the pattern just enjoys
it!
All those strangled heads and bulbous eyes
and waddling fungus growths just shriek with
derision!
I am getting angry enough to do something
desperate.
To jump out of the window would be admirable
exercise, but the bars are too strong even
to try.
Besides I wouldn’t do it.
Of course not.
I know well enough that a step like that is
improper and might be misconstrued.
I don’t like to look out of the windows
even—there are so many of those creeping
women, and they creep so fast.
I wonder if they all come out of that wallpaper
as I did?
But I am securely fastened now by my well-hidden
rope—you don’t get me out in the road
there!
I suppose I shall have to get back behind
the pattern when it comes night, and that
is hard!
It is so pleasant to be out in this great
room and creep around as I please!
I don’t want to go outside.
I won’t, even if Jennie asks me to.
For outside you have to creep on the ground,
and everything is green instead of yellow.
But here I can creep smoothly on the floor,
and my shoulder just fits in that long smooch
around the wall, so I cannot lose my way.
Why, there’s John at the door!
It is no use, young man, you can’t open
it!
How he does call and pound!
Now he’s crying for an axe.
It would be a shame to break down that beautiful
door!
“John dear!” said I in the gentlest voice,
“the key is down by the front steps, under
a plantain leaf!”
That silenced him for a few moments.
Then he said—very quietly indeed, “Open
the door, my darling!”
“I can’t,” said I.
“The key is down by the front door under
a plantain leaf!”
And then I said it again, several times, very
gently and slowly, and said it so often that
he had to go and see, and he got it, of course,
and came in.
He stopped short by the door.
“What is the matter?” he cried.
“For God’s sake, what are you doing!”
I kept on creeping just the same, but I looked
at him over my shoulder.
“I’ve got out at last,” said I, “in
spite of you and Jennie!
And I’ve pulled off most of the paper, so
you can’t put me back!”
Now why should that man have fainted?
But he did, and right across my path by the
wall, so that I had to creep over him every
time!