I did a linguistic experiment last year
I purposely filmed the newscasts for several months using Old Moscow pronunciation.
unfortunately the public didn't understand why I pronounced some words differently
so let this video serve as a radical clarification of all the questions in the comments on this subject
and by the way this video will also be on the old Moscow pronunciation so that all the nuances are not only in theory
but also perceived by ear
First let's break it down like this
the classic old Moscow accent
Its traits could be often heard in the late Soviet period among speakers of TV and radio, among actors.
actors, especially those who played in the theater.
like the modern literary accent, it was not only spoken by Muscovites by birth
it was easily adopted by the non-Moscovites, but in varying degrees
assimilating different traits
so the old-Moscow peculiarities could be heard in the speech of various prominent people of those years
and there's written or audio evidence of that, like this.
when orthography was not yet settled, Old Moscow features were often reflected in the writing
so the magazine published by Karamzin in the original spelling was called
Moscow magazine
Old Moscow pronunciation, at least implied in the reading of a particular work
can often be determined
from poetic texts such as Pushkin's Eugene Onegin
thus by their sounding these forms completely correspond to the feminine forms
genitive
high no high austere no austere and so on.
there is no need to pronounce them with some special emphasis or stress on the ending
otherwise it's a caricature.
not all combinations of chn become shn
there is no strict rule, but shn was avoided where it could cause unwanted associations
for example we didn't say oriental instead of oriental or redundant instead of personal
and also schn seems to have always sounded simply in new borrowed words
so it was also avoided, let's say we didn't say
romantic typical logical instead of romantic typical logical
Here are examples from the author's spelling of the classics
But there's also this restaurant in Moscow on Pokrovka, a stone's throw from the tower's economics department.
I invite all devotees of old Moscow speech to gather here for some imposing leisure
So, if in modern language we see a combination of consonant + consonant + softening vowel.
and in our language it's eeu ya, only the last consonant will be soft.
In Old Moscow pronunciation all consonants in a syllable become soft.
Softness can go not only through one consonant, but through two or three.
Of course, these are not all the features of Old Moscow pronunciation.
just the most important ones.
just in case
If you hear one or two Old Moscow traits in a speech, it does not mean anything at all.
the person may have nothing to do with Moscow,
and he certainly can't be suspected of having learned his pronunciation.
the fact is that each dialect contains not only some unique traits
but also those that it has in common with some other dialects and with the whole language.
so the ending oy of adjectives was characteristic of all Old Russian northeastern accents
that's why we still have it under stress
the pronunciation is common between Moscow and southern Russian accents
initial and was still in Proto-Slavonic and its traces can still be found in the various modern Slavonic languages.
the oppositional softness of consonants is still a pre-Blavonic invention.
It's survived equally in Lithuanian, Polish, Russian and other languages.
often when people listen to an old speech, not necessarily Russian, they think.
what a wonderful pronunciation it was. What a pity it's gone.
No, friends.
it hasn't disappeared.
and that could only happen if at some point the entire population of the city left or died.
as was the case several times in the history of Veliky Novgorod
the last time during the Second World War, all its population after the war were newcomers from other cities or from the region
all of its postwar population are migrants from other cities or from the region.
but luckily Moscow has never had that, and that's why we still speak with a lot of old-Moscow traits
now I will be guided not by theoretical knowledge but by my own linguistic experience as a fourth-generation Muscovite
But just in case, I decided to make my conclusions a bit more objective, and for this I conducted a survey in my facebook group
By the time the video was recorded, I had received 62 questionnaires
I asked only native Muscovites to participate in the survey
Of course, there were some additional questions, but the main task was this
I had to distribute 30 examples into three groups.
The first is what I said myself.
The second is that I've heard it, but I don't say it myself.
and the third is I haven't heard it, but I don't say it myself.
and by "hear" you mean
not in general, let's say the Internet, an old movie doesn't count, but it's in live speech in life
Yes, I already agree in advance with professional linguists this way of survey is the worst way to collect linguistic material
I have described the results of this survey in more detail in my group post.
the results themselves you can also follow the link in the description
this trait is gone from the speech.
but it can still be found where it's used for artistic purposes.
say in a play or in a song in a particular layer.
it's quite firmly associated with theatricality, in my opinion.
it's still often found in old actors and TV hosts.
but it's disappeared from the vernacular altogether, except for the combination of ls
Many people still say stayed, feared, confessed, married.
most of the words we say with a chn, new words always with a chn.
but there are still a few words you can almost definitely use to identify a non-Russian.
a Muscovite will never say of course on purpose
birdhouse egg
however, there are many words where Muscovites now say it both ways
mustard or mustardy chambermaid or chambermaid
rag or raggy or raggy no-nonsense or no-nonsense decent or decent
Now I'm going to be
linguistic subjectivism and also localism
there is such a word as boring
Muscovites pronounce it that way most often, of course they can also say boring, but this is rare
Again, look at the results of the survey
So, not far from where I lived as a child there are
Of course a local always has to say
a boring garden.
but a visitor, a person from the outside can say not boring
I don't know if the locals took part in my survey but the results are very strange
curious is also the word enough
I myself as a child talked both ways and so I distinctly remembered only a few people
who spoke as I did
surprisingly out of 62 respondents 10 said they could say enough too
I think that's a little bit
it's a little bit strange nevertheless it doesn't stop me from going on with my story
So there was this one time I was dating a girl.
she is not from moscow she just studied here and in general her speech was no different from that of all other Muscovites except for
except for one thing she was always talking
quite
when I noticed that she spoke so well, I was so delighted that I made a rule
one old Moscow trait in her speech with me kiss my cheek
Well, to her credit, she didn't get that pronunciation more or less often after that.
I wondered who else in my circle speaks enough and I remembered only
Four people are my former boss, a PhD candidate in philology.
and 2 other elderly philologists who often give talks at conferences, I take them off at work and also all of a sudden
Arseniy Klinchev from the N Cyclops Channel
even though he's from Khimki.
also, the surnames are still kept in the patronymics
I think that every man has ever wondered what to name his children
and how this or that name will go with the patronymic
but since I myself am Nikita, I am well aware that the feminine form is still
Nikitishna
and not nikitichna
but not everyone is aware of it so I had a girlfriend who is called Maria Nikitishna
and it was very annoying when someone pronounced her patronymic with a "n" once she even went on a tirade about it
So what so what so for some Muscovites are still unacceptable forms
Nikitichna Kuzminichna
Ilyinichna and others keep this in mind because the unfamiliar pronunciation of one's own name usually causes people
strongest emotions
It all depends somehow on the specific words. There are words where no one will ever say never.
although most people in my survey said they would say snow.
and also quite a lot of people admit
if
something about the soft r sound.
it's lost a little bit differently in the speech of Muscovites
so the researcher Antonova this is 2008
analyzed about four hours of tv recordings and in 17 percent of the cases the speakers still had
the soft "r" in the following words.
well in my speech it was always borscht borscht and
maybe also these words, I don't know about the others, it's hard to say.
It's very different here, too, depending on the word.
it turns out most people don't say comb and apparently they say comb
but what exactly a Muscovite will never say is man
Most of the Muscovites in the survey also pronounce these soft g's
we still say easy, easy even though we should say easy otherwise.
easy, easy.
these two words seem to be the only thing we have left of the old phonetics.
These forms seem very rustic, but we don't speak that way for sure
No, we don't.
let's go back to the Antonova research, she showed that up to 15 percent of young people have such variants in their speech
In the older age group the percentage goes up to 50
what I'm about to say applies to both modern and old speech
Muscovites speak Muscovite dialect, which belongs to the Middle Russian dialect group
moreover Muscovites speak in a literary language and even though the pronunciation of the Old Moscow itself has long since become
an extraordinary curiosity
it is still considered one of the literary standards
There is no contradiction here. Don't think that dialects are necessarily the language spoken in the provinces or in the countryside.
and a literary language is only the language of literature
Everyone speaks their dialect.
it is simply a territorial variety of speech, it may coincide with a literary, i.e. standardized
standardized language may not.
In our case, it coincides because the Russian literary norm
is based on the dialects of Moscow and St. Petersburg.
and the pronunciation itself, both of Muscovites of the past and of contemporary Muscovites
was not and is not unified, and has always been so
and so it's not surprising to think that
Pasternak the pastor from Moscow softened a consonant, he said the stars sleep, he said easy, but at the same time he didn't pronounce it firmly I'm afraid
or that Trotsky, for whom the Old Moscow pronunciation was not natural, but who wanted to master it, mastered it
he was good at it, but not good enough, and that's why he pronounced the same adjective endings differently within one and the same speech
a hundred and fifty years ago the gap between
the literary pronunciation and the common Moscow pronunciation was greater than even now
There is also an opinion that Old Moscow pronunciation is largely sociolect.
Today we're convinced that
it was more typical not so much for Muscovites as such but for educated people of that time not necessarily from Moscow
in moscow itself, it was more common to hear the so-called
Moscow urban vernacular.
you can also read about it in one paper, the link is in the description.
in particular, it was characterized by this mannerly
Moscow
pronunciation from the caricature of teasers
with the stretching of the first pre-vowel syllable in the acan, I always thought it was a stupid stereotype.
but that's not how it turned out.
It turned out that this was indeed how people in Moscow used to speak
but not by educated people but by those whose ancestors were from bourgeoisie
It took me a long time to find people who spoke that way and yet I found one
Platoshtin didn't come from Moscow, but from the suburbs
And it is possible that the way he speaks, and used to speak all over Moscow, but I must say right away that I do not have people with this pronunciation in my
I've never heard people with such a pronunciation in my neighborhood.
Two years ago I had the idea of making a program in the style of the sixties, linguofront
and it was inspired by both the cinema
Soviet and French new wave and in both countries at the time it was still in vogue
such a literary standard that was alien to most speakers, including in pronunciation
The Russian examples you've already heard, now you're going to hear
French I think there will be a huge difference between the pronunciation of the announcer
of the announcer who is trained in all the norms and the natural French speech of the singer who is being interviewed.
You don't even have to know French to do that. You'll notice this stiff intonation in the announcer's speech.
the longhts, the very distinct pronunciation of all the sounds.
so I turned to this tradition of ours and the old Moscow pronunciation I had in mind
was to create a kind of charm of those years and I studied the subject in detail myself and learned to speak it quite
at ease and also taught this pronunciation to my Sasha and then to the Encyclopa
and so at some point, from about June to October
2018 I was releasing all the videos on my channel in the old Moscow pronunciation
and then I decided to give it up because
people don't understand.
Yeah, some people appreciate the reference.
I think a lot of people noticed some weirdness in the pronunciation but
but a separate group of citizens didn't understand and started barking
I even made a tab under the video with explanations, but as you know
First of all, most commentators are lazy. Second of all, they write their
messages in a certain state of affect and most of the comments, unfortunately or fortunately
says that the commentators are still in a state of affect, i.e. they're in a very strong emotional turmoil.
that's why they can't read any of the other comments or the post and everyone asks the same questions for which at some point they want to
I'm going to get banned. What's your ending?
what's your dialect, what's your pronunciation, what's your profession, and so on.
But I will not say that this experiment was a mistake in my life, and here's what I made of it
first of all I created a lot of content in the old Moscow pronunciation in modern conditions with our contemporaries with a good quality of recording
at a modern pace of speech, that is, I showed how our literary language would have sounded if its history had gone differently in Soviet times
and this content was not only interesting in pronunciation but it was valuable in its own right
Pronunciation is just a curious thing.
Secondly, I felt myself in the skin of a person who doesn't know
the necessary pronunciation and intend to learn it, that is, I was like a collective farmer who in Soviet times in the years of urbanization
comes to town and intends to learn the accent that he hears from the townspeople.
the only nuance about the comments if the collective farmer heard rather reprimand for his
native accent is natural, then I hear censure for a learned accent
it's remarkable that
the mechanism of learning an idiom that is only a sneeze different from one's own
so yes, if you talk a lot, exercise a lot, then all these old forms
♪ Mayakovsky's first light-brown fly away ♪
but alas your native accent is stitched for life
so not everything, of course, but a lot of your learned pronunciation goes away
It's just when you're tired when you're nervous and less in control.
Thirdly, I'm not completely back to the way I spoke two years ago.
some of the individual words in the old Moscow sound I kept in my speech
and what's more I speak that way now, not only on video but all the time in life too
It's just mostly these very rare, barely noticeable peculiarities
that aren't unpleasant to the ear like the word first, let's say.
well, look at any of my broadcasts, that's how I talk, that's how I talk all the time.
with the old Moscow pronunciation I've given a certain charm to my speech.
Some people will say it's silly, but I'll partly agree.
But this is normal because the language of each of us ours and the dialect changes with age
and it doesn't always happen in some natural way
it can also be a deliberate move, for example, the study of literary norms at school, research
Old Moscow pronunciation was never quite equal to the pronunciation of Muscovites.
it was characteristic of various educated people in the past, mainly from Moscow, but not only
the later the bearer of the Old Moscow accent lived, the more likely it was that this accent was adopted
in Soviet times the Moscow standard was mostly pronounced by tv and radio presenters and by theatrical actors.
you can still hear it in some elderly representatives of those professions.
speech on the streets of Moscow differed in many respects from the standard we analyzed.
linguists call it Moscow urban vernacular.
The Old Moscow pronunciation as such has not disappeared completely.
it has simply dissolved into modern usage.
and in some words the old-Moscow traits seem commonplace to us
and in some words they sound obsolete.
and since the whole country has long been trying to talk like the capital
so features of the old Moscow pronunciation are now widespread everywhere.
Well, that's goodbye for now
♪ I'll throw the end ♪