last year I conducted one linguistic experiment,
I purposely shot episodes in the old Moscow pronunciation for several months,
unfortunately the mass audience then did not understand why I pronounce some words differently,
so let this video serve as a radical clarification of all questions in the comments on this subject
and  By the way, this video itself will also be in the old Moscow pronunciation so that all the nuances are not only in theory
but also perceived by ear.
First, let's analyze, let's say, the
classic old Moscow pronunciation,
its features could often be heard even in late Soviet times from TV, radio announcers, and actors
among actors, especially among those who played in the theater,
as well as in modern literary pronunciation, it was spoken not only by Muscovites by birth,
it was easily adopted by people from other cities, but to varying degrees
assimilating different features,
so old Moscow features could be heard in the speech of various prominent people of those years
and on  i.e. written or audio evidence, for example  this is
when the spelling was not yet well-established, the old Moscow features were often reflected in the letter,
so the magazine that Karamzin published in the original spelling was called the
Moscow magazine, the
old Moscow pronunciation, at least implied when reading a particular work
, can often be
determined from poetic texts, for example, Pushkin Evgeny Onegin
thus, in terms of sound, these forms fully correspond to the feminine forms of the
genitive case
high no high strict no strict, and so on, you
don’t need to pronounce them with some special emphasis and emphasis on the ending,
otherwise it turns out to be a caricature,
however, not all combinations of h became shn
no clear rule  but shn was avoided where it could cause unwanted associations,
let’s say they didn’t say oriental instead of oriental or superfluous instead of personal,
also shn apparently always sounded colloquial in new borrowed words,
so it was also avoided, say, they didn’t say
romantic typical logical instead of romance  typical typical logical
here are examples from the author’s spelling of the classics,
but even in Moscow on Pokrovka, a stone’s throw from the economic faculty of the tower, there is such a restaurant, I
suggest that all zealots of the old Moscow speech gather here for joint imposing leisure,
so if we see a combination of consonant + consonant in modern language  + softening vowel
and we have this and e yo yu i then we will only have the last consonant
in the old Moscow pronunciation soft all the consonants of the syllable become soft
softness can be thrown not only through one consonant but also through two and three of
course this is not all all the features  old Moscow pronunciation,
only the most important ones
, just in case, I’ll say
if you hear one or two old Moscow features in a speech, this still doesn’t mean anything a
person may have nothing to do with Moscow,
and he certainly cannot be suspected of having learned such a pronunciation
the fact is that each dialect contains not only some unique features,
but also those that are common  he has some other dialects, and in general with the whole language,
so the ending oh of adjectives was characteristic of all Old Russian northeastern dialects,
so it still remains under stress with us
pronunciation they hear Moscow has in common with southern Russian dialects
initial  and was still in Proto-Slavic and its traces can still be found in various modern Slavic languages. The
oppositional softness of consonants is generally still a Proto-Balto-Slavic invention.
it seems to them,
oh, what a wonderful pronunciation it was, what a pity that she disappeared,
no, friends,
she didn’t disappear anywhere,
and this, in principle, could only happen if at some point the entire population of the city left it or died,
as we say, it was several times in  history with Veliky Novgorod for the
last time during the Great Patriotic War, all of its post-war population is  travelers from other cities or from the region,
all of its post-war population are visitors from other cities or from the region,
but fortunately this has never happened in Moscow and therefore we are still talking with a large number of features of old Moscow origin,
now I will no longer focus on theoretical knowledge  but on my language experience as a fourth-generation native Muscovite,
but just in case, I decided to make my fabrications a little more objective and for this I conducted a survey for my VKontakte group
by the time the video was recorded, I received 62 questionnaires
in the survey, I asked only native Muscovites to participate, of
course there were  some additional questions, but the main one was such a task,
it was necessary to distribute 30 examples into three groups, the
first is that I say it myself the
second I heard it but I don’t say it myself
and the third I didn’t hear it and I don’t say it
myself  does not count, but it is in live speech in life,
yes, I already agree with the prof in advance  With the help of linguists, this method of questioning is the worst way to collect linguistic material.
More about the results of this survey, I told in a post in my group
with the results themselves, you can also find the link in the description,
this feature has already disappeared from speech,
but it can still be found  where it is used for artistic purposes,
say in a play or in a song in some separate layer,
this feature is quite strongly associated with theatricality, in my opinion
it can still be often found among old actors and TV presenters,
but it has completely disappeared from live speech  with the exception of the combination of ls
, many people still say they remained afraid, they confessed, they married
most of the words we already speak with ch, new words are always with ch,
but still there are still a few words by which you can almost accurately determine a non-resident
Muscovite will never say of course on purpose a
birdhouse  scrambled eggs,
however, there are many words where Muscovites now say this way and that
mustard mud  and mustard maid or housemaid
rag or rag serious or serious decent or orderly
now I will show
linguistic subjectivism and at the same time shtetlness
there is such a word as boring
Muscovites most often pronounce it well, of course, they can say boring, but this is less often,
again, we look at the results of the survey
like this  here, not far from the place where he lived in childhood, of
course, a local always has to say a
boring garden,
and a visitor, a person from outside can say
boring whether the locals participated in my survey, I don’t know, but the results are very strangely
curious, also the word is enough
I myself in  as a child, I spoke this way and that, and therefore I clearly remembered only a few people
who spoke the same way as I did,
which is surprising out of 62 respondents, 10 said that they can also say enough,
in my opinion this is a little
strange, however, this does not bother me, I continue my story
like this  there was somehow such a case, I met a girl,
she is not from Moscow at all, she  here she is only studying and in general her speech was no different from the speech of all other Muscovites, with the
exception of one thing, she constantly spoke
enough
when I noticed this speech nuance in her I was so delighted that I made a rule
one old Moscow feature in her speech from me kiss my cheek
well  and to her credit, after that, she didn’t have such a pronunciation more or less often,
so I became thoughtful and who in my environment still speaks enough and I remembered only
4 people, this is my former boss, candidate of philological sciences,
also 2 more elderly philologists who we have  often make presentations at conferences, I take them off in the service, and also suddenly
Arseniy Klinchev from the channel n Cyclops,
although he comes from Khimki,
also sh n are still kept in patronymics,
I think that every man once thought about how you can name children
and how  this or that name will be combined with a patronymic,
but since I myself am Nikita, I am well aware that the female form is still nikitishna
and not nikitichna,
but not everyone  I was aware of this so I had a girlfriend already different her name is Maria Nikitishna
so it was very annoying when someone pronounced her middle name with h n once she even staged a tirade about this
so so so so for some Muscovites so far  and the forms
nikitichna kuzminichna
ilyinichna and others are not acceptable, keep this in mind because people usually have strong emotions for the unusual pronunciation of their own name,
everything depends somehow on specific words, there are also words where no one will ever say never firmly,
although most people in  In my survey, they said that they would say snow,
and also quite a lot of people admit
that if
something about the soft sound r
is lost a little differently in the speech of Muscovites,
so researcher Antonova
analyzed about four hours of recordings from television in 2008 and in 17 percent of cases the announcers still
soft p was preserved in the following words,
well, in my speech, there was definitely always borscht borscht, and
perhaps also these words about others I don’t know labor  but it
’s also very different to say here, depending on the word,
it turns out that most people don’t say a comb and apparently they say a comb,
but what exactly a Muscovite will never say is a man,
most Muscovites from the survey, by the way, also pronounce these soft ones,
we still speak easily, light though  otherwise they would have to speak easily
lekko, lekky
seems these two words are the only thing that we have left from that old phonetics,
such forms seem to be quite rural, but no one speaks like that for sure, but
no,
let's turn to the same study of Antonova, she showed  that up to 15 percent of young people have such variants in speech
in the older age group, this percentage reaches 50
what I will now say applies to modern speech and old
Muscovites speak the Moscow dialect, which belongs to the group of Central Russian dialects,
while Muscovites speak a literary language  and even despite the fact that the very old Moscow pronunciation has long become
an extraordinary curiosity
about  but it is still considered one of the literary standards of the
contradiction here, no, you don’t have to think that the dialects are spoken by the provinces or in general in the village,
and the literary language is only the language of literature
in their own dialect, the dialect is spoken, everything
is just a territorial variety of speech, it can coincide  with the literary, that is, the normalized
standardized language, it may not
coincide in our case, because the Russian literary norm is
based on the dialects of Moscow and St. Petersburg,
and the pronunciation of both Muscovites of the past and modern
ones was not and is not the same, and it has always been so,
and therefore there is nothing surprising, let's put  in the fact that the
Moscow pastor softened the consonant, said the stars sleep, spoke lightly, but at the same time did not pronounce firmly, I’m afraid I
’ll return, or that Trotsky, for whom the old Moscow pronunciation was not natural, but who wanted to master it, he became skilled in it
, but not enough, and therefore, within the framework of one and  the same speech, he speaks differently about  wore out the same endings of adjectives
one hundred and fifty years ago, the gap between the
literary pronunciation and the everyday Moscow pronunciation was greater and more noticeable than even now
there is also an opinion that the old Moscow pronunciation is largely a sociolect
today we are convinced that
it was more characteristic not so much of Muscovites  as such, but generally educated people of that time, not necessarily from Moscow,
in Moscow itself on the street, the so-called Moscow urban vernacular was more often heard
about him, you can also read about him in one work, the link in the description,
in particular, such a mannered Moscow pronunciation was characteristic of him
from a cartoon of teasers
with a stretching of the first pre-stressed syllable when yelling, I always thought that this was some kind of stupid stereotype,
but it just
turned out differently, it turned out completely, and it turned out that they really once spoke in Moscow,
but not educated people, but those whose ancestors were from the middle class
I have been looking for people who say so for a very long time and yet 1 n  Ashel
Platoshtin is not from Moscow, from the Moscow region,
and perhaps, as he says, they used to speak all over Moscow, but I’ll say right away that I never heard people with such a
pronunciation in my environment at all
two years ago I decided to shoot a program in the style of the sixties language front
and did it  under the impression of both the cinema of the
Soviet and the French new wave, and in both countries at that time such a literary standard was still held in high esteem,
which was alien to most carriers, including in the pronunciation of
Russian examples, you have already heard now you will hear
French, I think that a huge  the difference between the pronunciation of the
announcer who is trained in all the norms and the natural French speech of the singer who is being interviewed
for this, even knowing French is not necessary, you will definitely notice in the announcer's speech these prim intonations of
longitude this very clear pronunciation of all sounds
so I turned to this tradition of ours  and the old Moscow pronunciation, according to my idea,
should have been created  some charm of those years and I studied the topic in detail, I myself learned how to speak quite
naturally and also taught this reprimand to my Sasha and then another encyclop,
and at some point, from about June to October
2018, I generally released all the videos on my  channel on the old Moscow pronunciation,
then I decided to abandon it because the
people do not understand,
yes, of course, someone appreciated the reference,
many, I think, noticed some oddities in the pronunciation, but
tactfully kept silent, but a separate group of citizens did not understand anything and started to babble,
I even made a fix under the video  with explanations, but as you understand
, firstly, most commentators are lazy; secondly, they write their
messages in a state of some affect, and most of the comments, unfortunately or fortunately,
indicate that the commentators are still in the affect one way or another, that is, they are in a very strong emotional  shocked,
therefore they cannot read either other comments or the fix itself, and everyone asks one and  the same questions for which at some point you want to
start banning and what is your ending
and what is your dialect and what is the pronunciation of the costs of the profession and so on,
but I will not say that this experiment was some kind of mistake in my life and  that's what I got out of it for myself
firstly, I created a lot of content in the old Moscow pronunciation in modern conditions with our contemporaries with good recording quality
at a modern pace of speech, that is, I showed how our literary language would sound if its history in Soviet times  went differently,
well, this content was interesting not only for pronunciation, but it was valuable in itself
pronunciation is just a curious feature, so to speak
, secondly, I felt myself in the shoes of a person who does not know the
necessary pronunciation and intends to master it, that is, I was like such a collective farmer who  in Soviet times, during the years of urbanization, he
comes to the city and intends to master there the reprimand that he hears from the townspeople, the
only nuance about the comments of the EU  if the collective farmer heard rather reproach for his
native natural accent, then I hear reproach for the accent learned
it is noteworthy that the
mechanism for mastering an idiom that differs only in some sneeze from his own
is such that if you talk a lot and practice a lot, then all these old forms of
Mayakovsky are the first light  brown ones fly away by themselves,
but alas, your native accent is firmware for life,
so not everything, of course, but a lot of your learned pronunciation goes away
just when you are tired, when you worry and, accordingly, control yourself less
in the third, and I have not fully returned to how I spoke for two years  ago,
I left some separate words in the old Moscow sound in my speech,
and moreover, now I say this not only on video, but in general, always in life, too, it’s
just basically such very rare, barely noticeable features
that do not strike an unpleasant ear like a word in  - first, let's say
in general, watch any of my broadcasts, that's how I say there, I always say that
old Moscow  I still gave some kind of charm to my speech with my pronunciation, of
course, someone will say nonsense, that's all I partly agree,
but this is normal because the language of each of us and our dialect changes with age
and far from always this happens in some natural way,
it can be  a conscious move, well, suppose the study of literary norms at school, research, the
old Moscow pronunciation was never completely equal to the pronunciation of Muscovites,
it was characteristic of various educated people in the past, mainly from Moscow, but not only
the later the bearer of the old Moscow accent lived, the more likely this pronunciation was put
in  In Soviet times, the Moscow standard sounded mainly from TV and radio announcers, from theater
actors, some elderly representatives of these professions can still hear
it, but the speech of Moscow streets differed in many respects from the standard we analyzed by
linguists, it is called Moscow urban vernacular
completely Staromoskovsk  its pronunciation as such did not disappear,
it simply dissolved in modern everyday life
and in some words the old Moscow features seem ordinary to us,
but somewhere they sound already clearly outdated,
and since the whole country has long been trying to speak like the capital,
then the features of the old Moscow pronunciation  now widespread
everywhere, well, but on that, goodbye for now I
’ll throw an end