About two thousand years ago,
during the reign of Cleopatra, the Queen of Queens,
the Egyptians spoke like this...
This language is certainly not easy to understand.
The film you are about to see will therefore be dubbed in French.
But the techniques of the time
being less perfect than those of today,
you will notice that, sometimes,
the lip movements are slightly out of sync
with the spoken words.
After this prologue, as interesting as instructive...
we have the honor and the advantage...
to present you a great historical fresco.
I, Cleopatra, cannot accept your contempt, oh Caesar!
I will not tolerate the insulting words of the chief of barbarians
who occupy my country only because I want them to!
The Romans are incapable of building solid monuments.
While our monuments
will accumulate millennia without suffering in the least.
And you dare to tell me that we are not
able to build properly anymore!
Any other than you would have already
met my sacred crocodiles.
You can't insult me with impunity!
If only you had the courtesy to listen to me,
but the Romans don't know the meaning of the word courtesy.
To say that we, the descendants of the pharaohs,
are unable to build,
it's ignoble, filthy, ridiculous, grotesque, unseemly!
To finish, what you say here is infamous, Caesar.
Face the facts.
- Your people are decadent. - They built the pyramids.
The tower of Pharos, the temples, the obelisks!
It's all old.
Enough of this!
I will prove to you that my people are not decadent.
In 3 months, I will have built you a sumptuous palace
here, in Alexandria.
Well, it's understood.
If you win your bet, I will recognize that your people
is still a great people.
She is cute, but the spices go up her nose...
which she has pretty, by the way.
Edifis,
you're the best architect in Alexandria, and that's not much.
Your houses are the laughing stock of those who don't live there.
My specialty is pyramids.
You have three months to redeem yourself by building a palace.
Here, in Alexandria, for Julius Caesar.
3 months?
If you succeed, I'll cover you with gold, if not,
I'll throw you to the crocodiles. Go!
Three months! To succeed, I would need the help of a mage.
A mage ?
I am saved!
I know just the man.
I will train him to carry menhirs.
Meanwhile, set the table.
The druid Getafix, please.
On the tree, picking mistletoe.
Getafix!
Ouch!
Oh, what a nice surprise!
I'm, my dear friend, very happy to see you.
It's an alexandrine.
Let me introduce you to my friend Edifis,
an architect from Alexandria.
I have to build a palace for Caesar
within 3 months.
If I don't..,
Cleopatra will feed me to the crocodiles.
- Do you eat crocodiles? - Hush, Obelix.
If you don't help me I won't succeed.
Calm down, Edifis.
I'll go to Egypt with you.
Us too, by Toutatis. Us too, by Toutatis.
By Osiris. Is that right?
We're going to have a nice trip, ldefix.
Are you taking him with you?
And why not, mister Asterix?
He's too small for such a big trip.
Go pack your bags.
I'm the stooge, the sidekick.
I have no say in the matter.
My friends, be worthy of us,
and may the sky not fall on your heads.
I have prepared a little departure song.
Oh no!
Ignorant!
Whoa, whoa!
It was me who went wow.
- Am I not allowed to do that anymore? - Come on, stubborn.
Let it out of the bag, your ldéfix.
We can set sail, Tumeheris.
Set sail!
In Egypt, we will have to fight against many
difficulties. And during the trip,
we may encounter pirates.
We'll take care of that. Right, Obelix?
Oh yes, we will.
Ship to starboard!
Pirates? The pirates!
Yoo-hoo! Yoo-hoo!
Wait for us, we're coming. Yoo-hoo!
So, children, we don't get upset.
We board them, we slit their throats,
we gut them, we slaughter them
and we sink them.
The usual routine.
When I yell boarding!
Boarding!
What do you mean, boarding?
I'll be right with you.
Didn't I keep you waiting?
Cheaters !
How, to the boarding ?
A'i'e !
Ouch !
Hou là !
What do you mean, boarding?
Ouch!
Come on, Obelix.
Let's go.
Yes, Asterix,
but there's still one upstairs.
No, no!
What do you mean, boarding?
The usual routine.
After a long and calm trip without any notable incident,
on a peaceful night,
the ship is nearing the end of its quiet journey.
That glow on the horizon?
It is the tower of the island of Pharos, whose fire guides the ships.
We will be in Alexandria tomorrow.
A tower to guide the ships?
These Egyptians are crazy!
The bath of Cleopatra!
It is the bath of Cleopatra
Limpid and perfumed bath
To bathe her body of alabaster
Let us pour the amphorae of milk
Cleopatra's soap !
Cleopatra's soap!
The soap of Cleopatra!
Cleopatra sovereign
You are beautiful, we know it
It is for you, Queen of Queens,
Let's bring the soap
Lalalalala lalala lala !
The lion of Cleopatra !
The lion of Cleopatra!
It is the lion of Cleopatra
It is the king of the animals
Courage like four
And spirit... So that, zero, eh!
La lalalalala lalala !
Badabadabada badabada!
Li lilililili lilili!
Badabadaba bada badabada!
Edifis asks for an audience.
Let him enter.
O my Queen, here are the Gallic friends:
A powerful magician and the brave warriors
who'll help me in my enterprise.
Fine, but hurry. Time is short.
If you succeed, gold for everyone.
If not, everyone for the crocodiles.
By the way, I'm warning you that Amonbofis, your rival,
is angry at you for having been chosen in his place.
I think he would be happy to see your career end in a...
- Crocodile? - That's right.
Now, come on!
Bad temper, but nice nose.
Very nice nose.
I'll take you home with me.
That's from me.
That's mine too.
That's still mine.
This was from me.
This is my home.
I would have guessed it.
The door is still stuck.
The humidity...
I'll give you a hand.
No, Obelix!
Don't scold him, the wood is too dry.
This is your home.
Please follow me.
Are you coming, Obelix?
This is where I work.
Master, the architect Amonbofis asks to see you.
My rival? Let him come in.
I'll get straight to the point.
Let's build Caesar's palace together.
If we succeed, we'll share the gold.
If not, you'll be eaten alone by crocodiles.
After all, where there's one to eat,
there's no need for two.
I refuse ! You are deceitful,
dishonest and unpleasant.
Get out of my house!
You will regret it.
You'll end up in a saurian, you scoundrel!
I'll take you to the construction site.
Yes, it will be interesting to see how you work.
Dogmatix!
Are they slaves?
No, they are free workers.
These Egyptians are crazy!
It's the lunch break. Come and see the plans of the palace.
What are they doing?
Overtime.
Here is the plan, I drew it myself.
I recognize your hand.
My friends!
Don't let this lousy architect exploit you.
He beats you too much and doesn't pay you enough.
Stop the work!
React against those who make fun of you.
Abandon them!
Go on strike!
Go home!
Master, the workers refuse to return to work.
Someone has turned them against me.
But who?
Who what?
Amonbofis, your rival, no doubt.
All these worries make me sick.
The sacred crocodiles will find me inedible.
Are you so keen on being a good meal?
They are sacred crocodiles, after all.
These architects are crazy!
Let's go and see what's going on.
We refuse to continue. The work is too hard.
Yeah!
They don't want to work anymore.
Oh, the work is too hard?
Asterix, light a nice fire under that pot.
No.
Not you. You fell into it when you were little.
Give them a little demonstration, Asterix.
It's a true prodigy.
But yes. Call your workers.
I'll give them a ration of my magic potion.
No !
Can he recognize me?
And hop!
I have to do something.
Screwdriver!
Yes, oh Amonbofis, my master?
Edifis is waiting for the stones
coming from the south by the Nile.
The stones must not arrive.
Here's some gold to deal with this matter.
You'll be obeyed, O Amonbofis, my master.
Amonbofis sends you this gold
so that the stones don't reach their destination.
D'ac, by Osiris!
Throw me those stones!
Hop, hop, hop !
There are no more stones.
It's an Amonbofis trick.
Without stones, no palace.
Without palaces, crocodiles.
Calm down, we'll go get your stones.
We'll be back soon with the stones.
We have little time left to finish the palace.
They must not return from this trip, Screwdriver.
They won't come back, master.
It's slow. It's too slow.
Let's connect the boats with ropes.
Finally, a little exercise!
By Toutatis, this boy will always amaze me.
There's a lack of boar and beer here.
Well, the appetite comes with eating.
Asterix's Cervoise!
When appetite goes, everything goes
Let's empty the barrels Let's have a feast
When the appetite goes, everything goes
When the appetite goes, everything goes When the appetite goes, everything goes
Long live the quenottes that crunch and nibble
When appetite goes, everything goes
Obelix's boars!
Listen to what follows
The old proverb is changed
You don't eat to live
You have to live to eat
When the appetite goes, everything goes For health there is only that
The worst emotion is to have your stomach in your heels
Little gourmets and fatties On an allegro rhythm
To eat and drink Make the jaws play
When the appetite goes, everything goes
The bones of ldefix!
Obelix, my dear love
I will always obey you
And the King of Kings from now on, it's you
When Obelix goes, everything goes
Cleo, I love your cute nose
I also like mushrooms
And then the sausages And the gingerbread
When appetite goes, everything goes
A good meal without cheese
It is a beast with only one eye
It's a bird without plumage
A forest without a squirrel
- When appetite goes... - Everything goes!
- When the appetite goes... - All is well!
- Come and pay tribute... - To the kings of cheese.
- When appetite goes... - Anything goes!
When the camel passes, alas When the camel passes, alas
We must praise its sobriety
When the camel passes, alas
But no, I have a hump,
I am a camel, not a camel.
Oh, it's annoying in the end.
When appetite goes, everything goes When appetite goes, everything goes
Long live the quenottes that crunch and nibble
When the appetite goes, everything goes
Don't forget it, good people The appetite comes with eating
Let's empty the barrels Let's have a feast
When the appetite goes, everything goes !
Tomorrow we will visit the sphinx and the pyramids.
It's worth it.
What do you say?
Ldefix, here!
Here, ldefix!
ldefix, here!
Leave him alone, ldefix.
There must be a beautiful view from up there.
Dogmatix, wait for me here.
Obelix!
Ouch, ouch, ouch!
Let's not linger here, come on!
From the top of these pyramids, twenty centuries contemplate you.
There must be a beautiful view from up there.
Obelix, be quiet.
Well, it's not worth a nice menhir, those pyramids.
I wonder if we can visit.
But yes, but yes, but yes, but yes.
I'm a guide and I can show the pyramids
to noble foreign tourists.
Well, we accept with pleasure.
Follow the guide!
In there, it's not for little dogs.
Wait for us here.
If you're good, you'll get a nice bone.
Very interesting, these pyramids.
Do not lose sight of me, noble strangers.
Without me, you wouldn't get out of this labyrinth alive.
Enter, enter...
The hieroglyphs that adorn this room are magnificent.
You will never get out of here,
strangers! This tomb will be your tomb.
Very interesting, these bas-reliefs.
In the meantime,
we have to get out of here.
It wouldn't have happened in a menhir.
Under the circumstances, Obelix..,
...for the first time..,
I'll give you a drink of the magic potion.
Really?
I'm going to have some magic potion!
I'll have some magic potion.
Galapagos, galapagos!
I'm glad I came to the pyramid.
Obelix, after you.
Can I have some more?
So, are you coming?
Very interesting, these labyrinths.
Let's try this door.
Can I have some more?
No, Obelix!
Oh well, that's not fair, then.
I barely have time to taste it before he rations me.
That's not fair.
I'm afraid that guide was right.
We won't get out of here alive.
I feel sorry for Edifis.
Without us, he'll never make it.
I feel sorry for my poor little Dogmatix.
Dogmatix!
He found us with his nose.
He can find his way back and get us out of here.
You will have two big bones.
You'll have a bunch of big bones.
It seems that he understands everything I say.
Let's follow the guide!
Magi... You are wise men.
Magi... They are magicians.
They came out of the pyramid.
These Gauls are prodigious.
But the Gauls haven't reached Alexandria yet.
They have to go up the Nile.
We must stop them.
I have the men you need, master:
Some dreadful pirates
having lost their ship, it seems,
of a false maneuver.
Bring them to me.
Here they are, master.
I offer you a boat.
With it, you will go down the course of the Nile.
You will cross a caravan of ships carrying stones.
If these ships don't reach Alexandria, you'll have gold,
a lot of gold.
Board them, slit their throats, gut them, slaughter them,
exterminate them
and sink them!
The usual routine.
Cruises are monotonous.
I'm bored, Asterix.
I have the impression that we're going to have fun soon.
Caravan carrying stones, straight ahead!
Okay, kids, let's not get too excited...
It's full of Gauls in there!
Gauls? Full back!
Run for it! Turn around!
You'll be able to distract yourself. Pirates, straight ahead!
Pirates? Fancy, fancy, fancy, fancy!
Yoo-hoo! Youhou!
Wait for me, I'm coming!
Faster, faster!
It's too late.
I think we can get back on track.
How about that? It bites.
Yuck, I don't eat that.
Well... uh... another false move.
But they're starting to get on my nerves, those Gauls.
Well, since it's like that,
I've got a terrible idea.
Is it a good idea, master?
It's a piece of cake. Follow me!
Poisoned pastry.
- The deadly doughnuts. - Yes.
- Lightning macaroons. - Not bad.
- Viper venom pie. - Classic.
- Clafoutis with curare. - Not so good!
Arsenic pudding.
Oh yes!
In a big bowl of strychnine, dissolve morphine
Warm it up in a saucepan
A good glass of oil
I'll put in two.
A few drops of hemlock Some leech slime
A scorpion cut very thin
And a little peppercorn
- No. - Ah.
Crumble your arsenic
In a glass of narcotic
Two spoonfuls of purgative that you boil on high
I'll put three.
In a small separate dish Tiédir of the blood of lizard
The value of a thimble
And a little powdered sugar
No !
Oh well.
You pour rat poison into cobra venom
To sweeten the mixture Squeeze three orange segments
I'll put in one.
Decorate with candied fruit Molded in verdigris
While your dough is soft
And a little vitriol
No.
Yes !
I knew it would be good.
Arsenic pudding
Allows us this prognosis
Tomorrow on the banks of the Nile What will the crocodiles eat?
Some...
Gau...
...laws !
A gift for you, O my Queen.
Let him enter.
The three Gauls offer this cake to the Queen of Queens.
Very kind.
You will thank them on behalf of Cleopatra.
My taster! Let them call my taster.
Here, here, here.
Taste, taster.
With joy, oh my Queen.
Hou là, hou là, hou là...
Finally, my friends.
You are back.
We bring you enough stones to finish the construction.
Gauls! In the name of the Queen, I arrest you.
Should we slap them?
No, Obelix, calm down.
Let's go and see what's going on.
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
You tried to poison me with that cake.
What cake?
Throw them in the dungeon while I decide their fate.
Not a moment to lose.
Let's drink this antidote and get out.
This potion
will make us immune to the poison.
We're serving an appetizer to the sacred crocodiles.
Move aside, we're going out.
Can we go in?
Guards, seize these men!
Gauls come from afar to overwhelm me with hatred,
I will show you how a queen dies
and what courage I have.
I'm ready, Osiris.
How well she plays.
We just want to know what you blame us for.
What do I have against you? This.
But that cake looks very good.
Obelix, go get a pie server.
May I?
Cut three slices of this cake.
Three shares, I said.
Ah yes, three parts.
Greedy, you!
Well, it's an excellent cake.
What's so special about it?
Ask my taster.
Hou là, hou là, hou là, hou là, hou là...
Hmm, let's see...
It's just a little indigestion.
Wow, wow, wow, wow, wow...
I'm fine.
I'm hungry.
I have been unfair to you, Gauls.
I give you back your freedom. Come on!
Someone wanted to harm us.
- Yes, but who? - Amonbofis.
- Edifis' rival? - I'm sure.
- Shall we visit him? - I was going to suggest it.
Amonbofis, please.
This way.
Let's drink to victory, Screwdriver!
The time has come for us to toast.
We will give you the opportunity to work with Edifis.
The palace is going well, Edifis.
You'll finish in time.
Cleopatra will be happy.
Very happy. The palace is finished.
I'll win my bet.
I'm delighted, my queen, absolutely delighted.
I will lose face in front of Cleopatra.
I had however been described her architect as an incompetent.
Things happen that I do not know.
Let them call my spy!
Here I am, master, here I am.
Come here.
Go see what's going on in Edifis.
I want to know why the work is going so well.
Let's do it.
Three Gauls?
An old druid, a smart aleck and a fat fool?
Asterix, Obelix and Getafix!
These three are capable of all kinds of wonders.
We must act.
Summon my Egyptian mercenaries.
Hail Caesar!
Those who will serve you for a small fee salute you.
Enter Edifis' construction site
without being noticed.
Spill the pot of magic potion
and take the druid.
A bag of gold if you succeed.
Execute, by Jupiter!
Let's go, o Caesar, by Osiris !
I'll take care of the pot.
You two take care of the druid.
Sure thing, brother.
Okay, brother.
If this potion is as good as they say it is,
I guess I won't have to share the bag of gold.
What do you want?
I have no sense of family.
Oh, look!
Who are you? And where's Getafix,
...our druid?
Julius Caesar sent us to capture the druid.
Our big brother double-crossed us to keep the reward.
Without magic potion or Getafix, we're lost.
- The sacred crocodiles, they... - Not again!
Let's go to Jules to get our druid.
Alright, Asterix.
Dogmatix, you're in charge of the construction site.
Keep your eyes open.
One of the mercenaries has returned, O Caesar.
Let him enter.
Mission accomplished, O Caesar.
You have earned your keep, mercenary.
Here is the promised reward.
Let this Druid be locked up
in the palace prison.
I am the cleverest!
I am the richest! I am the richest...
Where is our druid?
Caesar has locked him up in the palace prison.
Don't knock anymore, please.
- Let's go, Obelix. - Yes, Asterix.
It's brother.
Come on, brother.
Junior and I have a few words to say to you.
Yeah.
I hope we find our Druid.
You know, all prisons are the same.
It's just as easy to get in as it is to get out.
Halt! We're not going in.
- Yes, we're going in. - May I, Obelix?
Excuse me.
Asterix ! Obelix!
Out of the way, we're going out.
No, we're not going out.
Yes, we're going out.
Well yes, we go in and out.
How do you know? The druid is out of the prison?
These Gauls will know what it costs
to brave the wrath of Caesar, by Mercury !
Tomorrow, when they wake up,
I'll give them a little surprise and you'll tell me about it.
Master, master! The construction site is deserted.
The workers did not come this morning.
What's going on?
But what's going on now?
In the name of Caesar...
Gallic dissidents are hiding in this yard.
We order them to surrender,
or else we'll attack, by Jupiter!
We are here by the will of Cleopatra
and we will finish the work, by Toutatis!
You will regret it, by Mercury!
What are we going to do, by Osiris?
To build defenses, by Belenos!
You are right, by Belisama!
Couldn't we go away, by any chance?
Attack!
Back to the attack!
Join up, re-enlist, they said...
Here they come again!
To the attack!
You will see the country, they said...
Attack!
Hello!
- What's wrong with you? - No kidding!
Since it's like that, we'll bomb them.
Look, war machines.
Hmm, I don't like these things.
Fire!
My palate! They break my palace!
We should warn Cleopatra.
Only she can convince Caesar to stop the hostilities.
Good idea.
I'll write a message to the queen.
It's Dogmatix who will carry the message.
Dogmatix?
But he's too small.
No, it's not too small.
Don't be stubborn. Dogmatix cannot carry the message.
Yes he can! Mr. Asterix knows everything.
Mr. Asterix, he must be in charge,
Do you know what he's telling you, mister Asterix?
No, what is he telling me, mister Asterix?
Here's the message.
But how do we get it to him? We're under siege.
Ask mister Asterix, he knows everything.
Come on, Obelix.
Don't be offended. I wanted to tease you.
No good, my dog...
Dogmatix will carry the message.
And I'll carry Dogmatix.
Alert! One of the besieged is trying to get through!
He left as he came.
He was just passing through.
Gauls come from afar to overwhelm me with hatred,
I will show you how a queen dies.
- I will know... - But no, look. My dog
has a message for you.
Oh, how sweet.
Somebody bring a bone for this little dog.
It won't happen like that, by Osiris!
Julius Caesar is a cheat.
Go, Gaul, I'll take care of everything.
Alert! One of the besieged is trying to get in!
And there you have it, Obelix. Dogmatix fulfilled his mission perfectly.
Ah, you see? Who was right?
Provided that Cleopatra acts quickly.
These machines will completely demolish the palace.
You see, Caesar?
Even without capturing those Gauls, the result will be the same
because the palace will be destroyed.
Good, very good.
Hail Caesar!
There's someone here to see you...
My Queen, what good wind?
Enough of this!
I went out without changing when I heard the news.
When you make a bet, you don't cheat.
I've called on the Gauls.
I'll show you what my people are capable of.
I demand that you leave the builders alone.
And let me tell you that...
All right, I'm sorry.
Oh, all the same!
Go home, children.
What do we do, O Caesar?
We raise the siege, O fool!
The Romans lift the siege, by Belenos!
Victory, by Toutatis!
I'm very happy.
All this thanks to my ldefix.
And now, let's go to work !
And the work resumed, indeed.
It resumed with determination because, let's not forget it,
when the architect didn't respect his deadlines,
he was thrown to the crocodiles.
An old custom, a little forgotten nowadays.
Finally, one beautiful morning...
O my Queen, the palace is finished.
You kept your promise, Edifis.
Cleopatra will keep hers, by Osiris.
Let them cover it with gold.
O my Queen, the most beautiful of Queens,
I have lost and I bow to your triumph.
To you the honor of cutting this ribbon.
I am indebted to you, Gaul,
and you are entitled to my gratitude.
You will return aboard my ceremonial galley
with the thanks of Cleopatra.
You're welcome, Cleopatra. We salute you.
Will there be boars on your boat?
Obelix.
He always has to yell at me.
A ceremonial galley without boars,
It's not worth...
Everyone eats, everyone drinks,
everyone is happy
and celebrates the happy outcome of this adventure.
Everyone drinks, everyone eats.
Everybody?
Well, almost everyone.
And with the spring,
Cleopatra's magnificent ship approaches the coast of Gaul,
where the village welcomes its heroes
with its usual enthusiasm and banquet.
And it was ldéfix who did it all.
A nose, my dear, a nose!
Subtitling CEDRA