You are not a person, you are a planet,
made of roughly 40 trillion cells.
There is so much of you, that
if your cells were human-sized,
you would be as big as 20 Mount Everests. For your
creepy-crawly inhabitants, this makes your body an
ecosystem, rich in resources and warmth and space.
A perfect place to move into and have a family.
While some of these guests are welcome, most
are not. Your immune system is the guardian
of this planet, the force tasked with protecting
yourself against the constant danger of invasion.
Unfortunately your enemies in the
tiny world have a huge advantage.
Consider the effort it takes to make a single copy
of yourself and your trillions of cells. First you
need to find someone who thinks you are cute,
date and be awkward and if things work out in a
complicated dance, two of your cells merge
together. Then you need to wait for months
while the cell multiplies over and over until
it is released into the world as a human being.
And even then you only have a mini copy
that needs years to become remotely useful.
A bacterium consists of one cell. It can make
a fully grown copy in about half an hour.
A virus can turn into hundreds within
hours and billions within days.
Your enemies multiply orders
of magnitude faster than you.
Even worse, for a bacterium or virus
your body is a hostile ecosystem
applying selective pressure. Because they go
through so many generations so quickly, eventually
by pure chance, there will be an individual
that mutates and adapts in just the right way
to resist your defenses and then multiply quickly
again. In other words, you are facing a sheer
endless variety of different enemies and you’re
too slow to keep up with their evolution.
This is bad.
Luckily your immune system is just about
the most amazing thing ever. The second most
complex biological system known to us, after the
human brain, and so sophisticated that we still
haven’t discovered all its secrets. Since it is
so complicated we have to simplify and focus on
one thing at a time. If you want the full story,
wait for the announcement at the end of the video!
Ok, so why are we not all killed by some
new bacteria or virus? In a nutshell,
you actually have two immune systems, the
innate and the adaptive immune system.
The innate immune system was
ready when you were born.
It mostly consists of general purpose soldiers,
we introduced them in the last immune video.
The adaptive immune system carries two types of
cells T Cells and B Cells that are your super
weapons and are incredibly effective and deadly
for your enemies. These cells are complicated to
produce and take a lot of time to deploy but
once they are ready, they pack a real punch.
What makes your adaptive immune system
so powerful is that it has the largest
library in the universe. It has an answer to
everything. You have at least one of these
super weapon cells inside you to fight the
black death, the corona virus and the first
deadly bacteria that will emerge in a city
on Mars in one hundred years. This makes it
possible for you to counter the ability of
bacteria and viruses to change so rapidly.
How is this possible? To understand what is
going on here, we need to take one step back.
All organisms on earth are
made from the same basic parts,
mostly proteins. Proteins are
the building blocks of life
and can have billions of different shapes
- you can imagine them as 3D puzzle pieces.
There are billions of different puzzle pieces
your enemies can use to construct their bodies.
Why is this important? Because proteins are
in a way the “language” of the microworld.
Cells don’t have eyes or ears, so to tell friend
from foe, they have to touch them and recognize
if their protein is part of a friend or part of an
enemy. Recognizing means that cells have countless
tiny devices called receptors, that are able to
connect with a specific protein puzzle piece.
So your cells have tiny puzzle pieces on their
outsides that are able to click together,
or recognize other protein puzzle pieces.
When a cell connects together with a protein
and recognizes it as “enemy”,
it knows that it has to attack.
Only if your cells can make this
distinction between friend or foe
is your immune system able to fight an invader.
But since there are billions of
possible protein puzzle pieces,
this means there are billions of possible enemy
puzzle pieces. This is also one of the reasons
we still have to deal with diseases like the
flu each year – the influenza virus mutates
very rapidly and so the proteins that make
up its hull constantly change a tiny bit.
The soldiers of your innate immune system have
a large number of the puzzle pieces for common
bacteria and viruses memorized, that’s why
they are your all purpose weapons. But they are
ineffective against many billions of mutations
and adaptations that your enemies can develop.
So the reason you are still alive is that your
Adaptive immune system is able to recognize
between one billion and ten billion different
enemy protein puzzle pieces, which is enough
to be prepared for every possible enemy. But
how is this possible? How could your immune
system possibly have this much of a variety to be
prepared for every possible protein puzzle piece?
Well, the cells of your adaptive immune system
found a cheat code: mixing and matching their own
genetic code to create this stunning variety of
receptors. The details are way too complicated for
this video but in a nutshell, your adaptive immune
cells have official permission to take a tiny part
of their own genetic code and mix it in random
ways to create billions of different receptors.
A good way to explain this is by asking
you to imagine an army of cooks, with each
of them wanting their own special recipe. They
have 100 different ingredients to choose from.
Each ingredient stands for one tiny
piece of genetic code in this metaphor.
So each cook takes a few random ingredients
and randomly mixes them together.
Maybe Tomato, Chicken, Rice
and half an onion as entree,
Marshmallow, Pepper, Strawberries
and a quarter banana as a dessert.
Or Cucumber, Beef, Potatoes and two carrots,
and blueberries, chocolate and
cream with a pinch of cinnamon.
Even with slight variation
and with only 100 ingredients,
there are billions of possible recipes.
And likewise, with just a small selection
of gene fragments, your cells create billions
of receptors. The details of this are so cool
that they should get their own video – or
their own chapter in a book. In any case,
by mixing up gene fragments, you get up to ten
billion different combinations. So in the end,
you get billions of immune cells, and each of
them has one specific and unique receptor – the
dish from our metaphor – that is able to
recognize one specific protein puzzle piece.
In total, you end up with at least one cell
for every enemy that could possibly exist.
But here we run into a pretty dangerous problem
– if your adaptive immune system is making
weapons that can attack every possible
protein puzzle piece in the universe…
wouldn’t it also make some that can attack
your own cells? Yes, it happens all the time.
This is so fundamentally dangerous to
your survival that you have a whole
organ that does nothing but work on preventing
this: The Murder University of your Thymus.
Your Thymus is a chicken wing sized organ above
your heart and you've probably never heard of
it. Interestingly, your thymus is one of the
reasons why your immune system weakens as you age,
because it is in a constant state of decline once
you reach puberty. But what does the Thymus do?
In your murder university, your immune
system is putting your adaptive immune cells
through an intense and deadly curriculum.
Basically it is showing them all sorts of
protein puzzle pieces that are used by
your own cells to see how they react.
When a young cell recognizes a body puzzle piece
and wants to attack it, the teacher cells order
them to kill themselves and they are eaten up
and recycled. The immune system is so particular
about this process that around 98% of your
adaptive immune cells that enter murder university
die there. 2% graduate and get to do
their job of protecting you for real.
If this process goes wrong and cells escape that
can recognize your own protein puzzle pieces,
this can lead to autoimmune disease, where
your immune system attacks your own body
from the inside. Andt this, again
is another story for another time.
Ok, let us summarize. Your immune system has
two parts, one that defends you right after
birth and one that carries the largest
library of superweapons in the universe
but needs to boot up first. To create billions
of different superweapons, your adaptive immune
cells recombine a part of their genetic code to
create a breathtaking variety of attack weapons.
Then they enter a murder university that only 2%
survive to make sure they do not attack you. And
then you end up with billions of different cells,
that in total are able to protect you against
every possible enemy in the universe.
Now wait a second. If this is all true,
why do we get sick at all? Why was a new disease
like Covid-19 able to kill millions of people?
Well everything we just learned about is just a
tiny, tiny window into the amazing struggle for
life and death that plays out every day inside
your body and there are so many amazing details
and questions here: How does your body actually
find the right cell in time to protect you?
How do your enemies fight back and
overcome your immune system anyway?
And what about all the things
that did not fit in this video?
Well, today finally marks the release of “Immune
– A Journey Into the Mysterious System that Keeps
You Alive”, written by Philipp Dettmer,
the founder and head writer of Kurzgesagt.
First we had to push the release back
because of cargo trouble and then because so
many of you pre-ordered that we didn’t have
enough copies for the original launch day!
Thank you so, so much for that!
Immune tells the epic story of your
immune system and will forever change
how you think about your own body, how
you experience being sick and healthy.
The book is written to be as fun and easy to grasp
as Kurzgesagt videos but it is able to dive way
deeper iinto its subject. So go on a journey
through the hidden microverse within yourself.
Witness deadly wars between billions of invaders
and cells, learn how your immune system actually
works and protects you from cuts, cancer and
Covid. Never before have we so urgently needed
to learn about how immunity works. Immune is fun
and great to look at and it even smells good.
Follow the link in the
description to order it today.
This is the end of a decade-long
personal journey working on this,
thank you all so, so much for your support.
And thank you for watching. And reading.