- If I asked you to show me
a picture of your mother,
you wouldn't show me a, uh,
closeup shot of her elbow.
But you could,
and you'd be right.
That would be a photo of her,
but it wouldn't feel right
because it's not her face.
That's how important faces are
to us.
We're going to see if forcing
a facial expression
can change the way we feel.
- Are you comfortable
handling dog feces?
Okay.
- And if you remove the ability
to make facial expressions,
will it affect how you
perceive emotions in others?
- What?
- No.
- How could that--that--no.
- I don't think so.
- And what are we saying
by raising an eyebrow?
Do you know?
[electronic music]
♪ ♪
Why does doing this
make me look angry?
And why does doing this
make me look so happy?
Where does all this stuff
come from?
When it comes
to interpersonal communication,
it's easy to think
that speech dominates,
but yet,
we have hairless faces.
That's very unique
among mammals
that are easy
to see expressions on.
Facial expressions are
shared across humanity.
A smile is a smile
in any language.
Our faces seem uniquely adapted
for communication.
Before we developed language,
facial expressions
may have been just as vital
in communication
as shouts and grunts.
And we, of course,
still use them today.
But when it comes
to facial expressions,
it's not just about seeing
other people's expressions
and having them see yours.
It's also about seeing your own.
And the fact that our eyes
are deep-set
allows us to see our own
facial expressions
as we're making them.
If you smile,
you can see
your own cheeks rise slightly.
And if you furrow your brow,
it encroaches on the top
of your vision.
These things give you
instant feedback
on the degree to which you are
altering your face
and tell you instantly
what sort of expression
you are putting out
into the world.
No mirror required.
♪ ♪
Some of the most interesting
experiments
on facial expressions
have asked, "What comes first?
The emotion
or the facial expression?"
Studies have found
that if you hold a pencil
between your teeth all day,
you will have a better day.
Why?
Well, because holding a pencil
between your teeth
without your lips touching
is like smiling.
It uses pretty much
the same muscles.
Watch.
[muffled] I don't know--
I don't know I'm smiling,
but I am.
Conversely, pursing your lips
around the pencil
is like frowning.
And studies have found
that if someone does that,
they will actually report having
a less good day.
Well, we're gonna put that
to the test
and find out if
the facial contortions you make
can subconsciously affect
how you feel.
Studies on how
physiology affects mood
go as far back as the 1800s,
with early research carried out
by Charles Darwin
and French neurologist
Duchenne de Boulogne.
This work has continued
into present day
using various techniques
to create smiles and frowns.
But studies
have been inconsistent
as to whether
facial expressions
can influence emotions,
so we wanted to see
if we could demonstrate
a correlation between the two.
♪ ♪
Hi.
- Hi.
- Come on in, guys.
Chris, my name is Michael.
Nice to meet you.
My name is Michael.
We've recruited 20 volunteers
who think they're taking part
in an allergy study.
Today we are testing
a new kind of dog food,
and it actually seems to help
dogs produce fewer allergens,
so people who are allergic
to dogs
might be more comfortable
around them.
And we're going to be using
these allergen sticks.
Now, the purpose of this stick
is to collect saliva
to check the way
your body reacts
to possible allergens
in the air.
Put it between your teeth
like that, okay?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay.
- Half of our participants
will be unknowingly forced
into a smile.
Yeah, very simple.
- Uh-huh.
- The other half
will unwittingly be forced
to use their frown muscles.
Watch.
My teeth are together,
and then--hmm.
Got it?
both: Mm-hmm.
- We're gonna give the frowners
and the smilers
the same two tasks.
Go ahead,
and I'll see you guys soon.
Will the people who were forced
to frown
rank each task lower
than those made to smile?
- Come on in.
- To test their levels
of happiness,
our actor, Trin,
gave our subjects a task
everybody loves:
puppy herding
with lots and lots of puppies.
First up are our smilers.
- They're all wearing
little tags.
- Mm-hmm.
- So your job is to line them up
in alphabetical order.
Once you got 'em all lined up,
I'll snap a photo of you.
- Okay.
- And you got three minutes
to do it.
Starting now.
- Hello. I know.
- Make sure they're
in alphabetical order.
- They're naming the dogs.
- She's having fun.
- I just got the--oh!
Don't go away.
- [laughs]
- Swap those two.
- You got one minute left.
- This looks like fun,
but are they having
even more fun
because they're being forced
to smile?
- All right,
get ready for the photo.
[camera shutter clicks]
- Our smilers are laughing
and goofing around.
- Fantastic.
- Now, let's see how
our frowners react
to this fun task.
- Three minutes.
- [humming]
- He's running away from you.
- [groans]
- The question is,
will frowning emphasize
the parts that aren't fun--
in your mind, at least.
[dogs barking]
- Oh, we lost F.
Got one little strangler
right over here.
- Ugh!
- If the frowners seem
a bit frustrated
herding puppies...
- [mutters angrily]
- How will they like
their next task?
- If you would each grab
a pair of gloves.
Are you comfortable handling
dog feces?
Okay.
And we're also going to be
looking at whether there are
any protein deposits
that have collected, um,
in the fecal matter.
- She's like, "Are you serious?"
- So go ahead and spread it out
on the table.
- [stifled retching]
- Ooh.
Not happy.
- And what you're looking for
are small, hard deposits.
- Not much indication
that there's a smile
trying to come through.
- Hmm.
- Okay, great.
- [exhales]
- Thank you, that'll do it.
- Our frowners don't seem
to be enjoying this assignment.
Will the smilers have
a different reaction?
- Grab a pair of gloves.
It may be easier to kind of
smear it and spread it out.
- The hypothesis is,
that by smiling,
they'll focus more
on the funny aspects
of what they're about to do.
- [laughs] Yeah.
- Oh, my God.
- [laughs]
[groans]
Oh.
- There's disgust in his eyes
and his brow,
but his mouth can't help
but smile.
- [chuckles]
- Okay, great, guys.
Thank you so much.
Then, when you're ready,
just follow me and we'll do
a debrief with Mr. Stevens.
- Okay.
- Sure.
- Hey, welcome back.
Now, think about, um,
organizing the puppies
and taking a photo of them.
- Mmm.
- And how you felt.
Tell me what you were thinking
and feeling while you were doing
that task.
- I mean, the puppies
are extremely cute.
- Mm-hmm.
- Can I keep one?
Is it cool with you guys?
- The dogs actually cooperated
pretty well.
- Mm-hmm?
- I was able
to put them in order.
- They're amazing.
- It wasn't stressful.
- So on a scale of 1 to 10--
where 1 is
you cannot tolerate it
and 10, best day of your life--
how would you rank
the puppy photo task?
- I'm gonna say like a 9.
- 10.
- 8.
- I'm gonna go with an 8.
- A 9.
- That's an average
of 8.5
from our small sample
of ten subjects
who were forced to smile
during the photo assignment.
Now let's see how the frowners
rated the same task.
How did you feel
while you were doing that?
- Um, a little frustrated,
to be honest with you,
'cause they kept moving around.
- Well, it was difficult
getting them to stay in place
and put them in order.
- How would you rank
the photo taking task?
- Mmm, 4.
- About 4.
- A 10.
I love puppies.
- Still a 10?
- Yeah, me too.
- I would go more
on the middle ground,
maybe like 5.
- Many of the frowners reported
feeling frustrated
with this experience,
tallying an average score
of 7.4,
more than a point lower
than the smilers.
Now let's talk about
the poop checking job.
- Very unpleasant.
- It was disgusting.
- How would you rank
the poop checking task?
- 1--it was a 1.
- A 1?
- It was for sure a 1.
- 1.
- A 4.
- Is a zero possible?
- Our frowning subjects
averaged a low score of 1.9.
The question is,
did our smiling group feel
any better about digging
through poo?
- It wasn't too uncomfortable.
- It was sort of unexpected, but
it wasn't like it bothered me.
- I wasn't, like, disgusted
like, "Ew! This is disgusting!"
I just kind of held my breath.
- Many of our smilers reported
this unpleasant task
as being no big deal
or actually funny.
- I'd say a 5
because it wasn't--
neither here nor there for me.
- It was a 5.
- A high 4.
- 5, I guess.
- A 5? Okay.
- 5, right in the middle.
- The average score
for the smiling group
was 4.3 out of 10.
Smilers enjoyed
sifting through poop
an average of 2 1/2 points more
than our frowners.
And have a great day.
- Have fun with your poop.
- [laughs]
I will.
I always do.
♪ ♪
Our test found that people
who made smile faces
enjoyed tasks more,
and those who frowned
enjoyed them less.
This facial feedback concept
is still being debated though.
And other studies
have recently failed
to reproduce these findings.
But it's a very healthy thing
that we don't just look
at one test and say,
"Well, that's it.
That must be the truth.
We're done."
In the words of Brian Nosek,
lead researcher
of the Reproducibility Project,
science isn't about truth
and falsity.
It's about reducing uncertainty.
Facial expressions
are so important
to human communication
that people develop ways
to read your face even if
they can't see it.
Tommy, thanks for coming
to visit.
- Thanks for having me.
I love what you've done
with the place.
- Hey, thank you so much.
- [laughs]
- What I would like
to talk about
is facial expressions.
- All right, sir.
- 'Cause, Tommy,
you have been blind
since you were born.
- That's right.
- How did you learn
about facial expressions?
'Cause you make them.
You smile.
You--I've never seen you mad,
but I bet if you get mad...
- Yeah.
- You--I can tell.
- Yeah. When I'm laughing,
I smile, right?
It just comes naturally.
- So that part's innate.
- That part is innate.
Absolutely it is, no question.
But in order to imitate it,
that was the tricky part for me.
Right? 'Cause sometimes
I'd smile, like, too much.
You know, like that.
I don't know.
Like, I feel like
that's pushing it too hard.
That's not really natural.
But, you know, so it's probably
somewhere around here,
I guess.
- So could you make
an angry face for me right now?
That's close,
but do you think
if you'd seen an angry face
it would be easier to fake one?
- Yes, I think so.
- Let me ask you this.
Can you tell what
facial expression I'm making?
- Well, when you're smiling,
I can hear it in your voice.
- Right.
- Right? It's very obvious.
'Cause when you smile,
your lips don't really touch
the right way, so letters like M
and B and P, for example,
you know, they sound
just a little bit different.
- Right.
So it sounds like you know more
about how a smile affects speech
than most sighted people would.
- Thank you.
There's a lot of audible clues
that help me to get
the facial expression.
- Well, Tommy,
thank you so much for coming in.
I love having guests
in my home.
- Thank you, sir.
- Thank you.
[soft dramatic music]
♪ ♪
When we look
at other people's faces,
we often subconsciously imitate
their facial expressions.
It's called facial mirroring.
And it's a way for us
to let other people know
we understand them, that we feel
the same things that they feel.
Facial mirroring begins
in infancy
and continuous throughout
our lives.
Studies have shown that if you
can't facially mirror,
if you can't express things
with your own face,
you actually have trouble
understanding
what other people's faces
are expressing.
So to try that out,
let's hinder some people's
facial muscles.
What's a good way to do that?
Well, how about a dose
of botulinum toxin?
♪ ♪
We have gathered a group
of volunteers
for a facial expression
recognition experiment.
Thank you all
for coming in today.
We're going to begin
with a test.
A test of your ability
to recognize
facial expressions.
Our participants will be shown
pictures of eyes
expressing either positive
or negative emotions.
Your task is to look
at each face and to decide
which of those four emotions
the face is expressing.
Makes sense?
Each photo is designed
to display
one standard emotion
that is known to elicit
an established consensus.
For example, in this photo,
what emotion
would you identify?
If you said, "terrified,"
you'd be in the majority.
Now it's our participant's
turn.
Okay, everyone ready?
- Mm-hmm.
- Go.
[device beeping]
All right,
moving on to number 2.
For most people,
this is a simple task
that should come with
a relatively high success rate.
All right, card number 6...
Number 9...
Number 13...
19...
Our 12 volunteers
will give us an idea
of how well the average person
identifies emotions.
And 25.
All right, everyone.
Great work.
I hope you had fun.
Thank you for your time.
After 25 cards,
our participants were able
to identify the correct
positive emotion
77% of the time, and
the correct negative emotion
78.8% of the time.
But how well will they do
if we stop them
from mirroring the expressions
they see...
[cap pops]
By freezing their faces
with botox?
We forced all
of these participants
to receive Botox injections.
- How are you?
- I'm good.
I'm Dr. Ali.
Nice to meet you.
- Just kidding.
They were gonna do it anyway,
and they let us tag along
in the name of science.
- What areas were you looking
to get done?
- Um, I'd like to do this area.
- Okay, okay.
- I would like to fix this part
between my two eyebrows,
because I feel like--
I don't know.
I just look older and grumpy.
- Although we communicate
a ton of information
with our faces, in the interest
of looking younger,
many people pay to be injected
with a chemical
that essentially renders
our faces mute,
or rather, gives us a sort
of facial speech impediment.
Botox was first used
in the 1970s
to treat muscular eye disorders
like crossed eyes
and uncontrollable blinking.
The FDA didn't approve
the use of Botox
for cosmetic procedures
until 2002.
The active ingredient in Botox
is a toxin
produced by the bacterium
Clostridium botulinum.
This toxin can cause botulism
in larger amounts,
but in smaller amounts
when injected into, say,
the wrinkles between your
eyebrows or around your mouth,
the toxin blocks the nerves
from delivering signals
to the facial muscles,
telling them to contract.
[bell tings]
- Pull your hair back
a little bit...
- Yes.
- And then tell me what areas
you were thinking
of getting it done.
- So I was thinking here,
'cause I have a couple wrinkles
that are starting to show.
- Okay.
- I'm 31 years old,
and I want to get Botox because
I want to look young forever.
- Common expressions
that people want to get rid of
is the angry lines, the furrows
we get in between the eyes.
And the horizontal wrinkles
we get in our forehead,
that will go away.
- If the Botox procedure
prevents these patients
from being able to mirror
the facial expressions
of others,
will it also impede
their ability to recognize
the emotions associated
with those expressions?
- Have you had Botox before?
- I never have.
- Do you wanna touch everything?
- If we can, yeah.
- Yeah, definitely.
- Awesome.
I think Botox is probably
going to change my expressions
and I might have to overdo them
a little bit,
but I already do that anyway,
so I think that it won't matter
so much.
- You doing okay?
- Mm-hmm.
- We'll soon explore
whether paralyzing
their facial muscles affects
how these patients score
on the facial recognition test.
- You may not see the results
for at least
three to seven days.
- Oh, yeah. Okay.
- We'll check back in
with our subjects in two weeks
after they've settled
into their new,
expression-free faces.
In the meantime,
let's meet two people
who've had modified faces
for quite a while.
Lacy, Justin, welcome.
- Hi.
- Hi. How are you?
- Great to see you guys.
- Hi.
It's nice to meet you.
- Thanks for coming over.
- How are you?
- Good to see you.
So, I'm so thrilled
to have both of you here.
How does it feel to be known
as the Ken and Barbie
of real life?
- I don't know--the world
just pinned me as that,
and then I happened to meet
my best bestie
that is Ken.
- And what about you?
Did you intend to be
like a Ken doll or...?
- No. I mean, initially--
initially this all had to do
with the passion that I had for,
like, body sculpture, right?
I just did what I loved,
and I saw this as a medium
to be--to be creative,
to be open,
to be expressive,
and to be different,
right, to set myself apart.
So I'm the first person
in the world to have
three-piece shoulder implants.
We are the first people
to try that, right?
We're own guinea pigs.
We're our own--
- We create them.
- We're our own
Dr. Frankenstein
and Frankenstein, right?
- Okay, so have both of you
had Botox done?
- Absolutely.
- Every--every three months
since I've been 25 years old.
- How has Botox
or other procedures on your face
affected your ability
to make facial expressions?
- I waited a year to have it
this year so I could actually
see a little bit of my own face,
because my kids are like,
"Mom, you know, we can't
really tell if you're mad at us.
You always look like
you're surprised."
I'm, like, walking
around the house like this.
I'm like, "Ohh!"
So I haven't had Botox
in a year
just because I wanted
to be able to do this.
"Go to your room!" No.
- Interesting.
Do you feel like
you've lost something
by not being able to show
when you're mad?
- I don't know
what you're talking about.
- Well, when you look at me now,
you can tell I'm smiling.
I just don't have
the lines here.
It's a bit
of a subtle change.
- Have you noticed Botox
affecting your ability
to read other people's
facial expressions?
- What?
- No.
- How could that--that--no.
- My answer would be no.
- No. It's actually--
- You haven't noticed that?
- Not at all.
[laughter]
- Barbie and Ken
may not ascribe
to the facial mirroring theory,
but let's check back
with our Botox recipients.
It's been two weeks,
and now they've brought
their wrinkle-free faces back
to see if their
limited expressions
will affect their ability
to read emotions.
So, to refresh you on the rules:
look at the eyes,
determine what emotion
is being conveyed,
write down your answer,
and then we'll move on
to the next one.
Go.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- My face feels
a lot more relaxed.
And it's--it's kind of nice.
- Okay, slide number 9.
[device beeps]
- When I look at people,
they don't really know
that I'm angry.
- I actually can't.
- I did have a friend--
um, she noticed.
She gets Botox too,
and she was like,
"Your Botox looks amazing."
- If I'm angry,
probably how you would know
is by my eye contact with you.
- Because I can't move
my forehead.
- This subject has definitely
limited her ability
to make a facial expression,
as have our other
Botox recipients.
But will that affect how they
interpret emotions in others?
All right, just 75 more.
[women scoff]
Kidding.
That's the end of the exam.
In our pre-Botox study,
our participents identified
77% of the positive emotions
and 78.8% of the negative
emotions correctly.
But after Botox,
our participents
correctly identified only 73.8%
of the positive emotions
and 68.8%
of the negative emotions.
So, at least
in our modest sample,
once our participents
lost their ability to frown
they found it
especially difficult
to identify negative emotions
in others.
But if modern advances
like Botox can impede
our capacity
to read other's faces,
can other forms of technology
enhance our ability
to see emotions?
Author and theoretical
neurobiologist Mark Changizi
has developed a scientific way
to read facial expressions.
Mark, I'm glad you came over,
because you have knowledge
about facial expressions
and what's going on
beyond just the more obvious
external stuff.
Is blood flow part
of facial expressions?
- Yeah, so we don't
usually think about it,
but at all times you're seeing
these subtle modulations
of color.
And as you get more blood
or less blood under the skin,
it becomes bluer or yellower,
and as it becomes more
or less oxygenated,
it becomes redder or greener.
And this is true independent
of what ethnicity you are,
what race you are,
or what kind of primate you are.
It's the same.
- What emotions correlate
to what colors?
- Well, there's a rough sense
in which when you're angry,
you're showing
oxygenated blood.
When you're sad,
it's more likely
to be showing greener.
If you're fearful,
your blood pumps away
from the periphery,
which means
that it gets yellower.
- So, Mark, you've brought
some tools with you,
an invention of yours,
actually, that helps us
better perceive
these color changes.
- That's right, so these
are what paramedics wear
'cause they're nice,
protective eyewear
that they should
be wearing anyway,
and when you wear these,
your veins,
suddenly they're glowing
a little bit.
The same technology that helps
paramedics see veins
also allows you
to see emotions better
because it's enhancing
that same oxygenation signal
that those emotions rely upon.
- So you've got glasses
that allow us
to better see the colors
that are related to emotion
and how it's affected
by blood flow.
- That's right.
This is not the kind of thing--
it's not like you look
and it says, "angry,"
you know,
written across the screen.
No, it works on your
normal intuitions.
The idea is that it makes
those signals easier to see,
so it should give you
more insight
into what their mood,
what their intent is.
- Whether through technology
or evolution,
we humans have always found
a way to read
and use facial expressions.
And those expressions
show no sign
of becoming less important,
unless we evolve past
having faces, of course.
So, did you like the show?
If you didn't,
put a pencil in your mouth
and go watch it again.
If you enjoy it more
or less or the same,
just let us know.
Science will thank you.
And as always,
thanks for watching.
[electronic music]
♪ ♪