Nuclear energy creates an uneasy
feeling of danger for many people.
Ancient and dangerous minerals
are concentrated
to awaken seemingly unnatural powers,
creating horribly toxic elements
that if they escape,
can and have killed people
in horrible ways.
How many people has
nuclear energy killed and how?
♪ Intro music ♪
Nuclear energy has been
a thing since 1951
and since then, there have been
around 30 reported accidents globally.
Most of them were
pretty minor compared to
the two disasters everybody
is familiar with:
Fukushima and Chernobyl.
Chernobyl is undoubtedly the worst
nuclear accident in history
for a number of reasons.
The reactor technology was old
and ill-prepared for emergencies
and the government response was slow
and more concerned about
image than damage control.
Still, only 31 people died
directly in the accident.
But what makes nuclear energy scary
is not reactors blowing up
but the radiation they release.
So the real question is
how many deaths through
cancer and other diseases
will Chernobyl cause?
Here, things get really complicated
because you dip right into controversy
and just discussing the different
estimates and how they were calculated
deserves a video of its own.
The most pessimistic estimate
comes from a study
commissioned by the
European Green Party
and projects up to 60,000
premature deaths by the year 2065.
Most scientific studies come up with
numbers much lower than this.
The WHO has estimated that in total
the long term death toll
will be around 4,000.
While the UN Scientific Committee on
the Effects of Atomic Radiation
concluded that even this figure
could be too high.
For more details on this,
check our research document.
The second big nuclear accident
was Fukushima Daiichi in 2011.
Fukushima did not only operate
with much better technology,
that was less dangerous
in the first place,
much better security measures
were in place
and the official response
was fast and decisive.
And so the current death toll is only 573.
The major difference here is that
these deaths were not a
consequence of radiation.
They were indirect deaths from
the stress of the evacuation
of the areas around the reactors
and occurred almost entirely
in older populations.
Estimates of the possible long-term
deaths from radiation vary widely,
from none at all to about 1,000.
In terms of the other
long-term consequences,
an increase in thyroid cancer
in children has been observed,
but according to the WHO this is related
to the increased screening rates.
By 2018 there had been only one
confirmed death among workers
as a result of radiation
induced lung cancer.
Now let's compare this
to renewable energy.
Solar, wind and geothermal energy
basically only cause deaths
as a result of construction
and maintenance accidents.
Unfortunately, their current share
of global energy is pretty low.
The major player in renewable
energy is hydropower,
which mostly means building dams and
letting water flow through turbines
from a higher elevation
to a lower elevation.
In total, hydro has been the most
fatal in terms of accidents
with hundreds of thousands of
deaths in the last half century.
One accident clearly stands out,
the 1975 Banqiao hydroelectric dam
failure in china,
which has striking
similarities to Chernobyl.
Old technology, poor design
and poor management
by authoritarian governments
concerned about appearances.
In a nutshell, a massive typhoon
triggered intense flooding
that destroyed the dam
and subsequently
a number of smaller dams
in a chain reaction,
unleashing a flood of over 15 billion
cubic meters of water in total.
Kilometre wide waves
as high as buildings
devastated thousands of square
kilometres of countryside
and countless communities.
All in all, the death toll
from just this one accident
and its direct consequences
is estimated to lie between
85,000 to 240,000.
But all of these deaths caused by
nuclear and renewable energy
are actually negligible in comparison to
the real killer energy source:
fossil fuel, the most widely used
source of energy and electricity.
When we burn fossil fuels to heat up
water and make turbines spin,
or to cause mini explosions to move
cars with internal combustion engines,
gases like ozone, sulfur dioxide,
carbon monoxide and nitrogen dioxide
are released into the atmosphere.
Breathing in these gases
disrupts lung function,
which aggravates chronic conditions
like asthma and bronchitis
and causes a wide range of respiratory
and cardiovascular diseases
but even more dangerous
is the fine particle pollution
burning fossil fuels causes.
A mixture of solid and liquid droplets
of poisonous substances
as small as 2.5 microns in diameter.
They easily find their way
deep into your lungs
and increase the risk
of deadly diseases
like lung cancer,
stroke and heart disease.
Fossil fuel related air pollution
is the number one cause of
environmental related
deaths in the world.
According to the WHO, it accounts for
29% of all cases of lung cancer,
17% of deaths from acute
lower respiratory infection,
24% from stroke, 25% from
ischemic heart disease
and 43% from chronic
obstructive pulmonary disease.
All in all, outside air pollution adds up
to the deaths of 4 million
people each year.
What makes air pollution especially
problematic and sinister
is the fact that the damage
it causes happens very gradually,
which makes it hard for our brains that
didn't evolve with subtle dangers in mind
to realise the scope of the problem.
Collectively, air pollution from
fossil fuels is estimated to have killed
around 100 million people
in the past 50 years.
But wait, is that really fair?
Fossil fuels also provide
over 80% of global energy
so it makes sense that
they cause the most deaths.
So let's compare deaths per energy unit.
Deaths per energy unit produced.
A few studies have compared the death
rates from different energy sources
per one terawatt hour.
That's about the annual energy
consumption of 27,000 EU citizens
or 12,600 US citizens.
To produce that much energy for
one year, coal causes 25 deaths
oil causes 18 and natural gas 3.
Renewable energy causes
one death every few decades.
And nuclear, in the worst case,
nuclear energy would cause
one death every 14 years.
One study even found that nuclear
energy actually saved 2 million lives
between 1971 and 2009
by displacing fossil fuels
from the global energy mix.
The numbers are clear, even when
using wildly pessimistic numbers
nuclear energy is among the
safest forms of energy generation
and at a time when we're struggling
to slow down rapid climate change
it's a really valuable low-carbon option.
However, all these facts still
leave one major argument
that is fielded against
nuclear power.
Opponents of nuclear energy
argue that nuclear waste
and it's lack of long-term
storage solutions
is an unacceptable problem and risk,
while proponents of nuclear energy
say that until renewable energies
are able to cover the complete
energy demands of mankind,
it's arguably safer to store
nuclear waste for the time being
than to inhale poisonous gases
and promote rapid climate change.
But a detailed discussion about
nuclear waste would go too far here,
more about it in our sources.
Let us know if you'd like
a whole video about it.
So looking at the comparative
death rates, it's a bit concerning
that some countries are replacing
nuclear energy with fossil fuels,
mostly coal.
Especially Germany and Japan
have been the most active
in dismantling their nuclear fleet.
In a ploy to appease the public,
the German government shut down
11 of its 17 nuclear facilities
and plans to close the
remaining reactors in 2022.
The immediate gap in energy production
was filled by temporarily
increasing coal production,
the energy source with the
largest health impacts
and the worst consequences
for climate change.
A 2019 analysis concluded
that as a consequence,
the nuclear phase-out has led to
1,100 avoidable deaths
per year in Germany
due to the increased air pollution
in the years after 2010.
So, in conclusion, nuclear energy feels
way more dangerous than it actually is.
No matter how you look at it,
the one thing we should strive to
get rid of as quickly as possible
are fossil fuels to prevent the
deaths they cause each year
and to slow down climate change.
Regardless of how much you personally
care about climate change issues
or which energy source you favour,
saving millions of lives should be
something we can all agree on.
Maybe you've actually made
some kind of resolution
to try and be more sustainable this year.
Or maybe your goals are
more about you as a person
and you'd like to pick up
some new skills.
Still being stuck mostly inside is the
perfect time to work on that plan.
We've partnered with Skillshare,
an online learning community
that offers thousands of
classes for all skill levels
in tons of creative skills like
illustration, animation or film and video.
But you could also dive into
classes about productivity,
growing houseplants
or interior design.
All perfect for making your
time at home more enjoyable
and learning something new.
You get unlimited access to all classes
for less than ten dollars a month
with an annual premium membership.
And the first one thousand
Kurzgesagt viewers
to click the link in the description
will get a free trial.
And if you can't decide
which class to take,
maybe get started with
something super practical
like learning how to best approach
your creative process.
We liked Productivity for Creatives:
Build a System That Brings Out
Your Best by Thomas Frank
but whatever makes you feel good and
gives you new ideas is worth a try.
If you want to get creative with new
skills and support Kurzgesagt,
give it a go.