- Did you find it? - Yes, madam, this time I have.
- And who? - The cobbler's son, Mistress.
And you are sure that he is...
The best, Mistress, the best! There is no one in the whole kingdom...
You know what I'll do to you if you deceive me again.
No, Mistress! Not this time, I mean yes!
Well, I'll visit him tomorrow.
♪ (SINGING): "Summer rain ♪ ♪ get the forest cool ♪
♪ And the road home is easy ♪
♪ In the blue of dawn ♪ ♪ The world is as clear as a palm ♪ ♪
# For you alone the sun will rise again ♪
♪ Take your time, ♪ ♪ and you'll hear the grass grow ♪ ♪
♪ For you, for you..." ♪
- Dad, I'm off to see my mother! - Yeah, but hurry up, there's a lot of work to be done.
All right!
Jacob, look what Daddy made me!
Heh! It's great, it's almost like a real one.
Listen up, people of the kingdom!
Yesterday the royal daughter, Their Highness Princess Greta, disappeared from the palace.
- Poor Princess. - What happened to her?
Whoever helps us find her will be rewarded royally!
- Mother, the princess is missing! - Yes, Jacob, I heard.
- Will they find her? - Of course they will, they will.
- What a helper you have! - I can't complain.
Well, run along, helper, your father is waiting for you. And I'll manage on my own.
It's a piece of crap, not a product!
Crap...
Crap!
Why do you say that? It's very fresh...
Ah...
Friend Jacob...
If the dear lady would like to buy something...
I do, I do. Ha-ha-ha!
Here, put five cabbages in my basket.
And let your boy take me home.
- My father is waiting for me! - Come on, Jacob, don't be lazy!
Look how heavy the lady's bag is.
Don't be lazy, Jacob, I'll thank you.
Do you like it? Come in, Jacob, don't be shy.
Urban, have you prepared everything?
- Yes, ma'am. - Yes, ma'am. Good.
Come on, let's go and see how I live.
- I promised my mother I'd come right back. - And I promised to thank you.
Are you afraid?
No, but the house is strange: small on the outside, big on the inside.
It's a trick: You see one thing, but it's another.
Come on, you need to get some rest.
I can imagine how tired you are of carrying human heads.
What heads? I was carrying cabbage!
See, that's how you do tricks.
All right, get up.
Let me out of here at once!
Please...
Now I'm going to show you something amazing.
Can you guess who it is?
His name is Dougal and he brings... happiness! But first we have to bring him back to life.
Is he dead?
Do you know what happens when good and evil come together?
There's a great power in their union, and that power will bring my stone to life!
And you will help me do it. Look!
Well? Do you want to ride wooden horses all day?
No?
Ah! Maybe you want a real knight's armor, huh?
Do you like it? Well, there you go.
I can't give you those presents, but we can exchange them.
- For what? - That's funny to say!
It would be another trick: you just have to put your hand here.
(Urban sneezed.)
- I don't want to. - You don't want to? Why not?
It's no big deal, come on.
No.
Don't you have enough toys? Good!
You'll get money, lots of money.
And your parents aren't rich, think how happy they'll be.
Mom says it doesn't matter if a person is poor or rich...
It's important that he has a good heart.
- A good heart? - Yes, a good heart.
A poor man with a good heart...
What if he suddenly grows a hump or a nose? Would a good heart help him?
Yes.
- You must want to put it to the test! - Me? Why?
I'll tell you when you come to me.
And I'll make you do it!
Where are my shoes? Your mistress let me go.
No, they're not mine.
(church bells tolling)
Mother, are you unwell? Are you angry with me?
What do you want? Go your way.
What's the matter, Mother? Are you angry that I'm late?
It's that old woman's fault, she wouldn't let me go.
Mother, what's the matter with you? You're the one who sent me with her.
Why are you making fun of that poor woman? Her son disappeared seven years ago.
How seven years? I just took the old woman the cabbage.
- No, what a rascal, huh? Get out of here! - Mother, don't you recognize me?
It's me, Jacob.
- I told you to get out! - Well, why?
You hear me, boy, get out of here in a nice way.
Well, Mother... Well, look at me!
- Jakob was handsome, and this one... - Yes, he should be chased away!
- No, look at his nose! - Quiet!
Do you really think you're Jacob, son of the greengrocer Hannah?
(guards laughing)
What are you... What are you running around for, huh?
Yes, you almost killed us with your huge nose!
Let's shorten it a little bit. А?
Aha! Well, where's the nose?
- What do you want, have you come to beg? - No, no, sir!
Here... This was Heinz the shoemaker's shop, wasn't it?
What kind of a master am I? Heinz died seven years ago.
Hey, kid! What do you want? Although... Need a pot?
(thunder rumbling)
- What took you so long, where have you been hanging around? - Come on, Auntie, I...
Don't you dare call me aunt! How many times do I have to tell you?
Yes, auntie... Oh! I mean, I mean, madam.
Report, you bum. Did you follow him?
- Yes, ma'am, we'll have him soon. - Good!
Keep watching, don't let him out of your sight.
Oh, great Dougal! It's only a matter of time.
Soon you'll have the kindest heart you can find.
Are you still there?
- Ouch! Princess, Mistress, what should I do? - Do I have to think for you?
I should have got rid of her a long time ago. Idiot!
Here's a transformation for you.
Turn her into a goose, then sell her to the king's kitchen.
What a laugh when she gets to His Royal Majesty's table!
Good morning! Do you need an assistant, sir?
An assistant?
I can't take you as my assistant or my pots will burst.
- Ah... From what? - Laughter!
Rascal, look what you've done! Go away!
Don't let my eyes see you! Get out! Get out at once!
And don't you ever stick your big, ugly nose in here again!
Scoundrel, scoundrel!
Ugh, couldn't turn her into something lighter, silly old woman!
It's a long way to the palace.
Hey, sir! What have you got in the bag?
What have you got... in the bag?
Nothing special, just a goose. A goose, actually.
- A big one? - A big one.
Hmm...
- Do you know what happens for stealing? - Why is it for stealing?
Then why do you have a big goose?
Me? I don't have a big one. I have a medium one! I mean, in general...
Come on, show me!
Yeah, it's a big one.
I must arrest you immediately and confiscate the goose... uh... confiscate!
Sir, I swear there must be some mistake. It's not my fault!
Let me give you one thaler and you don't have to arrest anyone.
- How much? Two! And not a thaler less! - And not a thaler less!
Two? It's a hornbeam... Uh... All right, all right, I'll do it.
- What are you standing there for? We have to pull. - Pull it!
Who's stealing from me here?
I wanted to ask you, sir, do you need an assistant?
What? Are you still laughing at me?
Hold on! I'll rip your long nose out!
(guards laughing)
- Hey, why are you having so much fun? - What? Sorry, we didn't recognize you right away.
We didn't! Cackling like hyenas, scaring people.
Excuse me!
Look, it's great!
- Oh! What are you doing here, huh? - Nosey hunchback!
- Oh, what a handsome man! - Wow, you scared me!
- After him! - After him! Catch him, he'll get away!
Can we go now, Mr. Chief Speedwalker?
- Yes, go. - Fatty, follow me.
Wait! What's in the bag?
In the sack? What sack? Oh, in the bag...
Nothing.
What do you mean, nothing? Then why are you carrying it?
Do you know what happens for stealing?
That's... why theft?
Also, I will confiscate the bird and turn you over to the chief of guards.
Uh... Well... Sir, don't! Let us give you two thalers.
- What? Five, five thalers!
Ten! And not a thaler less!
I only have five, give me five more.
Oh, I'm hurt! It's all your fault, you scoundrels!
Sir, you'll have to get a lotion!
A lotion? Yes, yes, a lotion. Pampusha, I'm hurt!
- It's all because of you! - Why is it my fault?
- Please, somebody help me! - Because you're a jackass, that's why!
Calling me names.
- Help me, please. - Are you talking to me?
Look, she's getting all dolled up.
Hey, she's about to run away!
Hey, why are you throwing?
I'm not throwing anything.
Well, then catch her! What are you standing there? Look, she's getting closer to the fence!
Oh, you, are you? Well, wait for me!
Is that you again? Come on, drop the goose!
- Drop it! Surround him!
What's that noise over there? Wait for me. Don't move around, sit still!
Don't drip on the carpet, or you'll get it from me!
Monster!
What? What did you call me?
- No, you didn't, pumppuppuppuppu! - What?
- You're not the monster. - Oh, I'm not?
Oh, your vase!
What are you doing?
That's, that's who's to blame! Mr. Blum, quick!
Get him, get him!
Hurry up! Come on, hurry up!
Wait! Wait!
Shoes come to your senses! Stop it! Come on, stop it!
Tr-r-r-r!
But! Come on! What are you looking at?
Damned boys, running around like mad, only scaring the cattle.
Wow... Magic shoes, no way.
Hurry up!
Wait, wait, t-r-r-r-r!
Tricks! The old woman showed you magic tricks? She did.
Could she have mistakenly made me...
Yes, of course she could! I can't believe I didn't think of it before.
What if it wasn't a trick? All right, we'll figure it out.
Oh, and the shoes need to be returned. She's probably looking for them and thinking, "Stolen!"
Here she comes, madam! Here she comes, here she comes.
You'll be smiling later, get the key to the mirror room.
He's here, madam.
Oh, finally!
What's that?
Nothing, Auntie! A mouse must have run by.
A mouse?
The key, where's the key?
- Jacob, run quickly! - Hold them off until I find the key!
- Run, run faster! - Damn, it's the same place again!
Wow!
Give it to me, Mr. Dwarf. It's a good thing you caught her.
- We have to run. - Don't listen to her, come on!
Mr. Midget, that's enough. Mrs. Stewart...
- Mr. Midget... - Please...
- Please... - Run!
Aaah!
Ouch...
Shoes, stop! T-r-r-r-r! We barely made it!
We need a place to wait out the rain. Let's go that way.
You're nothing! I'll beat you to a pulp!
- I'm sorry... My bad... - Idiot!
You ruined everything. I had the boy in my hands.
- Who could have known that a girl would get involved? - You should have known!
She belongs in the oven, but now there's two of them, and they're up to something.
Find them, find out what they're up to. And remember, you have to make it right!
Did anyone ask you to do that? Why are you meddling in your own business?
I didn't meddle in anything.
- Well, not at all. Does it hurt? - It hurts.
Now, wait!
It'll go away in a couple of days.
Thank you. Who taught you that?
My mother knows herbs very well.
Then your mother should say thank you, too.
- I'll never see her again. - You won't?
Maybe I will, but she won't recognize me anyway.
Oh, so that's why you went back to the old woman! Did you think she'd magic you up?
Of course, you had to touch a stone, didn't you?
The old woman was doing tricks. And so... - Tricks?
Do you want me to tell you what kind of tricks they are? Well, listen.
Many, many years ago, a dying monk...
...asked the king to hide a book and never take it out of the palace.
And more recently...
I think it's in here somewhere.
Aha!
His name is Jacob. Jacob is the cobbler's son.
- Why are you laughing? - Who are you, sweet child?
Я? A princess! Why did you take Daddy's book?
He won't let anyone take it. Not even me.
But you wouldn't tell him that, would you?
I can't lie to my daddy.
And you don't have to lie to him. Just don't say anything, that's all.
- Your Highness, Princess! - Look me in the eye.
- We're looking for Her Highness, and... - Her Highness?
Yes. What are you doing here?
- So you're a princess? - I was a princess.
Until that nasty guy I baited came along.
That's how I found out it's been seven years.
- And you have seven years? - Yeah.
And then he said I'd make a great roast and turned me into a goose.
Well, wait, we'll show you!
Look, I know what to do.
What?
We have to read this book, I have to look at the palace.
What for?
We'll figure out a way to get in at night.
No, Jacob, please, you'll get caught!
I'm not going anywhere, I'm just going to look, that's all.
And you... Do you want to hang out with the son of a shoemaker?
Silly, of course I do.
And what shall I call you? Your Highness?
What "Highness"? Just call me Greta.
Greta...
Your Highness, we've searched the entire kingdom seven times in seven years.
For seven years...
Your Majesty, they say there's a lot of witchcraft going on here.
I don't think anyone would do such a thing, Your Majesty!
Witchcraft is punishable by death!
Then where is my daughter?
Your Majesty! The foot soldiers have gone astray. We're short of men.
Look for new ones!
In the name of His Royal Majesty, tomorrow a race is announced for runners.
The winner will be inducted into the royal service of speed walkers!
- Where are they? - In the old mill, ma'am.
What are you doing here? Go there at once!
I must know what they're talking about, every word they say!
- But it's night, madam. - Are you afraid of the dark?
Yes! I mean, no, mistress!
But may I take the spirit of transformation with me?
I have few of them left myself.
Go on, I don't want to hear any more.
- Who's there? - Don't you recognize your king, soldier?
Of course I do, Your Majesty.
It's just that they say it's turbulent here, Your Majesty.
- What do you mean, "uneasy"? - Well, there are spirits, ghosts...
Talking. You, lad, don't be so concerned with all this nonsense.
Yes, Your Majesty!
There, there, look, there's another one flying!
We had a big pipe on the roof.
A pipe?
Yes, a pipe, only with glass, and you could look into it.
- Why would you look in it? - Just for fun.
It magnified everything, my dad and I even looked at the moon.
That's great!
And me and the boys used to tease the guards by throwing acorns at them.
It was funny, too!
- Funny? - Well, yes.
Ouch! Damn dwarf! Well, wait, I'll show you again.
- Did the girls play with you? - Girls? No! Well, maybe sometimes.
If a girl had red hair, would you tease her?
No, I wouldn't!
I didn't tease anybody, just the guards.
Why do you ask?
No reason.
Would you want to be friends with a girl with red hair?
I don't know, if she's interesting, yes. But who would be friends with me?
Who would be friends with me? Who needs me now?
Come on, Greta, I need you. In fact, I'm sure you're very beautiful.
What makes you say that?
Because you're a princess, and princesses are always beautiful.
- Have you seen many princesses? - No, not many... You're the first.
And you're a goose, too. In fact, I have red hair.
That's great! So now I'm friends with the girl with red hair.
Ouch!
What if something goes wrong tomorrow? You know how worried I am.
- Don't worry, you'll do great. - I'm not scared, I'm just worried.
Oh...
Tell me more about the moon.
Did you look at it a lot?
Yes, we wanted to see people. Daddy said people live there, too.
Wow!
And these people on the moon, what do they look like? Have you ever seen them?
No. Maybe they were sleeping. What do you think?
They must have been asleep, because you have to look at them during the day, and there's no moon during the day.
Oh, yes...
Stupid old woman! You should have jumped around with the frogs, then you'd have known.
What if they also have such pipes, and they're looking at us now?
Sure they do, but we're all asleep, too.
But we are not asleep! Why don't we wave our hands at them?
Let's do it!
Hey! Hey!
♪ (SINGING) Behind the white glass of the moon
♪ You'll see a shadow ♪
♪ Under the thin smoke of sleep ♪
♪ The doors are clear for you and me ♪
♪ Gentle as silk, the wind ♪ ♪ Twirls the leaves of the day ♪
# Wipes away the rustle of words... ♪
# Shadows will fade into starry dreams ♪
# The night, tired, lies on the carpet of flowers ♪
# Shadows fade into starry dreams ♪
# In the stars of dreams..." ♪
Dear Sir, how can I find Mr. Chief Speedwalker?
- What do you need him for? - I want to compete in the runners' competition.
- Yeah, runners. - Buddy, are you even...
Heh-heh-heh-heh-heh!
Mr. Speed Runner on duty! Here comes another one, running faster than the wind.
- Let him in, they said to let everyone in. - Thank you very much, gentlemen of the guards.
Well, they also said all sorts of nonsense. About the moon...
They wanted the book, they went too far.
Listen, what we need to do...
In the name of His Royal Majesty...
...I ask the runners to prepare for the start of the race!
(crowd cheering)
Your Majesty, everything is ready. Shall I begin?
Yes, Mr. Blum, you may begin.
But first I'd like to know why you're wearing a ceremonial uniform.
Were you preparing for a ball?
Your Majesty, do you want me to run away too?
Not just run, Mr. Blum.
The chief speed walker must be the fastest. Isn't that right?
That's right, Your Majesty.
On your mark...
Ready...
March!
Hurry up!
What a wretch!
Madam! The boy... He was bringing you the cabbage! Do you remember?
The boy... Madam! Madam...
Please.
- What is your name, runner? - Jacob, Your Majesty.
You're a fast runner, Jacob. It's been a long time since anyone has pleased me like that.
Your Majesty! He has magic shoes. I saw everything!
Is that so?
Your Majesty! Let Mr. Blum demonstrate their magic properties.
Mr. Blum, don't bore us.
If the shoes are magic, you don't need any squatting.
Let's go!
Run! Quickly!
Quickly! Quickly! Quickly!
Trot! Quickly!
- Quickly! - Quickly...
Enough, Mr. Blum. The test is over.
Well, do you want to be my chief speed walker, Jacob?
- I do, Your Majesty. Only... - Only what?
- Just a request, Your Majesty. - Speak.
I would like to employ, Your Majesty, my goose.
A goose? And how will she serve me?
She won't, she'll just live with me.
Very well, Jacob. You've been hired as head footman.
And soon you will have a very important assignment.
Wow, wow!
That's great!
Yes... But when we're done...
What "when we're done"?
Nothing. You'll be a princess again...
...and you'll still be my friend. You are my friend, aren't you?
You know, I've never had a friend like you.
Do you want me to show you the palace?
No, Greta, come on! What if someone sees us?
So what? You're the king's chief footman! Don't you remember?
Come, I'll show you my chambers.
- What's this? - This is my and Daddy's favorite game.
We used to go in here and lock ourselves in, so no one would find us.
And Daddy would always say, "Well, ponytail, show me how nimble you are."
Why the ponytail?
Well, when I was little, I always followed his tail.
That's why he called me "ponytail." It was our secret.
This is my great-grandfather, a very formidable king.
And this...
And this is you?
Mr. Chief Speedwalker, are you touring my palace?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Is this your goose, Jacob?
Strange, but she reminds me of someone.
Jacob, can your goose cry?
Your Majesty, this is your...
This is your... Mmm... illumination! The smoke makes her eyes water.
Ah! I'll need you tomorrow morning.
- Oh! I almost gave us away. - Oh, I'm good too!
Listen, Greta, shouldn't we tell your father?
Jacob, remember your mother. Did she believe you? What about me?
I can only talk to you, no one else can understand me.
Yes, but I don't feel comfortable.
Your father's been so good to me, and we're stealing a book he treasures.
No, we're not stealing it. We're borrowing it.
I'm sure my father won't be the slightest bit angry when he finds out the truth.
You think so? I don't think he will if we can make it work.
Well, of course we're going to make it!
(guard's footsteps can be heard)
Who's there?
I am the angel of death! Why have you disturbed my peace?
They found the book.
It's you, it's all your fault.
Madam, will you let me catch the damned dwarf?
We'll put him in our cave of horrors and let him jump!
I'm a little scared there myself.
А?
Huh?
You're an idiot, Urban, yes... You're a moron! You can't be trusted with anything.
You're nothing but trouble. What should I do with you?
- What should I do? - Pack up, donkey, we're going to the palace!
"I," he says, "am the angel of death!"
- Uh... - Uh...
- "...take who tears the taraxacum..." - Taraxacum?
Yes. "...and burn his head with the sun, and scatter his ashes in the wind...
...He shall break the evil spell and bring it all back."
I don't get it: do we have to burn someone?
No, no, I think that... You see, it says "break it."
I think we're talking about some kind of plant.
That's right! "Taraxacum" - is some kind of herb.
You know what we're going to do? I'm going to go to my mother right now.
She'll help us!
Wait, what does "burn his head with the sun" mean?
Maybe if it's a plant, it should be dried in the sun?
No, that's different. It says exactly "burn it."
And then the ashes have to be scattered. Shall we read some more?
No, we can't waste time. You keep reading while I run to my mother.
"And only Jacob shall touch the stone, as Dougal shall have his heart.
And evil will be united with good: Dagal will come to life, and there will be no one more ruthless in the world.
And Dagal will do her evil will as many times as she wishes."
- Greta, the shoes are gone! - My shoes?
Oh, what happened to your voice? Are you sick?
No, I just got a little hoarse from the excitement, that's all.
Who wanted them?
I don't know, it's getting light, and the king is about to call me.
And without them I won't have time to run to my mother.
You don't have to, Jacob!
I read in the book that if you touch the stone, everything will be fine.
It's our own fault, we're imagining fears of our own!
We've got to get to her, she'll help us.
How is that possible? Is that written in a book?
Yes!
Maybe there's something you don't understand. Let's see it again!
Mr. Chief Shifter, His Majesty demands to see you.
- I don't believe it. Get out! - What, auntie, you don't believe me?
Come here!
Mind you, the last transformation. Don't get anything wrong!
What are you doing, you idiot? Don't you know how to walk?
- It's so dark in here, auntie. - Come on, dummy, it's dark for him.
Hey, pick me up.
You're the one I want.
Who are you?
Я? I'm your friend. The magic knight! Come closer.
A magic book is missing, run, report to your superiors and you'll be rewarded.
The book... ah... It's gone... Wow!
Stop, donkey! I didn't tell you who stole it!
- I'm glad to have you in my service, Jacob. - Thank you, Your Majesty.
Now you have your first and very important task.
I have a story to tell you.
Seven years ago, my daughter disappeared, and you must go in search of her.
Yes, Your Majesty.
What?
A magic book was stolen from the library. There are thieves in the palace! Where is the chief of guards?
Here, Your Majesty!
- Who was on guard? - There he is, Your Majesty!
He's telling everyone about some angel of death!
- What? Yes, Your Majesty.
Ah, it's you again? What happened?
I was standing on my watch, Your Majesty, standing there...
Suddenly, out of the blue, the angel of death appeared right in front of me.
Yes! "I am," he said, "the angel of death!"
And then the magic knight told me to report everything, so I did.
That's enough, get him out of my sight!
There he is, the angel of death! Only without wings for some reason.
Now, either this soldier's gone mad, or...
Search the room of the head speeder immediately!
Well, elephant boy, think again, maybe "faster"?
I don't remember, maybe "faster."
Ah, ah, ah, ah...
- Oh, elephant boy, well done! - I don't know how to stop them!
- Oh, oh! Oh... - Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah!
- Ah-ah-ah-ah! Oh! Ohh! - Uh-uh-uh-uh...
So, the angel of death... So it was you who took the book?
- Your Majesty... - Did you or did you not?
- Yes, Your Majesty, but... - No buts!
In my kingdom, witchcraft is punishable by death.
And you're also a thief!
Your Majesty, I can explain!
It's too late to explain, tomorrow you'll have your head cut off.
Take him to the tower! The goose to the kitchen, to the cooks!
No, Your Majesty! It's your daughter!
You still dare to make fun of my grief?
Despicable man...
Take him away!
(goose squeaks)
Mr. Dwarf, Mr. Dwarf!
Mr. Dwarf! Oh, Mr. Midget! I beg you, tell me, how do they stop?
I will spare nothing for you, I will do everything for you!
What can you do?
Mr. Dwarf!
(note): "Find out from Mrs. Ganna, who sells herbs in the market, what kind of herb is it?"
Taka, caka... And you... you wouldn't cheat?
No, run away!
Jacob, Jacob, you stubborn little man! Do you want to die, you fool?
Do you know how it ends? Your girlfriend's feathers will be blown away by the wind.
And your ugly head will fall into the hangman's sack!
Remember, Jacob, all you have to do is whisper, "I do!"
And you'll get it all back.
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
And no one, no one can help you but me!
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
Help me, please! Tell me, what is this weed, huh?
- Why do you need it, who sent you? - Oh, don't ask!
The hunchback dwarf sent me. He's going to be executed today.
Executed?
Mr. Dwarf, I found out everything!
Ah-ah-ah-ah!
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Ow, ow! Ow, ow, ow! Uh-uh-uh!
Don't you ever pry into other people's secrets again!
Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah!
I'm waiting for you, Jacob. Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
His Royal Majesty ordered the beheading for witchcraft...
...to Jacob, the former head speedster.
Oh, look, she's crying!
You are a sorcerer and a thief, besides, you tried to get away with it.
In spite of that, you have one last wish. Speak.
Speak, speak!
The condemned man's last wish!
Sir!
You wanted to know about the herb taraxacum? It's the dandelion.
I think I understand... I got it!
Your Majesty! Tail, remember the tail!
Tail? How, how did you know that?
Your Majesty, we do not have much time. Believe me, please!
Let me do something. Right here, now.
First you must tell me, from whom did you learn it?
Your Majesty, my words will not convince you. You must see it with your own eyes.
You have touched my heart with doubt. What do you wish to do?
I dare ask the Lord Obergofmeister for his monocle.
A monocle?
Your Majesty, I dare say it's a great impudence!
It can't be!
- Jacob, my son! - Mother!
- Jacob, Jacob! - Greta!
- Greta... - Greta!
No, Jacob, don't touch it! It's Dougal, I know! I know.
Don't listen to her! You don't want her to die, do you?
You're wasting your time, Jacob.
My good subjects!
This young man brought my daughter back, and saved us all from the terrible, evil sorceress!
(people cheering)
Your Majesty, we did it together with Her Highness.
My name is Greta, have you forgotten?
Save yourselves, Your Majesty!
It's the magic knight. Stand back, I'll hold him off!
Mr. Dwarf, I never approved of my aunt!
I've always... I've always been on your side.
She made me do it! And it was so dark...
(all laughing)
- Pampusha, why don't you do it? - No, elephant, I want to do it myself.
Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh! Ow! Ow, ow!