For much of human history, the population grew slowly
until new discoveries brought us more food and made us live longer.
In just one century, the population has quadrupled.
This has led to an apocalyptic vision of an overpopulated Earth.
However, the rate of population growth reached its peak in 1960.
Since then, fertility rates have plummeted as countries industrialized and developed.
The world population is currently projected to be
around 11 billion people towards the end of the century.
But the big picture hides some details.
Let's look at one region in particular.
Sub-Saharan Africa.
In 2019 it was home to a billion people, in 46 different countries.
Although its growth rate has slowed in
recent decades, it is still much higher than the rest of the world.
While some projections suggest the population will reach around 2.6 billion people,
others say it will be around 5 billion by 2100.
Such growth would be a major challenge for any society.
But Sub-Saharan Africa is also the poorest region in the world.
And then sub-Saharan Africa is doomed?
And why do the projections have a gap of 2.4 billion people?
As always, it's complicated.
Sub-Saharan Africa is an artificial concept.
And in many respects even harmful.
Botswana is as far from Sierra Leone
as Ireland is from Kazakhstan.
And they have, more or less, the same in common;
However, without a bit of generalization,
this video would last an hour.
We talked to many scientists to make this video
and they disagreed on many aspects.
Mainly, on how fertility
can be correlated with poverty.
We have done our best to summarize our research and what we have been told,
but take it with a grain of salt, and check our sources
where the subject is discussed in more detail.
Now, let's go back to a global view again.
A few decades ago many countries in Asia
were in a similar situation to that of sub-Saharan Africa today: a
large part of the population lived in extreme poverty
and fertility rates were very high.
For example, in Bangladesh in 1960,
an average woman had seven children over the course of her
life, 25% of them would die before they could turn five
, and of those who survived, only one in five
would learn to read and  write.
Life expectancy was around forty-five years,
and per capita GDP was the lowest in the world.
Thus, in the early 1960s, Bangladesh
initiated a family planning program based on three fundamental pillars:
1. Greater education
helped change the perspective of women;
women with a higher level of education tended to have fewer children
and to become mothers at an older age
2. A quality health care system lowered infant mortality by
encouraging parents to have fewer children as they would survive.
3. Health workers brought contraceptives to even the most remote areas;
this increased the use of contraceptives,
from 8% in 1975
to 76% in 2019.
Together, these measures greatly slowed
population growth.
In 1960, an average Bengali woman
had seven children, four in 1995
, and only two in 2019.
This also changed the demographic profile and the economy:
before, many children were born,
but they would die before they could contribute to society;
that is until fewer children began to die and be born,
then things changed: children could be educated
and become productive adults.
The government thus had the possibility of diverting part of its resources from reducing infant mortality,
to strengthen the economy.
By 2024, Bangladesh is expected to
be promoted from the underdeveloped nation category to the
developing nation state.
Other Asian nations, such as South Korea
, India, Thailand or the Philippines have gone through the same process,
often even faster:
investments in health and education
led to fewer births, which changed the composition of the population,
and allowed  the government to boost the economy.
Why didn't such a thing happen everywhere, even in sub-Saharan Africa?
Africa itself has made great progress
in reducing infant mortality, however, especially in sub - Saharan Africa
, education has been implemented more slowly
than in other parts of the world.
Furthermore, although contraceptive use has doubled since 1990,
the lack of modern contraceptives among adolescents
is still around 60%.
The reasons are complicated,
and it is impossible to give a single answer.
Africa is a very large territory, with cultures and people different from each other;
however, there are some common factors.
Many sub-Saharan nations were subject to colonial domination
until a few decades ago,
and had a troubled path towards independence.
The new nations were often ethnically heterogeneous and lacked unity;
many areas were repeatedly ravaged by civil wars,
military conflicts, or suffered from unstable governments;
this made it difficult to develop infrastructure and a health system.
So Africa had a worse starting point than Asia
Foreign aid, and how it was used, especially during the Cold War,
is still a controversial topic.
However, this topic is too complex for it to be summarized in a few sentences,
so, in the future, we will create a whole video about it.
Finally, there are cultural aspects that make it difficult to talk about family planning in the African context.
Critics argue that trying to lower fertility
is an intrusion into culture and tradition,
but not talking about a problem won't help solve it.
Not all of this is true for every nation in the region,
after all, we are talking about forty-six nations
some with serious problems, others already thriving;
they are all different but face the same problem:
if population growth continues at the current rate
then sub-Saharan Africa will reach over four billion by 2100.
Well, then, what can be done?
In fact, a lot!
Especially investments that help build systems for education,
family planning and health care.
Surprisingly, small changes
can have a big impact:
for example, if women had a better education,
they would have their first child two years later.
This small gap between the first generation and the second
would lead to 400 million fewer people by 2100,
with 3.6 billion in total.
If education and family planning became available to every African woman,
universal access to contraception would make having a child a choice.
If families could choose how many children they want,
both projections drop 30%
to 2.8 billion people.
This is not just theory.
There are already examples that are a reason to be optimistic.
Ethiopia, the second largest nation in Africa by population,
has made a lot of progress in a relatively short period of time.
Innovative health services have led to a reduction in infant mortality
from 20% to 7%
since 1990.
In addition, more than 30% of the annual budget
has been invested in schooling,
and the number of schools has increased twenty-fivefold in two decades.
So, to sum it up:
there are many challenges to be faced, but they are far from unsolvable.
Sub-Saharan Africa does not need to be given anything,
but attention and prudent investments.
it is a region rich in resources, culture and potential.
If things go right, we will see a change similar
to what we have seen across much of Asia over the past 30 years.
Translation of: Memenorio