Hey, Vsauce. Michael here.
And our faces
have a lot of holes.
We have two ears and two eyes.
It makes sense, because the difference in
time it takes for a sound to reach one ear
and the other,
allows us to localize where the sound is coming from.
And having two eyes gives us two
slightly different perspectives that we
can put together
in order to perceive depth.
But why do we have two
nostrils?
I mean, our sense of smell isn't good enough to localize
one nostril over the other,
why not just have a big hole in our nose,
like we have a mouth.
Well, Stanford University's olfactory research
project
investigated this and they found that
throughout the day
one nostril inhales air better and faster
than the other. Now, which one is dominant
changes throughout the day, but having
a good air sucking nostril and a not so good
air sucking nostril is important.
We need both,
because you see, odorants and molecules
are absorbed by our skin and snot
at different rates.
Some things are absorbed so quickly
they need to be rushed on the olfactory
receptors before they're
absorbed earlier on in the nose.
Other
molecules, other odorants, are slowly absorbed
and they need to be given time to get to
the receptors and not just rushed right
to the lungs.
And so having two nostrils allows us to smell
more things.
Alright,
so let's smell some weird stuff, like
outer space.
What would space smell like?
Okay, right, it's a tough question,
it actually doesn't make much sense because
space
is a mere vacuum.
If you went into space and took your helmet off to
smell it, well, all of the air in your lungs
and throat, nose would be violently
sucked right out. In fact, even if you
really tried to get some sort of
olfactory sensation, about all you
would feel is the quick evaporation of
water coming out of your mucous membranes
and you might smell,
for the few seconds that you were conscious,
nasal fluid and blood.
That doesn't sound fun at all.
But here's the thing.
Objects
that have been taken out into space and
then returned to a
habitable atmosphere, like inside a space station,
smell differently than they did before
they went into space.
Astronauts report that their suits,
after being in space, have a strange metallic
burn meat arc welder fumes smell.
It's believed that the odor is caused by
high energy particles
that cling to the suit and then, once brought inside,
react with the air, creating a burning
smell.
One particular type of high energy molecule found
all over interstellar space are polycyclic
aromatic hydrocarbons.
These guys are the result
of combustion. And in 2004,
the University of Toledo, Ohio found evidence
that those very molecules may exist in old
nebula. The result of convection currents
cooling carbon and hydrogen
allowing them to bond into giant shapes.
Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons are also formed,
when cooking meat at high temperatures.
So, in order to train astronauts even
more realistically here on earth,
NASA actually reached out to Steven
Pearce of Omega Ingredients
to replicate the smell of things that
have been to space
as a perfume.
If we know the chemical makeup of something,
even something light years away from us,
we can assemble those ingredients
here on earth and get an idea of what it would
smell like.
Recently, researchers have discovered
Ethyl Formate in the dust cloud Sagittarius
B2.
Now, again, if you were to go there
and lift up your space suits visor and take a whiff,
you would die. You wouldn't be able to take
a whiff, all of the air in your nose and
lungs and throat would be
immediately expelled.
But if you were able to take a
bucket of Sagittarius B2 home with you to earth
and then give it a smell,
because of the ethyl formate
Sagittarius B2's stuff
would smell like raspberries and rum.
Pretty neat, right?
But let's get closer to home.
What does the inside of your nose
smell like?
Well, it's kind of hard to know
because we are smelling it
all the time and our bodies become desensitized
to constant stimuli to keep us from
being overloaded
and to keep us prepared to sense any out
of the ordinary smells that
we might need to know about.
This happens to us all the time.
When you first step into a restaurant,
you can smell all the food,
but halfway through the meal you're
no longer aware of the smell.
It's called neural adaptation.
I guess the point I'm trying to make
is that in order to figure out what the
inside of a nose smells like
you'll need to smell a novel one,
like, for instance, smell the inside of your friend's nose.
It might seem weird at first,
but it could be a great way to form
new memories. Our sense of smell may not
be as acute as our other senses,
but it seems to be tied to memories very very closely.
A single whiff of an odor can instantly
remind you of where you used to smell
that smell
and maybe even who you were with.
This may be
because of the olfactories' connection to
the limbic system
in the brain.
Olfactory information is sent
through the limbic system,
which is known to be involved with
emotions and memories.
No other traditional sense is connected
to the limbic system in this way.
We've also found
that patients who have memory loss
caused by brain damage
tend to also have an impaired ability
to smell.
So treasure your sense of smell,
because it not only keeps us safe from gross
odors or rotten food, it can also keep us safe
from incest.
Individuals who are
raised together in the same home for the
first few years of their life,
whether they are genetically related or not,
will tend to be less physically
attracted to each other
later in life than they are to strangers.
This is known
as the Westermarck effect and one of the
main mechanisms it works via
is the olfactory system.
Us humans have an interesting ability to
distinguish the smell of a stranger
from someone that we are genetically related to or
grew up in very close proximity with.
This entire phenomenon may be a
natural way for us to avoid inbreeding.
But what about someone who can't smell?
What do we call them?
Someone who can't see is blind,
someone who can't hear is deaf and
someone who can't speak is mute,
but what do you call someone who can't smell?
Well, there's a word for the inability to smell - anosmia.
Now, even though the adjective form is very very rare,
it exists.
A person who can't smell
is anosmic.
There's another word we should have
investigated a long time ago.
Olfactory.
What does is it come from? Well,
the "ol" part comes from odor and from smell,
but "factory?"
Well, factories make
things, but the nose doesn't makes smells,
it smells smells.
Right?
Well, here's the thing. We
smell objects because molecules from those
objects react in certain ways with our olfactory
receptors.
And molecules have
specific shapes and vibrations and ways of behaving,
but the smell is not actually
intrinsic to the molecule.
The smell is merely a
consequence of how that molecule reacts
with us.
No us,
no smell.
So, olfactory
is a fantastic word.
Every sight
and feeling and sound and smell we get
from our universe
is actually just the universe reacting with
us.
Everything we know about the universe we know
because it has already been processed
and changed and analyzed and filtered
inside the factory of our sense.
And as always,
thanks for watching.