A blizzard covers the slopes of the mountain peaks.
And the ground is white.
Silent kingdom
I have become the queen.
And the wind groans and my heart is a hurricane.
I wish I could contain it, but I couldn't.
Not reveal, keep a secret
Be a good girl for everyone.
Lock up all your feelings
But it's all in vain
Let it go and forget
What's past can't be undone
A new day will show the way
I'm not afraid of anything
Let the storm rage on
The cold has always been to my liking.
And I run higher and higher
On the icy surface.
And the fears of days gone by
Can't catch up to me
It's time to find out what I can do
I'll call the blizzard for the service
I'll be free on the ice
Forever!
Let it go and forget
The world of your dreams
And there will be no more tears
This is my home
My snowy home
Let the storm rage...
The air sparks
And the ground from my magic.
Frost and ice are in my power
What a marvelous gift.
And now I know how to go on!
I'm not going back
I've got to forget everything
Let go and forget!
And go up in the sky
Let it go and forget
Shine like the polar star
I'll see
My first sunrise
Let the storm rage on
I've always liked the frost