Good Morning.
[kiss voice]
What's going on with the moon?
Sorry grandma. I fell over.
Girl, it's like we're going to make love.
-Repent, repent. -Repent, of course.
[shouting and screaming]
[ani akan su sesi]
Lan!
Lan.
I'm so beautiful.
[refrigerator opens]
[egg drops]
[peppers turn red]
[breaks egg]
[TV turns on]
[voice from the street] Son, we broke a mirror. What cav are you doing?
Don't talk, my son is in front of me. Look, he's still talking.
What's going on?
Shut up. Get your car, walk away.
Look bro. I fly to you.
[shouts] Lan. We're having breakfast, don't shout.
Don't talk girl. You come in.
Son, who are you to park a car in front of my place?
who are you? who are you?
Do you know who I am son? [discussion voices]
Fato, what happened?
Sucu put Tayyar's car there.
Tayyar got angry and broke the mirror of the car.
Pig.
The waterman said, "What did you do?" said.
Tayyar said to the server, "Have a good day, brother." said.
Aysuju said, "Why should I give my right to you, animal?" said,
"Pig." he said, "Dog." said.
Fatma sister,
You're starting to be very rude.
Talk a little decent, decent. Uh, come down.
Let me go, I'll dive into it. Don't hold me, okay, don't hold me.
It's enough for my life, it's enough. Let go. Come man.
-Hold on, hold on. -Come man. Come man.
Shut up. Go away.
Look, he's still talking. Look, you know my opposite.
Rain.
What happened man?
What happened? You were talking. Tosun? Let's have a couple.
-Shst. Tayyar. -Ha?
[your session]
did i get burned?
[Screams] I'm on fire!
Because of you!
You will see, Deliha.
I'm burning.
I don't like unrest in my neighborhood.
You burned the boy's suits. You burned your future, you burned the child.
What would I do, Eve, huh?
They were locked.
Would they slip on each other if I let them, huh?
It wasn't boiling anyway.
Somewhere between boiling and warm.
Already my aunt is my son. I'm getting annoyed. What to you, huh?
Girl Zeliha. Are these dogs? When you say they were locked or something.
-Let him go and we're going, right? -We're going, we're going.
Girl, let me put on some lipstick, I'm ready right away.
I'll tell you, I'll tell you, let's not go.
-Take it out of us, sin is sin. -Put the sin on me.
The sin is on my neck, Eve.
Groove!
I want to think about puppies today.
-What's wrong? - Puppy.
Be downstairs in three minutes.
[draws curtain quickly]
Put it on girl instead.
Oh, I can never wear it.
Look at me, I say plug it. I already have a bad temper.
-So hot. -Don't suck my energy, mom.
I have important work to do today.
-What are you doing? -Special.
- Give me a little money. -No money.
I'll ask your aunt for a loan.
Definitely 40 degrees.
Look at me, we don't have men on our heads.
Going out with a woman like that, oh my.
-I'll throw the slippers on your head, huh. -I swear I'll hang you from the ceiling by your ears.
Shut up girl, that's my word.
You burned the cover again.
The cover is lousy, the cover is.
Mom, your type is so bad huh.
You didn't hit it.
[moving music starts]
Shh granny. I'm getting money, good luck.
Shall I get the face paper?
I got one hundred and fifty.
I'm going to the fortune teller, grandma. I'll take care of you too.
Maybe your luck will come out, what do you know? Ha?
Do not be afraid girl, I will not put you in the ground without a shroud. I will give it back.
Come on, say goodbye.
God bless you grandma.
Come on, I'm out, draw.
[scream]
Mother fell.
[door closes]
[moving music ends]
God, if I get downstairs in ten seconds, I'll find the love of my life. Amine.
Get out!
Ulan yuh be.
[shouts] That's it.
Come on come on come on. Little pace. Let's.
Good luck with.
I am very sorry for them. They fall in love with me more every day.
This is the maniac.
Ya, he he, we fall in love, he.
[throws it with his mouth]
Ah. Are you crazy?
Walk walk, I accidentally hit you.
Ay, I don't like this type of person, I don't like his mother at all.
His mother kicked his mother-in-law out of the house. The woman is on the street.
Thank God his brother came and took it, but that's it.
It's a pity, a pity.
kids.
Enough is enough, should I cut your ball, huh? should i cut it?
What is it that I took from you? Give me that ball quick.
David Brother. Give give.
Give it a go. Come come come.
They say so and so for you in the neighborhood, huh. Get the news.
Come on come on.
-Go on. -Thank you, Zeliha Abla.
[Speaks with a Greek accent] Have a good day, Aunt Efkoptiya.
-You too, crazy girl. -[kissing sound]
-Good morning, Sam. -Good morning.
[November tries to start the car]
-Good morning, Uncle November. -Good morning, baby.
-I bought you a tape, take it. -Thanks.
Thank you.
It will run soon. I will execute.
Let's hope.
- Let it be hours. -Thank you.
Girl Zeliha, "Good luck." isn't he?
There are those who say about health, and there are those who say about hours. Honestly clocks, know them.
-So you're going to open a photographer, huh? -[Ege şivesike] We'll see, good luck.
Yes, I think we will open the last photographer in this period.
my brother! This is our number two.
-Are you number one? -Astagfurullah.
One day it came; "Brother." he said, "I'm going to read photography." said. Look.
"My son, don't go, don't go. A photograph is not something to be read,
Even though we said it was something that was photographed, he didn't listen, he went and read it.
When we graduate, we said, let's open a shop at least so that he can get his bread.
Well, I didn't want a shop.
Also, is the shop thing left? Everyone's hands are ringing with a phone.
Don't put water in, delibas, we talked about these.
It's more warm my son to take the photo, it's more beautiful.
-I feel cold when I look at the screen. -Touching is another thing.
So, so.
-Take a picture of me and let me see. -How is it, brother?
How is it, son? You're going to center it and press it.
[in a low voice] Pull, son, pull. Let me see.
[shutter sound] Retrieve.
How is this a photo?
My five year old nephew does this too. What feature do you have?
Five years old, hey mashallah. Look.
Here it is.
Look at me.
Fortune is very outdated now. Let's have a reincarnation session.
Let me tell you who you were in your previous life.
What a volume to me, what I am.
Tell me about my current love life.
Uff. Very boring.
-Your name? -Zeliha.
Day month Year?
Frontend. March.
One thousand nine hundred and eighty eight. What's left?
-Okay, you just said it. -Also, my zodiac sign is Leo.
-No, fish. -My lion is hafiz.
No, your sign is Pisces. Your Ascendant is Leo, your Moon sign is Scorpio.
[shouts] I'm not a Pisces.
Pisces is emotional, what's emotional about me? Ha? Stupid.
This is retarded.
I can tell you live with your mother and grandmother.
Dad died, he was a truck driver.
You grew up like a man. Your mother is in menopause. Let's go to grandma's head.
And there is no one in your life.
It has never been. You've always been platonic.
You loved, no one else loved you.
-You've always been such a loser. -[surprised] Girl.
He knows this. Look, I'm stuck like this huh.
-A bit like you know. -You're a loser, he told you.
-By Allah, he knows. -Lan, Fatma sister.
I swear I'll blow your nose, huh. It's in everyone over there. Shush.
You are at home.
fortune teller
Even if we don't say we stayed at home, let's say we are selective.
No, your cousins ​​are talking behind your back.
Durdane, right? My aunt's daughter, my cousin.
He has Hashimoto, he can't lose weight.
Shut up. What about us?
You will look at me, my fortune. Haci, you will look at me horoscope.
In a previous life you were a Bedouin in Egypt.
What girl is she?
I can tell you like a boy in the neighborhood too.
Short, baby-faced.
In your previous life
You were one of the warrior amazon women.
You are not very keen on fortune-telling.
Sorry, his information just came. Sorry.
Its.
You make such weird songs. In your previous life
-You threw it. -I'm not interested in horses.
Are you doing it on purpose, huh?
Are you making a fuss? I came to give you fortune-telling.
You will look at me. You will look at me, not at them.
Well, it's not clear what you were before.
What's wrong with me! What am I anyway?
Are we asking him?
Will I fall in love? Ha? Is anyone going to fall in love with me?
How should I know, destiny is destiny.
damn whistle.
Then why did I come here? Ha?
[bangs his hand on the table]
You threw it, you were a butterfly, what the hell?
Tell me who I'm going to fall in love with.
I swear I'll stick my fingers in your eyes, huh.
- Someone who will be very soon. -Who?
A brand new one. You fall in love, and then marriage appears.
Kim? Kim?
It has the letters C, M, L inside.
C, M, L.
-Like Selim? -C, M, L.
-David? -I say C, M, L.
When I'm in love -By God, this job will be done in ten, fifteen days.
[slap sound] Ah.
-There was a fly. -I know, the information has arrived.
Whoa.
Guys, this is the shop.
Clean up now and start shooting.
Brother, is there a dark room or something?
No never.
Everywhere gets light. Brilliant, spacious.
[in a low voice] What am I saying, what is this saying?
Now, the handsome one is Cemil.
Jamal, who is clueless. You're that older brother, aren't you?
[in Aegean dialect] Yes. I'm my brother too, it would be nice if you didn't call me uncool.
Why do you speak with such a dialect and he speaks normally?
My Cemil studied high school and university here. He became urban.
-We stayed in Şirince. -Is it Sirince? I've never heard of it.
How did you not hear? They said that the end of the world will break, but everyone gathered.
-So? Doomsday did not break. -It could have broken, though.
That's where we grow grapes.
Grape? How grape? Black or white?
Green. But nah like that, big.
off. Either the big one is different, the round one is different.
Especially when it's upright like a drop.
Actually, we have a peach, split peach. Aqueous.
Oh man, stop, don't add fuel to the fire, what are you doing?
Of of of.
-Juicy juicy, isn't it a peach? -Of course.
It's like honey.
There are furry lovers, there are hairless lovers.
Although I like both.
-The man adores fruit. -Yeah, of course.
Guys, you guys, come inside and have a look.
[in a low voice] It's okay, it's okay here. OK, this is it now.
Look, you throw a mattress over there, just in case.
No, I don't look for sleep or something like that.
What about sleeping at this age?
To make love.
-Brother, we have no such intention. -Oh, intention is important.
For example, I am always intentional. -Pardon?
I'm saying that the white of the woman will be different. Like grapes.
Brother, is that all here? So where is the kitchen?
There is no kitchen. But there is a counter in the kitchen at my house.
Aha, as much as this shop.
Gee. What are you doing at the counter so much?
I shoot meat.
-Is it unbreakable? -Unbreakable. Even if it breaks, I'll take your heart.
Brother, let's think about it, let's take a look.
I say don't decide before you see the toilet.
Look, I'm showing.
Let's not decide without seeing the toilet. Let's see the toilet.
Look.
Wow, look.
Isn't it very cool? Look.
You go in here, you go out of here. You are sitting here.
You act like a king like this.
We got it!
We got it, we got it. We've been holding on.
Who is C, M, L? Even if it's Hasan, it doesn't have C in it.
-[low voice] It is forbidden to have fortune telling. -Are you out of money?
Haram, haram.
I liken fortune-telling to funerals. You lean your back on the coffin.
Shut up, shut up. You vomit inside us.
Why are we making friends with him? -[whispers] He doesn't have any other friends.
Mom, I'm sad now.
-Zeliha! -Ha?
Girl!
-Look, look, look. -What? What?
OK. Well, it would be better if it was black.
Girl, I'm not saying that, look at the plate.
34 CML. Ana is the love of my life.
[ambulance passes]
Oh, I'm going to fall in love now.
[clicks glass]
[window opens]
Ana!
Uncle is out.
- What's your name, uncle? -Sıtkı.
-Shitki? -Yup.
Come on, walk away.
go go. He also eats the hamburger. Let's.
[window closes]
Tue. Filthy.
-Come on, good luck Cemil Efe. - All right, brother Cemil, this is the job.
I swear, for my brother's sake, brother.
Otherwise, I will not open a shop that will go bankrupt in two days.
-By God, you know, brother. -[emotional music begins]
My moms said, "Open him a shop." said.
"At least he'll have a place to lay his head." said.
-[music cuts] -But if you say
I won't open it, let's go to Şirince.
Uff. OK, whatever.
At least that owner hadn't asked for three months' rent upfront. What was it?
What to do man? He needs cash.
-Let go bro, all of these are dishonest. -I own it, you know?
Born?
The man was kidding us. [laughs]
-Why are you telling me now? -I can't get a commission if I tell you first, baby.
There is no brother. If we give commission or something, we do not keep the shop.
Look, you signed, signature. There is a contract.
[Faik] How relieved.
-It's been empty for two and a half years, huh. - Hop hop hop.
You know, they emptied the shop last week? That's what you were telling me.
Who said that? Did I say?
Wow.
Let's do this bro.
Let's go to bed, brother, over there, you slip on us and relax. What do you say?
-What? -Nothing. No.
[laughs] Nothing, his brother is joking.
Let's go and do our business at the bank.
What are you talking about son? Rudeness.
Brother, just come over for a minute.
Let's stop by somewhere, then we'll go.
[hits my glass]
Efşopşiya Hanım, Efşopşiya Hanım.
[Speaks with a Greek accent] Efpraksia. This is my name.
Okay, what did I say? Didn't I say Efchoopsia?
-What happened to our money? The rent is only a week late.
Look, the next time the rent's late, he has to get you out of the house.
[Greek makes an offer] I will stay. baby.
[speaks Greek]
What are you talking about? Where will I go?
For example, I can have this place demolished and a residence built instead.
-What? -Residence.
-Sounds good, huh. -[bumping sound]
Ah! Delilah!
Not Deliha, my name is Zeliha.
Is this trying to get you out of the house too, Aunt Efkoptiya?
My daughter says I will get you out of the house.
[Speaks with a Greek accent] What do you mean you're going out?
Who are you kicking out of the house bro?
This woman has always been here. No one can take it out.
Why are you talking like that?
To get this woman out of this house, you have to break my death.
Got it, got it?
I'm half the town. Even your house is mine.
If I want I can remove it immediately, but in order.
You make shit.
You will come out. Stupid.
Lan!
[shouts]
[shouting] I couldn't bite!
Don't take it out on the street without a collar. It bites children.
- Let it go, I couldn't quite bite it. Let go! -Shoo!
[screams] You got it.
I hope they take you to the mountain and have it.
I hope you will thank you who came before you.
-Who is this girl, Mr. Faik? -He's the neighborhood idiot.
I like his mother alone.
She's a very genuine girl, it's hard to find such a thing nowadays.
-What? -I hope you squat towards the horse.
I say bank, before closing.
What do you mean squat? Ha?
I read the wrong curse. Let it go.
[car starts]
İt. İt!
Filthy! Leave.
Zeliha. Look, it's gone.
Calm down. Gone. sit down, sit down.
Look, calm down.
Hop! What's going on?
-Don't get involved, bebeto. -[Mumbling] Faik Zelihaları...
Are you going to work from home for an exorbitant price?
Whoa! You don't look like that type at all, huh.
Faik was going to drive Zeliha out of the house.
-Ha. So take it out. - By the way, I'm going to hit your head with this fist.
Thanks to you. Why did you burn me?
It's still burning here and there.
I wish I was cousin with dog instead of you. Disguised as a wife.
Be a little lad and protect your aunt's daughter.
Look at me, speak straight.
Tayyar, be ugly!
[Laughs]
I'm telling you, don't do this, my daughter.
I didn't get my ambition. I'm going to loot this realtor.
Hoot! What's going on?
Whoa!
Whoa.
Who are you? Are you working here?
No, we took over the shop from Mr. Faik.
Which shop?
Well, right here in the square, Foto Neco.
-Photo Neco. -Yeah.
Haa.
Hadji, I had a animosity.
I came to loot the shop. you know
I was going to throw my head left and right. Maybe table-breaking attempts with elbow strength.
Maybe a little flying kick, I don't know.
But you just arrived.
And oh...
... you are very handsome.
Now it would be a shame for you, if I come and wash it again.
Understood.
-What is your name? -Camil.
It's okay, Cemil, see you soon.
[something comes to mind]
-What did you say my name was? -Camil.
[whispers] C, M, L.
[moving music starts]
[your session]
-[moving music cuts] -So?
-I am very pleased with you. -I do not understand?
Shall we go dancing tomorrow afternoon, you, me, the three of us?
-What rope? - Uncle Kadri has a wedding.
Who is your Uncle Kadri? I can't reach you.
Don't you like to dance, huh? I think it's great to be the head of halay.
What?
I will go. I have a vest on the stove, don't let it overflow.
It's done, we've seen it.
[romantic music begins]
Allah Allah.
[Eve] Zeliha?
What's going on?
[music cuts]
-Assalam Alaikum, brother. -Aleykum Selam.
-Where did Faik Abi go? -Faik Abi, very short went to the bank.
-Who is short? Did you say it to me? I say it won't take long.
Oh, you're tall, I'm short. Are you saying that, are you saying that bro?
Come on! My brother Faik Abi will go this far. The event is stunted.
Oh, that's it. You didn't give up, bro.
The event is stunted huh?
[shouting] Camels are tall too!
Camels also have stature.
OK.
No problem. No worries. It's possible.
Look at the neighborhood.
I had a dream last night, I hope it's okay.
Such a lot of horses, they are running.
But I see that they tied cloths to the horses' shoes.
I say moon, how can these horses run with those cloths?
Your fate is tied to the moon.
Shut up girl.
Then the horses see me and start galloping towards me.
I look at the moon when I say they are running towards me.
On the horse is your girl Zeliha.
I'm afraid I'm running back and forth, I'm awake.
-I hope it is good. -What's up.
God, I don't know now. It was not such a strange dream.
God bless the moon. Will your sister or Zeliha fall into the wrong path or something?
Girl Songul, you are making everything worse, my girl.
If I get up, I will tear your face into pieces with the back of my slipper.
My rose.
[laughs] Love it, sister.
If you do this, your husband is right to turn away from you.
Who said it's cold?
You said to Aysel that she was lying on her bottom.
Elder sister!
[surprised] Ay, what? When did I say such a thing?
Girl Aysel called me the other day and said, "My brother-in-law doesn't click on Songul anymore."
"Well, the man is right." didn't you say -Said. Said.
Huh. I also have a witness.
[door closes]
[shouting out of breath] I'm in love.
Tonti, I'm in love, tontim.
Mother! I'm in love, mom.
Aunt, I'm in love, aunt.
Aunt Makbule, get it for me.
Henna engagement wedding, pretty much.
Talk about what you're going to wear at the wedding. Because I'm in love.
Come on horseback.
[takes a deep breath] We need to talk.
I can never look into your eyes.
But I have to say.
baby.
I fell in love with someone else.
Listen for a minute, don't say anything, listen.
We went to the fortune teller. with letters C, M, L inside
He said you will fall in love with someone.
Jamil.
What did I say the first day I pasted you?
I said don't trust me too much.
Here they eat the goods of those who do not eat. Squeeze, squeak, tsk.
No no, you will be happy too.
You will have beautiful loves with other people.
You are already very worn out, the relationship has tired you a lot.
The edges are torn.
Already my grandmother is ashamed that you are looking at her while she is praying.
We always cover your face.
If you don't look, I will do it more easily, don't look at me. Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
[poster tears off]
You only have one eye left.
Bye bye Kenan.
Welcome, Jamil.
Good Morning.
[joyful music begins]
[kissing sounds]
Good morning Tony.
[jumping sound]
[door handle breaks]
[kiss voice]
[ani akan su sesi]
I'm so happy.
[door slams, key falls]
[joyful music ends]
[shouts] Eve. Eve.
Eve.
[glass breaks]
What happened to the moon, Zeliha?
Be downstairs in three minutes.
[neighbor] God.
[cries out loudly] He's gone. Who broke this glass?
Ben.
It's weird when you fall in love, uncle.
So what?
It's weird when you fall in love.
AA. Ill mannered.
-So you want a flat white like that. -Oh, such solid color, white.
Shall I make delicate roses in between? It would be very nice.
Brother, no, no. No pattern needed.
What about such tiny tiny, tiny tiny wildflowers?
-It would be great. -Brother, I'm straight...
What are you objecting to son? Tiny tiny, tiny tiny man lay it out.
Even if it's my grandmother's house, brother, it's a photography studio.
Shall I make rosy pink cameras? The mana will be huge.
Brother, you don't understand, let me explain to you.
You're painting this wall straight, okay?
Look, I don't want this shop job anyway, for God's sake, don't force it.
So we gave up the flower for sure, right?
Hah brother, there are no flowers.
You're going to paint it plain white. It's over, it's gone.
-Bird? -Bird?
There are...
Your bird is not finished. It's not over, your bird, your insect.
-Who is he bragging about? -No, its air is for itself. Uff.
Hişt.
Repentance astaghfurullah.
-Something has happened. -What happened?
-Something happened to you. -No, what happened, what happened?
Why did you run past us like that yesterday?
No, I didn't run. Why should I run?
You talked to a kid inside, and then you ran home.
Is it Jamil?
No. No, no.
My grandmother called. She liked a boy.
He texted the boy. The boy did not answer this.
He said come on to the phone together, he said let's blow.
Don't lie, Zeliha. Tell the truth.
You were impressed by that boy, weren't you? Was her name Jamil?
-Ha? -Camil?
Jamil. C, M, L.
-Mother, is that Cemil? -Who is Cemil?
Ah, it's going.
-Aunt? -Is she an aunt?
-Yes, aunt. -How does he look like Cemil?
So why did you call me?
To get some air.
Come here, there's a place to get some nice weather.
[music starts]
-What are we doing here now? -We're not doing anything, we're getting air.
Why do we look in those directions and get air?
I'm not looking anywhere.
Brother, come on, okay, white. Come on, that's enough.
Ana Cemiller is getting whitewashing done, look.
-Ha. Here is that boy. He's got the shop. -Oh, it was.
-Come on, let's go for good. -No.
Let's not go to his feet, let him come.
I'll say something.
If I touch that leaf, let Cemil say hello. But as a friend.
Ha?
Oh, I didn't.
[sighs]
Brother, where are you looking?
What is he doing?
Son, this girl is a very young girl.
-Who? That bouncing curly, brunette one. -Yup.
Let him go, he's crazy, he's crazy.
I really like it.
-Is he looking? He never looks, he never looks.
-I think you're not telling. -Ya Zeliha, why shouldn't I tell you if she looks?
-Looks, looks. -Swear.
How many times has he looked? Did he look three times or five times?
Did he look like a lover?
Did he look like he was saying come, did he look like he was saying go?
Tell me!
Okay, what did you exaggerate?
I will go and say good luck to your shop. What is there to exaggerate so much?
Allah Allah.
[brush sounds]
Your shop is open.
What do you call a shop?
Where did you find that shop?
Which shop?
Have you ever been in a wedding?
-Mother, what am I saying? -What does that say?
I don't understand what she is saying, but she is a very sincere girl.
I'm Zeliha. We met at the real estate agent the other day.
-I remembered. -We met too.
You know, there was a fight in front of your Greek aunt's house.
-How did you get used to the neighborhood? -Wall.
This neighborhood is good. It is beautiful. Everyone loves everyone.
I have things I don't like.
Our women have entered the menopause.
From carbohydrates, we have slightly wider hips.
Men are henpecked.
My mother also sweats a lot.
He's also from menopause.
My love life is not good.
I've never had a girlfriend before.
Last night, Kenan and I parted ways. We always talk about them.
-I get it, the wall. His hand is a... -It's nice, it's slippery.
It's wet. Paint has been applied there, it's new.
Ha?
Ana.
I say, is there a damp?
God, the face is gone too.
[fake laughs]
No, nothing will happen.
White suits me.
They say it opens.
Like a wedding dress, maybe.
Ha?
Which I think even a shroud would suit me.
[gets angry] What did you do, sister? Have you no respect for art?
- [quietly] Hush, okay. - [shouting] What are you yelling at?
What are you shouting? Nothing happened, what happened?
-Sister, you ruined the wall. -I normally
I'll lay this man on the ground and step on his face.
But now you have just arrived, it would be a shame.
I come and lay it on the ground for a while,
I will walk on it. pu. [spits]
[sad music begins]
-What happened Zeliha, your face is white? -My blood pressure dropped.
No, really white.
-Mother, I'm white. -Why did you purse your lip?
Am I shrunken?
I'm shrunken. It means I'm sad.
Wait, let me call Fatma sisters. Let's meet in the park, let's talk. Is it OK?
[sad music ends]
-[sings playing the organ] - One eye is looking at the ground
One eye looking at the ground
-Brother, you are not allowed to make music here. -Reason?
-You are disrupting the mental health of the society. -I don't go here or there.
What Zeliha?
OK, OK, I'm coming.
Guys, let's speed up.
[moving music starts]
[music ends]
-She fell in love with this boy. -Which kid?
Here's to the kid who's new to the neighborhood. He does not accept whether his name is Cemil or what.
I liken love to frogs' legs. Wet, loose.
Fevzi, stop.
Look, Fatma sister, her hands are painted on the tape from excitement.
Is the child interested in it too?
Sence?
Said the fortune teller. C, M, L said.
It's Jamil.
Fevzi, please shake me.
-Zeliha. -Ha?
-Are you okay? -I'm good.
Is there anything you want to share with us?
No.
-I will ask. -No, don't ask. He doesn't answer.
Zeliha.
Are you in love with this boy now?
[dropping sound] Zeliha!
Did something happen, Zeliha?
No.
Yes, I'm interested in Cemil, I may have fallen in love.
-How did you fall in love right away? -This boy is my destiny.
My destiny. I understand. Also,
she's brunette, i'm blonde. We look incredible.
Of of of.
And I think he loves me too.
We meet eye to eye, I swear
the seas are pierced, the mountains are drying up. Even my mouth is dry.
But no man has ever loved you.
I hope five people will take you to the mountain, huh.
[whispers] God forbid, God forbid, my God.
five people.
Not four, five.
Take a minute to write.
If I stop, I won't be able to escape again.
-Give me some milk, sister. -As if the baby will suckle too. Crazy boy.
Girl yes. Hişt al. Hişt.
Eat! Girl!
I don't want it, grandma.
-Girl, eat. -I won't eat, mom.
I was cut off without eating or drinking. That's what happens when you're in love.
Oh, don't try to kill yourself this time either.
No. This time it's mutual.
Who is the girl?
Jamil.
They took over Foto Neco in the neighborhood. We stare at him.
[Laughs]
Girl, is it okay with a look?
-So hot. -She's a menopausal mom.
How good is the rice?
-Ha? Is it buttery? -[speaks forcefully] Buttery.
I'll take a little.
Fig tree in front of the hospital
The doctor couldn't find me the medicine
mom medicine
[shouts] I'm a young man, I'm the best of a young man.
Did you understand?
Tayyar, Tayyar, are you okay?
-Who is it? -I'm Eve.
Oh beauty.
Girl, I never saw you at night.
-[laughs] Good night, then. -Stop, stop, stop, don't go.
Let me take a look at you.
Girl, are you getting prettier?
As you go, then let me go.
Don't go, don't go, don't go, come Let me kiss you one.
[kiss voice]
Thank you.
Fig tree in front of the hospital
[Zeliha calls out] I saw everything, Eve.
What did you see?
You are my aunt's son. Aha, you became each other's right there.
Not at all. Don't make it up yourself, there is no such thing. He just kissed my cheek.
This idiot kid, don't get to that.
I know her very well because she is related to Eve.
Hush. I'll say something.
Did she kiss wet or dry kissed girl?
Are you dirty, Eve?
[Eve cries]
[cat meows]
Could.
squeak tsk tsk
Well, the opening has come. Cemil Efe.
What opening?
Are we going to make an opening? What are we going to say bro?
"We're those last two idiots, come and take a closer look." shall we say?
Don't be silly. "The certified photographer is here." we will say.
"Art has come to your door, neighborhood man." we will say. Shall we hire a violinist?
Oh man, don't neglect it.
You look and he will come too.
Who is it?
[salesman passes by] Garlic, garlic.
Garlic.
A cure-all for homes. Garlic, garlic.
-Easy, bro. -Here you go.
- Is the microphone allowed? -No, what are you selling?
-I'm not selling anything, I'll make an announcement. -Are you going to propose?
-No, I will call the neighborhood. -Good, come on.
-You're going to talk like that, okay? -I know, I saw it in Zuğurt Ağa.
God bless you. I hope you have nothing to do with the police.
-Amen. - Yes.
Dear residents of our dear neighborhood.
As Foto Neco, we are opening today.
We hope to see you among us on this beautiful day .
Do you want to see us too?
I can hear you saying yes.
A new breath in photography: Foto Neco.
The photo is in our Neco neighborhood.
What did he say, what did he say?
He meant that today is the best day to experience love at the heights.
-What? -Today we will experience love in the peaks.
A pervert.
Take it away, good piece.
[Laughs]
Make a bread break, fold it and eat it.
[violin plays Roman air]
- Brother, is this the violinist? -What do you think? What is it in his hand?
It plays the Roman vibe you know. If he plays something more classic.
My son, why do you find a handle for everything, my beautiful child? We say it will ring.
Brother, is there anything more classic suitable for opening like this?
Of course. Selami Şahin - "I Miss You"
-Really? Lets. -Wonderful.
[violinist starts singing]
What is this?
- Take it easy, Uncle Kasım. -Thanks.
-Brother, where are you looking? -No, my son, I look at it in general.
To see if anyone is coming.
Oops.
Congratulations.
[kiss voice]
-We were like kissing on the lips. -Huh.
This is Fevzi, a dead type. Shake hands, Fevzi.
-Hi there. -Hi there.
-This is Fatma sister, an older sister who stayed at home. -No dear.
I can't say I stayed at home.
Just last month, the fireman came to ask for it, but I did not arrive.
Because it was his third marriage. Shall I look at the old man?
- Should I deal with his prostate? -True. One must be in love.
-Uh huh. -This is Eve. She's a pure idiot, but she's good.
This is Jamil. You already know Cemil.
Cemil is sweet.
Very handsome. Masallah.
-Cemal brother. -My brother.
What a beautiful cat my mother is. Masallah.
He's so handsome, Eve.
Oh, he's pretty handsome.
A butt boy.
He has black eyes.
It's weird when people look at it. Is not it? Ha? His love is coming.
It sounds like she's caressing her hair or something.
On sheepskin in front of the fireplace like this
-naked for hours... -Cemilim.
-We were going to take pictures. -Of course. Sure come on.
[draws curtain]
-Girl Zeliha, but you hit on the child, huh. -No, I didn't.
[in a low voice] Slow down a little, act badly.
Guys don't like girls who jump on him like that.
Let me act wrong, huh?
Come on girl smile, look brother will shoot.
-It's Sisi. -She's probably not in the mood today.
No, he laughs normally.
If it's over, let's get me.
aa aa.
-Come on come on. -Anyway.
-Are you going to take a picture? -Well, I guess. Isn't that your job?
-Come on, blow it up. -Okay, stay a little to the right.
Don't talk to me like you're commanding. who are you? Stupid!
It's a shame, but huh.
Shame on you, let the boat come in.
Check!
[shutter sound]
-Take a bite like that, jerk. -Talk to me properly.
What happened? Has he lost his strength? Pig.
[Roman mood continues with violin]
Allah Allah.
Everyone was here too. You never inform us.
Good luck bro. What are you doing, handing out lemonade?
Here you go.
-Tayyar. -[shouting] What are you doing girl hackberry?
[laughs]
-Last night was beautiful. -Who would go around naked?
I mean last night, you kissed my cheek.
ah? Did I kiss?
[Laughs]
What a man I am. Hush, look.
Look, I tucked the kid in a secluded corner last night.
I don't remember at all.
[Laughs]
Look, I'll kiss you right away, that's it.
-[in a low voice] I'm not justifying myself. -I don't understand what, my dear.
I'm not justifying myself.
Eve, don't joke girl, let's get your right.
[shouting] I'm not halal.
-Despicable. -Come on.
- You bastard. -What's going on?
damn! I will act the opposite. Not you. what's going on huh?
-I acted badly, but I think it was broken. -You didn't give a face, did you?
-I said push. -Did you say push? Whoa!
-Whoa! -You said well, even a little. Dog, asshole.
And all the vile bad words.
Did you put cologne in this lemonade, what did you do?
-Hisht Eve. Is he looking? -He's not looking.
Lan, stop crossing with Tayyar. He won't take you.
A retarded rascal, a scumbag. Keep your eyes on Cemil.
As soon as he looks at me as if to say come, I will go to him, come on.
What are you looking at? Goods.
-Mother, come, he said. - He didn't say come.
I saw, "Come, come." said.
Brother, okay. That's enough, thank you.
[laughs]
What are you doing?
-I swore at you. -What did you do?
I swore.
-Ya baby okay, let's make peace. -Were we offended, I don't understand?
I pissed you off inside.
Hush, my black eyes, my honey lips, my baby. Come here nut.
What are you saying son? Come on, go to work.
Is it my son?
[sad music begins]
Zeliha.
Translate. Turn, turn, turn.
Translate.
-My son told me. -What is there to upset yourself so much?
Shut up, turn it.
He doesn't want me.
-Like the others, "My son." said. -Bad bastard.
Nobody will love me. I will die alone.
-[music ends] -It won't be like that this time, Zeliha.
we exist. Who is he?
What do men think of themselves?
We can also fight if necessary.
Yes?
- We will meet tomorrow morning and start in this park. -What the hell?
-Zeliha movement! -Whoa.
Here we go, Zeliha.
[shouting] If this Cemil doesn't fall in love with you, I'm not Eve either.
Lan started talking this loudly, nothing got in it, huh?
-We see it, we watch it on the news. -Shut up and listen.
Plan one: You will go where Cemil went. You're going to pretend it's a coincidence.
"Aa? Aa, were you here too?" like. -OK.
[moving music starts]
-What's up, Cemil? -Is good.
Don't worry, I'll go out in a sweat.
Good luck with.
Thanks.
What's up, Cemil?
Look, we were coming to the same barbershop. Do you see? Coincidence.
Cavit Abi, I'm going to get those eyebrows removed too.
Shoot it there. God damn.
[the sound of the football game comes from the TV]
Hello.
-What's up, Cemil? -Is good.
Come on, cut the middle, cut the middle.
Come on dad. Come on dad.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
[in unison] Goal!
Helal be.
Didn't I tell you
that you will go places to go together, woman and man?
How can I know?
I'm already in the game, I forgot the kid.
You are going to the movies or something.
Eat corn.
Eat eat. Very nice.
What are you doing?
[smacking corn]
God God!
[moving music ends]
[the bagel maker passes]
It didn't happen. It didn't work.
Look, you got it in his head. You got it in his head.
Now you will surprise him, you will get his attention.
You will do things that you never expected. -Things he never expected, huh?
What!
[torpedo explodes]
Hello.
That's scared!
I couldn't. It is not happening.
Jealousy.
You will envy him.
Great, smile.
Jamil.
Sir?
Who is this?
Aunt? I do not know.
I don't want you seeing other women ever again. what's wrong with you?
Hush, look girl. Don't come to the shop like this and pose for the boys,
Is it good to throw smiles or something?
-What is it, girl? - Stop pretending.
Your eyebrow is playing, can I eat these?
I know people like you well.
Talking sexy like that and hunting guys and stuff.
Whoa, what are you after?
What are you saying? Get out.
Exit!
Aysel.
Your girl also cooked with the painter, huh?
They met secretly at night.
Look at me. The boy used to be a draper.
It went bankrupt after that.
Me.
He was from Adana, he had kebab shops.
I heard that they are doing very well in the country.
He was going to lock Zeliha at home.
He also beat me up saying you're going to have three sons with me. either.
Guys, where do you get these things from? No Such Thing.
The girl just said, "I like the boy." said she, that's it.
This was good for everyone when he was little.
Mom, what are you saying for God's sake?
Ay Pazarcı said, "Sister," she said, "the wedding," she said, "They will hold it in Adapazarı." said.
"Aysel sister," she said, "I'm from Adapazarı.
That's why my daughter will get married there," he said.
Girl Ayten. Am I not Aysel?
Am I from Adapazari?
I don't know, the marketer said.
It's best to go and ask the boy about it.
What is this, my dear, everyone has become a gossip.
I don't like such things. Get up. Get up.
[together] Get up. Get up.
[shutter sound]
-Where are you from, my child? -I'm in Şirince.
-Your father just got out of prison, huh? -Is he a prisoner? No dear.
-So you're single? -Yup.
-How single are you? -I do not understand?
-Have you met, talked to? -Is it from this neighborhood?
Don't play around like that, own it. Will there be a bass wedding right away, my child?
Not without marriage.
We were young too.
I'm not saying don't. But name it. Family is very, very important.
Certainly.
Come on, my child, take our photos.
[shutter sound]
Get close to his family.
Get on well with them.
-Lan's family is not here. -He has an older brother.
-Ha, he has a brother. -What was his brother's name?
How can I know.
I don't know, just spend time with his brother. Love yourself.
No time will pass with that loser.
[calm music begins]
[music ends]
[tram sound]
Wow!
This is Taksim Square, huh?
Ha, bad.
Good thing you invited me, Zeliha. I couldn't have fun if I came alone.
-Mother, look at the birds. -[music starts]
[Birds fly]
-[music ends] -Where do you get these words from girl?
Wait, there's something in your hair.
-Ay Zeliha, I had a lot of fun. -[With Aegean accent] I had fun too.
Those birds and stuff went over us beautifully, didn't they?
-But we saw how much they would get dirty. -You're talking like we're from there.
-Aha, we're here, our house is here. -Hey, okay.
OK.
-Do you like taking pictures? -Hey, I love it so much.
like this
-I love you more if he is a beautiful person. -Ha.
[Eve shouts]] Zeliha!
Mine have arrived.
Thanks.
Say hi to Cemil.
Tell us what we did.
-You know, he's your brother. -Of course it will. Good evening.
What are you doing there, in the apartment?
We were waiting for you. What happened?
-What, what happened? -What happened with Cemil's brother?
What happened?
We had fun.
-Your mouth is in your ears. -Indeed.
Me.
I had fun, after all, he's his brother.
It seems to me that her brother is looking at you differently.
As if.
He is my mother-in-law, my mother-in-law.
my brother-in-law.
Was it my mother-in-law? What was it?
But what do they call this mother-in-law?
Whoa!
Don't be silent, I'm scared.
-Something superfluous has happened. -What happened?
Isn't there a Velev Bar in Beyoğlu? This is live music.
How will we know?
I'm an old bartender, we used to go. There is also live music.
I will sing there tomorrow night.
The owner of the place "Come, let's try, let's listen." said.
How nice. be happy. Be what you always wanted.
-I don't think it's right for people to be happy. -Let's go, let's go, let's sell the mother.
Zeliha, what are you going to do? Tomorrow you will call Cemilleri, this is a good opportunity.
We will succeed. God help us. disperse!
Let's break up.
-Good job. -Thanks. Welcome.
This will sing at Velev Bar in the evening, and you can support.
-So it's not really necessary... -Of course, what does it mean?
If we're going to support, we'll come for sure. I'll take Cemil as well.
-Come on girl, we'll have a lot of fun. -If we're going to have a lot of fun, we'll definitely come, girl.
What are you doing?
What should I do, Cemil didn't want it. I howl at each other at the photos.
He.
Actually, if you squat that bride and put the groom on her back.
It seemed to me that something much sweeter would happen, don't suck.
I swear I will do that, you know? Our tastes are unbelievably similar.
Now you need to do a very natural make-up.
Far.
I've never driven before.
Whoa.
Whoa. I wish I had driven.
Blusher. two poofs
I think that's enough.
Whoa.
Whoa. I'm so beautiful.
I'm pretty good. Jamil.
Hello. I've never kissed anyone before.
But I will kiss you.
Girl! [kiss voice]
What are you doing? Are you kissing the mirror?
I have. Me.
My grandmother was fond of a boy. The boy wanted to kiss it.
My grandmother didn't kiss me.
The child made a trip to this, my grandmother left.
Born?
I say my grandmother didn't kiss me.
They are separated. My grandmother is crying inside.
Their relationship is over. So my grandmother found it early, so she didn't get kissed.
You go kiss.
Come on, I ran.
[They play horon with overalls]
- Fatma sister, what are you doing? -Girl Zeliha.
At my friend's wedding, the horon kicked in.
I couldn't get over it either, because I was overweight.
It stayed inside me.
I said, now I'm at least weak, let me shed my worms.
Either walk, walk.
Walk.
Come on.
-We'll go inside. -Is there a reservation?
-No. -You are not very suitable here, my sister.
But we have to go inside, brother.
Let's go, my sister. Come on, don't bother me. Let's.
İdris.
-Girl, isn't this Idris? -Who is Idris?
Ay, aren't you the son of Aunt Sevcan?
[kiss voice]
I can't hurt you.
You've grown this much and you're waiting at the gates?
Well done, work well. Earn your bread.
Say hi to your mom for us too.
Fly fly.
I'm not Idris.
[loud animated song plays]
This is a very warm, fun place, huh.
Well done, Fato. How did you know the boy?
I don't know girl. I said number.
But there is an Idris I know.
I don't like her mother at all.
The woman comes to the day, what's up, she secretly puts it in a napkin
then it was gone.
Ayol once stole a towel. One also says
The boy took out a sty and says I bought it from him.
Look. Look. Look. When a sty comes out, copper is stolen from the house.
This towel says this as an excuse. Ill mannered. Dense.
We never listened to you.
[in a low voice] Zeliha, I'll tell you, I'll tell you.
It's an environment I'm afraid of. Why did we come here?
You came for your friends, Eve. My elderberry. The future of Fevzigil.
What happened? Get out now.
No, what happened to the brave warrior, huh?
Tayyar slapped you girl, let me remind you.
[loudly] You reminded me and you were right.
Fevzi.
Hello.
Ayy, Fevzi. Can I drink beer?
I'm sick of it, it's so cold, cold.
Drink it, Fato. Let's unwind a little today.
-Here you go. -One beer.
One beer.
-I'll have an apple juice, my volume. -One apple juice.
-I'll have a little tea. -A tea.
[boss whistles]
Fevzi Bey, you can go on stage.
[reads quickly] A beer, a tea, a water, apple juice.
Whiskey Coke, 2 beers, one raki.
-Come on quick, come on. -Ulan, say it slowly.
Whiskey with cider? Who is drinking these?
[cheers]
Death is blowing in my face
Oh, uncle loved me so much.
My shroud is tatty
Oh, what a bitter apple juice. But it was good, it was nice to drink.
I carved your name on my coffin
-What are we doing here? -Our friend is on the stage, son.
- Come on, die with me . -Aha, the crazy girl is here too.
Is it called crazy? Rude. Hello.
Has it been out long?
come on die with me
The stage looks better from here, doesn't it?
Yes.
Whoa.
I touched your leg. It was warm. Is love labor?
Girl Zeliha.
I think you should sing too.
He is very impressed.
Are you saying so?
I carved your name on my coffin
-My brother, if you go there? -Make your brothers laugh.
Enter Fevzi. "Always Later."
[Fevzi starts playing the song]
[cheers].
I felt like singing a song.
Come to my love.
He knows himself.
Neither you are Leyla nor I am Majnun
Neither you are tired nor I am tired
We drank on a sad evening
we are drunk This is everything
- You are neither Leyla nor Mecnun - Brother, I ran away.
Neither you are tired nor I am tired
We drank a sad evening, we were drunk
This is everything
My mind always comes later myself
always later, later
always later
Long live my beautiful. You are super.
My mind always comes later myself
-Does it bother you? - always later
You are amazing, my beautiful.
-Long live my beautiful, long live. -It's just that the lady is bothered.
But wait a second, the lady is bothered.
-What's going on with you? His wife is on her way to me. -Who is the wayward rude man?
Ana, there was a fight.
Mother, a fight broke out.
-What are you doing? break up. -Let me go, I'll kill you.
[shouts]
-Zeliha. -Ha?
You're going to hold it to your eyebrow, not your mouth.
I'm holding your eyebrow, Eve.
It's a shame they beat it so much.
-Your voice is beautiful, Zeliha. -Oh.
Why did you fight?
I was afraid something would happen to you. -I'm a boy girl. I protect myself.
No. You don't need to protect yourself when you're with me. I protect you.
Reason?
[slurping sounds]
Actually, you're a good boy too, huh.
You are kind hearted.
I can call you a man to fall in love with.
No man has ever loved me, you know?
But I think very soon I will be loved.
I think so too.
-I loved you very much. -Me too.
Hoop soup man, is your soup hot?
Aa bebeto came, huh.
Aaaaa.
-Deliha'ylan ekürisi. -Deliha sensin lan.
Hush girl Eve.
Even if you give me justice for the sake of that soup maker
I wish I could sleep well even if I go. Ha?
-I do not. -It doesn't. Even if he does, I won't.
[whispers] Look. Look. Now look.
Hişt Tayyar.
Let's be an ugly.
I'm telling you, girl, don't do this. Do not do this.
What do you smell girl?
Zeliha, you are currently drinking garlic instead of soup.
Ana.
Whoa.
But can I say something?
It had a sharp taste.
It's not that bad.
Ana.
It felt like something was happening to me right now.
What happened to you?
Eve brought me the quintet of hearts. What happened to you, huh?
Then let the song that is playing now come to all of us.
What's your name, what's your name...
His blood pressure dropped.
[Laughs]
Get up girl, get up. Can you sleep until these hours?
-What happened? -Faik sent an executive paper.
He was going to kick us out of the house. Now he sees that day.
Hush stop. Don't go to the woman. I will come too. They kidnap.
What does this room smell like?
Garlic.
-Look at me, Faik Efendi. -Tell me, my smile.
Are you seriously kicking us out now, huh?
What if we don't talk about this in front of that crazy guy?
-We rent you. -You don't give what you have to give, my rose.
-You have no right to kick us out of the house. -The house is mine, you know?
But don't worry. First, I will take out Mrs. Efşopşiya.
After that, I'll take you out. Be comfortable.
Aysel.
And did I ever tell you about my widow fantasy?
Ill mannered.
Hisht bana bak bana.
Well, you know my realtor fantasy?
Let me explain.
Now three steed-like men throw you in a car and take you to the mountain.
They find a big tree on the mountain.
That's how they tie you down.
While you look with your groaning eyes, don't do it brothers
they don't hurt at all, they pull their pants down.
-Go girl, walk. -Then when you say ah woah...
-I will explain it to you practically. -I'm telling you to walk, walk.
-Pompish. -Okay, walk.
Yeah yeah. Come without wasting any time, mother. We want a girl for me tomorrow.
Born?
I'm in love, mom.
I will marry.
Yes, the girl is beautiful.
I don't know the shoe size, mom. Skip it, it's tomorrow. Lets.
Let's kiss. Lets.
What's going on bro?
Son, we want Zeliha for me tomorrow night.
-Who, that crazy girl? -Don't say that, son.
So sweet girl. Very brave girl. I love you so much.
Are you sure bro? He didn't seem very interested in you, though.
It didn't seem like that to you though.
What did he say while singing last night?
“He knows himself.” He looked at me. said. I know myself.
-Good bro, if you're sure. -I'm sure of course.
We will be very happy, son. Don't get involved. Let my mothers want it tomorrow, let it be over.
-Good luck. -Let's see, I hope.
Come on, go home. Close the door too.
who are you? Ha?
Who are you to kick us out of the house? Stupid!
Dirt.
Ugh. Everything is coming together.
-What's going on, Zeliha? -Faik kicks us out of the house.
Cemil is not interested in me. I remained like Malak.
Whoa. I guess I'll be a winemaker. It's all over.
I love these flavors.
Hello. How are you Zeliha?
What happened to your mother's face?
-Girl, there was a fight yesterday and they beat me. -I don't remember at all.
I will say something.
We say that we will come to you for a good job tomorrow evening, as a family.
Should we come?
-To who? -To you?
-Is it for a good deed? -Yup.
-Is it family? -We said so.
-What time shall we come? - Come around eight, I think.
Like eight. Okay, done.
Whoa. He sent word with his brother.
-Whoa. -I wonder?
I wonder if what I'm afraid is not happening to me. This is Cemil's brother.
- Don't you get burned by Zeliha? -Hush girl.
[car approaches]
Shall I take you for a walk on the beach?
-Uncle Kasım, is your car running? - That lad fixed it.
-Which lad? -The lad in the photo studio.
The most handsome and kind hearted man in the world.
He's coming to ask for me tomorrow night. Whoa.
[joyful music begins]
[joyful music ends]
-How are you? -We're fine, you?
Thanks. Good.
-How are you? -Thanks. You?
We're fine too, thanks.
-How are you, my son? -I'm fine thanks. You?
I'm fine, fine. Are you my child?
Thanks, I'm fine too. Thanks a lot, you?
-I am fine too. -Masallah.
-You're fine too. -Thanks.
-Very good. You? -Everybody is fine.
[turns on tv]
When the sexual intercourse between rhinos is over
male rhino falls to the ground.
[they cough]
This sexual intercourse, which is now rare,
makes rhinos tired.
Our grandmother always watches such documentaries.
[laughs]
Ha?
what do you say mom?
My Zeliha, make us coffee if you want.
Yes, of course.
My God, I am so happy.
Eve, I am so happy.
I eat you girl.
Look, you'll end up marrying whoever you want.
Zeliha, I'm going to say something.
-I wonder if this is Cemil's brother... -Havva stop.
Look now, I'm going to hold my hand to the fire. If I hold on for five seconds, we will marry Cemil.
Which is already obvious.
One two Three.
Whoa.
I couldn't stand it.
Why did that happen?
Tayyar, go.
[whispers] Tayyar, go.
Girl shut up. Did we come to you? Gee!
-Eve. -Go, Tayyar.
-Have a right to Eve. -Don't, Eve.
Well, if you make your right, I won't give you my right.
Hişt Fact. Fact.
Are we putting salt or pepper on this Cemil's?
They came to ask for me three times. I put salt in all three of them, salt.
Oh, I'll put pepper then.
Well, auntie, did someone you know die recently?
Me.
You also have a dead energy.
Allah Allah.
Well, we came here in such a hurry, don't suck.
Our boy insisted.
good luck.
So you shouldn't be in a hurry, sucking.
Here the children loved and liked each other.
-Our Zeliha is also a good girl. -Yeah yeah.
If you spill, I'll piss on your mouth, huh.
Zeliha. What are you doing?
[laughs] Oh girl.
Thanks girl.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Health to your hands.
[in a low voice] Sir, I don't want this girl.
This is something crazy. Let's get out of here reluctantly.
Is there such a thing? We've come this far.
The child loves it.
[in a low voice] I love it.
-Sorry. -[mother coughs]
-Halal, halal mother. Halal. -Give it, bro.
Sir, the children loved each other. -We loved it.
We are here to fulfill our duty.
With the command of Allah, with the words of the prophet
We want your daughter Zeliha for our son Cemal.
Ha? Is it Jamal?
Cemil, my uncle Cemil, is divine.
-No, my cousin. to Cemal. -No, Cemil.
Daughter, the older one is Cemal. The little one is Jamil.
Is there such a thing? to Cemil.
I did not understand. Is Cemil's name Cemal?
Okay, we are making love with Cemil, brother.
Born?
What does it matter?
One minute, one minute. I don't understand now.
Who do you want Zeliha for?
We want me.
Zeliha!
[Laughs].
-I wasn't even going to laugh. -Shst. Shush.
Maybe there is a misunderstanding then.
One minute, one minute, one minute.
What am I doing with you, are you crazy girl?
[arabesque music begins]
[tray falls noisily]
Get out.
[arabesque music ends]
I've never seen anything like this. What rude people.
says Jamil.
Son, didn't you say we were in love?
I misunderstood.
Don't worry about it bro. The girl is an idiot, a maniac.
I told you, didn't I? You went and believed it naively.
What's wrong with you, what's wrong with you?
What's it to you? I loved, I gave my heart, I wanted what to you?
-Abi! -Abi, abi ya.
I am your brother.
I'm going to love one girl, and you're going to talk about her back and forth?
You don't get it, you're naive, it's easy to fool you.
Enough, enough.
I have loved only one girl in my life.
He didn't, what can I do?
I'm the one who's in trouble.
Let him think, it's a way to be left to me.
Brother, okay, I'm sorry.
It's time to commit suicide for Zeliha.
If you don't, girl?
-Did I drown? -[all in unison] Get out.
Get out!
Zeliha.
My daughter.
[door closes quickly]
Zeliha! Zeliha, open the door, girl, open it.
I will kill.
I will kill myself.
Is this okay? Can this be done to me?
Zeliha, don't scare us.
Go. Go from here.
leave me alone.
I will die alone.
I will die in peace.
Whoa. I'm on the verge of death, man. Whoa.
Aysel Aunt, this time she will kill herself.
What an aunt. You are the aunt. I am the same age as you.
-Come on, trust God. -[water runs into the tub]
Oh my blood pressure has dropped.
I'm upside down, mom.
Help, help.
Oh, I can't die.
I'm hanging myself.
I'm dying too.
Fevzi! Come put this on.
Open up.
[door opens loudly and key falls]
-Am I dead? -[all in unison] Get out.
I'm going to throw myself out the window.
-[yelling] -Get out.
Hard.
Don't do it Zeliha.
[jumps into the hall]
Is the moon dead?
I do not think so.
What are you looking at?
Look at me. Who cured me, huh?
I wanted to die.
I will try to kill myself again.
I can't, I don't want to live.
[phone rings].
Sir Makbule?
Are we sobered, Mrs. Zeliha?
I don't know, let's see if we are sober?
-Ha? Doctor. -Sorry.
If I shoot you fifty lira
Could you add a drop of cedar to this solution?
-Is it serum? -He.
Live long, huh?
[laughs, imitating the doctor]
damn! Are you kidding, huh? We're asking a serious question here.
I'll break your hippopotamus oath. Stupid!
Zeliha. Faik was getting Efpraksia out of the house. He's executed.
There are three or four chairs there, is that on the record?
You too, like that. Okay, done.
We're only going to buy that chair, too, unfortunately, Mrs. Efşopşiya.
-It's just a shame what you did, Mr. Faik. -What's wrong with you, son?
Putting the old woman in front of the door...
Dude, wait a minute, I'm talking bullshit. Wait a minute.
Does it suit you to put the old woman in front of the door?
Honey, look, don't get involved in things that are not your business.
- Go take a picture. - Put that hand down, that hand...
What the hell, are you going to beat me up?
[Zeliha shouts]
Aha! Deliha has arrived.
Who the hell are you kicking out of the house?
Look, speak right.
I don't have a hangover, I hurt all over.
Don't make me beat yourself up.
Well done last night, you know?
-Aha! He took the key to the jeep. -[jeep unlocked]
Girl, Deliha!
-Girl, come here! Deliha! -[Jeep unlocks]
Look, girl, it's a shame. Give me the key, come on, Deliha.
Hey Deliha!
My daughter.
Gel al, gel al.
-Leave. Girl what are you after? -[laughs from the neighborhood]
-Do you give the house or not? -I'm not giving, I'm not.
Tear off your pants, guys.
damn! Stop, stop, stop. OK, OK, OK. stop.
What happened, Iffet, are you scared?
My Deliha, my dear, my sweetheart, let's talk. Come on, lower the glass.
Samim!
Whoa! damn!
-Okay, okay, I gave the house. -Shout for the whole neighborhood to hear.
Okay, I'm giving the house, I'm giving it.
-Scream more. -Efşopşiya Hanım, the house is yours.
It's not Efchopsia, it's Efkoptia.
Efkoptiya Hanım, the house is yours.
[cheers]
Thanks.
[laughs] God! What a happy day.
Do you give your right to Eve?
-No. -He says no.
So you tried to kill yourself, huh?
[Speaks with a Greek accent] That's it. I don't want to live.
What do you mean wanting to kill yourself vre pedimu?
You are a young girl, my dear.
But everyone saw vre pedimu.
Cemil was in love with me. She was slowing down, wagging her tail.
Well, his brother wanted you.
Yup. Sly dog.
baby look.
-You made a mistake somewhere. -Where exactly did I do it?
You may not see someone who truly loves you.
You may not notice.
But maybe his brother loved you.
No, nobody loves me. Nobody loved me.
maybe you
You chose the wrong man. What do you say?
-I'm thinking. -Think about it, though.
[downloads shutter]
No where?
Mind your business bro. Let's.
We're going to the country. To Şirince, to the wedding.
Is that so?
Come on, let's treat God.
Bye bye, bye bye.
Forgive me. Thanks for everything.
Good job. Let's clear your way.
Thanks.
Hush, what happened?
They were going to Şirince for their wedding. He would not return again.
Girl Sevim what happened, what happened?
This is Cemal, he was getting married.
Dressed so cutely, they were going to their hometown.
"I won't be going back ever again." said.
What is it?
Because of his sadness, Cemal was going to his hometown and had a lightning wedding with a cute girl.
subscription!
Eve.
Hush girl, Eve.
-Come on, make it right. -I do not.
Tayyar shut up. I'm thinking.
Zeliha girl, look what the young man left you.
-Which lad? - The one who fixed my car.
-Camil. -Not Cemil, Cemal.
Is it Jamal?
Let's see what Cemal sent.
Yeah, now I'm wondering too.
[tears the package]
"I've always seen you like this. You are the sweetest girl in the world.
Have a nice trip. Jamal."
-This boy loves you. -Does she like it?
Of course she does, Zeliha, don't you see? look at it.
But no man has ever loved me.
I do not know how to be loved. How can I understand?
Who would love you, for God's sake? Take a look at this type of person first.
Tayyar.
Do you know why I'm annoyed with you?
He?
Because you always make fun of me like that, "Look at your look." you say.
[emotional music begins]
Would I want to be like this? Ha?
When I was little, they dressed me in your little ones.
I've always traveled like a man.
"Mom dress." I said, "No money." said.
You still laugh at me.
Oh Zeliha.
"Do you have a problem?" Did you ask, huh?
I do not have a father. My father is dead.
I thought if I became like a man, maybe I would protect my mother and grandmother.
Zeliha, I'm sorry, I never thought of it that way.
Men always called me my son. He said my haji. said Rambo.
They also said memati.
Hey, let me shit myself.
None of them liked me either.
Whoa.
Am I now missing the man who loved me first and only?
[emotional music ends]
All because of that goddamn fortune teller. I turned to the wrong person.
He said it had the letters C, M, L in it.
Whoa.
Jamal. C, M, L.
There are C, M, L in Cemal too.
Jamal. [moving music starts]
Zeliha!
Sketches!
[moving music ends]
Mother, the door is locked.
They went to the wedding.
Did they go to the wedding?
This Cemal has thrown himself on the road from sadness.
He used to have a lightning wedding with someone else.
Did Yıldırım go to the wedding ceremony?
-Where is it? They said in the hometown, in Şirince.
-Whoa. It means Jamal is getting married. -Come on, girl Zeliha, we'll catch up.
No, how are we going to go, Fatma sister.
Let's jump.
Uncle November.
[joyful music begins]
Go on.
What happened, what happened?
This crazy Zeliha and Cemal escaped.
They became each other at night. Now they had to marry.
Born?
Girl Aysel, they defiled Zeliha. He went to marry.
Let's go mom. Let it go, let it go. You open the window.
Open the window, it's too hot.
The moon is very hot.
[Speaks with an Aegean accent] Wow wow wow, who do I keep seeing?
-Did you know me? -I didn't know.
Aren't you Cemal, the son of our Nesrins?
I am an aunt.
Didn't you know yet, couldn't you figure it out?
No, sorry I couldn't make it out.
Just give up, Jamal. You used to come when you were little
"Aunt Hatce, what beautiful breasts you have." you would go hand in hand.
-You couldn't get it out again? -I didn't know.
-When are you getting married? -I won't get married, I don't think so.
Look at me, so many beautiful girls, bitches are coming here tonight.
Like one of them, I'll take care of you right away.
It's possible.
Look what I'll say.
From now on, you will lie on your wife's nipples.
You fall asleep playing it. He has no name.
Brother, they want to have a photo taken in the village.
I've been shooting since morning, I'm tired, you go.
Am I a photographer son? Go get it yourself.
Brother, come on, you'll lose your mind. Besides, our cousin's wedding should be a gesture of ecstasy.
Give good.
Thank you, Aunt Hatce.
-If you had stopped, I just found you. -I will take a photo.
Hush, come and go like this, you. sit down, sit down.
Or are you Cemil, the youngest son of the Nesrins?
-He is me. -Did you know me?
-I didn't know. -Am I not your Aunt Hatce?
When I was little, you used to come to my breasts, hand in hand.
-Oh really. -You still didn't know?
-No. -Tawba astaghfurullah, repentance.
How long is Uncle November left?
Whoa. It's rude.
[in a low voice] I'll tell you, I'll tell you, blasphemy is a sin Zeliha.
what's going on? Eve!
I'm printing Zeliha, I'm printing.
The girl had come to ask for me tee three years ago.
This Aunt Feryal had a nephew.
If you see him wearing such a tie, his bottoms are always filthy.
Of course, when I saw this, I was disgusted, I said abo.
-Give Eve her right. -I do not.
Oh, if he does, I won't.
If this Cemal gets married before I go, I swear I'll kill myself. Whoa.
Whoa. There's something inside all of you.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Something happened to me.
Oh thank god.
damn! My dear Kasım Uncle is me.
Damn, something happened to all of you in my dream.
You were dressed as a wife, I swear.
I'm telling you man. Wake up, wake up, what sleep is this, what?
Finally. [tire bursts]
[brake sound] What's going on?
Uncle November?
The tire burst.
And. Lastik be.
Like you...
Get off.
Whoa.
It was old, of course.
-There is no spare. -What do you mean, grandpa?
We're going to the wedding. We can't be late.
Whoa! I'm done.
I will die unloved.
Okay, okay, calm down. I'll take care of it.
Girl Zeliha.
Our Dürdanes also bought cars. 2002 model.
Did you know they threw an air on the moon?
They were going home for the holidays. You hold the car, stay on the road.
-Fatma Sister. -Here you go, my rose.
[shouting] Shut up.
Come, come.
-Well done, Tayyar. Walk. -What a beautiful month, we'll go wide, girl.
Uncle November.
-You take care of yourself, don't you? -I'll see, baby, I'll see.
Take care.
I will name my child Kasım, Kasımcan.
Gel.
November bro.
Whoa.
-Selamun aleykum. -Aleykum Selam.
Welcome.
Hello guys.
[slogans] Goz Goztepe. Eye Eye Goztepe.
Eye Eye Goztepe. Eye Eye Goztepe.
Let's see, let's laugh together. Today is the happiest day.
Yup. [shutter sound]
It was very nice. The classics are over, shall we move on to the concept?
[With the Aegean dialect] It's okay, let's move on.
God, come on girl. How eager are you?
Come on, grab Nusret's tie then pull it off.
[shutter sound]
This was the best. It is clear that we will walk from here.
Come on, come on girl, the whole weight of the house is on your shoulders, think like that.
Get on top of it, Nusret.
It was great, change places immediately.
Come on girl, get on top of it.
My sister-in-law, who resents this, pinches the bride's neck.
Still, they're taking your son, don't let go of your arm.
-Is this what happens in Istanbul? -Of course, it's the latest fashion.
You are the eldest in the family. Open your arms like an eagle and put your weight on it.
-Brother Ibrahim, you were idle. -Abo.
You found it yourself. Come on, well done. "I never want to see it." gaze.
It was very nice. Shall we build a tower?
All right, let's do it.
Yes, now the bride is running away and you are chasing them together.
No progress, brother-in-law, stay put. Just let the arms play.
Well done see, keep the wicked expression.
masterpiece. The concept is: The bride is dead.
Nusret is in rebellion. The family is devastated.
Come on.
Die, beautiful girl.
Yup. Nusret, rebel, my son.
Hanife, why are you miserable, my beautiful girl?
You are my sight. But you have to be happy.
Come on, let's.
My aunt, let me see the crocodile tears, yes.
Brother İbrahim, you don't have any respect for me, but have some respect for the dead.
Come on, please take your position.
-Abo. -Hah, well done.
Unbelievable.
When I was 19, I fell in love with a handsome, tall boy named Kadir.
Whoever came to ask because I'm in love with him, I didn't face anyone for five years.
Wow.
Then they said he was old.
So children, Kadir ate my life and my youth.
You are the killer of my youth, Göztepe.
You are the killer of my youth, Kadir.
[in unison] Shame on you. Shame on you Kadir.
Then for Fatma Abla, for love.
[they chant together] Oooooo!
Prophet Moses, holding the staff Hu in his hand, I drank wine.
I'm sorry, sad, sad.
Oooooo!
!Şş!
One two Three.
[applause] Goztepe. Goztepe.
Lay laylay laylay laylay laylayaay. Goztepe'sin.
Crumble, crumble, crumble. Police, police, police.
Get down, we'll search, guys.
Only officer, we do not have such a trust.
I decide it, my dear.
-Who are you? -We are your hooligan.
Hadi ya.
Revolt against your regiment, out of spite, Göztepe commissioner.
Let me go, my sister, for God's sake. Come on, come on. Let's.
Get down guys. Let's.
[moving music]
Where are they going?
I understood everything, but what is this tuff?
It's not ours, officer.
-Who's? -I do not know.
[tractor works]
Female hooligans.
Start, start, start the car.
[siren sound]
Whoa. They came.
I will rot in jail before I get my love.
I am like an unopened package, I am like a rose bud.
Our load is too heavy, we cannot accelerate.
- Let's throw the watermelons. -Yes, let's do it.
Watch out, watermelon. Watermelon, be careful.
No.
Many sins. Don't throw it away, it's a blessing.
True.
-I'm slowing you down. -Don't be ridiculous, Fatma Sister.
Get your right.
[shouts]
[siren sound]
Ana, he fell.
Thank you, Fato.
I will never forget this kindness.
Nothing will happen to him, don't be afraid. He will find a way. Go ahead.
Ay, ay, ay.
What are you doing, my sister?
-Idris? -Yup.
Aren't you the son of Aunt Sevcan? -Yup.
Sevcan Aunt is our day friend.
Well done to you, well done. Did you become a cop and come to save me?
Come come. Moon. Come.
Ismail is my time, come on, let's save this one, come.
[tractor sound]
You get off here.
I will go back. I will leave this, and I will look at Fatma sister and come.
-How? -How about what, girl?
We can't get enough of that anyway. You get off, go to the wedding, I'll come and find you. Let's.
Eve, halal...
Anyway, okay.
We'll do something, let's say thank you.
Come on, what are we going to do, how are we going to go?
We don't have money, we always gave it to gas.
We will ask for a car.
It's not enough to beg.
In movies or something, sexy women spread their legs like this and hitchhike.
Eve.
-Hello, we are going to Şirince. -Good jump.
I'm dirty.
I will never forget this kindness, Eve. Come on, get on.
[wedding music and applause sounds]
You, Mr. Nusret Baldemir, Ms. Ayşe Demir, with your free will...
Oh my god, please don't get married.
-...do you accept? -Yup.
Based on the authority given to me by the Mayor of Selçuk
I declare you husband and wife. You can kiss the bride.
Kiss! Don't kiss, stop.
-Who is this girl Nusret? -I don't know, my love.
Oh, who are you? Where is Jamal?
Who is Jamal, Nusret?
My uncle's son, my love, had taken our pictures.
Aha there.
OK, you can kiss.
[clapping sounds and romantic music]
Jamal.
Welcome.
Why did you come?
I brought you this.
I made it for you.
Cemal, I didn't realize that you loved me.
-I couldn't see it. -People see what they want.
But he called me a fortune teller.
Otherwise, I had a lot of fun with you.
When we run into those birds, he's at the amusement park.
Even Eve said, "You," she said, "were looking at Cemal very differently at the soup shop." said.
-Zeliha, do you love me? -Ha?
-Do you love me? -Ha?
I say, do you love me?
-Jamal. -Ha?
I love you.
Born?
I love you love you.
-I love you too, crazy girl. -Don't say crazy.
[applause]
Shall we Dance?
Let's do it.
Ah ah, look at the type our boy likes while there are pretty girls.
But mom, it's okay now.
-Are we done? -We've grown, we've grown.
Fatma sister, are you okay?
I am good. I'm also very good.
Where is Fevzi?
Excuse me, let me ask you something.
Are you the girl side or the boy side?
-Man, you? -I gave the bride's gold.
I am my own. They invited me to come.
Good thing I came.
Shall we Dance?
My God, you are great, my Lord.
Come on, let's.
You came, thank you very much.
What happened? Curious?
Of course I did.
Then make it right, Eve.
How important was it?
Eve, look, my grandmother couldn't give me justice before she died.
The patient was lying down. I asked, "Grandma, are you giving me justice?" said.
He left without answering.
I have a lump here since that day.
Every time I get halal, I forget about that lump for a few minutes.
What do I do?
I do.
Havva helal et be.
I do, Tayyar.
Don't say that girl, do it.
I said I'm planning, I'm doing it.
do you?
Allah be.
[kiss voice]
-Zeliham. -Ha?
I couldn't propose at first.
Born?
Will you marry me?
When?
Whenever you want.
Whoa.
Bride and groom,
to all lovers
I just wanted to sing my aunt's favorite song.
- Well done Fevzi. -[everyone applause]
[animated music player]
I threw fire into the straw
Look at the smoke, the smoke
your cruel mother
I brought faith
squeak, whimper, shimmer
Oh so coy and move
Oh my hazel eyes move too
[klarnet solo]
I also put coffee in the cup
say hi to your uncle
If my uncle doesn't give his daughter
Let the pickle in the cup
squeak, whimper, shimmer
Oh so coy and move
Oh, you move so coyly
[clapping and cheering]