Good morning.
What's going on?
Sorry, granny. I fell over you.
It's like we were about to make love.
-Shame on you.
-You said it.
Hey!
Hey.
I'm so beautiful.
All I did was break a mirror.
What's the big deal?
Put a sock in it!
He's still mouthing off.
What's going on?
Shut up. Get your car and beat it.
Look, buddy. I'll send you flying.
Hey, I'm having breakfast! Stop shouting!
Shut up! Get back inside.
Who are you to park in front of my place?
Who are you? Who are you?
Do you know who I am?
Fato, what's going on?
The water guy parked his car
in front of Tayyar's place.
Tayyar got pissed off
and broke the car mirror. That prick!
The water guy asked why he did it.
Tayyar told the water guy
to forgive and forget.
The water guy said "why?"
and called him a prick and a dog.
Fatma...
You're getting seriously foul-mouthed.
Clean it up a little. Shame on you.
Let me go! Let me get him!
OK, just let me go!
I've had it with you. Come on, have a go.
-Grab him, grab him.
-Come on. Come on.
Shut your mouth. Get going.
He's still mouthing off.
You know how I get when I'm mad.
Hey!
What is it?
What happened?
You were mouthing off? Now scram.
-Tayyar!
-Huh?
Did I get burned?
I got burned!
Because of you!
All because of you.
You just wait, Deliha.
I'm burning!
I hate trouble in the neighborhood.
You scorched the boy's family jewel!
You scorched the poor kid's future!
What else could I do, Havva?
They were locked together.
Should I have let them become welded?
Anyway, it wasn't boiling.
It was between tepid and boiling.
And he's my cousin.
He bugs me. What's it to you?
What are they, Zehlia, a couple of dogs?
What do you mean, locked together?
-Enough of that. Are we going?
-We're going.
Let me put on my lipstick
and I'll be ready.
I'm telling you, we shouldn't go.
-It's a sin. We'll pay for it.
-It's at my peril then.
It's at my peril, Havva.
Hey, deadbeat!
I want to think about whelps today.
-What the hell's a whelp?
-A puppy.
Be downstairs in three minutes.
Fix that.
I can't.
Fix it, I said. My nerves are shot.
-It's so hot.
-Don't suck up my energy, mom.
-I have important stuff to do.
-Like what?
It's private.
-Give me some money.
-I don't have any.
I need to borrow from your aunt.
It must be 40 degrees.
We don't have a man around.
A woman going out on her own, my, oh my!
-I'll throw this slipper at you.
-I'll hang you by your ears.
Shut up, that's my line.
You burned the tablecloth again.
It's a lousy tablecloth.
Mom, you look a real wreck.
You missed.
granny, I'm taking some money. Forgive me.
It's 100, OK?
I've taken 150.
I'm going to a fortune-teller.
I'll get yours read too.
Maybe you'll get lucky. Who knows?
Don't worry, there'll still be enough
to get you a shroud. I'll pay it back.
Now say you forgive me.
May your prayers be answered, granny.
I'm off.
Oh, my God. She fell.
God, if I'm downstairs in ten seconds,
let me meet the love of my life. Amen.
Out the way!
Shame on you.
I made it.
Come on. Step on it.
How's it going?
I really pity these guys.
They're more and more
in love with me every day.
What a wacko.
Yeah, right. We're so in love.
Are you crazy?
Go on, keep moving. I hit you by mistake.
I don't think much of her or her mother.
Her mother kicked her mother-in-law
out to the street.
Thank God,
her brother came and rescued her.
Such a shame.
Kids!
That's enough.
You want me to slash your ball?
Why do you give me such grief?
Give me that ball quick.
Davut! Hand it over.
Give it to me. Come here.
The neighborhood thinks you're "loose".
Thought you should know.
Get going.
-Get to it.
-Thanks, Zeliha.
-Good day, Eftoptia.
-You too, you crazy girl.
-Good morning, Samim.
-Good morning.
-Good morning, Kasım.
-Good morning, sweetie.
-I got you a cassette. Here.
-Thanks.
Thank you.
It'll work soon.
-I'll get it to work.
-I hope so.
-Hang lose.
-Will do.
Zeliha, isn't it “hang loose”?
Some say “loose”, some “lose”.
“Lose” is right. You should know that.
-So, you're opening a studio?
-We'll see if we can.
I guess we'll be
the last ever photo studio to open.
Come on now! He's number two.
-So you're number one?
-No, not like that.
One day he said
he was going to study photography.
I told him not to bother.
Photos aren't something you study.
Photos are something you take.
He didn't listen.
When he graduated
I thought we may as well open a studio.
But I never wanted a studio.
Who goes to studios anyway?
-Everyone takes photos on their phones.
-Don't back out. We talked about this.
Feeling a photo in your hand
is something else.
-Seeing it on a screen leaves me cold.
-Feeling it is much better.
-That's right. Exactly.
-Go on, take my picture.
-What's that?
You mean you don't know?
Just center it and press the button.
Take it, sonny. Go for it.
Here.
What kind of a photo is that?
My five-year-old nephew can do this.
What makes you special?
Five, that's great.
STUDIO NECO
This is it.
Tell my fortune.
That's old-fashioned.
Let's do a reincarnation session.
I'll tell you who you were
in your past life.
I don't care who I was back then.
Tell me about my love life right now.
What a bore.
-Name?
-Zeliha.
-Day, month, year?
-March 13th.
1988. Anything else?
-That's all I need.
-And I'm a Leo.
-No, you're a Pisces.
-I'm a Leo.
No, a Pisces. Your ascendant is Leo
and your moon sign Scorpio.
I'm not a Pisces.
Pisces are emotional.
What's emotional about me? Dickhead.
What a jerk.
Both your mom and grandma are alive.
Your dad's dead. He was a truck driver.
You grew up like a boy. Mom's in
menopause, granny's not all there.
There's nobody special in your life.
There never has been.
You've only had platonic love.
You've loved, but haven't been loved back.
-You've always been a loser.
-Girl.
He knows everything. I'm in shock.
-He got some things right.
-He said you were a loser.
-I swear he knows everything.
-Hey, Fatma.
I swear I'll smash your face in.
Zip it!
You're a spinster.
Mr. Fortune-teller,
could we not say that?
Can we say I'm choosy?
No, your cousins always
talk behind your back.
It's Dürdane, isn't it?
My aunt's girl. My cousin.
She has thyroid issues.
She can't lose weight.
Shut up. What do I care?
Tell me my future, mate!
Go on, tell my future.
In a previous life
you were a Bedouin in Egypt.
What's that?
There's a guy you like
in your neighborhood.
He's short, a baby face.
And in a previous life
you were an Amazon warrior.
You don't like fortune-telling.
Sorry, I just got that information.
Pardon me.
You.
You write weird songs.
And in a previous life...
-You were a horse.
-I'm not into horses.
Are you doing this on purpose?
Are you trying to annoy me?
I came to have my fortune told.
Do mine. Do my fortune, not theirs.
There's no telling what you were.
I don't care! I am what I am.
Is that what I asked?
Am I going to fall in love? Huh?
Is someone going to love me?
How do I know? It's up to fate.
Look, buddy.
Why did I come here? Huh?
You're a horse, a butterfly.
What do I care?
Tell me about my love life.
I'll poke out your eyes.
-There'll be someone soon.
-Who?
Someone new.
You fall in love. Then marriage.
Who? Who?
I see the letters C, M, L.
C, M, L.
-Like, Selim?
-C, M, L.
-Davut?
-"C, M, L," I said.
-When will I fall in love?
-In ten days, two weeks.
-There was a fly.
-I know, that information came.
Wow!
Boys, here's your shop.
Clean it up, and start snapping.
Is there a dark room somewhere?
No, no way. The whole place gets light.
It's clean and airy.
We're talking past each other.
Now, the handsome one is Cemil
and the ugly one Cemal.
You're older, right?
Yes, I'm, but I wish
you hadn't said “ugly”.
Why do you have an accent,
but he doesn't?
Cemil's a city boy. He went to
high school and university here.
-I stayed in Şirince.
-Şirince? Never heard of it.
What? You know, where everyone ran
when the world was going to end.
-Well? It didn't end.
-But it could have.
We grow grapes there.
Grapes? What kind? Black or white?
Green. But like this, huge.
The big ones are something
and the round ones something else.
Especially the big hard ones.
But our real specialty is peaches.
Freestone and juicy.
Bro, stop fanning the flames.
What are you doing?
-Real juicy peaches, huh?
-You bet.
Like honey.
Some like them fuzzy,
others like them smooth.
I like both kinds.
-The guy sure loves fruit.
-Yeah, right.
Boys, come in and have a look.
This is it. This is just the place.
Stick a mattress in here, just in case.
No, I don't take naps.
Napping at your age?
To make love.
-We don't intend to do that.
-Intentions are important.
-Take me, I'm always up for it.
-On for what?
I'm talking about women.
White-skinned ones. Like grapes.
Is this it? Where's the kitchen and stuff?
There's no kitchen.
But I have a counter top at home.
It's as big as this shop.
Really? What do you do
with a counter that size?
-I beat meat.
-Can it have it?
Sure. If not, I make up for it.
Bro, let's think about it.
Don't decide until you see the bathroom.
Let me show you.
Let's not decide until we've seen it.
Look.
Wow, look at that.
Great, isn't it? Look.
You go through here,
and up here. You sit here.
You do it like a king.
We'll take it! It's taken.
Yeah, “taken” is right.
Who's C, M, L?
If it's Hasan, there's no “C.”
-Fortune-telling's a sin.
-You're done in?
It's a sin, a sin.
Fortune-telling is like a funeral.
You shoulder the casket...
Shut up. You're such a downer.
-Why are we friends with him?
-He doesn't have any others.
Now I feel bad.
-Zeliha!
-What?
Hey!
-Look, look.
-What?
OK, it's nice, but black would be better.
I'm talking about the license plate.
34 C, M, L... Ah, the love of my life!
I'm going to fall in love on the spot.
Oh, my God.
It's an old man.
-What's your name, old man?
-Sıtkı.
-Sıtkı?
-Yes.
Bugger off! Go on, get going.
Munching on a burger! Get going!
The rat.
-Good luck to us, Cemil.
-It's all done, Cemil.
It's for my brother's sake.
Otherwise why open a shop
that'll go bust in two days?
You know best, bro.
Mom said to open a shop for you.
She wanted you to have
a roof over your head.
But if you don't want it,
let's go to Şirince.
OK, whatever.
But what's with the landlord
taking three months in advance?
What could the guy do? He needs cash.
-They're all a bunch of crooks.
-Did you know I'm the landlord?
What?
The guy pranked us.
-Why are you telling us now?
-So I get the commission.
If you want commission
we're not renting it.
You signed. There's a contract.
What a relief.
-The place was empty for two years.
-Hang on.
You said someone moved out last week.
Who said that? Me?
Unbelievable!
I know what we should do.
We'll both lie down here
so you can screw us again.
-What?
-Never mind.
He's just kidding.
Let's go to the bank.
What kind of talk is that? Watch it.
Come with me a second.
I have to make a quick stop.
Efshopshia, Efshopshia.
Efpraxia. That's my name.
OK, what did I say?
Didn't I say, "Efshopshia?"
-What happened to my money?
-The rent's only a week late.
If it's late again
I'll have to evict you, babe.
What are you talking about?
Where would I go?
I could tear down this building
and put up a condo.
-What?
-A condo.
That has a certain ring to it.
Deliha! Crazy girl!
My name's Zeliha, not Deliha.
Is he trying to evict you too, Efkoptia?
-He says he'll evict me.
-What's that supposed to mean?
Who do you think you're evicting?
She's been here forever.
Nobody can kick her out.
Why are you talking like her?
You'll evict this woman over my dead body.
Do you understand?
Half the neighborhood is mine.
So is your flat actually.
I'll evict you all one by one if I want.
You're not going to evict shit.
You'll all end up moving
whether you like it or not.
Hey!
I didn't get to bite him!
Don't let her out without a leash.
She'll bite a child!
-Let me go! Let me get a bite!
-Whoa!
You rat!
I hope they drag you to the mountains
and screw you until your ass falls off.
I hope everyone has their way with you.
-Who's that girl, Faik?
-The neighborhood nutcase.
-You bastard!
-But I fancy her mother.
She sure is sassy.
Girls like her are rare these days.
-What?
-I hope horses have a go, too.
The bank, before it closes.
What do you mean, horses? Huh?
I said the wrong curse. Let me go.
You dog. Dog!
Rat! Let me go.
Zeliha. Look, he's gone.
Calm down. He's gone. Sit down.
Calm down.
Hey! What's going on?
-Mind your business, baby face.
-Faik, Zeliha, her home...
There's a fake Zeliha at home?
What are you talking about?
Faik's evicting Zeliha's family.
-Ah. Well, so be it.
-I'll punch you in the nose.
Serves you right. Why did you scald me?
I'm still burning in certain places.
I'd rather be cousins
with an animal than you. Pussy!
Man up and protect your cousin.
Watch your mouth.
Tayyar, make an ugly face!
I told you, don't do that.
I'm still mad as hell.
I'm going to bust up that realtor's ass.
GÜVEN REAL ESTATE
Ugh! What's going on?
Whoa!
Whoa.
Who are you? Do you work here?
We're renting the shop from Faik.
Which shop?
The one in the square. Studio Neco.
-Studio Neco?
-Yeah.
Ah.
Mate, I have an issue.
So I came to wreck the shop. You know...
I was going to head-butt everything.
Maybe smash a desk with my elbow.
Or maybe a flying kick.
But you're new here.
And, whoa...
You're pretty good-looking.
Out of respect for you,
I'll wreck this joint another time.
I see.
-What's your name?
-Cemil.
OK, Cemil, see you.
-What was your name again?
-Cemil.
C, M, L.
So?
-Meeting you pleased me.
-What was that?
Want to dance tomorrow?
You, me, the three of us?
-What dance?
-Uncle Kadir's getting married.
Who's Uncle Kadir? I can't keep up.
Don't you like dancing?
I like leading the dance.
Huh?
I've got some foot on the stove.
Don't want it to overflow.
See you ladder.
Good grief.
Zeliha?
-Hello.
-Where did Faik go?
-To the bank for a short visit.
-Who's short? You calling me short?
-I mean he won't be long.
So you're tall and I'm short. Is that it?
Faik's just down the street.
He'll be back shorty.
I mean, shortly.
You're messing with my head.
Shorty, huh?
Well, camels are tall, too!
Camels are tall, too!
OK.
No problem. Whatever you say.
What kind of neighborhood is this?
I had a dream last night.
I hope it bodes well.
There was a herd of horses running.
But then I saw their hooves
were wrapped in cloth.
I thought, "How can they run like that?"
It means your luck's dried up.
Shh.
Then the horses see me
and start galloping toward me.
I'm asking myself
if they're really running toward me,
when I see Zeliha on a horse.
I start running away and then wake up.
-I hope it bodes well.
-I hope so.
I can't figure that out.
It sure is a strange dream.
God forbid, could it mean
Zeliha is going to go astray?
Songül, you always put
a bad spin on things.
I've half a mind to get up
and chuck this slipper at you.
Sweetie.
Now that takes the cake.
Your husband's right to go off you.
Who said he went off me?
He turns his back on you in bed.
That's what you told Aysel.
Aysel!
What? When did I say that?
Aysel, you called last week
and said Songül's not getting any.
-Didn't you say the poor man's right?
-She did. She did.
I have a witness.
I'm in love.
Honey bun, I'm in love!
Mom! I'm in love.
Auntie, I'm in love.
Auntie Makbule, get him for me.
Hen party, engagement, wedding.
Fix them all right away.
Decide what you're wearing
at the wedding. I'm in love.
The bride arrived on horseback.
We need to talk.
I can't look you in the eye.
But...
I have to say it.
Baby...
I'm in love with somebody else.
Just listen. Don't say anything.
We went to a fortune-teller.
He said I'd fall in love
with someone
whose name has the letters C, M, L.
Cemil.
What did I say the day I put you up?
I told you not to trust me.
You should have grabbed me
while you had the chance.
No, don't. You'll be happy, too.
You'll fall in love with someone else.
Anyway, our relationship
has worn you out, too.
You're torn at the edges.
And granny gets embarrassed
when you watch her do her prayers.
We always cover your face.
It'll be easier if you don't look.
In the name of God...
You only have one eye left.
Goodbye, Kenan.
Welcome, Cemil.
Good morning.
Good morning, honey bun.
I'm so happy.
Havva! Havva!
Havva!
-What happened, Zeliha?
-Be downstairs in three minutes.
Hey!
Who broke this window?
Me.
People go all funny
when they fall in love.
What happened?
People go all funny
when they fall in love.
You have no shame!
-So you want plain white.
-That's right, plain and white.
Shall I paint a few roses?
They'd look great.
No, thanks. No need for a design.
How about some tiny wildflowers?
-That would be amazing.
-Just plain...
Why are you against it?
Let the guy do tiny flowers.
If this were a grandpa's house,
not a studio, OK.
How about some pink cameras?
It would be meaningful.
You don't get it. Let me explain again.
You're to paint the wall
all one color, OK?
I already don't want this shop,
don't make it worse.
-Sure you don't want flowers?
-Yes. No flowers.
Just paint it white. That's all.
-Birds?
Ugh...
Still the goddamn birds and bees...
-Who does he think he is?
-He only thinks of himself.
Oh, my goodness.
-Something's happened.
-What is it?
-Something's happened to you.
-No. What is supposed to have happened?
-Why did you run off yesterday?
-I didn't. Why would I do that?
You were talking to some guy,
then you ran off.
Cemil?
No. No, it's nothing.
Mom called me. There's a guy she likes.
She texted him. But he didn't reply.
She said we should
blow on the phone together.
Don't lie, Zeliha. Tell me the truth.
You like that guy. Was it Cemil?
-Right.
-Cemil?
Cemil.
C, M, L.
-Is that Cemil?
-Who's Cemil?
-She's walking away.
-The auntie?
-Is she an auntie?
-Yes.
She looks just like Cemil.
Why did you call me here?
To catch some fresh air. Come on,
I know a great place for some air.
-What are we doing here?
-Nothing. Getting some air.
Why do we keep looking over there?
-I'm not looking anywhere.
-That's it. Enough. Just plain white.
Cemil's having the place painted.
-That guy! He's renting the shop.
-So they say.
-Let's go wish them luck.
-No.
Let him come to us.
Listen.
If I reach that leaf, Cemil says “hi.”
But as a friend.
-OK?
-Yes.
I can't reach it.
What are you looking at?
-What's she doing?
-You see that girl? She's so spunky.
-The dark one jumping up and down?
-Yes.
She's crazy.
Well, I fancy her.
-Is he looking over here?
-Not at all.
-I think he is, but you won't say.
-Zeliha, why wouldn't I?
-He's looking.
-Swear on it.
How many times did he look?
Was it three, five?
Was it a look of love?
Did his look say “come”
or did it say “go”?
Tell me!
OK, you're getting carried away.
I'll go in the shop and wish him luck.
What's the big deal?
Good grief.
The barn door's open.
I meant the shop door.
Where'd you find the shop?
Which shop?
Have you ever been married?
-What am I saying?
-What's she saying?
I don't know,
but she's a straightforward type of girl.
I'm Zeliha. We met at the realtor's.
-I remember.
-We met too.
You know, there was that fight
at the Greek lady's house.
-How are you settling in?
-The wall.
It's a good neighborhood.
Everyone likes each other.
There are some I don't like.
Our women are in menopause.
They've got big bums
from all the carbohydrates.
The men are constantly being hen-pecked.
My mom sweats a lot.
That's from the menopause.
My love life sucks.
I've never had a boyfriend.
Kenan and I split up last night.
We'll talk about that later.
-Yeah, but the wall. Your hand...
-It's nice and smooth.
It's wet. It was just painted.
Huh?
Oh, my God!
I thought it was just damp.
There goes your face too.
Oh my!
It doesn't matter.
I look good in white.
They say it suits me.
Like a wedding dress maybe. Huh?
I'd even look good in a shroud.
What is this?
Do you have no respect for art?
-Shh, OK.
-What are you yelling about?
Did anything happen?
-You ruined the wall.
-Normally...
I'd knock this guy to the ground
and step on his face.
But you've just arrived,
so that would be shameful.
One day I'll come
and walk all over him.
-Why is your face all white?
-My blood pressure dropped.
No, it really is white.
-I'm all white.
-Why are you pouting?
Am I pouting?
I am. I guess I'm upset.
I'll go get Fatma.
We can meet in the park, OK?
♪ We have one eye on the earth ♪
-You're not allowed to play here.
-Why?
-You're depressing the public.
-I'm not budging an inch.
What? Zeliha?
OK, I'm coming.
Step on it, guys.
-She fell for this guy.
-Which guy?
The new guy, Cemil or whoever.
She won't admit it.
Love is like frog's legs.
All wet and floppy.
Fevzi, quiet.
Fatma, she got so excited
she got paint all over herself.
-Is he interested in her?
-What do you think?
The fortune-teller said C, M, L.
That's “Cemil”.
Fevzi, give me a push.
-Zeliha.
-What?
-Are you OK?
-I'm fine.
Is there anything you'd like to share?
No.
-I have a question.
-Don't ask, she won't answer.
Zeliha.
Did you fall for that boy?
Zeliha!
Are you OK, Zeliha?
I'm fine.
Yes, I'm interested in Cemil.
I might be in love.
-How could it happen so quick?
-He's my destiny.
My fate. I understand these things.
What's more...
He's dark and I'm fair.
We're the perfect match.
And I think he loves me.
When our eyes meet,
the seas move, the mountains dry up.
Even my mouth dries up.
But no boy's ever loved you before.
I hope five men
drag you off to the mountains.
God help us. God preserve us.
Five.
Not four, five.
Hold on, Red Scarf.
If I stop, I'll never get away.
-Spare a little milk, will you?
-As if the baby will nurse. Crazy boy.
Eat. Hey!
Eat, girl.
I don't want any, granny.
-Eat.
-No, mom.
I've gone off food. Love does that.
Don't try to kill yourself this time.
No way. This time he loves me back.
Who is he?
Cemil.
They took over Studio Neco's.
We're making eyes at each other.
Does making eyes do it?
-It's so hot.
-That's the menopause.
Is the rice good?
-Huh? Is it buttery?
-Yes, it's buttery.
I'll have a little then.
♪ A fig tree in front of the hospital
The doctor has no cure for me
♪ My mom is the cure ♪
I'm a man, a real man!
Understand?
Tayyar, are you OK?
-Hey, who's that?
-It's me, Havva.
Oh, pretty girl.
I've never seen you at night.
-Good night then.
-Hang on, don't go.
Let me get a look at you.
You're getting prettier as you go.
As I go? Well then I'll go.
Don't go. Come here.
Let me give you a kiss.
Goodbye.
A fig tree in front of the hospital
I saw everything, Havva.
What did you see?
You're hot for my cousin.
You came together right there.
Not at all. Don't make things up.
He just kissed me on the cheek.
He's an idiot. Stay away from him.
He's blood so I know him well, Havva.
Hey, I want to ask something.
Was it a wet kiss or a dry one?
Did he soil you, Havva?
It's time we have our opening, Cemil.
What opening?
Are we going to have an opening?
What will we say?
"We're the latest dopes to move in.
Come see for yourselves."
Stop that. We'll say
there's a photography graduate here.
We'll say we brought art to the hood.
Shall we hire a violinist?
-Wouldn't want to leave that out.
-And maybe she'll come.
Who?
-Garlic, garlic!
-Garlic.
Cures all ills! Garlic, garlic!
-Hello.
-What can I do for you?
-Is your microphone free?
-What are you selling?
-I want to make an announcement.
-Are you going to propose?
-No, speak to the neighborhood.
-Fine, jump in.
-Talk like this, OK?
-I know, I saw it in the movies.
Thanks. I hope the police
never give you trouble.
Amen to that.
Dear residents of our neighborhood.
We're opening Studio Neco today.
We hope to see you on this special day.
Would you like to see us too?
I can almost hear you say yes.
A fresh take on photos: Studio Neco.
Studio Neco, now serving you.
What did he say?
He said today is the best day
to live love to the hilt.
-What was that?
-We're living love to the hilt today.
Ah! Pervert.
Dig in and enjoy.
Stick her between
two slices of bread and eat her up.
FREE PHOTO FOR OPENING DAY
-Is that the violinist?
-What does it look like?
He's playing gypsy tunes.
We need some classics.
Why do you always find fault?
Let's ask him. He'll do it.
Can you play something more classical?
Certainly. "Miss You" by Selami Şahin?
-Really? Go ahead.
-Great.
What's this?
-Take it easy, Kasım.
-Thanks.
-What are you looking at?
-Just taking in the view.
Oh, no.
Best of luck.
-Our lips almost touched.
-Uh-huh.
This is Fevzi. He's a deadbeat.
Shake hands, Fevzi.
-Hello.
-This is Fatma, our spinster.
-No, my dear.
I can't really say that.
A fireman asked for my hand
just last month. I refused.
He'd been married twice.
Am I to take care of an old man?
-Deal with his prostate problems?
-Right. You should be in love.
-Uh-huh.
-This is Havva. She's dumb, but nice.
That's Cemil. You already know him.
Cemil's great.
He's so handsome.
-Cemal.
-Yes.
What a beautiful cat.
He's so handsome, Havva.
I mean, real handsome.
So young and strong.
And those dark eyes.
His eyes make you go all funny inside.
You feel like stroking his hair
on a sheepskin in front of a fire...
-Naked, for hours...
-Cemil.
-I'm having my photo taken.
-Go right in.
-Zeliha, you really hit on him.
-No, I didn't.
Play it cool and slap him down.
Guys don't like girls who are too forward.
Slap him down, huh?
Smile, he's taking our photo.
-Missy Sisi.
-She's not up for it today.
She normally smiles.
If you're done, I'm ready.
-Come on!
-Well, anyway.
-Are you having your photo taken?
-Yeah. Isn't that your job, mutt?
-Pop that flash.
-OK, turn to the right.
Don't order me around.
Who do you think you are, dickhead?
-But you're being shameful.
-Shameful, up yours blameful.
Take it!
-Take one like this, idiot.
-Don't talk to me like that.
What's wrong?
Hurt your feelings? Oaf!
For goodness' sake.
Everyone's here. Nobody told me.
Best of luck. What are you doing?
Handing round lemonade?
There we go.
-Tayyar.
-What are you up to, ducky?
-Last night was nice.
-You want some ice?
Last night, when you kissed my cheek.
Oh? I kissed you?
I'm something else. Hey, listen up,
I cornered her last night.
I don't remember a thing.
Watch out, I'll plant a kiss on you.
-I'll never forgive you.
-What? What was that?
I'll never forgive you.
Havva, stop kidding around. Forgive me.
I won't forgive you!
-You rat.
-Oh, my God!
-Dirty rat.
-What's going on?
Hey.
I'm supposed to slap him down.
What are you doing?
-I think I hurt his feelings.
-You didn't spoil him, did you?
-I called him a mutt.
-A mutt? Whoa!
-Whoa!
-He deserved it. The dirty dog.
And all his filthy language.
Did someone put cologne in her lemonade?
-Hey, Havva. Is he looking?
-No.
Stop looking at Tayyar.
He's never going to marry you.
He's a womanizing scumbag.
Keep your eye on Cemil.
I'll go up to him
the second I get an inviting look.
What are you looking at?
-He told me to come.
-No, he didn't.
I saw him say, “Come, come.”
OK. Thanks. See you.
What are you doing?
-I splat at you.
-You did what?
I splat.
-Come on, baby, let's make up.
-Did we fall out?
I made you mad.
Hey, my dark-eyed, honey-lipped baby.
Come here, cutie.
What are you saying, sonny?
Leave me alone.
Sonny?
Zeliha!
Spin it. Spin it round.
Keep spinning.
-He called me "sonny".
-What's the big deal?
Shut up and spin it.
He doesn't want me.
-He called me “sonny” like the others.
-That dirty rat.
Nobody will love me.
I'm going to die all alone.
Not this time, Zeliha!
We're here. Who's he anyway?
Who do these guys think they are?
We'll go to battle if we have to.
-We're meeting in the park tomorrow.
-What for?
-The Zeliha Movement!
-Whoa.
We're starting, Zeliha.
If Cemil doesn't fall in love with you,
my name's not Havva.
She's finally speaking up.
Is she possessed?
-We see it on the news.
-Shut up and listen.
Plan one: go everywhere Cemil goes.
Act like it's a coincidence.
-Like, "Oh, are you here too?"
-OK.
-What's up, Cemil?
-Fine.
I'm just here to work up a sweat.
Have a good one.
Thanks.
How's it going, Cemil?
We go to the same barber.
See that? What a coincidence.
Cavit, I want to get my eyebrows done.
Kick it!
Hello.
-How's it going, Cemil?
-Fine.
Come on, right down the middle.
That's it. Come on.
Whoa! Whoa!
Goal!
Good on you!
Didn't I tell you to go
to places where men and women go?
What do I know?
I was so busy watching the match
I forgot all about him.
You should go to the cinema.
Have some popcorn. Go on. It's good.
What are you doing?
BABY PEAS
Oh my God!
It didn't do any good.
But you got him to notice you.
Now surprise him and grab his attention.
-Do something totally unexpected.
-Totally unexpected, huh?
Peekaboo!
Hello.
He's scared!
I failed. It's not working.
Jealousy.
Act like you're jealous.
Great. Smile.
Cemil.
Yes.
Who's that?
Her? I don't know.
I don't want you seeing other women.
What's going on between you two?
Hey, look. What's with coming here
and posing and smiling at guys?
-What's wrong?
-Stop playing dumb.
You're making eyes at him.
You think I don't notice?
I know your type.
Sexy-talking man hunter.
Just what are you after?
What are you talking about? Get out.
Get out.
Aysel.
Your girl's going out
with that photographer, I hear.
They meet secretly at night.
Listen. He used to be a draper.
Then he went bankrupt.
No.
He had a kebab shop in Adana.
I heard his wraps were great.
He's going to keep Zeliha shut up in home.
And he'll hit it because
he wants three sons from her.
Where did you get all this?
She just said she liked him, that's all.
She let everyone feel her up
when she was young.
Mom, what are you saying!
The vendor said
the wedding will be in Adapazarı.
Aysel said she was from Adapazarı
and insisted Zeliha get married there.
Ayten! I'm Aysel, aren't I?
Am I from Adapazarı?
That's what the vendor said.
Let's go ask the boy himself.
What is this?
Everyone's just spreading gossip.
I hate this sort of thing.
Get up. Get up and go.
Get up. Get up.
-Where are you from, my boy?
-Şirince.
-So your dad just got out of jail?
-Jail? No.
-You're single?
-Yes.
-How single are you?
-What?
-Are you seeing anyone?
-From the neighborhood?
Don't play with hearts.
Put a ring on it right away, OK?
-Get married first.
-We were young once.
I'm not saying don't do anything.
But be clear. Family is important.
-Of course it is.
-Come on, take our photo.
Get close to his family.
Get along with them.
-His family's not here.
-His brother is.
-Right. His brother.
-What was his name?
-How do I know?
-You don't know!
Spend time with him. Get him to like you.
The time will never pass with that loser.
Wow!
-This is Taksim Square, huh?
-Yeah.
I'm glad you asked me, Zeliha.
I wouldn't have had fun alone.
Look at the birds.
SUPER WHEEL
How do you come up with
the things you say?
Wait, you've got something in your hair.
-Zeliha, I had so much fun.
-I had fun too.
Wasn't it great
when those birds flew over us?
-I was scared they'd poop on us.
-You've picked up my accent.
-I live up there.
-OK then.
OK.
-Do you really like taking photos?
-I love it.
Especially when...
-There's a beautiful subject.
-Ha.
Zeliha!
My friends are here.
Thanks.
Say "hi" to Cemil for me.
Tell him what we did.
-He's your brother, he should know.
-Of course. Good night.
-What were you doing in there?
-Waiting for you. How was it?
-How was what?
-How was it with Cemil's brother?
What did you do?
We had fun.
-You're grinning ear to ear.
-Really.
No.
I had fun. He's the big brother after all.
-He was giving you such a look.
-He sure was.
He's my law-brother.
My in-law.
My brother-in-law, right?
What's it called?
What do they call the husband's brother?
Whoa!
Don't sneak up on me.
-Something silly happened.
-What?
You know Velev Bar in Beyoğlu?
The place with live music.
-How would we know?
-I used to go there. They have live music.
I'm singing there tomorrow night.
The owner said he'd try me.
That's great. Be happy.
It's what you always wanted.
-I don't find it right to be happy.
-Let's go. Why not?
Zeliha, ask Cemil and his brother.
This is your chance!
God help us all! Now scatter!
Let's scatter.
-How's it going?
-Good. Welcome.
He's singing at Velev Bar tonight.
Come support him.
-You don't really need to...
-Sure I will.
I'd love to support you. I'll bring Cemil.
-Be sure to come. We'll have fun.
-Oh, I'm sure we'll have fun!
What are you doing?
Working on Photoshop.
Cemil didn't want to do it.
Huh.
You should have the bride kneel
and stick the groom on her back.
I think it would be a lot cuter that way.
You know what? I'll do that.
We have incredibly similar taste.
OK, make-up. I need a very natural look.
Eye shadow.
I've never used it before.
Whoa.
Whoa. I wish I had.
Blusher. I reckon two strokes
will do it.
Whoa.
Whoa! I'm so beautiful.
I'm seriously good. Cemil...
Hello. I've never kissed anyone before.
But I'd kiss you.
Girl.
What are you doing?
Kissing the mirror?
No.
granny fancied this guy.
The guy tried to kiss her.
granny wouldn't let him.
The guy was miffed at her.
granny left him.
What?
granny wouldn't let him kiss her.
They broke up. granny's crying in there.
It's over between them.
granny thought it was too soon to kiss.
You go let him kiss you.
-What are you doing, Fatma?
-Zeliha.
They danced at my friend's wedding.
I was too heavy to dance it then.
It stayed with me.
But now that I'm slimmer,
I thought I'd get on down.
Come on, let's go.
Move!
Yes?
-We want to go in.
-Do you have a reservation?
-No.
-This is not your kind of place.
But we have to get in.
Come on, move along.
Stop giving me grief.
İdris?
-Look, it's İdris, isn't it?
-Who's İdris?
You're Sevcan's son, aren't you?
Ah, look at you!
You got all grown up
and now you wait at doors?
Good for you. Work. Earn a living.
Say a big "hello" to your mom.
Bye!
I'm not İdris.
It's a fun place here. Very friendly.
Nice one, Fato.
How do you know the guy?
I don't. I just pretended.
But there's an İdris I do know.
I can't stand his mom.
She'd come to our tea parties,
stuff a napkin with goodies
and leave.
One time she nicked a towel.
And she says
she only took it
because her boy had a stye.
Imagine! With styes,
they say you should steal copper.
She made it an excuse for the towel.
Rude cow.
-I didn't hear a word.
-Zeliha, I'm telling you,
this place scares me. Why are we here?
For your friends, Havva.
For me. For Fevzi's future.
What's up? You're cowering.
What happened to the warrior woman?
Tayyar slapped you, let me remind you.
You reminded me and it's true.
Fevzi.
-Hi.
-Fevzi, can I have a beer?
I'd kill for a cold one.
Go for it, Fato. Let's hang loose today.
-What can I get you?
-A beer.
One beer.
-Apple juice for me, bro.
-One apple juice.
-And me, I'll get a small tea.
-One tea.
Fevzi, you can go on stage now.
One beer, one tea, one water, apple juice.
Whiskey and coke, two beers, one raki.
-Come on, get to it.
-Say it slowly, dammit!
Whiskey and apple juice?
Who's drinking that?
Death is blowing in my face...
Whoa! The old boy likes me.
My death shroud is in tatters...
Whoa! That's sour apple juice.
Nice, though. I feel warm inside.
I scratched your name in my coffin...
-What the hell are we doing here?
-Come on, it's a friend's gig.
Come on, die with me...
-The crazy girl's here.
Don't be so rude. Hi there!
Has he been on a long time?
Come on, die with me...
-You can see better from here, huh?
-Sure.
Whoa!
I felt your leg. It was warm as toast.
Is love hard work?
Zeliha.
I say you should sing.
He'd be so impressed.
You think so?
I scratched your name in my coffin...
-Let's swap places.
-You're the best brother.
Fevzi, start the intro. "Always Later".
I suddenly felt like singing a song
for the person I love.
He knows who he is.
You aren't Layla, I'm not Majnun
You aren't tired nor am I
We felt blue one night
We got drunk that's all
You aren't Layla, I'm not Majnun
Hey, I'm out of here.
You aren't tired nor am I
We felt blue one night, we got drunk
That's all
I always come to my senses later
Always later
Awesome, baby. You're terrific.
I always come to my senses later...
Is he bothering her?
Always later...
You're fantastic, baby!
-Bravo, baby! Bravo!
-But you're harassing the lady.
-Wait, you're harassing the lady.
-Whoa.
-Screw you! This bitch is mine.
-Watch your mouth!
Oh, my God, a fight.
Oh, my God, a fight!
-What are you doing? Break it up.
-Get off me! I'll kill you!
Zeliha,
hold it to his eyebrow, not his mouth.
I am, Havva.
Shame they beat him up so bad.
You have a beautiful voice, Zeliha.
Why did you get into a fight?
-I was worried about you.
-I'm tough. I can fend for myself.
No way. You don't have to
when you're with me. I'll protect you.
Why?
You're a nice guy, too, actually.
You have a big heart.
I could say you're a man
one could fall in love with.
No man has ever loved me before, you know?
But I think I'll be loved soon.
I agree.
-I like you a lot.
-Me too.
Hey, soup man. Is your soup hot?
Baby face is here.
-Deliha and her stable mates.
-It's you who needs the stable.
Hey, Havva.
Suppose you forgive me
for the soup man's sake
-so I get a good night's sleep?
-I don't.
And even if she did, I don't.
Here, watch this. Hey, Tayyar.
Make an ugly face.
Hey, don't! I told you. Don't do that.
What do you smell of?
Zeliha. You're now eating garlic
rather than soup.
Oh, my God!
Whoa!
But you know what?
It had a certain tang to it.
It wasn't that bad.
Oh, my God.
I feel like something's happening to me.
What do you feel like?
Havva, I have the five of cups.
What do you have?
Then let this song be for all of us.
What was your name?
Your name...
Her blood pressure's down.
Get up! What's with the sleeping in?
-What's up?
-Faik. He sent an arrears notice.
He wants to kick us out. Let him try.
Wait. Don't go alone.
I'm coming too. He'll kidnap you.
What's that smell?
Garlic.
-Look, Faik!
-Go ahead, petal.
Are you seriously evicting us?
Let's not discuss it
with this crazy here, huh?
-We pay rent.
-You don't give me what I want, petal.
-You've no right to evict us.
-It's my house, you know?
But don't worry.
I'm going to kick out Efshopshia first.
Then it'll be your turn. Relax.
Aysel.
Have I ever told you
about my widow fantasy?
Rude idiot!
Hey! Listen here.
You know my real estate agent fantasy?
OK, I'll tell you.
You're kidnapped by three guys
built like stallions.
They find a big tree up on a hill.
They tie you up face down.
You look up at them with pleading eyes,
but there's no mercy with them.
They pull down your pants.
-Out of here, girl!
-Then as you're wailing...
-I'll do it with demos next time.
-Come on, move!
-Pumper!
-OK, go!
Yes. Be here by tomorrow, mom.
We're asking for the girl's hand.
What?
I'm in love, mom.
I'm going to get married.
Yes, she's pretty.
I don't know her shoe size, mom.
Just hurry here tomorrow, OK?
Bye. Kisses.
What's going on?
Tomorrow night
we're asking for Zeliha's hand for me.
-Who? That crazy girl?
-Don't say that.
She's so sweet.
So feisty. I love her to bits.
Are you sure?
She doesn't seem that keen on you.
Not to you she doesn't.
How did she start her song last night?
She looked at me and said:
"He knows who he is." I do.
-OK, if you're sure.
-Sure I am. We'll be so happy.
Leave it to me.
Let's just get tomorrow over with.
-Let's hope for the best.
-Totally.
You go home. And shut the door.
Who do you think you are?
Who are you to kick us out? Dickhead!
Scumbag!
It's one thing after another.
-What's up, Zeliha?
-Faik's kicking us out.
Cemil isn't interested in me.
I look like an idiot.
Whoa! I guess I'll become a wino.
The game's over.
Now that's what I like.
Hi. How are you, Zeliha?
-What happened to your face?
-I got in a fight yesterday.
I remember nothing.
Um, I was going to say
we want to come by tomorrow night
in a good cause. As a family.
Should we come?
-Who to?
-You.
-In a good cause?
-Yes.
-As a family?
-I thought so, yes.
-What time?
-Around eight, I'd say.
Around eight o'clock. OK.
Whoa. He sent a message
with his big brother.
I hope...
I hope this isn't what I think
-and that Cemil's brother fancies her...
-Shh, girl!
How about a spin by the water?
-Kasım, is the car working?
-That young fella fixed it.
-Which young fella?
-At the photo studio.
The nicest,
the most handsome man in the world.
He's coming to ask for my hand
tomorrow night. Whoa.
-How are you? Are you well?
-Fine. And you?
Fine, thanks.
-How are you?
-Fine, thanks. You?
Yes, we're fine, thanks.
-How are you, son?
-Fine, thanks. You?
I'm fine. Fine.
-And you, son?
-I'm fine, thanks very much. You?
-Me too, I'm fine.
-Wonderful.
-And you're well?
-Yes, thanks.
-Very well. You?
-Everyone's fine.
Once the act of mating has finished
between a pair of rhino,
the male sinks onto the ground.
Copulation is rarely seen
at the present time
and leaves both rhino exhausted.
granny always watches
documentaries like that.
Huh?
What's that, mom?
Zeliha, why don't you make us coffee?
Ah, sure.
God, I'm so happy.
Havva, I'm so happy.
You're the cutest.
See? You'll finally
marry the man you want.
Zeliha, I want to say something.
-You think Cemil's brother...
-Havva, wait.
If I can keep my hand in the flame
for five seconds, I'll marry Cemil.
Not that it's in any doubt.
One, two, three...
Whoa.
I couldn't do it.
Why was that?
Tayyar, go away!
Tayyar, go away.
Shut up! I'm not here for you.
-Havva.
-Go away, Tayyar.
-Havva, forgive me.
-Don't, Havva!
If you do, I'll never forgive you.
Hey, Fato. Fato.
Do I put salt in Cemil's coffee or pepper?
They asked for my hand three times.
I did salt all three.
OK, I'll go for pepper then.
-Has someone you know died lately?
-No.
You have a dead person's energy.
No, really?
Well, we've come here in a big rush,
but our boy insisted.
Let's hope for the best.
Except, these things
shouldn't really be rushed.
Well, the kids have taken
a shine to each other.
-Our Zeliha is a great girl.
-You can tell.
Screw you if you spill.
Zeliha, what are you doing?
Funny girl.
Thanks, dear.
Whoa!
Thank you.
Husband, I don't want this girl.
She's insane. Let's get out of here, fast.
Absolutely not. We've come all this way.
The boy loves her.
I love her.
Well, now.
Bless you, mom. Bless you.
-The kids seem to love each other.
-We do.
And we've come to do what falls to us.
By the will of God
and word of the Prophet,
we ask for your daughter, Zeliha's hand
for our Cemal.
Huh? Cemal?
Cemil. It's Cemil.
-No, dear. Cemal.
-No, Cemil.
Girl, the older one's Cemal.
Cemil's younger.
No way. It's Cemil.
I'm confused. Is Cemil's name Cemal?
OK, but it's Cemil who's into me.
-What?
-Don't be ridiculous.
Just a second. I don't understand.
Who do you want Zeliha to marry?
Me.
Zeliha?
I can't help laughing.
There seems to be a misunderstanding.
Just a second.
What would I want with you?
Are you mental?
Get out.
I've never seen anything like it!
What rude people.
Her thing was Cemil.
Didn't you say you two were in love?
-I guess I got the wrong idea.
-Never mind. The girl's an idiot. Mental.
Didn't I warn you?
And you fell for her like a sucker.
What's it to you?
I fell in love. I wanted her, not you.
-Bro.
-Yes, bro.
I'm your big brother.
I love a girl and it's for you
to sound off about her, huh?
You're too trusting,
you're too gullible to know.
Enough, dammit!
All my life I've loved only one girl.
It didn't work out. What can I do?
It's me who's suffering.
Just leave me alone, it's all I ask.
OK, bro. I'm sorry.
Time for Zeliha to kill herself.
Suppose you don't, honey?
-Have I choked?
-No.
Out the way!
Zeliha!
Honey.
Zeliha! Zeliha, open the door!
I'm going to kill...
I'm going to kill myself.
Is that right?
How can this be happening?
Zeliha, stop scaring us!
Go away! Get away from here!
Leave me alone!
I want to die alone.
I want to die in peace.
Whoa. I'm on the brink of death.
Auntie Aysel, I swear
she'll kill herself this time.
Don't call me "auntie"!
I'm the same age as you.
OK, it's goodbye.
Whoa! My blood pressure dropped.
I was upside down, mom.
Help! Save me!
Whoa! I can't die.
I'm hanging myself.
There. I'm dying.
Fevzi! Come fix this!
Make way.
-Am I dead?
-No.
I'm going to throw myself out the window.
-Out the way!
-Wait!
Zeliha, don't!
Is she dead?
I don't think so.
What are you staring at?
Now look. Who made me better, huh?
I wanted to die.
I'm still going try to kill myself.
I can't go on. I don't want to be alive.
Hello, Makbule?
-Have we come round, Zeliha?
-I don't know. Have we?
-Huh? Doctor.
-Yes?
If I pay you 50 lira,
can you inject
nitric acid in that solution?
In your drip?
For a long life, right?
Are you taking the piss?
I asked you a serious question.
I'll break your hypocritical oath.
Dickhead!
Zeliha. Faik is evicting Efpraxia.
He's sent in the bailiffs.
There are three or four chairs there.
Are they listed?
Sorry. We're taking
that chair too, Efshopshia.
-But this is shameful, Faik.
-Mind your own business.
Throwing an old lady out...
Just hold it, I'm saying something here.
Isn't it beneath you
to throw out an old lady?
Keep your nose out of things
that aren't your business.
-Go take photos.
-Put that hand down!
What's your problem?
Are you going beat me up?
Ha! Deliha's here.
Who are you kicking out, dickhead?
Watch that mouth.
I have a hangover. I ache all over.
Don't make me beat you up.
I sealed a great deal last night,
you know?
She's got the keys of the Jeep!
Deliha!
Come here! Deliha!
Shame on you!
Come on, give me the keys, Deliha.
Deliha!
Honey.
Come and get it.
Stop that. What do you want?
-Are you renting the house or not?
-No, dammit! No!
Pull his pants down, guys.
Hey! Hey, stop! Stop! OK, OK.
What's up, İffet? Scared, are you?
Deliha, sweetheart.
Let's talk. Wind down the window.
Samim!
Whoa! Hey!
-OK. I'll rent it.
-Now, so all the neighborhood hears.
OK, I'll rent the house.
-Louder.
-Efshopshia, the house is yours.
Not Eshopshia, Efkoptia.
Efkoptia, the house is yours.
God! What a happy day!
Havva, do you forgive me?
-No.
-She still says no.
So you tried to kill yourself?
I guess so. I don't want to be alive.
You want to kill yourself, Pedi Mou?
And you're so young, dear.
But everyone saw, Pedi Mou.
Cemil was in love with me.
He was hitting on me, wagging his tail.
And his older brother wanted you.
Yes. Sly dog.
Listen, dear.
-You made a mistake somewhere.
-Where exactly was that?
You may be blind
to someone who truly loves you.
You may not notice.
Maybe his brother
fell in love with you, though.
No. No one loves me. No one ever has.
Maybe you...
picked the wrong man. What do you say?
-I'm thinking.
-Well, think carefully.
-What's up? Where are you going?
-Mind your own business.
We're going home.
To Şirince, to a wedding.
Really?
-Goodbye then.
-Goodbye.
And thanks for everything.
No problem. Have a good trip.
Thanks.
What's up?
They're going to a wedding in Şirince
and not coming back.
Sevim, what's up?
You know Cemal? He's getting married.
They're going back to their hometown.
He said he's never coming back.
What's going on?
Cemal's so upset he's going home
for a spur-of-the-moment wedding.
Oh, my God!
Havva.
Hey, Havva.
-Come on, forgive me.
-No.
Tayyar, shut up! I'm thinking.
Zeliha, look what the fella left you.
-What fella?
-The one who fixed my car.
-Cemil.
-No, not Cemil. Cemal.
Cemal?
Open it. See what he's given you.
Yes. Now I'm curious too.
This is how I always see you.
As the sweetest girl in the world.
“Good luck. Cemal.”
-See? He loves you.
-He does?
He does, Zeliha. Don't you see? Look.
But no man has ever loved me before.
I don't know what it's like.
How can I tell?
Who'd love you, for goodness sake?
Just look at you!
Tayyar...
You know why I get mad at you?
Because you always make fun of me.
You keep saying, "Just look at you."
Do you think I wanted to be like this?
When I was small,
I had to wear your castoffs.
I walked around looking like a boy.
I'd ask for a dress,
mom would say we were broke.
You keep laughing at me.
Hey, Zeliha.
Have you ever asked
if I have any problems?
I don't have a dad. My dad's dead.
I figured if I was like a boy
I could protect mom and granny.
Zeliha, I'm sorry.
I never thought of it like that.
Guys always called me “son”.
They called me "mate", or "buddy."
They called you "tomboy" too.
Dammit, I'm have such a big mouth.
None of them loved me either.
Whoa.
Have I just lost the one and only man
who ever loved me?
It's that damn fortune-teller's fault.
I turned to the wrong person.
He said the name had C, M and L in it.
Whoa.
Cemal. C, M, L.
Cemal has C, M and L in it, too.
My Cemal!
Zeliha!
Junk man!
Oh my God, it's locked.
-They went to a wedding.
-A wedding?
Cemal was so upset he's gone away
to have a spur-of-the-moment wedding.
A spur-of-the-moment wedding?
-Where?
-In his hometown, Şirince.
-Whoa! So Cemal's getting married.
-Come on, Zeliha. We can make it.
But how do we get there, Fatma?
Come on, hop in.
Kasım!
Drive on.
What's up?
Zeliha's run off with Cemal.
They slept together
so now they have to get married.
What?
Aysel, Zeliha's been deflowered.
She's gone off to get married.
Let her go, mom. Just open the window.
Open the window. It's so hot.
It's so hot.
Well, well, well! Look who's here!
-Remember me?
-No.
Aren't you Nesrin's son, Cemal?
Yes, that's me.
-You still don't remember?
-No, sorry.
Well I'll be damned.
You used to come to me as a boy and say:
"What nice boobs you have."
Then you grabbed a handful and go.
-You still don't remember?
-No.
-When are you getting married?
-I'm not.
There'll be the prettiest girls
coming here tonight.
-Take your pick and I'll fix it for you.
-OK.
I tell you what.
You'll be able to go to sleep
on a wifey's boobs
and play with them
to your heart's content.
They want photos taken
in the village, bro.
I've been at it all day. You go.
-I'm not the photographer. Do it yourself.
-It'll be a distraction.
And a gesture
seeing as the groom's our cousin.
OK. Give it here.
If you'll excuse me...
-But I only just found you!
-I have to take photos.
Hey, come here. Sit down.
Aren't you Nesrin's son, Cemil?
-Yes.
-Remember me?
-No.
-Come on, I'm Hatçe, aren't I?
You'd come and squeeze my boobs as a boy.
-Still don't remember?
-No.
Shame on you!
How much further, Kasım?
Whoa. Fuck!
I'm telling you, Zeliha.
Swearing is sinful.
What's going on? Havva?
I'm stepping on it, Zeliha.
They came to ask for my hand
three years ago.
Remember Feryal's nephew?
He was wearing a tie.
The ends were all dirty.
I felt sick when I saw him.
I thought, oh, my God!
-Havva, forgive me.
-No.
Whoa! If she does, I don't.
If Cemal marries before I arrive,
I swear I'll kill myself. Whoa!
Something's gotten into all of you.
In the name of God...
Something's happening to me.
Oof! Thank God!
Dear Kasım.
Something got into you all in my dream.
I swear you were dressed as a woman.
Hey, I'm talking to you!
Wake up! What's with the sleeping?
What's going on?
Kasım.
We've blown a tire.
Man! Damn tire!
You...
Out the way!
Whoa!
Well, it was old.
-There's no spare either.
-What do you mean?
But the wedding... We can't be late.
Whoa! I'm finished!
I'm going to die unloved!
OK, girl! Just calm down!
I'll handle it. Wait.
Zeliha.
Our Dürdane got a car, you know.
A 2002 model.
And boy, did they show off.
They'd planned a trip back home.
And guess what? The car broke down.
-Fatma.
-Yes, petal?
Shut up!
Over here, come on!
-Bravo, Tayyar. Go!
-Good! We'll have lots of room.
Kasım...
-You'll be OK, won't you?
-Sure, dear.
Goodbye.
I'll call my child Kasım, Kasımcan.
Come on!
Kasım.
-Hello.
-Welcome.
-Hi, guys.
Göz Göz Göztepe! Göz Göz Göztepe!
Come on, smile.
It's the happiest day of your lives.
Yes.
Very good. Time to move on
to the concept shots, OK?
-Sure, let's do it.
-Good grief, bride. Aren't you keen!
OK, grab Nusret's tie and pull.
That's the best yet.
We've got our concept.
OK, squat, bride.
The entire household is on your shoulders.
Climb on top, Nusret.
Perfect. Now swap places.
Climb on top, bride.
Groom's sister, you're fuming.
Throttle the bride.
Aunt, they're taking your son.
Grab his arm. Don't let go.
-Is this what they do in Istanbul?
-Sure. It's all the rage.
Uncle, you, head the family,
spread your arms; show your authority.
-İbrahim, you were out of it.
-Oh, no!
You got it! Bravo.
It's like you don't want to see.
Perfect. How about we do a tower?
Sure, let's do it.
Now, the bride's fleeing
and you're all chasing her.
Don't move. Stay put. Just move your arms.
Bravo, groom's sister.
Keep up the grimace.
Masterful.
Now a new concept: the bride's dead.
Nusret's in pieces, the family distraught.
Let's do it. Die, gorgeous.
Nusret, you go to pieces.
Hanife, what's with the long face?
You're the groom's sister.
You should be happy.
Come on then.
Aunt, let's see
those crocodile tears. Yes.
Ibrahim, forget me,
but at least have some for the corpse.
OK, please. Take in position.
-Oh, no.
-Ha, bravo!
Incredible.
At 19, I was in love with a tall,
handsome boy called Kadir.
For five years I turned down anyone
who asked for my hand.
Then they said I was over the hill.
So boys, Kadir wrecked my youth,
my whole life.
You killed my youth, Göztepe!
You killed my youth, Kadir!
-Shame on you!
-Shame on you, Kadir!
In that case,
for Fatma, for love...
Moses moseys to the shrine
I have to grab a swig of wine
I feel blue, blue, blue
One, two, three
Göztepe
La-la-la-la-la-la-la-la la, Göztepe...
Sit down! Police!
Out of the bus.
We're doing a search, friends.
But officer, no one's given us
anything to carry.
That's for me to decide.
-Who are you?
-Hooligans.
-Come on.
-Fight all to the end, Göztepe!
Drop it for God's sake.
Get out of the bus. Move.
Get out, guys. Come on.
Where are they going?
-OK, fine. But what's this peashooter?
-It isn't ours, officer.
-Whose is it?
-No idea.
The women hooligans.
Start the car!
Whoa. They're coming.
I'll rot in jail
before I hook up with my love.
I'm like an unopened parcel.
I'm like a rosebud.
It's a heavy load. We can't go faster.
-Let's dump the watermelons.
-Yes!
Watch it! Watermelons!
No!
It's such a waste!
Don't! That's food!
True.
-I'm slowing you down.
-Don't be crazy, Fatma.
Forgive me!
Oh, my God, she fell off.
Thanks, Fato!
I'll never forget that favor.
She'll be fine. Don't worry.
She'll find a way. Keep going.
What do you think you're doing?
-İdris?
-Yes.
-Aren't you Sevcan's son?
Sevcan was in our tea party group.
Bravo, you're a policeman.
So have you come to rescue me?
Come here! Ah! Come on!
İsmail, buddy, come over
and let's rescue her.
You guys get off here.
I'll go back to dump this
and check up on Fatma. I'll be back.
-How?
-What do you mean?
We won't make it on this anyway.
You go to the wedding. I'll find you.
Havva! Forgive...
Never mind.
It's OK. Bye.
OK. What do we do? How do we get there?
We spent all the money on petrol.
We'll ask a car for a ride.
You can't ask like that!
In movies you get sexy women
showing their legs to hitch a ride.
Havva.
-Hi. We're going to Şirince.
-OK. Jump in.
I'm soiled.
I'll never forget this favor, Havva.
Come on, climb in.
Please God, don't let him be married.
-As your wife?
-Yes.
With the authority vested in me
by the Mayor of Selçuk,
I pronounce you husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Don't kiss her! Stop!
-Who's that girl?
-I don't know, sweetie.
Whoa! Who are you? Where's Cemal?
Who's Cemal, Nusret?
My cousin. He took the pictures, right?
Look, he's there.
OK, you can kiss her.
Cemal...
Welcome.
Why did you come?
I brought you this.
But I made it for you.
Cemal, I didn't realize you loved me.
-I couldn't see it.
-People see what they want to see.
But the fortune-teller told me.
Otherwise I had a great time with you.
Chasing the birds
at the amusement park.
Havva even said I was staring at you
in the soup place.
-Zeliha, do you love me?
-Huh?
-Do you love me?
I said: "Do you love me?"
-Cemal...
-Huh?
I love you.
What?
I love you. I love you.
-I love you too, crazy girl.
-Don't call me crazy.
-Shall we dance?
-Let's do it.
Look who the boy picks
when there are all these pretty girls!
Hey, come on, mom. OK.
-Did we make it?
-Yes, we did.
Fatma, are you OK?
Fine. It couldn't be better.
Fevzi, where are you going?
Excuse me a moment.
Are you the bride's side or the groom's?
-The groom's. You?
-I fixed the bride with her gold.
I'm a jeweler. They invited me, so I came.
I'm glad I did.
Shall we dance?
Dear God, you're a great God.
Come on then.
Thank goodness you're here.
Why? Were you worried?
Sure I was.
In that case forgive me, Havva.
Why is it such a big deal for you?
Look. My granny never got to forgive me
before she died, Havva.
She was sick. I asked her to forgive me
for everything I'd done to hurt her.
She died before answering.
I've had a lump here ever since.
Whenever someone forgives me,
I forget that lump for a minute.
I can't help it.
-OK.
-Come on, Havva. Forgive me.
OK, Tayyar.
-Don't say that. Come on.
-Tayyar, I said OK. I do.
Do you really?
My God.
-Zeliha...
-Huh?
I didn't get to propose before.
What?
Will you marry me?
When?
Whenever you'd like.
Whoa.
For the bride and groom,
and all those who love each other.
I just want to sing
my aunt's favorite song.
I set fire to the hay
See the smoke blow away
Your mean mother
I convinced her
Shake it, shake it, come on, shake it
Ah, let's see you coyly shake it
Shake it, hazel-eyed dearly beloved
I'm pouring a cup of tea
Greet your father for me
If he won't let me wed his girl
He'll see tragedy unfurl
Shake it, shake it, come on, shake it
Ah, let's see you coyly shake it