Electricity is all around us all the time.
It makes our lives easier, safer, more fun,
and most of us never think about it.
But are we using too much electricity?
Is it possible that the foundation of our modern world
is slowly killing us?
Before going deeper,
let's try to understand what electricity is
and how it affects us.
Electricity is the movement of an electric charge.
This movement generates electric and magnetic fields
that disperse through space and carry energy.
This phenomenon is called "electromagnetic radiation".
"Radiation" is a very nervous word.
But to radiate simply means to "emit."
As when your home's radiator gives off heat
in the form of infrared radiation.
Different parts of the electromagnetic spectrum
correspond to different types of radiation.
And many of them are perfectly harmless.
However, some can be dangerous
Very short wavelength radiation,
such as UV rays, X-rays and gamma rays,
is strong enough to tear electrons from their atoms,
which can cause burns and genetic damage
This is what  that many people have in mind when they hear the term "radiation".
The rest of the spectrum covers a wide range of other wavelengths
from visible light, infrared, microwaves
to radio waves.
This is the type of radiation emitted by all kinds of technology
Cell phones, Wi-Fi routers,
power lines, and household appliances.
This type of radiation does not disturb the molecules of our body.
However, certain types of radiation can stimulate muscles and nerves as
well as vibrate the hairs on your body,
which can sometimes cause tingling above certain values.
Other types are useful for preparing
food Microwaves circulate the water molecules in your food
which heats it up
This happens to us all the time.
For example, the pleasant warmth you feel at the beach
is that of your skin being warmed by the presence of infrared radiation emitted by the sun.
We are surrounded by sources of natural, and generally harmless, electromagnetic radiation all the time,
and always have been.
But since the industrial revolution
we have added many in our immediate environment.
Whether it's really
dangerous first came to public attention when a 1979 study
linked leukemia to living near power lines.
But this study was soon discredited.
The connection could not be explained
and no causal link could be confirmed.
But once it was suggested,
the idea persisted,
and thousands of studies of potential dangers
show that it is still seen as a real threat.
Many people claim to be sensitive to the radiation
emitted by our phones and other devices.
They report symptoms such as headaches,
nausea, skin reactions, eye burns or fatigue,
but these are only day-to-day effects.
A few studies have found much more disturbing results
as a possible link between the part of the brain
used when you're on your phone
and the development of brain tumors.
The question science is trying to answer
is not so much about the acute effects of radiation.
We know, for example,
that X-rays cause immediate DNA damage in our cells
but that radio waves do not produce the same effect.
The question is rather:
does this kind of weak electromagnetic radiation that surrounds us  constantly
is harmful in the long term due to phenomena that are still unknown?
Answering this question was much more difficult than we thought.
There are thousands of primary sources
, reports and statements made by many different organizations.
So we read a lot for this video.
You can take a look at our research in the description
What we found is that this debate is a good example
of how science should be communicated, and how it shouldn't be
Many of the most popular studies  quotes that sow panic about electromagnetic radiation
are highly controversial
For example:
a series of population studies based on polls and self-reports
Which means that, for example,
asking patients with brain tumors how long  they think they've spent on their phone for the past few years.
The problem is that people are unreliable
We tend to misremember things or can be swayed easily
In addition to this
, studies or news reports can select results that support their views
or will make headlines  best selling
For example,
a study looking for cancer in rats and mice due to phone radiation
The results seemed to show a connection
But, for some obscure reason, only in male rats
and absolutely none in mice
but it was  publicized as if the study proves
that cell phone radiation causes cancer
Unfortunately, this is the case for studies showing both positive and negative results on the problem
Another aspect is that the WHO has officially classified the fields  radiation
as potentially carcinogenic
But what that really means
is that there are a few clues that suggest it may  may be carcinogenic
but we can't prove it and we'll keep an eye on
it So, taking a step back, what's the big picture?
Altogether,
there has been no consistent evidence in human studies
that exposure to electromagnetic radiation below the limit values causes health problems There
are some correlations but t
ey are generally weak and incon
istent  If there were real cause and effect relationships
we would already know, thanks to all the data we have
So according to the current state of science
should you be worried about the radiation emitted by your computer  , your phone, or your TV?
The answer is no.
You should not.
But what about people who claim it harms them?
Research shows they can experience what's called the Nocebo Effect.
If you have a headache and feel better right after turning off your computer,
you might see a connection between these two events.
Once you have that suspicion, the very idea that low radiation might harm you
might be the thing that hurts you.
It's easy to put these people down;
most of them do not feel taken seriously
, which aggravates their situation.
They should be supported
But, it is important to be aware that, so far,
we have no solid evidence that electricity below safe limits has a negative impact on humans
In the economy of the world.  he attention we live in,
talking about potential unproven dangers can cause us to overlook other things that we know are actually dangerous to us.
Just one example
: Outdoor air pollution is responsible for 4.2 million premature deaths every  years
and it's clearly something we could act against today
However, to reassure people, and just to be really sure
There are already several long studies in progress
For example, the "Cosmos" study which  is testing the potential impacts of phone use on our hearts
by measuring the frequency and duration of phone calls,
but while we wait for the conclusion of this long-term study,
there are many more issues.  my urgents that we could focus on
"squeak"