Villages near Moscow: Troparevo, Chertanovo,
Medvedkovo, Belyaevo-Bogorodskoye, and, of course, Cheryomushki
they did not know that they were gaining immortality
in those sad days for them,
when they are swept off the face of the earth forever.
The village of Cheryomushki gave its name to Moscow's new buildings,
which are located in the south-west of our capital .
Now almost in any Soviet city
there are their Cheryomushki.
In the old days, when a person found himself in an unfamiliar city,
he felt lonely and lost.
Everything was strange: houses, streets, and even life
But now it's a completely different matter.
A man finds himself in an unfamiliar city,
but he feels at home in it.
To what absurdity our ancestors reached.
They agonized over every architectural project.
And now all cities are being built
typical movie theater "Raketa", where you can watch
a typical feature film .
-And you have some oranges -Oranges are there.
Everyone to the fair here, There are toys and firecrackers,
We have a lot of gifts here, Come to us, friends .
Street names are also not very diverse.
Which city doesn't have a 1st Sadovaya or 2nd Zagorodnaya street?,
3rd Factory, 1st Park, 2nd Industrial,
3rd Street Builders! Beautiful, isn't it?
Identical staircases cells
painted in a typical color colour.
Standard apartments are furnished standard furniture,
and the faceless doors are cut in typical locks.
Zhenechka, I have a question for you an unexpected offer.
Really?
Do not be afraid.
Zhen, let's meet New Year's Eve together?
Together, of course. We're getting together.
No.
You did not understand. Let's all be together, eh?
Is it like "not at all" ? I don't understand.
We won't go to the Katanyans.
No, Galya, this is inconvenient. We agreed
These are my friends . And you I made a crab salad.
I love crabs so much !
All the more so! Let's eat them together.
Where are we going to eat them?
How incomprehensible you are!
We'll meet you here, at your place.
Right here?
What about the Katanas?
Oleg offers to meet new year
in the Ostankino Tower restaurant.
Give me an aunt.
"It's spinning. "Who?"
The restaurant rotates.
Well, if you want to spin, then of course you do.
I want to celebrate the New Year with you.
Really? Come on!
"How stupid! "Who else are we going to call?"
That's the trick, no one.
Wait, what's "no one" ? And my mother? With us will meet
And my mother will leave. Everything will be prepared,
She'll set the table, and I'll help her. You have a world mother!
Great idea! Why didn't I figure it out myself?
But someone has to be smart, right?
"It'll be you ." - Eugene, stop it!
What about Katanyans ? I don't understand...
Oleg offers to meet me new year
in Suzdal in the monastery!
To hell with Oleg! To hell with the monastery
I don't want to go to a monastery I want to be with you.
With me?
Excuse me, how do I get to 3rd Stroiteley Street?
The face of the Builders behind those tall buildings.
"You'll see a church there-thank you."
We will meet New Year's Eve together. You and me.
I'll have a drink ...
Razbuyanus, raskhrabryu. ..
And finally, I'll tell you everything I have to say
Eugene!
Are you really going to ask me to marry you?"
After two years of dating...
Let's wait until the New Year, the chimes must strike ...
Let's wait...
It's just that I'm afraid that you have never have the guts.
This is cowardice .. the old one a bachelor.
You know, I already did proposal to one woman.
To my great surprise, she agreed
But when I imagined,
that she will live in my apartment. the room,
And every day. ..
Flash before my eyes with your eyes...
Back and forth, back and forth...
I couldn't stand it and ran away to Leningrad.
And you'll run away from me, too
No, I can't run away from you.
Everything is finally decided and irrevocably.
Held on, held on and collapsed.
Zhenya...
What do you think, when do people sing?
Singing?
When? At demonstrations.
- So... And what else? "They sing at the opera.
When they drink, they sing.
You idiot! Do you know when people sing?
- When there is no hearing or voice?- no.
"When they're happy ." "That's right.
No one will be in the house,
Except for twilight,
One winter day
In a through opening Uncluttered curtains,
Uncluttered curtain.
Only white wet lumps
Quick flash of the flywheel,
Only roofs, snow, etc.
No roofs or snow,
No roofs or snow.
And again it will draw frost,
And then he'll spin me around again
Last year's gloom And the affairs of winter are different,
And the business of winter is different.
But unexpectedly on the curtain A shiver of intrusion will run through you,
Measuring the silence with your steps, Measure the silence with your steps,
Measuring the silence with your steps, You, as the future, will enter.
You'll show up at the door,
In something white, without quirks,
It's really one of those things,
From which flakes are sewn,
From which flakes are sewn.
No one will be in the house,
Except for twilight,
One winter day In a through opening
Uncluttered curtain,
Uncluttered curtain.
- Maria Dmitrievna... "Hush!
Happy New Year.
Why are you shouting
And what?
"Mother! Who's there? "A neighbor came to get some onions.
"What happened - Pavlik, come back tomorrow.
I'm leaving for Leningrad today.
Have a nice trip!
Why are you being a bully
"Mom, who's there again "A telegram from Aunt Vera .
Do you remember when you were a child they taught us to speak
just the truth?
There are such cases, when it's a good idea to lie
And the fact that they are waiting for us in the bathhouse Mishka and Sasha?
It's nothing.
And from the bathhouse I fly to Leningrad.
Why are you flying to Leningrad?
Irka lingered there on a business trip,
And I'm flying to meet her new year. What happened
"It's still a mystery. "What secret?"
"You'll find out in time "Zhenya has no secrets from me.
Go to the bathhouse.
Eugene, I have to go. I still have so much to do!
- Galya!.. - what?
Galya...
The thing is...
Well, as they say?..
I love you.
I want you to be my wife.
But I'm always going to flash around right in front of your eyes.
Flash it.
I really want to do this.
Here's the key. Come back at 11 celebrate the New Year.
Can I get you a salad?"
Salad?
I didn't understand the main thing: do you agree?"
But I took the keys.
What does this mean?
And it doesn't mean anything.
See you tonight." Hi to Mom Pass on.
- Katanyans are not very good... "They'll be fine.
Mother!
Amid a noisy ball,
Accidentally...
In the anxiety of worldly vanity ...
"I think I'm getting married "I think so, too.
Well, how do you like Galya?
You're going to marry her, not me."
But you're my mother!
The main thing is that you remember it after getting married .
I understand that Galya is for you I don't like it.
I can't say I'm from her I'm thrilled,
but, in general, it is not stupid, well-mannered.
I see.
If you don't get married now, you'll never get married!
I'm 36 years old, by the way...
That's tactless of you remind me of my age.
I'm not offended, though.
Let go!
Come on, I'm not offended. I'm a global mom!
I'll get everything ready and go to a friend's house.
"Where did the glasses go ?" "We'll find it now." Glasses !
They're here
You won't find anything with this move.
They're not here.
Here they are!
And yet, what did she see in me?
She's a lot younger than me.
Besides, she's such a beauty!
I'm also surprised that she chose such a blockhead.
A blockhead?
Why did you tell her about Leningrad?
When you make an offer to one woman,
then they don't remember the other one.
"Ah, that's what they do! - Yes, it is.
Now I understand everything!
How to make an offer, I understand now.
Good-bye!
"Who's been calling all this time?" - Pavel.
He's leaving for Leningrad. I put him out so he wouldn't get in the way.
Maybe I should go after all to the bathhouse?
Nothing will be wrong,
if you celebrate the New Year clean.
It's decided, I'm going to wash up.
Bathroom in each apartment - That's correct.
This is a civilization.
"You're telling me "You."
But the washing process itself ,
which in the bathhouse looks like, as a solemn ceremony,
in the bathroom, just washing off the dirt.
And then, a wish "with light steam" in the bathroom!
In the fresh air.
But is there steam in the bathroom?
Misha is right, the bath cleanses.
Oh, guys!
No matter how beautiful it is here, But I have to go.
You're not a good person after all.
We're all waiting...
What are you waiting for?
Do you want to get away with it? Not celebrating your marriage ?
In the bathhouse?
Actually, Zhenya is right, they don't let you go to the bathhouse.
If it wasn't for me, you'd all be they disappeared here.
Here!
No, I won't, I can't.
One at a time, because personally I'm going to the airfield.
People, don't worry
Everyone needs to be in shape.
Guys, let's do it tomorrow. Come and see me.
I'll introduce you to my wife.
Tomorrow I will be in Leningrad.
Well, drink up.
I wonder what you chose?
Not "what", but "who"!
It's terrible: vodka after beer.
I had a night vision on duty...
Here's a chocolate bar, at least some of it a snack.
All right, let's have a sip.
Pavel, make a toast.
You're the best of us all eloquent.
"And you're the least intelligent of us all." "Thank you."
I say...
Here's to Zhenechka Lukashin.
Come on, no fooling around.
The shyest of us all,
which finally overcame this is the quality and married.
The last of us.
Zhen, it's serious now. Be happy!
"Be happy, Zhenya. "You should drink to that
This is really serious.
Hey, what's her name?"
She has a beautiful name.
Galya.
And, remarkably, rare.
Guys, the situation is hopeless.
For Galya!
For Galya to the bottom!
Well, Jackdaw, be happy!
What scoundrels you are !
I was on night duty...
Oh, it's warm!
Tell us how you met
That's the whole story.
She came to me to the clinic.
Is she sick?"
No.
She was dislocated.
Everything is clear. That's exactly why she she's marrying you.
Here's to both of them they were healthy .
Are you giving birth to them Put it away now!
My wife told me to take it for the guests.
If we continue at this rate, get promoted,
I won't get to the airfield.
Pasha, rely on me, I never get drunk.
Give me your ticket.
This is categorically me not for your health!
She'll think I'm an alcoholic!
Unheard of! Doctor refuses to drink to health .
The devil made me go with you in the bath.
Tell me how you are with her did you meet someone?
Will you tell me? With whom?
With Galya. Or do you have anyone else
No, I don't have anyone, I'm single.
"For what?" "Here's to the bachelor."
For a single life hooray!
You should drink to that
It's good for you!
But how can I imagine, what a scandal it will be,
If I maybe come home to celebrate the New Year!
People, I was born very an important toast.
You can't do this anymore, you're getting married today.
I haven't forgotten that.
If you forget, I'll remind you.
Guys, let's have a drink for our friendship!
Good girl!
You speak beautifully You're a natural speaker!
Move over a little.
Let's weigh in to bruderschaft.
How much are you and I in total can we pull it?
Guys, a lyric was born tender toast.
Everything! We need to go to the airfield.
"Why?" -Someone is flying to Leningrad.
"Let's go quickly. "We didn't go, we flew.
They strapped themselves in with sheets. From the screw!
Under the wing of an airplane Singing about something
Green sea of taiga.
Attention! Being announced boarding the TU-134 aircraft,
next flight 392 on the route Moscow-Leningrad.
Пассажиров просят пройти на посадку.
-По-моему, это наш самолет. -Я с тобой согласен.
А ты не помнишь, кто из нас летит?
Нет.
Подожди, положись на меня.
-Пойдем логическим путем. -Пойдем вместе.
-Ты летишь в Ленинград? -Нет.
И я нет.
Продолжается посадка в самолет ТУ-134.
Павел может лететь в Ленинград?
Может.
А Женя?
Тоже может.
Они оба могут.
Будем тянуть жребий?
Мы не будем полагаться на случай.
Мы в бане пили за что?
По Лукашину.
Потому что он женится.
-У тебя поразительная память. -Сейчас не об этом.
Значит, Женя летит в Ленинград
на собственную свадьбу.
И он бы об этом сказал, если бы его не развезло от усталости.
Подожди!
He met his the bride in the clinic,
When did she come to him for an appointment.
I'll give you an answer.
What does it mean?
That she came to Moscow on a business trip.
Iron logic.
Boarding ends to the TU-134 plane,
next flight 392 Moscow - Leningrad.
Be careful!
"Where are you taking me?" - Towards your happiness .
Wait a minute! It's good that we have it washed it.
Attention! Made a landing plane,
arriving on flight 392 from Moscow .
"Watch out! "Forced himself on my head!"
The plane landed, arrived from Moscow .
It's cold!
Heck!
You should drink less!
Pavlik!
Attention of flying passengers flight 361 to Krasnoyarsk.
The plane's departure is delayed until 24-00
according to weather conditions in Krasnoyarsk.
What time is it?
New Year's Eve is 2 hours and 50 minutes away.
Young man, watch out!
"Where am I?" "Same place I am."
"Where are you?" "At the airport.
On the way to Krasnoyarsk non-flying weather.
And in the worst case, I will meet New Year's Eve in this chair.
And in the best case?
Also in the chair, only in the air.
Did you celebrate the New Year in the air?
No. I don't want.
And I don't want to, but what to do
"Who are you?" - A person.
We saw Pavlik off, and now I'm going home.
Very well, go ahead.
- Happy New Year. "And you, too.
No need for familiarity.
It's a little early, comrade!
Are you free ?"
Please, 3rd Stroitelei Street,
building 25, apartment 12, 4th floor.
At least the 5th!
Taxi service!
Let me pass."
People! Happy New Year to you!
I'm finally home!
Arrived.
"No one will be in the house."..
What people! Aren't you afraid of me?
Caution!
I failed. Thanks.
Come on in.".. Only after you.
We don't bite?
Well, here we go.
Come visit me, apartment 12.
"Give me a lucky paw, Jim." Come on.
It doesn't work!
Happy New Year to you!
Dogs walk!
Mother!
Quiet, quiet...
Please wait.
Hey!..
Wake up, you hear!
Wake up immediately Get up!
Are you alive or not?
Ah, so!..
Wake up immediately Do you hear me?
Get up! What are you doing here?"
Don't shake me!
I'll get some sleep.
Who are you? How did you get here
"Don't drag me down "Get up!"
"It hurts!" "Get up now!"
You're disturbing my sleep
A nightmare!
Well, look out
I'll see you for the last time I'm warning you.
Oh, how good! More!
Oh, let's go.
Well, what is it?
Come on ! It's wet! Stunned!
Has everyone gone mad?
I'm not a flower bed.
Who are you, eh?
What a nightmare!
Get out of here!"
This is unheard of!
"What are you doing here?" "I'm sleeping here."
What is it? What do you want here?
Come on, stop fooling around
"Why not?" "Why are you sprawled out here
Come on, get out of here!"
Alive!
Rudeness! Not only that, you they broke into my apartment,
you're acting like a bandit!
What's the matter?
"To your apartment?" - Yes, I live here!
"Where do you think I live?" "I do not know.
I'm not interested at all. It's an outrage!
By the way, now here my fiancee Galechka is coming.
I don't want,
so that we can be caught together.
Explain to me why your will the bride come to me?
I'm not joking right now! My head is breaking.
What time is it?
Oh my God, it's almost 11. They must come to me.
And your presence here not necessarily.
Why your friends will come on New Year's Eve to my place?
I'm thirsty!
Are you out of your mind? Why are you being naughty?
Listen to me!
Do you have any sense?" Where do you think you are?"
I'm at home. 3rd street 25 Stroiteley Street...
No way!
I live on 3rd Stroitelei Street, house 25,
apartment 12.
No, honey.
Bryce
What are you hooligans about?!
My mother and I live here. The usable area is 32 meters.
No, it's my mom and me the apartment is 32 square meters.
Congratulations! We don't have much large apartments .
A very valuable observation.
Who rolled me up?
I would be extremely grateful to you I appreciate it,
if you would, as soon as possible, they disappeared
Don't beat me up! I demand respect for myself!
Mother!
My mother was gone.
I'll kill you !
"Whose mom left?" "Fortunately, we have different mothers .
Yes?
Sorry about that... And both moms left?
One of us, I think crazy.
I can guess who.
I know who, too.
Are you referring to me?
Caution!
Why did you rearrange my closet?
As it was introduced, so it stands.
This is my headset, Polish.
-830 rubles. - And 20 on top.
No, I gave 25.
That's your business.
What a nightmare! An obsession!
And our family screen snatched away!
Why did my mother put it on other people's plates?
Finally, you're getting started to see clearly
And what is there to see through?
So you entered, rearranged furniture. ..
We changed the plates.
Where did you put my chandelier?
I took it to a thrift store.
What for?
Where am I?
25 3rd Stroiteley Street, apartment 12.
That's right, this is my address, my word of honor.
But I have a feeling, That I'm not home.
That's fine!
You can leave safely.
Where will I go in this form?
"My dress ! "Don't expose me!"
"Give me your coat!" "You crushed my leg!"
What are you hooligans about?! This is my home, I'm registered here!
"Your house?" - Yes, mine and my mother's!
"I'll show you my passport." "Drunkard!
A hooligan! Where's my jacket?
"How do I know?" "Who knows?"
Grey herringbone pattern...
From Mostorg.
Here it is my jacket hanging.
Now I'll show you where I live, otherwise it breaks in...
Here it is ..
25 3rd Stroiteley Street, apartment 12, Moscow.
Read this document, by the way.
And everyone, please get out of here.
Come on, stop fooling around.
"What is it?" - Moscow!
Да, Москва.
-Yes? - Yes what ?
Do you think that you are in Moscow?
Where do you think I am?
Да, да..
What is it? In Moscow, my dear, in the capital.
Wait...
Why are you going there?
Why are you always poking around in my furniture?
"Please." "What have you got here?"
Well, what is it?
Leningrad, 3rd Stroiteley Street, 25, apartment 12.
Uh-huh what ?
Are you implying that I'm in Leningrad?
"Here! "Here's what?"
In Leningrad.
How did I get here?
Poor.
"We went to the bathhouse. - With light steam!
"Now go away!" "Where will I go?"
No need to wave your hands
Can you explain to me that I'm in Leningrad now?
This is now...
Is this a city on the Neva River?
Wait... I remember everything perfectly.
We went to the airfield to see Pavlik off.
Before that, we washed
Did I just fly away? Pavlik?
- Don't drink it "I don't drink at all .
It was an accident.
So I'm in Leningrad now?
What a nightmare!
So, the Pebble is now in Moscow,
And I'm on the floor in Leningrad.
Oh, God, I wish I could fly away to some other city.
Not necessary... What's going on there?
Don't open it, please!
- If you don't open it right away, it's worse. "Don't open it at all!
FYI, this is: him!
Who is "he"? I'll get dressed. Don't open it! I'm not wearing any pants.
"Hello," I said. "Hello," I said.
Happy New Year, Nadenka.
Well, come on.
"How did you get there?" "Don't ask me!
It's slippery and icy right now.
Be careful, I've got you such a reckless driver.
Thank you, Nadyusha.
If you only knew, honey, I've missed you so much.
I've been waiting for you, too.
Thank you, my love.
I've made you mine New Year's gift.
Thanks. I made it too a present for you.
But he's in the room.
Ippolit, I owe you something to report.
It's impossible to believe
You'll die laughing!
I come home, and on my the ottoman
a strange man is sleeping.
You know, I couldn't do it wake me up.
I watered it from the kettle.
- So... "I'm begging you!
Happy New Year! Behave yourself!
I'm begging you!
Great gift. Thanks.
I'll explain everything to you. It's not her fault.
It's my fault.
I'd like to know one small detail
Find out.
"Who's that?" "I don't know him.
This is a strange man.
Man...
How did it get here?
This is an incredible coincidence.
He lives there too
on the 3rd Stroiteley Street, 25, apartment 12, only in Moscow.
In Moscow!
"What's this?" "And these are my pants ."
Be careful, remember!
He and his friends went to the bathhouse. There they drank.
"Look at him. "I'll make it."
And it was stuffed in by mistake get on the plane.
Where, in the bathhouse?
No, there are no planes in the bathhouse.
And they don't ask you!
Tell him we bathed there with Pavlik.
Oh, shut up !
They drove from the bathhouse to the airport.
Pavlik is seen off.
- To see Pavlik off. - Pavlik is also here!
Pavlik isn't here. I'll take his place.
Instead of Pavlik
did this guy come in?
No one was supposed to come.
"He got on the plane by mistake. "Was it checked in?"
What kind of luggage? Although maybe, I don't remember.
I'll explain everything in a moment, but I need to get dressed.
Hold this, my friends .
I'll get dressed and explain everything to you.
"How unsympathetic he is! "Just disgusting!"
No, this is a moot point. I didn't do anything wrong to you.
"How did he end up in your bed?" "By accident.
Sorry, girl.
What is your name?
He's in your bed, but he doesn't even know your name.
No need to push!
Ippolit, wait!
Something fell on me!
If he knew my name, would you have stayed?
"Stop it!" "Oh, come on !
I don't know his name either. This is the first time I've seen him!
Now I believe you. Modern mores !
Why do you keep dropping me?
I hit my shoulder right here.
I'm leaving now for good.
Let's not spoil New Year's Eve.
Don't make me make excuses.
I didn't do anything wrong to you.
Some drunkard got into my apartment!
I'm not a drunk, I'm a doctor.
Suppose he happened to be in Leningrad,
and it has the same address.
"But why did you let him in?" "I didn't let him in!"
You will finally understand I entered by myself!
"I have a key that fits." "You gave him the key?"
I didn't give it to you! Well, how stupid you are!
Don't push me Some pushers.
Why don't you believe me
Why don't you believe us?
I hate this guy as much as you do.
Of course, I'm disgusted with myself.
Sorry.
Goodbye.
The house is exactly the same.
A young man like me get to the airport.
There's a 30 bus around the corner it stops.
-Is this really Leningrad? - You should drink less.
Well, stop sulking.
Don't you dare be jealous of me.
If I fall in love with someone, you'll be the first to know.
"Don't you dare be jealous."
I'm not angry, it's just that you are too You must understand
-I come, and here... "I know what you mean.
I understand very well.
I'd roll my eyes if I were you this!
His appearance in your home, fits your character.
"Why not?" "You're careless.
Be quiet! You're a bad girl.
I don't think he's in my house it could have appeared.
It's weird that you're even using it found it.
You never know what's lying around there.
You guessed it, I didn't get it right away I noticed it.
These are real French ones perfume!
"They're so expensive!" "It's nothing.
"And I've made you something." "Another gift?"
You are welcome. It's a razor the most recent brand.
Why, Nadia!
With floating knives.
Such an expensive gift.
I take an example from you.
I forgot to wear my birthday dress dress up!
Now, wait a minute.
You can't come here.
You should drink less
It suits you very well.
I am very glad that you like.
I really like.
Let's spend the old year.
After all, this year I met you.
And i you.
How I love to meet New Year's Eve!
Nadia...
What?
Nadenka, I have a question for you...
One request.
Here...
I love it when you sing.
You're just being biased about me.
Yes, indeed!
Still how biased!
On my street What year is it
Footsteps sound, My friends are leaving.
My friends Slow care
That darkness Outside the windows is pleasant.
O loneliness, How cool is your character,
Flashing a pair of compasses Iron,
How cold it is You're closing the circle,
Do not listen to Useless assurances.
Let me stand on tiptoe In your forest,
At the other end Slow motion gesture,
Find foliage And bring it to your face,
And feel orphaned Like bliss.
Grant me peace Your libraries,
Your concerts Strict motives ,
And wise, I'll forget those,
Who died Or still alive .
And I will know Wisdom and sorrow,
Your secret meaning They'll trust me with items ,
Nature leaning against To my shoulders,
Will announce its own Children's secrets .
And then Out of tears, out of the dark ,
Out of poor ignorance Of the past,
My friends Beautiful features
They will appear And they will dissolve again.
"Whose poems are these?" - Akhmadulina.
What should I put for you
"Salad or roast beef?" - Salad... and roast beef.
Nadia, listen to me...
Tonight is the last night Old year's day I intend to
put the question squarely.
It seems to me,
that it's time for us to end our idleness.
What do you think of that
I look at it with pleasure.
But only if you don't get so jealous.
You see, I'm not young anymore, but I can feel it...
Who is it?
I have no idea.
No, I'm sorry!
I'm sorry.
Sorry, I was too shy to open it with my key.
What do you need again?
You see, here's the thing...
I have no one else in this city but you.
And no money, either.
Not a penny, as it turned out.
And they won't give you a ticket without money.
Could you borrow 15-16 rubles?
I'll send it to you tomorrow.
I'll send it by wire.
You'll have to pay to leave us alone."
Please pay me.
Now, man to man: what were you doing here?"
"Right here?" "Yes, here.
For God's sake, don't worry, I'll explain everything to you.
You see, we have a tradition.
Every year on December 31, my friends and I go to the sauna.
We're washing up. It's been a long time coming
Pavlik was supposed to fly to Leningrad after the bath.
I was supposed to get married today.
On whom?
Get married?
Well, it doesn't matter.
We had a drink in the bathhouse.
For my bride, for me.
Are you an alcoholic?
No, I don't drink at all .
I drink tea, coffee, well, kefir,
different drinks, water...
"I'm sorry, Nadenka. "Get a grip on yourself!
I'm calm!
And after the bath we went to the airport.
Well, we had another drink there, but I don't remember that.
I think me instead Pavlik was shoved on the plane.
My word of honor.
"It's very simple. -And, most importantly, reliably.
"What were you doing on the plane?" "I was flying.
"Fly?  "Sleep."
I was asleep...
Suppose you don't remember, how did you get on the plane,
but, how did you get out of there, you should have remembered
Yes! You must remember.
But I don't remember.
Because I remember coming here by taxi.
I said my home address the address and I was brought.
Let's assume the key fits.
Nadenka...
Let's assume the key fits, the address matched,
but you couldn't help but notice that the apartment furniture is different!
Yes, the same!
But the apartment is a mess, because people have moved!
We just moved in too! With my mother.
That's enough! Here's 15 rubles for you and go away!
Friends, you helped me out so much!
You have to pay for pleasure
I just need to give you one last kiss
At least wait until I'm gone.
"Hippolytus, wait! "Don't make an idiot of me!
Ippolit!
"What did you tell him?" "The truth.
What other truth?
Please help me up.
I'm completely exhausted with you today.
I told him we were going to the bathhouse.
December, 31st. This is our tradition. We wash . Annually.
I explained this to him in detail.
Don't cry,please I'm asking you very much.
I'll catch up with him now. Ippolit!
Wait, don't leave!
Ippolit, I'm sorry, I do not know your patronymic!
Wait!
Don't leave ! Wait!
Well, don't be a fool!
In fact, be you a man!
He's gone.
He drives faster than I do I run.
Take your 15 rubles.
Thank you, I'll tell you tomorrow I'll send it to you.
I hate you, you hate me ruined my life
He'll be back, I promise, you'll see.
Hot-tempered and jealous they leave quickly.
If only you knew how I understand you.
My situation is even worse.
Me in Moscow in an empty room a woman is waiting in the apartment,
The one I love.
And I'm here in Leningrad.
So what?
Does she know where you are ?"
No, she's going crazy.
"Call her. "I don't have a ticket."
Call on credit, call on the vending machine.
You are a sensitive person.
"Can I get undressed "Do whatever you want.
Thanks.
The girl!
Happy New Year to you Happy New Year!
Accept the order.
To Moscow.
Phone number in Moscow?
454-60-21.
Who will do? Galya.
Well, if it fits...
In Leningrad? Just a moment.
Quietly.
"What's your phone number?"
-14-50-30.
The girl! 14-50-30.
When?
And earlier?..
They said within an hour.
Lord...
I'll sit on the stairs, you can call me."
Or, if you want, explain all Gale by yourself.
I'll go now.
No, you can explain yourself.
Until the New Year left 2 minutes .
Open the champagne.
It's in the refrigerator.
And then no luck! What is it today?
Excuse me.
Happy New Year.
What's your name?"
Nadia.
My name is Zhenya.
Happy New Year, Nadia.
Happy New Year.
The New Year starts well.
You can't say anything
Already yes.
There is such a sign:
how to celebrate the New Year, so you can spend it
What kind of doctor are you?
I'm a surgeon.
And you?
I'm a teacher.
Russian language and literature.
Literature is great.
I need to call the airport, find out when the first flight is scheduled.
-How to do it "There's a book in there.
Hello there! The girl! Happy New Year.
Be kind when first flight to Moscow?
Is this the first one?
At seven o'clock in the morning.
Nadia, don't worry, I'll talk to Galya and leave.
It seems to me that you will never you can't leave here.
Well, please don't worry.
Everything will work out.
Here is Moscow!
Moscow?!
I think it was the caller Ippolit.
"Who?" - Ippolit.
Why did you pick up the phone? Who asked you to?
How did I know? I thought it was Moscow.
I'm sorry, for God's sake.
Hello there! Hello there!
Leningrad?
Don't touch it, I'll do it myself.
Hello there! Yes, Moscow was booked.
Moscow? Hello there!
Sorry.
"Galechka, it's me. -Are you in Leningrad?
Thank you for even calling.
Galechka, congratulations...
Happy New Year to you.
You called to congratulate me Happy New Year to me?
"Not only that. "I'm touched.
I'll explain everything to you now.
An incredible thing happened history.
I just can't believe it
And I'm worried, all the hospitals I called all the morgues.
And you just ran away from me.
I love you very much.
Now I understand why you he told me about Leningrad.
That's a different story altogether.
This has nothing to do with you.
We are with the guys on December 31 we go to the sauna.
We have a tradition.
I have nothing to talk about with you to talk
You can check it out My phone number is 14-50-30.
I'm taking the first flight.
You can take your time.
I'll leave your key on the table."
No, don't, don't leave it!
It's me! Don't pick up the phone! Hello there! Galya!
3 minutes ? Thanks.
Well, that seems to be all.
I don't have a fiancee .
Never mind, you'll find another one.
Another one? What do you know about this?!
I've been searching all my life.
Never married.
And now, I think, I found it...
Why are you yelling at me?
That's enough! Don't give stupid advice.
Don't forget that you're in my apartment.
Damn your apartment!
Together with you and your Othello.
Ham!
Just a cad.
I'm a cad, and you are ...
Well, what am I?! Get out!"
But I'm not going anywhere! I have nowhere to go.
"My plane leaves at 7 a.m." "Then I'll leave."
Good riddance. And I'm hungry.
"This number won't work!" "I'm hungry!"
You're a shrew.
One more word and the next plate will fly to your head.
And your Galya is gone.
And you did the right thing.
Now she will find the real person.
"Well?" "What do you mean?"
Don't mind?
Nothing to cover
No, I'm just afraid of the next plate.
It is right.
This is Hippolytus.
Jump from the balcony.
I wanted to break my legs.
Nadenka, Happy New Year to you!
We were walking by and decided to take a look at you.
They left my man downstairs.
-You can't put him out later-Yes, it's hard to put a man out.
Well, where is he? Show me."
Here it is. In all its glory.
Valia.
Tanya.
Dear Ippolit Georgievich,
"We're Nadya's friends. "And we work at the same school.
And she's hiding you from us.
We have specially stopped by to congratulate you.
You should know which one we have a wonderful Nadia.
How teachers love it, parents and even children.
She's very responsive.
Conducts community service and it hangs on the honor roll.
I'm not the one...
Don't listen to him! Have a seat."
"Call your husband." "What's there to get in the way?"
You can't interfere, Nadia and I don't know each other .
What's your middle name?
Vassilyevna!
With Nadezhda Vasilyevna we've known each other since 11 o'clock.
Hippolytus, don't fool around. All.
Let him fool around, he has it's so nice coming out.
But I'm not Hippolytus.
I love yours so much relationships.
The relationship is quite complex.
I need a towel, or it'll shoot."
Don't, I'll be careful.
Well, brothers, for your family health happiness!
Thank you, I won't drink.
"No, no, I won't. "You will
"Are you out of your mind?" "Drink up!"
- Well, guys, it's bitter! "It's bitter!
I absolutely refuse Don't make a fool of me!
Leave me alone! I don't want to go with you kissing!
Stop it! Well, explain you are them, finally!
Nadia, Nadia, come on !
And even after that, I'm not Hippolytus.
Ippolit Georgievich,
do you like the way she sings?
I don't know, I didn't hear it.
"You never sang to him?" "This is an unforgivable mistake.
-I don't like amateur performances! -This is not an amateur activity
Give us our favorite -  "Trailers".
On Tikhoretskaya Street The train will leave,
The trailer will move, The platform will remain,
Brick wall, Railway station hours,
White handkerchiefs, White handkerchiefs,
White handkerchiefs,
White handkerchiefs, Her eyes are sad.
It will start asking questions Smoking compartment
About my past And the present,
Navru with three boxes, Let them be surprised,
Who did I say goodbye to, Who did I say goodbye to,
It's none of your business.
Open your soul to me Sailor in a vest,
How hard it is in the world Live the poor thing,
It will get off at the station And say goodbye,
The trailer will move, The trailer will start moving,
The trailer will start moving,
The trailer will move, And he will stay.
On Tikhoretskaya Street The train will leave,
The trailer will move, The platform will remain,
Brick wall, Railway station hours,
White handkerchiefs, White handkerchiefs,
White handkerchiefs,
White handkerchiefs, Her eyes are sad.
I've never heard that before.
Brothers, it's a good thing!
Come on, the guy's cold."
Nadia and Ippolit, be happy !
I'm tired of objecting I'm not Hippolytus.
Good luck to you! Nadechka, let me kiss you!
Everything!
A good guy, positive and serious.
God grant you happiness ! Happy New Year!
Why did you do this?
And you also started talking like a parrot!
"I'm not Hippolytus, I'm not Hippolytus."
What do you want me to tell them about the bathhouse?"
So that the whole school can talk the next day,
That I'm celebrating the New Year with some crook!
I'm not a crook.
I'm an unhappy person.
As if an unhappy person can't be a crook.
How are you going to show them the real Hippolytus now?"
And the real one probably won't be there anymore.
Why do I have to comfort you all the time
Why is no one comforting me?
It's a thousand times worse for me, even if you're at home.
"But it's your fault , not mine! "But I didn't mean to.
I'm also a victim of circumstances.
Can I eat?"
Eat as much as you can.
Don't throw it away.
I haven't eaten anything since last year.
Delicious!
"Did you cook it yourself?" "Of course, by myself.
I wanted to show off.
And you did it
In the sense that I love to eat delicious food
I hate cooking
True, there is still no time with my loafers.
"Re-educating them?"- yes.
I am them, and they are me.
I'm trying to teach them to think
Just a little bit
And have your own judgment about everything.
"Can I have some more?" "Please."
"What do they teach you?" "Probably the same."
This is not a fish, not a jellied fish.
This... I don't have enough horseradish for it.
And I am a representative of the most conservative profession.
We can compete with you.
No, I'm serious.
It is especially difficult to have your own opinion here.
Maybe it's wrong.
Doctors ' mistakes are costly.
Teacher mistakes are less noticeable ,
but, in the end, they are no less expensive.
Maybe you're right .
And yet we have with you
the most wonderful professions, the most necessary ones.
Judging by the salary, no.
Yes, probably.
You know, Nadia, that's when your friends praised you,
God knows why, I need this it was nice.
Don't suck up.
By the way, unlike you, your friend noticed,
that I'm a positive person.
You didn't break in to her house.
That's right, I'll go to her again I didn't break in!
We are with you in a peculiar way Let's celebrate the New Year.
If we are with you ever Meet me, by chance,
I think we're going to die laughing.
Let's just say I wasn't laughing,
When I saw you here spread out
What about me?
Imagine me waking up in your apartment,
and suddenly a woman he pours water on me from the kettle.
And I say: "Get out of here!"
And I say: "Roll out yourself from my apartment !"
I'm just outraged confused
Who are you?
If the thief, why did you lie down?
The thief who got tired and went to bed in a robbed apartment.
And you know, at first I thought so didn't like it
And you were like that to me disgusting !
I can imagine
Open