Even since school we can recall that in Russian pronouns are personal -
are those that directly refer to the one who performs the action.
These are such words as "I", "you", "we", "you", "he", "she", "it", "they".
And then there are
possessive pronouns. They refer to something whose subject is: "my," "your," "our," "your."
These words can be modified: "my", "your", "your", "your", "from our".
However, from the words "he", "she", "it", "they"
possessive pronouns
are not formed.
And the form "their" is not a possessive pronoun, but a genitive plural form
of the plural "they."
That is, it is already a case form in itself, it cannot once again
it cannot change its gender, number, and case.   To correct this unfortunate misunderstanding.
some people add the suffix -n-
and endings of possessive pronouns.
This is how not only the word "ikhni," but also "yevoniy" and "herni" appeared.
*music* Speech nuance
Nuance 1.
"THEIR" versus "THEIR."
History of the word
The first time in a written text in Russian the word ikhni appears as early as
in 1595!
The first time the word ikh is found in the Russian written text, even in the year 1595, "They cheered us, but they said that in the past, in the ninety-fourth year,
they had taken a fiefdom, a town and an ostrog for us for the Siberian roads of their fathers".
Almost 200 years later a linguist speaks about this form for the first time.
in 1788
in the "Russian Grammar" the scholar Barsov writes about it. He says that this form
is indeed widespread among the people, but nevertheless it
Nevertheless it is a colloquial form and anyway "is not adopted in common use".
However, during the whole 19th century the frequency of the use of this word becomes wider and wider,
And it becomes more and more neutral. Examples from literature.
Griboyedov:
- Is this your man?  - Ichnyi-s.
Gogol:
"He's gone over to their side, he's all theirs now."
Notice how the author plays on style. In one sentence
both "their" and "theirs."
Tolstoy:
"And so I keep all the expense; and their German only smokes a pipe, and that is all."
However, in all these early examples from literature the word "ikh" is used by people of clearly
of low education. Those who do not speak
the literary language sufficiently. They are a servant,
a Zaporozhe Jew, a soldier-denier. Yes, it's a good device for conveying the speech
of the illiterate or rural population, but no more than that.
However, there was one lover of the word who put it even into the mouths of
of educated characters and could even write it himself.
"Kiss my children, my angels, my gods. Yours and theirs is all F. Dostoevsky."
Of course, in his texts Fyodor Mikhailovich wrote simply "them" dozens of times more often.
But for such a language game, it was sometimes possible to bring back a dashing folk word.
But by the early 20th century, even
serious people in serious texts without a blush on their face
to use the word "theirs." And it's not some subtle wordsmiths and acrobats of the pen,
they're people of a completely different profession, not writers,
not philologists. For example, Dmitri Ivanovich Mendeleev.
a chemist, a scientist. And Peter Alexeyevich Kropotkin.
a revolutionary.
"However, our hopes that these young men would become propagandists among the other
workers, whose situation is much worse than theirs, were not quite fulfilled."
"Lithuania and Poland for their many
pressures on our country, too, have paid the price of subjugation and partition, because Russian realism
is higher and stronger than their Latin-inspired beginnings."
But comes
Soviet power.
After all the twists and turns
language policy in the twenties, in the late
1930-х
The authorities come to a new conclusion - the language must be strictly rationed.
A lot of words with the dictionary markings "colloquial," "obl.", "dial.", "simple." are stigmatized.
School teachers, editors, dictionary compilers
deny them life.
And "theirs" falls into their ranks.
No matter what educational literature you open, it says "it's wrong" everywhere,
that "such words" supposedly "don't exist." As if anything has changed now!
Read more about language policy in the Soviet Union
and how attitudes towards the norm have changed throughout history,
you can see in the video "Conversation Two".
*music* How the word "IHNY" came about
Here we should immediately discard the assumption that the appearance of the word "ikhni" is
Ukrainian influence.
"Ikhni" is a word in itself, which became widespread
only with the light hand of the Soviet rulemakers of the 1920s.
Of course, this form existed before. But first, it was not considered
literary, and secondly, it was not predominant.
Exactly the same can be said of the Belarusian language
with its forums "yegny", "yagony", "ikhni".
Even rarer is the word "ichni" in Polish. Nevertheless, it is there.
It has never claimed to be a literary norm,
it has never been in wide use. And in writing, it has always been used only
to convey the speech of the villagers.
"The apostates are called Hussites, and it comes from their prophet Gus, not from geese at all."
Although in Polish, in any written text.
the word first appeared even earlier than in Russian.
Back in the 15th century one can find not only the word "ichni" and not only "jejski" and "jegojski,
but even "twójski", "mojski", "naski", "waski".
At the very beginning of the video, we already mentioned that from the words "he", "she", "it", "they",
that is, third person pronouns,
forms of possessive pronouns are not formed.
But why?
Originally, this situation was characteristic of all Slavic languages without exception,
and, more broadly, all Indo-European!
Slavic, Germanic, Baltic, Romanic, Indo-Iranian, and others.
Look, now in Russian we have
third person personal pronouns, but
we don't have possessive pronouns; well, like there are none,
but even that wasn't always the case.
Once upon a time we didn't have third person personal pronouns either!
All of these words are derived from short forms of the word "oni."
Let us now turn our eyes to other ancient languages.
Latin.
Here are their personal and possessive pronouns:
ego - meus
tu - tUUs (*there's a reservation*)
nos - noster
vos - vester.
Personal pronouns and, consequently, third person possessive
are simply absent. Instead of them are used
hic", "ille" and others, which mean "that", "this".
Sanskrit.
aham - madīyaḥ
tvam - tvadīyaḥ
vayam - asmadīyaḥ
yūyam - yuṣmadīyaḥ.
There are simply no personal pronouns and hence no third person possessive pronouns.
The personal pronouns are replaced by "saḥ", "eṣaḥ"
and others that mean "that," "that."
Now let's look at modern languages!
French is a descendant of Latin and already has third person personal pronouns:
il, he, elle, she.
But they in turn come from the index Latin "ille", "illa".
"this," "this."
"their" in French is "leur.
This word comes directly from the Latin "illorum"-
"their" or "these."
It was, as in Russian, the genitive form of the
plural.
However, modern French also
literally says "theirs," that is, he modifies the word like adjectives.
For example,
"leurs amis" - their(their) friends
"leurs mots" - their(s) words.
If there is a hole in the language system, one wants unconsciously to fill it with something,
but if there are possessive pronouns
first and second person possessive pronouns, why don't we use similar models
why not also build third person forms?
Finally, let us take a curious example from the Baltic languages.
Here is how Lenin said: "We will go the other way!", -
so would the Baltic languages.
They didn't make up words like "their", "her", "his",
they just removed the words "my", "your", "our", "your".
In Latvian, however, the words "my" and "your" still remain.
For example, "mana sieva" - my wife
"tavs brālis" - your brother.
But the words "our" and "your" no longer exist.
For example,
"mūsu valdība" - our government.
Literally it means "our government".
Or "jūsu nauda" - your money.
Literally it is "your money".
And the Lithuanian language doesn't even leave the words "my," "your," anymore.
For example,
"mano nuotraukos" - my pictures,
"mano gynyba" - my defense,
"tavo problemos" - your problems.
As we can see, the Baltic languages
have made their changes in exactly the same way by the so-called analogy.
But another thing is that this analogy went in a completely different direction
than most other European languages.
* music plays* Bottom line.
The emergence of the word "ichni" in Slavic languages
is a natural and expected phenomenon.
But it's worth remembering that any word, it doesn't float somewhere in the space
of thoughts and ideas, but it has its own peculiar both stylistic and social coloring.
Therefore, whoever says that the word "ichni" does not have one's mind.
But whoever says you can use the word "Ichnyi",
we say to him, "You can, but be careful."
Arrivederci, friends!
*music* Links to materials on the topic of the issue - under the video