From school, we can remember that in Russian there are personal pronouns -
these are those that directly designate the one who performs the action.
These are words such as "I", "you", "we", "you", "he", "she", "it", "they".
And there are
possessive pronouns.  They name that whose object is: "mine", "your", "our", "your".
These words can change: "to mine", "your", "your", "your", "from ours".
However, from the words "he", "she", "it", "they"
possessive pronouns are
not formed.
And the form "their" is not a possessive pronoun, but the plural genitive form
of the word "they".
That is, this is already a case form in itself, it cannot
change again in gender, number and case.
To correct this unfortunate misunderstanding
, some people add the suffix -n-
and the endings of possessive pronouns to this form.
This is how not only the word “theirs” appeared, but also “evony” and “eyny”.
*music*
Speech nuance
Nuance 1
"IKH" vs. "IKHNIY"
History of the word
The first time in a written text in Russian the word "ikhniy" occurs as early
as 1595!
“That they beat us with their foreheads, and said that in the past, in the ninety-fourth year, they
took from them for us for the Siberian roads of their fathers their patrimony, town and prison.”
Almost 200 years later, a linguist speaks about this form for the first time.
in 1788, the
scientist Barsov writes about this in the Russian Grammar.  He says that this form is
indeed widespread among the people, but nevertheless it is
colloquial and still "not accepted into general use."
However, throughout the 19th century, the frequency of use of this word is expanding and growing,
and it becomes more and more neutral.  Examples from the literature.
Griboyedov:
Is this your man?
- Theirs-s
Gogol:
"He went over to their side, he is now completely theirs."
Pay attention to how the author plays on style.  In one sentence
, both "their" and "theirs" are found.
Tolstoy:
“And so I keep everything;  and their German only smokes a pipe, and that’s all.
However, in all these early examples from literature, the word “theirs” is used by people of obviously
low education.  Those who do not speak the
literary language sufficiently.  This is a servant, a
Zaporozhye Jew, a batman.  Yes, this is a good technique for transmitting the speech of an
illiterate or rural population, but nothing more.
However, there was one lover of this word, who even put it into the mouths of
educated characters and even could write it himself.
“Kiss the kids, angels, my gods.  Yours and theirs are all F. Dostoevsky.
Of course, in his texts, Fyodor Mikhailovich wrote simply “them” dozens of times more often.
But for such a language game, sometimes it was possible to return a dashing folk word.
But by the beginning of the 20th century, even
serious people in serious texts without a blush on their faces could
use the word “theirs”.  And moreover, these are not some subtle words and acrobats of the pen,
these are people of completely different professions - not writers,
not philologists.  For example, Dmitri Ivanovich Mendeleev is a
chemist and scientist.  And Pyotr Alekseevich Kropotkin is a
revolutionary.
“However, our hopes that these young people would become propagandists among the rest of the
workers, whose situation is much worse than theirs, were not entirely justified.”
“Lithuania and Poland, for their numerous
pressures and on our country, paid with subjugation and division, because Russian realism is
higher and stronger than theirs from the Latin inspired beginnings.”
But the
Soviet power comes.
After all the vicissitudes of
language policy in the 1920s, in the
late 1930s, the
authorities came to a new conclusion - the language should be extremely rigidly standardized.
A lot of words with dictionary marks "colloquial", "reg.", "dial.", "simple."  are branded with disgrace.
School teachers, editors, compilers of dictionaries
deny them life.
And "theirs" falls into their number.
Whatever educational literature you open, it is written everywhere that “this is wrong”,
that “there are no such words”.  It's like something has changed!
For more information about the language policy in the Soviet Union
and how the attitude towards the norm has changed throughout history,
you can watch the video "Second Conversation".
*music*
How the word “THEHNIY” appeared
Here it is worth discarding the assumption that the appearance of the word “theirs” is a
Ukrainian influence.
"Їhniy" is a word in itself, which became widespread
only with the light hand of the Soviet rule-makers of the 20s.
Of course, this form existed before.  But firstly, it was not considered
literary, and secondly, it was not predominant.
Exactly the same can be said about the Belarusian language
with its forums "eyny", "yagony", "ihni".
Even less often the word "theirs" can be found in the Polish language.  Nevertheless, it is there.
It never claimed to be called a literary norm,
it was never in wide use.  And the letter has always been used only
to convey the speech of the villagers.
“Apostates are called Hussites, and this is taken from their prophet Hus, and not at all from geese.”
Although in Polish
this word first appeared in any written text even earlier than in Russian.
As far back as the 15th century, one can find not only the word "ichni" and not only "jejski" and "jegojski",
but even "twójski", "mojski", "naski", "waski".
At the very beginning of the video, we already mentioned that the words “he”, “she”, “it”, “they”,
that is, third-person pronouns,
do not form possessive pronouns.
But why?
Initially, this situation was typical for all Slavic languages without exception, and
even more widely - all Indo-European ones!
Slavic, Germanic, Baltic, Romanesque, Indo-Iranian - and so on.
Look, now in Russian we have
personal pronouns of the third person, but
we don’t have possessive ones;  well, like they don't exist,
but even this state of affairs was far from always.
Once upon a time, we didn’t even have third-person personal pronouns!
All these words come from short forms of the word "onyi".
Let's now turn our eyes to other ancient languages.
Latin language.
Here are their personal and possessive pronouns:
ego - meus
tu - tUUs (* clause here *)
nos - noster
vos -
vester There are simply no personal pronouns and, accordingly, possessive third persons
.  Instead, the
words "hic", "ille" and others are used, which mean "that", "this".
Sanskrit.
aham - madīyaḥ
tvam - tvadīyaḥ
vayam - asmadīyaḥ
yūyam -
yuṣmadīyaḥ There are simply no personal pronouns and, accordingly, possessive third persons.
Instead of personal words, the words "saḥ", "eṣaḥ"
and others are used, which mean "that", "this".
Now let's look at modern languages!
French is a descendant of Latin, and it already has third-person personal pronouns:
il - he, elle - she.
But they, in turn, come from demonstrative Latin "ille", "illa"
"this", "this".
"their" in French is "leur".
This word directly comes from the Latin "illorum" -
"them" or "these."
This, as in Russian, was the genitive
plural form.
However, the modern French also
literally says "theirs", that is, he changes this word like adjectives.
For example,
"leurs amis" - their (s) friends
"leurs mots" - their (s) words
If there is a hole in the language system, a person wants to unconsciously fill it with something,
but if there are possessive
first and second person pronouns, then  why
not build the forms of the third one on the basis of similar models?
Finally, let's take a curious example from the Baltic languages.
That's how Lenin said: "We'll go the other way!"
- just like the Baltic languages would say.
They did not come up with the words “theirs”, “hers”, “evony”,
they simply removed the words “mine”, “your”, “ours”, “your”.
True, the words “mine” and “your” still remain in the Latvian language.
For example, “mana sieva” is my wife,
“tavs brālis” is your brother.
But the words "our", "your" are no longer there.
For example,
"mūsu valdība" is our government.
Literally, it is "us government".
Or "jusu nauda" - your money.
Literally "you money".
And the Lithuanian language has not even left the words “mine”, “your”.
For example,
“mano nuotraukos” are my photos,
“mano gynyba” is my defense,
“tavo problemos” are your problems.
As we can see, the Baltic languages
d out their changes in the same way according to the so-called analogy.  But
another thing is that this analogy went in a completely different direction
than in most other European languages.
*music plays*
Results
The appearance of the word "theirs" in the Slavic languages is a natur
l and expected phenomenon.  But
it is worth remembering that every word, it does not float somewhere in the space of
thoughts and ideas, but it has its own peculiar stylistic and social coloring.
Therefore, whoever says that the word "theirs" does not exist - he does not even have a mind.
But whoever says that the word “theirs” can be used
, we will say to him: “It is possible, but carefully!”.
Arividerchi, friends!
*music*
Links to materials on the topic of the release - under the video