Once upon a time... a very long time ago now,
about last Friday,
there lived a little bear under the name of Winnie the Pooh.
And why 'under the name'?
Because it said "Winnie the Pooh" above his door,
and he lived under it.
One day Winnie the Pooh went into the woods to get some food.
He always didn't mind getting something to eat.
He was also a poet, and in his spare time, he wrote poems...
...and even songs. Something like this:
Tram-param-purum... in the back of his head pum-pum-pum-param.... shrieks
Poom-poom...  Poom-poom-poom....
If I'm scratching in the back of my head - no problem!
There's sawdust in my head - yes, yes, yes!
But though there's sawdust in there, there's shouting and yelling...
And also noisemakers, marshmallows, snot-noses...
I compose quite well sometimes - yes! (ding, ding)
Winnie the Pooh lives well!
That's why he sings those songs out loud!
It doesn't matter what he does if he doesn't lose weight
...and he won't lose weight... ...as long as he gets his food in time... YES! (gurgle!)
Trump-pump-pump-pump-pump-pump-pump-pump-pump!
Trum-purum-pum-pum, pum-pur-pum-pum Pum-pum-pum!
Pum-pum-pum-pum-pum..... Poom-poom-poom-poom....
Poom-poom-poom-poom... pum-pum
zzz-zz-zzzzzz
This zzzzz is for a reason.
The tree itself can't buzz.
So someone's buzzing around here.
Why would you buzz if you're not a bee?
I think so. What are bees for in the world?
To make honey.
I think so. What's honey for?
For me to eat it.
I think so.
If bears were bees,
they wouldn't thought...
would never thought of building a house so high.  OH! The bear loves honey. (boom) Ow!
Why - who will understand? In fact, why does he like honey so much? Oh, ma...!
So Winnie the Pooh went to his best friend Piglet,
who lived in a house marked "Trespasser B."
And who was the Trespasser V. - even Piglet didn't know about it.
- Good morning, Winnie the Pooh!
- Good morning, Piglet.
I wonder if you have a balloon?
- A balloon?
Yes. I was just passing by and I thought:
"I wondered if Piglet had a balloon."
- What do you need a balloon for?
HONEY - What? Honey. - Who is it that goes to get honey with balloons?
- I do.
And just the day before Piglet visited Rabbit,
and they gave him two beautiful balloons -
a blue one and a green one.
- Which one do you like better?
Here's what. When you go to get honey, the main thing is not to let the bees see you.
- Yeah. - If it's green, they might think
it's a leaf and they won't notice it. - Uh-huh.
- And if the balloon is blue, they'll think it's just a piece of sky,
and they won't notice it either.
- Do you think they won't notice you under the balloon?
- Maybe they will, maybe they won't.
Oh, I'll pretend I'm a little cloud.
Then they won't know.
- Yeah. Then you'd better take the blue balloon.
Where are we going with Piglet?
A big, big secret! And we won't tell about it, oh, no and no...  И!
- Yes! Do you have an umbrella?
- An umbrella? - See, I was just wondering if we should bring an umbrella just in case.
You can expect anything from these bees. - Aha!
Where Piglet and I are going is a big, big secret!
And we won't tell about it - oh, no and no... И!
- Yes. Hold this.
Here we go. Now I'm just like a real black cloud.
Where Piglet and I are going is a big, big secret!
And we won't tell it oh, no and no... И!
- Yes? No.
Inflate the balloon. - Yeah.
- Yep. Let it go. Yay! Isn't that great?
So, what do I look like now?
- Like a bear flying in a balloon.
Don't I look like a little cloud?
No, you don't!
- All right. Maybe I look more like one from here.
Does one know what those bees will think? B-J-J-J-J-J-!!!!
- Piglet! - What?
- I think the bees suspect something.
- Suspect what?
- I don't know, but they're acting suspicious.
- Maybe they think you're trying to steal their honey.
Piglet! They don't seem to believe I'm a black cloud.
- What should I do?
Open your umbrella and walk back and forth.
I'll sing the cloud song, and you look at me and say:
"I think it's going to rain..."
- Yeah.  I think it's going to rain...
Looks like it's going to rain. I think it's going to rain.
I'm a cloud, a cloud, a cloud, I'm not a bear at all.
Oh, how pleasant for a cloud in the sky (phew!) to fly!
Oh, Piglet! - I think it's going to rain... What?
I thought, I thought, I figured it out!
Turns out they're the wrong bees. They're not right at all.
And they must be making the wrong honey.
I... I'm going down.
I think it's going to rain...  How?
- I haven't thought about that yet...
- I think it's going to rain...
- Piglet! - What?
- Do you have a gun at home? - Yes, I do.
- Bring it quickly! - Yeah.
And in the blue-blue sky there's order and comfort... (Phew!) That's why all the clouds sing so cheerfully... Ouch, Piglet!
- I'm here! Shoot!
What are you shooting at?
The bees, of course.
Not the bees!  You have to shoot down the balloon.
But... If I shoot, the balloon... it'll be ruined...
And if you don't shoot it, then I'm ruined!
Yeah.
Uh-oh! Ooh!
Did I miss?
Uh... Not that you did miss. You just didn't hit the balloon.
I'm so sorry.
Winnie! Winnie! Winnie!
Uh...  Pooh... Phew...
Maybe that's why, although you can't say for sure,
he was named Winnie the Pooh.
Isn't it about time we had something to eat? I think it's time!
Well, that's the end of the story. That is, the end of this story.
And there are others: about Pooh and Rabbit, Piglet and the old grey donkey.
And about all the others :)