Once upon a time, a very long time ago now,
about last Friday,
a bear cub lived in a land
under the name of Winnie-Pooh.
And why 'under the name'?
Because there was a sign over his door that said:
'WINNIE POOH'.
And he lived under it.
Once Winnie-Pooh went out to the forest,
to have a little snack.
He would never mind having a snack!
Besides, he was a poet and composed verses
and even ditties (little songs) in his leisure time...
They went like this:
Winnie: Pam-param-the back... of my head
Poom-pooh-room-taram... the shouties
Poom-poohpoompoom...
If I scratch the back of my head, it's okay!
There is only sawdust in it, yeah, yeah, yey!
But although there's only sawdust,
All these shouties & those screamies...
And also the noisies,
pantloudies and sighpuffies...
I compose them rather nicely on some days! Yes!
Winnie-Pooh lives quite a good life in this land,
That is why he sings these ditties all aloud!
What he’s doing doesn’t matter,
If he doesn’t grow much thinner,
And I know that he won't get there...
If he doesn't skip the dinner... Yes.
Tram-param-pam-pam-parapam-pam
Pam-pam-pah!
Poom-pooroom-poohpoohpoohroom-poom
Tram-pam-pah!
Poom-poom-poom-pooroopoom-poompoom...
Poompooroom-poompoom...
[There came a loud buzzing-noise]
It HAZZ to BEE for a reason!
A tree cannot buzz by itself,
So this means somebody is making a buzzing-noise,
And the only reason for making a buzzing noise
is because you're a bee,
I guess...
And the only reason for being a bee...
Is to make honey, ...
I think...
And the only reason for making honey is...
So as I can eat it!
I believe so!
It's a very funny thought that
If Bears were Bees,
They'd build their nests
At the bottom of trees.
Oh!
Isn't it funny? Bang!
How a bear likes honey? Bang!
Buzz-buzz-buzz! Bang!
I wonder why he does?
Mama!
So Winnie-Pooh went round
to his friend Piglet,
Who lived in a little house with a
"TRESPASSERS W" sign.
And even Piglet himself didn't know
who "TRESPASSERS W" had been.
- Good morning, Winnie-Pooh!
- Good morning, Piglet.
I wonder if you've got such a thing
as a balloon about you?
- A balloon?
Yes. I just thought to myself coming along:
'I wonder if Piglet has such a thing
as a balloon about him?'
- What do you want a balloon for?
... honey...
- What?
Honey.
- But you don't get honey with balloons!
- I do.
Well, it just happened that Piglet
had been to Rabbit's house a day before,
and got two perfect balloons there -
blue one and  green one
- Which one would you like?
When you go after honey with a balloon,
the great thing is not to let
the bees know you're coming.
- Aha.
- Now, if you have a green balloon,
they might think it is only a little leaf,
and not notice it.
- Aha.
- And if you have a blue balloon,
they might think it is only part of the sky,
and not notice it either.
- Wouldn't they notice YOU
underneath the balloon?
- They might or they might not.
Oh, I shall try to look like
a small black cloud.
That will deceive them.
- Aha! Then you had better have
the blue balloon.
The place where we are going
Is 'secret big and great!
That we're not telling anyone
Oh no, oh no... And...
- Yeah!
- Have you an umbrella in your house?
- Umbrella?
- You know, we should bring an
umbrella with us, just in case.
You can expect anything from these bees.
- Aha!
The place where we are going
Is 'secret big and great!
That we're not telling anyone
Oh no, oh no... And...
- Yeah!
Hold it.
That's it. Now I'm just like
a real black small cloud.
The place where we are going
Is 'secret big and great!
That we're not telling anyone
Oh no, oh no... And...
- Yeah?
- No.
- Inflate the balloon!
- Aha.
- Let go.
Hooray!
- Isn't that fine?
- So, what do I look like?
- You look like a Bear
holding on to a balloon.
- And not like a small
black cloud in a blue sky?
- Not very much!
- Ah, well, perhaps from up here it looks different.
- And, as I say, you never can tell with bees!
Buzzzzzzz!!!!
- Piglet!
- What?
- I think the bees suspect something!
- What sort of thing?
- I don't know. But something
tells me that they're Suspicious!
- Perhaps they think
that you're after their honey?
- Piglet! It seems they don't believe
I'm a small black cloud.
- What do we do?
- Put the umbrella up and walk up and down.
I shall do what I can by singing
a Little Cloud Song,
And you look at me and say:
'Tut-tut, it looks like rain...'
- Aha.
Tut-tut, it looks like rain...
- Tut-tut, it looks like rain.
I'm 'rainy little Cloud
And not at all a Bear.
How sweet to be a Cloud
Floating (phew) anywhere!
- Ow, Piglet!
- Tut-tut, it looks like r... What?
- I have been thinking, and I've
come to a very important decision!
It turned out
THESE ARE THE WRONG SORT OF BEES.
Quite the wrong sort.
So I should think they would make
the wrong sort of honey.
I... So I think I shall come down.
- Tut-tut, it looks like r...
But how?
- I hadn't thought about this...
- Tut-tut, it looks like rain...
- Piglet!
- What?
- Have you got a gun at home?
- I have.
- Bring it quickly!
- Aha.
It makes him very proud
To be a little cloud (phew!)
Every little (phew!) cloud
Always sings aloud...  OWW, Piglet!
- I'm here!
- Fire!
What are you shooting at?
- At the bees, of course.
- Not at the bees!
You must shoot the balloon down!
- But... If I do that...
it will spoil the balloon...
- But if you don't shoot,
that would spoil me!
- Aha.
- Ow-ow-ow! Ooh!
- Did I miss?
- Ow.. You didn't exactly MISS.
But you missed the BALLOON.
- I am so sorry.
Winnie!
- Ooh...  Phooh... Pooh... Pooh...
Perhaps this is why,
although we cannot say for sure,
he was called "Winnie-Pooh".
- Isn't it time for a little snack?
I think it is!
And so this is the end of the story,
But of that one only.
There are others:
About Pooh and Rabbit,
About Piglet and the old grey donkey.
And everyone else!