In and out, in and out.
Staying alive is about doing things.  At this point, your cells burn glucose molecules with oxygen
to make energy available, keeping you alive for another precious moment.
To get the oxygen to your cells, you breathe.
Breathing is an answer to a very difficult problem: how do you get the resources your cells need to survive,
from the outside in your cells?  Every living thing has to solve this problem,
and the solution is surprisingly different, depending on one of life's most important regulators:
size.
As we've discussed in other videos:
At different scales, the physical laws of the universe affect its inhabitants differently.
Simple things like temperature, microgravity, or surface tension may not matter to you or pose a deadly hazard
— depending on how tall you are.
Living things need many different materials to stay alive.
And they have to somehow transport them from the outside in.
This was a huge problem for the first things that were about to come to life, because doing anything in our universe requires energy.
And the first living things on Earth did not have the abundance of tools and techniques
that life has today after billions of years of evolution.
So in the very beginning, life had to find a way to get good things inside
and bad things outside of itself without using energy.
Fortunately, the very first life forms were very small.
And because they were so small, they were able to use a free form of
transportation based on a law of physics called diffusion.
Diffusion is the rule of the universe that molecules, especially in liquids or gases, are
constantly moving in all directions.
And because they move and collide with each other and other molecules, they tend to disperse.
For example, if you drop a sugar cube in water, there will be a lot of
sugar in one place and not in another.
When sugar molecules dissolve in the water, they will randomly collide with the water molecules
and other sugar molecules.
Slowly, all the sugar molecules will disperse and form multiple phases with different concentrations.
These random movements continue endlessly, until at some point the sugar
is evenly distributed in the water.
The beauty of diffusion is that life can use it for free, it doesn't require any energy.
And life likes free things.  All life on Earth is therefore dependent on distribution.
Let's take a look at the smallest living thing on Earth, a bacterium.  Specific are surfaces.
Cell membranes allow for diffusion of certain molecules.
This particular bacterium consumes oxygen to live, while inside it produces carbon dioxide
as a waste product.
So there is not much oxygen in the bacterium, but a lot of carbon dioxide.
Through diffusion, these molecules will eventually spread evenly, causing the carbon dioxide to diffuse,
while oxygen is constantly replenished from the outside.
But this kind of 'breathing' only works for the very small world.
For bacteria, amoebae or your cells and some very small animals.
For example, insects have a fine network of trachea, tunnels with a pressure gradient,
into which air can diffuse very slowly and exchange gases with the insect cells.
But even insects seem to be able to contract their windpipes,
and some even have specialized respiratory organs such as spiracles and air sacs.
At certain scales, diffusion is simply too slow to keep cells alive.
The fundamental problem is that the exchange with the environment can only take place on the surface
and diffusion of materials can only support a certain amount inside.
Small living beings have only a little on the inside, or volume, and a lot on the outside,
or surface.
But what if we wanted to make a bacterium the size of a blue whale
and had a very handy magnifying machine?
We would unfortunately be confused by the square cube law.
In a nutshell, it means that if you make something ten times bigger,
the outside or the surface will be 100 times bigger, but the inside or the volume will be 1000 times bigger.
If we compare the bacterium Pseudomonas aeruginosa with a blue whale,
we see that the bacterium has 10,000,000 times more surface area than the whale in relation to its volume.
The bacteria has a lot of outside, while the whale has a lot of inside.
If we make a bacterium the size of a whale - our giant bacterium now has too much inside
and most of the inside is now far from the surface.
The oxygen our bacteria needs will never reach the inside until the oxygen runs out.
Our giant bacteria would just die.  However, being bigger has many advantages.
From making it harder to eat to making it easier to eat others.
But the size of cells is limited by the distance that oxygen and nutrients can effectively disperse
to supply enough resources inside.
So life avoided this problem by forming multicellular structures —
creatures composed of many cells instead of one.
Because diffusion works better if you have many small units rather than one much larger one.
Over time, the cell mates began to share work and specialize.
Some cells focused on feeling the environment, others on digestion, others on movement.
But that wasn't enough.
The problem of diffusion and surface and energy production remained,
limiting the size of these first multicellular life forms.
So to get even bigger,
life solved the diffusion problem by having holes, caves and tunnels and by folding itself in
so that diffusion could easily take place in each of the cells.
Take yourself: what you consider to be your outside, your skin, has an area of about 2 square meters.  But
your lungs have an area of about 70 square meter
.  They're not like balloons, they're more like sponges filled with lots of tightly packed little balloons,
surrounded by blood vessels.
When you inhale, all these little balloons fill with fresh air.
Blood filled with CO2 is pumped around the balloons.
And then the magic of diffusion happens.
The oxygen diffuses into the blood where it is absorbed by red blood cells.
And the CO2 diffuses out of the blood and into your lungs, where it can be exhaled again.
Your blood then carries oxygenated blood to the farthest corners of your body
and absorbs the CO2 waste.
Diffusion in the body is effective from about one millimeter,
so each cell in your body is a maximum of one millimeter away from a blood vessel.
So medium-sized animals like you need a lot of blood vessels to reach every cell in the body.
Your body alone has about 100,000 kilometers of capillaries,
the smallest of your blood vessels, covering an area of about 1,000 square meter
.  This applies to all parts of you that want to exchange something with the outside world.
Your body needs surfaces to absorb nutrients from your food,
so your gut is the size of half a badminton court, about 40 square meters.
The bigger you are, the more hidden surfaces you need.
Grab a tree.  The way to stay alive is to make sugar out of thin air and sunlight.
So it needs as much surface area as possible.
An orange tree with two thousand leaves has a leaf area of 200 square meters.  But
the area in the leaves where diffusion actually takes place is 6000 square meters.
The same goes for roots, where water diffuses from the soil into countless tiny hairs that
maximize surface area.
The roots of one square meter of grass together form about 350 square meters of surface!
When we look at the breathtaking diversity of life on this planet, it seems like everything is quite different.
And it is.
But some basics are the same for everyone and haven't changed significantly for billions of years,
if we look at the very small or the very big:
waste goes out and fresh fuel comes in.  Big animals just need a lot of complexity.  sanitary to make it possible.
Fresh fuel is something we can all use from time to time, especially for our creativity.
All it takes is to try something new and we have the perfect opportunity to get you started:
we've partnered with Skillshare, an online learning community that offers courses on almost any creative skill,
such as design, illustration, animation,  photography and cooking.
They have thousands of courses from every level,
so wherever you are, there is always something for you.
For example, you might want to take a look behind the scenes of our animations:
we created a few Skillshare lessons that teach you how we animated scenes from our videos
using video lessons, lessons and hands-on projects.
Or if you prefer to look at the illustration first, we recommend
Adobe Illustrator: Level Up Your Colors by Hayden Aube.
But what you choose first doesn't really matter that much - the most important thing is to get started, have
fun and get new inspiration.
Unlimited access to all classes is just ten dollars a month with an annual premium membership.
And the first 1000 kurzgesagt viewers who click the link in the description get a special treat:
you get a free trial of Skillshare Premium.
If you want to break out of your rut by exploring a new skill and supporting kurzgesagt, give it a try.
And we've got something else to really make your learning experience perfect:
our new Ocean Explorer Notebook!
It has beautiful sparkling foil letters and 4 illustrated infographic pages inside,
taking you on a journey under the sea.
The perfect companion for all your note-taking needs
, designed and produced with love by the kurzgesagt merch birbs.
Thanks for looking!