Imagine, I wake up in my own bed, at home,
and suddenly a woman is pouring water on me from a teapot.
I say, " Get out of here! "
And I say: "I won't roll out, roll out yourself!"
"Get out of here!"
You know, I was just confused with indignation.
Who are you? If the thief, why did you lie down?
A thief who got tired and went to sleep in a robbed apartment.
You know, Nadia, I didn't like you very much at first.
I just really didn't like it!
And how you disgusted me! It's terrible!
And you just seemed like a shrew to me!
Nadenka, I'm sorry.
I was wrong. Overreacting.
Nothing. Well done for coming.
Really?
"Thank you." "I thought you weren't coming."
Give me your coat."
Let's go.
"Is he still here?" "Don't put him out on the street!"
The first plane doesn't arrive until 7 am.
I could spend the night at the airport. Not a big bird!
Sit down.
- Well settled in, had dinner. "You can't just sit around hungry!"
Music... Very good. Great!
- Join us. "To you?" Thanks.
"Don't cling to words. "Can I talk to you for a minute?"
Just for a moment, please.
We'll call him a taxi and let him ride to the airfield.
On New Year's Eve, the taxi will arrive only in the early morning.
Then let him walk.
"Walking to the airfield?" "Yes, to the airfield.
This far away?
Do you feel sorry for him already?
Even my angelic patience is coming to an end.
Mine, too.
Maybe you've already had something going on?
Shame on you!
No one is asking you!
If you love a woman, you must trust her.
Nadia, stop this guy.
This is a wonderful woman as a person.
She's smart and a great cook. I ate!
Stop this guy, or it's all going to end badly!
She's tactful, she's beautiful, finally!
"I'll beat him up!" "Apologize to her!"
"What are you doing?" "What about you?"
Ippolit, stop it!
The scoundrel! I'll show you!
Only a fight wasn't enough!
Ask her to forgive you.
Why are we talking about "you"?
You're the defeated one!
Zhenya, stop it!
It remains to be seen who is defeated! You'll break your arm!
I'll break it myself, fix it myself!
"Zhenya! "Oh, he's already Zhenya!
Well, in your opinion, I should be Vasya?
Let go of your hand, I said!
Well, stop it!
Ask for your forgiveness.
Enough already!
Get off me.
I didn't want to hit him, he went first.
Now go away, both of you!
Both of them!
Both, so both!
I will remember this New Year for the rest of my life.
Please remember. Do your best.
"Please." "Oh, for God's sake.
"Please come through." "I'm in no hurry.
Stop making faces!
Tanya, I'll be right with you.
No, nothing happened.
I'll tell you later.
Well, then you're in.
"Which way do you want to go?" "I'll go there."
"I'll go there, then." "We're not on our way."
- So... "You were turned away."
We were both turned away.
Well, let's wait, I have plenty of time to get to the plane.
I have a day off today.
"It's not hot. "Yes, it's cool.
And your underwear, as I noticed, is unseasonable.
Grab pneumonia and aha...
"Yeah what?" - Fatal outcome.
And you have shoes with thin soles.
"So we'll die together." "I'm not going to die.
I can sit in the car.
Ippolit Georgievich, what do you think?
I'm not going to answer to you.
You look like you're talking about me.
Yes, about you, adventurer.
Nothing is sacred to you.
People like you stick your nose in everything.
They believe not in reason, but in impulse.
You're out of control!
For you, the main thing is not the mind, but the feeling, the impulse.
You are a threat to society.
Very flattering review.
"What do you think?" "Hot tea."
But still frankness for frankness.
You are welcome.
People like you are always right about everything,
because you live as you should.
As prescribed.
But that's also your weakness.
You are not capable of insanity. You can't do great things.
And life cannot be adjusted to a profitable scheme.
"Hooray!" "Cheers for what?"
I'm coming back, I forgot my briefcase.
"You made that up on purpose! "Why would I be cold?"
I'll get you a briefcase.
I don't trust you, I have a valuable broom there.
- Why did you go to the bathhouse? "You don't understand that?"
Hello there! Moscow? Galya?
Yes. Please ask, Lukashina.
He's already gone to the airfield.
A casual acquaintance.
Tell me, how did it get into your apartment?
I'll explain everything to you now.
Yesterday Zhenya went to the sauna.
To the bathhouse? Girl, which bathhouse? He has a bathroom.
They have a tradition.
He is with his school friends every year...
Have you known each other for years?
No, we met a few hours ago.
Look, I have the same address as him in Moscow.
25 3rd Stroiteley Street, apartment 12.
And he came to me as if I were his home.
So you know his Moscow address.
You are welcome.
You don't have to worry.
Please don't specify it.
"Do you want me to help you?" "No, I don't want to.
My hands were cold.
Everything is much simpler.
The crook.
No, that's not how you understand it.
Galya, I'm begging you, don't hang up.
Zhenya is very nice, he is very kind.
Galya, I must say that I envy you a little.
Yes, I really liked it.
Well, forgive him.
Why are you defending him?
Are you married?"
Well, what does it matter?
Unmarried, then.
So, he flew to Leningrad to celebrate the New Year with you.
"How old are you?" "A lot.
"Last chance?" "Shame on you!
Am I ashamed?
I didn't steal your fiance.
Galya, you misunderstand everything!
You're a predator.
In the end, at the last moment, he will also leave you.
Sorry.
I'm sorry, for God's sake, I left your briefcase with a broom.
Galya called you.
Galya?
How did she know the phone number?
Oh, yes, I told her myself. Besides, you have a simple phone number.
I tried to explain everything to her, but she didn't believe me.
I told her you'd gone to the airfield.
In the sense...
Yes, thanks.
Well, I'm off.
"Have a safe journey." "Thank you very much."
Sorry again for intruding.
"Thank you." "You're welcome."
I went...
I just wanted to tell you...
What?
May I call you?"
Do you remember my phone number?
14-50-30.
Call us.
- Happy New Year! "Thank you."
- Happy New Year to you too. "Thank you."
And ... fuck me.
And ... how will you get to the airfield?
"The buses aren't running yet. "I'll get there somehow."
Well, go ahead.
Go ahead.
Well, what are you doing!
I'm leaving.
You're looking for an excuse to stay.
Yes, I'm looking for it, but I can't find it.
And I can't find an excuse to keep you.
"Do what?" "Really?"
Then I'll take off my coat and stay late?
Sit down.
"Come on." "No, no, nothing.
"Would you like some herring?" "No, no, thank you.
Maybe some champagne?
Let me sing you something.
Good.
Because the pause was too long?
That's probably why.
I don't really sing very well, but I love to sing.
"If you don't have an aunt."
Executes...
In general, the aria of the Moscow guest.
If you don't have a home,
He's not afraid of fires,
And the wife will not go to another,
If you have, if you have, If you don't have a wife.
No wife.
If you don't have a dog,
She won't be poisoned by a neighbor,
And there won't be a fight with a friend,
If you have, if you have, If you don't have a friend,
I don't have a friend.
The orchestra thunders with bass,
Trumpeter blows copper,
Think for yourself, decide for yourself, To have or not to have.
If you don't have an aunt,
Then you won't lose it,
And if you don't live,
Then you don't, then you don't,
Then you don't have to die,
Don't die.
The orchestra thunders with bass,
Trumpeter blows copper,
Think for yourself, decide for yourself, To have or not to have.
To have or not to have.
That's it. That's it.
Problematic song.
I didn't just pick up my guitar by accident.
Now, as a gracious hostess, sing me something.
You don't like the way I sing.
Like. I was lying. I'm lying.
Always?
Almost.
Nice photo.
I like her too, even though she's almost 10 years old.
Ten years?
You haven't changed at all.
Lying again?
Almost none.
"Where do you work?" - In the clinic.
I accept patients.
Sometimes 30 people a day.
Bored?
Of course, but what to do, they are sick, they need to be treated.
All right, I'll sing it to you.
Even though you don't deserve it.
Thank you very much.
I like, That you're not sick of me.
I like, That I'm not sick of you.
What never Heavy globe of the earth
It won't float away Under our feet.
I like, That you can be funny,
Disbanded, And don't play with words,
And don't blush A suffocating wave,
Slightly, Touching the sleeves,
Thank you With your heart and hand
For being me, Without knowing it yourself, you love it so much.
For my night's peace,
For the rarity of meetings By sunset hours,
For our negulyanye under the moon, For the sun is not over our heads.
For being sick, Alas, not by me,
For the fact that I, alas, am not sick of you.
Nadia...
I want to ask you something...
I have a request for you, perhaps a little impertinent.
But what is it?
You... don't get angry?
I will try.
And don't send me away?
Well, if I haven't already...
"Do you want me to sing again?"- no.
Let me take a picture of Hippolytus out of the closet
and tear it up?
No, you can't.
Are you very upset that he left?
"Why would you want to know?" "I'll ask you again."
Yes, I'm upset.
Are you sure about that?"
How old are you? 32?
"Thirty-three?" "Thirty-four."
Thirty-four?
And then everything, well, didn't work out.
Bad luck, it happens.
And then he appears.
Like this...
Serious and positive.
Beautiful.
It's convenient.
Reliable.
Behind it, as if behind a stone wall.
Yes, and the groom is probably profitable, and friends advise...
"Watch out, don't miss it."
And you, it turns out, are cruel.
Excuse me.
I'm a surgeon, and I often have to hurt people,
so that they can live well later.
Do you feel sorry for your patients?
Sure.
Yes...
I feel sorry for myself sometimes, too.
I come home...
I sit down in a chair and start feeling sorry for myself.
But this rarely happens to me.
Have you never been married?
Was. Half of it.
How's that? For which half?
And so... We met twice a week.
For ten years.
And on Saturdays and Sundays I was left alone.
Since then, I don't like Saturdays or Sundays.
In general, I don't like holidays.
Was he married?"
He is still married.
Do you still love him?
No.
Let's go get some coffee."
And I've never been very popular with women.
Since high school. My word of honor.
We had a girl in our class Ira, nothing special.
And so I fell in love with her, as they said at the time.
And she didn't pay any attention to me.
Then, after high school, she married Pavel.
For the one you went to the bathhouse with?
And instead of which you flew to Leningrad?
Yes. They got married, and I was invited to the wedding.
I was terribly worried and made a toast:
"Ira, I wish you to leave Pavel and come to me as soon as possible."
I was kicked out for that, of course.
- Are you and Pavel friends now? "We've been friends all our lives.
It wasn't his fault that she chose him.
He was just about to fly to Leningrad to see her
celebrate the New Year.
Poor Ira, she was hurt too.
Why also?
I don't feel like a victim.
I'll go make coffee with pleasure.
Why you?
Because you sing beautifully, but you can't cook.
This is not aspic fish, this is some kind of strychnine.
"You've been praising me." "I was being sycophantic.
"You're not being very polite." "It's true.
I don't recognize myself, I'm getting impudent before my eyes.
In general, everyone thought I was shy all my life.
Everyone rides me, and my friends call me a mattress.
I think they flattered you.
No. I felt the same way about myself.
You were obviously being modest.
And now I can feel it...
That I was becoming a different person.
"More brazen?" "No, bold.
"More brusque?" "Determined.
"More cheeky?" "You can't guess.
I feel that...
Capable of anything.
Just some power,
maybe she was dozing and now she's waking up?
Maybe it's because we met?
Thanks to you.
Do you know what you're saying?
That I made a cad out of you.
This is simply unheard of!
I've never been called a boor before.
Nadia, I'm happy.
How can you be so persistent?
I do not know what I will do with it now!
Don't you dare... I myself.
"Nadia, what happened?" "Did you have a fight?"
My dear, was he a bully?
Raised a hand against you?
And I made such a good impression!
And we old fools have our ears open.
"He's probably married." "Does he have a child?"
I'll explain everything to you.
What kind of news is this? Who called you?"
Let's get out of here." Go home, both of them.
Are you out of your mind?
She asked us to.
"Nadia, you'd better come to my place. "Give me your coat."
Give me your coat!" It's someone else's!
"I'm not letting her go anywhere!" "What a tone!
- The tone is normal. "Why are you running this place?"
Because I'm Hippolytus.
"What are you laughing at?" "Because you're lying.
Girls, don't believe her.
"Last time... "Don't believe her.
"You're sweating yourself out. "It's not Hippolytus.
This is a complete stranger.
She wouldn't spend the night with a strange man, would she?
"I came home... "Tell me about the bathhouse."
"And I saw it... "That I'm in your bed!"
- Tell me, this is already interesting. "I think we'll go."
- Zhenya, stop the farce! "Which Zhenya?" Where is he?
Did you bring Zhenya?! Divorce!
"Shut up! "Quiet, quiet!
You'll beat him up later. Well, tell me."
I'll ask him a question!
Girls, let's have a drink.
New Year's Eve, after all. Let's.
Let's drink to friendship!
Come on, come on for friendship.
She's been lying on the floor all night."
Dear Nadia and Ippolit,
"It's not Hippolytus. "That's enough!
Stop it, this isn't funny anymore!
"Here you go." "I don't want to!"
I drink to the fact that in the new year you never quarrel.
We won't.
"Girls, I'm leaving with you. - Enough, I'm tired of it!
Calm down, Hippolytus.
Why don't you shout "bitter"?
It's bitter! It's bitter!
I won't kiss him!
This is inconvenient. Why do you refuse?
The people demand it!
Where are Tanya and Valya?
You have good friends.
"Did we switch to 'you'?" "A long time ago.
Didn't you notice?
This is not a house!..
A passing yard of some sort!
Honestly, whoever it is, I'll kill you!
Do the Sinitsyns live here?
What's your last name?"
Sheveleva.
"We are Shevelevs, comrades! "We got it wrong again!"
"What's your last name?" - Lukashin.
"And your middle name?" - Mikhailovich.
Evgeny Mikhailovich Lukashin.
Very nice to meet you.
"Where are you calling?" "To the airport.
I want to know when the second flight to Moscow is.
Have you decided to postpone your departure?
I don't want to leave, that's all.
Hello there! Girl, when is the second flight to Moscow?
I see, but the third one?
And the third?
And the fourth?
The devil knows what! They leave every half hour.
I don't understand why Do I have to leave?
What are you talking about?
I have to go to work on the 2nd.
We can take a walk in the afternoon,
go to the Hermitage, and in the evening I'll leave.
By train.
You're being cavalier.
I don't think I invited you."
So what's the big deal? Invite them.
What for?
I can't do this, I feel like there are three of us.
Don't you dare touch him.
I won't do anything to him, just stick him between the books.
Okay, let him eavesdrop, but let's turn his back.
It's better when you can't see it.
Leave him alone!
You stand up for him as if he's as precious to you as a memory.
It's none of your business.
"Beloved Nadenka"?
Well, you know!
This is already going overboard!
"What are you doing?" "Let him get some air!"
It's good for him.
"Go and pick up Hippolytus." "I wouldn't think of it.
"I'm telling you again. "Don't tell me again!
"You should take the first flight. "And I'll fly!"
"And you'll fly!" "And I'll fly!" I'll fly!
I'm just going to shave."
With a razor! And I'll fly.
By plane...
This isn't a barber shop.
Don't stop me from shaving. I'm overgrown.
I can't fly to my fiancee's house unshaven.
I completely forgot that you had a fiancee.
Run and open it.
It's probably Hippolytus, he's been gone for a long time.
He's already shaving with my razor!
Now, I hope he's gone forever?
thank god!
By the way, why is his razor here?
You're flying to your fiancee, so fly!
"And this is my fiance's razor. "My ex-fiance.
There is no Hippolytus, there was and floated.
Where is he? Ippolit! No way!
And if he comes here again, I'll throw him down the stairs.
Upside down.
What right do you have to talk to me like that?
Why are you interfering in my life?
You should be at the airfield long ago.
No, my train leaves late at night.
So!.. Well, that's enough!
I don't want to eat, I don't want to drink either.
I want to rest.
I'm tired today.
- "Foggy morning"... "Then I'll leave!"
Good riddance. "Foggy morning"...
"Good riddance"...
- I will come, but with a policeman. "Bring the entire squad.
"Bring the entire squad."..
"Policemen"...
Hand me my coat."
I'd love to!
Ask you.
"Not too tight?" "Fasten it."
- what? "Button your boots."
With pleasure!
Thank you for your trust.
Why are you yelling like that?
Be patient, my patient.
Second.
I've been dreaming about this all my adult life.
Don't try to rob the apartment. Please note that I know your address.
Let me go."
Taxi service!
Actually, we don't put them in the parking lot.
All right, where should I go?
"I have no idea. "Get out!"
No, I have an idea.
Let's go to the Moscow railway station.
Chief, are you free?"
Pour, pour glasses.
Who's lying, what...
Who are you?
Who are you?"
I can guess...
"I'm sorry... "Don't come any closer, or I'll scream."
I'll explain everything to you in a moment.
"Just don't move! "I'm not moving.
You don't have to be afraid of me.
Why are you here?"
How can I explain it to you?
My friends and I have a tradition.
In Moscow, every year on December 31, we go to the sauna.
Come on, turn out your pockets.
I stole only 15 rubles.
Sparsely populated. Put it on the table.
Where are you?
Where did you disappear to?
Gotcha.
One to Moscow.
I asked Ash,
Where is my favorite?
Ash didn't answer me,
Shaking his head.
I asked poplar,
Where is my favorite?
Poplar threw me
Autumn foliage.
I asked autumn,
Where is my favorite?
Autumn answered me
Heavy rain.
I asked the rain,
Where is my favorite?
Long rain tears poured down
Outside my window.
I asked the month,
Where is my favorite?
The month disappeared in the cloud,
He didn't answer me.
I asked the cloud,
Where is my favorite?
The cloud melted away
In the blue of the sky.
Friend you are my only one,
Where is my favorite?
Tell me where you've disappeared,
Do you know where she is?"
Friend replied the devotee,
The friend replied sincerely,
You had a favorite,
And my wife became me.
I asked Ash,
I asked autumn,
I asked poplar...
Mother! Why are you sitting in the hallway?
I watch a criminal, and he entertains me with songs.
I'm the culprit.
Happy New Year, Nadenka.
Mom, let's set him free.
Well, are you cold?
No, I took a taxi.
Where did you take the taxi to?"
I bought you a ticket for the morning train.
Did you buy me a ticket?
Thanks. I'm awfully grateful to you.
Lower shelf.
I don't even know how to thank you!
Saved me from having to wait in line.
Thanks.
And although I do not have a very large salary...
I'll go to Lyuba's to continue celebrating the New Year.
Thank you, you are a wonderful mom.
See to it, Nadia, that you are ready for my arrival
no third party started up.
Don't worry about that I won't allow it.
If you remember, I promised you
return with a photo of Hippolytus.
"Oh, what a nightmare! "You're an adventurer!
"Oh, what a pity! "You're impudent!
Oh, what small pieces!
"You shameless brat! "Of course.
"The bandit! "Of course.
"Barbarian! "Of course.
"You're an alcoholic. "Of course.
"You're awesome. "Yes, yes.
You know who?..
We won't open it.
We're not home.
Whoever it is, we won't open it.
Strange people.
We don't open it, so we're not here.
And if we're at home and don't open the door,
so we don't want to see anyone.
What tactlessness!
What bad manners!
This is just hooliganism!
Out of spite, we won't open it now.
Be strong, Nadia.
Are they out of their minds?
Be courageous.
I'll have to open it.
Otherwise, they'll break down the door.
Well, then I'll do it.
Zhenya!
Get a grip on yourself!
Guys! And this is me breaking down the door.
I'm here...
I wish you a Happy New Year, Happy New Year.
Accept it... and so on.
I really want to eat! I'm hungry as an animal.
This is the first time I've seen you like this!
And this is my first time in this form.
This is the first time I've seen myself like this.
"A baby was walking down the street, I'm blue and cold all over."
Thin-soled shoes. Now he knows.
He knows everything.
But there were people! Found it!
Sheltered, warmed up, robbed...
No, they picked it up and warmed it up...
After all, life is an amazing thing.
Full of surprises.
Sorry...
This, by the way, is beautiful!
How can it be programmed,
expected, planned happiness?
Oh, my God! How boring we live!
The spirit of adventure is gone from us.
We stopped climbing into the windows of the women we love.
We stopped doing the big, good stuff.
How disgusting! This is your aspic fish!
Next New Year's Eve I will definitely go to the bathhouse.
Why wait a whole year?
Right! That's the idea!
Very true!
Let me pass.
Thank you.
I think he opened the water.
What for?
Are you out of your mind? Stop it now!"
I won't even think about it!
Do you know what you're doing?"
Don't get in the way!
Ippolit, you'll ruin your coat.
Well, don't be petty, Nadenka!
Ippolit, I beg you, get out.
At least take off your hat.
And I feel good in my hat. And you wouldn't say anything at all!
Lukewarm went!
On New Year's Eve, a person goes to the bathhouse.
This perfectly characterizes him.
Then he gets drunk there on the occasion of his marriage.
This is also in his favor.
Then they put him on the plane like a chock.
And he ends up in another city.
Rub my back, please.
Well, is it difficult for you, or what?
Don't want it as you want it
What can I do?
In this city, he gets another one.
Naturally, he forgets about the Moscow bride.
Gets a new one, the Leningrad one.
And all because he is a man of high moral standards.
Please stop.
Are you offended?
No offense, it's true.
And you can't take offense at the truth, even if it's bitter.
Nadia, in such a short time, the old can be destroyed,
and creating a new one is very difficult.
Must not.
The end of New Year's Eve, tomorrow there will be a hangover.
Emptiness.
The interesting thing is, you both know I'm right.
Sorry.
Where are you going?" You'll catch a cold!
Leave me alone.
I beg you, don't go, stay.
It's freezing outside!
Maybe I want to...
Catch a cold and die.
My God, I'm tired.
What a crazy night.
If he shows up again...
He'll set the house on fire.
And to be honest...
I really liked it.
He said things that we don't dare say to each other.
You're crazy.
Come to your senses.
That's exactly what's happening to me.
Lyuba's already going to bed. And it's cold on the stairs.
Was it you who doused Ippolit?
He was now walking all wet.
He's the one who's wet with tears.
You've offended such a good person!
Oh, well...
You should go."
But the planes run every half hour.
Half an hour won't save anything.
This is ridiculous, just plain stupid.
We will never forgive ourselves for this for the rest of our lives.
You need to be able to restrain your feelings.
What for?
Haven't we held back too often in our lives?
Understand, Hippolytus is right somewhere.
We're a little crazy.
New Year's Eve is over.
And everything falls into place.
I want it in the mirror,
Where is the haze and the foggy dream,
I elicit,
Where do you want to go And where is the shelter,
I see
Ship's mast,
And you're on deck.
You're in the smoke of the train, Fields, fields,
In the evening complaint,
Evening fields in dew,
Above them are crows,
I bless you,
I bless you
On all four sides.
I bless you,
I bless you
On all four sides.
It's already morning.
I have a feeling,
that we had lived a lifetime together that night.
Pick up the ticket.
I think it can be found.
No, I'm not going by train.
Shake for 7 hours.
You, please...
Remember me.
You too.
Go, Zhenya, go.
Can I kiss you good-bye?"
No, don't do that.
Don't, I'm begging you.
Let's sit in front of the road.
I stole your picture.
I am very pleased that you will still have my photo.
And if the weather is not flying, can I stay?
No, then take the train.
How painful, my dear, How strange,
Akin to the earth, Intertwining branches.
That hurts, honey. How strange
Bifurcate under the saw.
The wound will not heal on the heart,
Shed pure tears,
It will spill like a fiery tar.
As long as I'm alive, I'll be with you,
Soul and blood are inseparable,
As long as I'm alive, I'll be with you.
Love and death are always together.
You will carry it with you, my love,
You'll carry it everywhere with you,
You'll carry it everywhere with you
My native land, sweet home.
What if I have nothing to hide from From an incurable pity?
What if I have nothing to hide from From the cold and dark?
After parting, there will be a meeting, Don't forget me, my love.
After parting, there will be a meeting,
We'll both go back, me and you.
And if I go into obscurity, Short beam daylight light,
But if I disappear into obscurity
For the star belt, Milky smoke?
I will pray for you, So as not to forget the ways of the earth.
I will pray for you, I want you to come back unharmed.
Shaking in a smoky train,
He became homeless and humble.
Shaking in the smoky train, He was half-crying, half-sleeping.
When the train is on a slippery slope
Suddenly it bent with a terrible lurch,
I tore the wheels off the rail,
Superhuman strength
In one press of all crippling,
The mundane was thrown off the ground,
And you didn't protect anyone, The promised meeting is far away,
And no one was protected by the Hand calling in the distance.
Do not part with your loved ones,
Do not part with your loved ones.
With all your blood, sprout in them.
And each time forever say goodbye,
When you leave for a moment.
Tell me what happened."
I don't understand anything! I'm all excited!
Where did you go?"
Tell me, what's wrong?" Where is Galya?
I went to Leningrad.
Where to?
To Leningrad.
I'm sorry, for God's sake, I'm terribly tired and sleepy.
So you ran away to Leningrad again?
Mom, you know that.
Every year on December 31, my friends and I go to the sauna.
We bathe in the sauna.
We had a drink in the sauna.
And me by accident, unintentionally, you know, but by accident,
mixed up and sent to Leningrad instead of Pavlik.
How was this sent?
What are you, a parcel, a parcel, a suitcase?
Please, my head is breaking.
Didn't you think straight?"
No boom-boom.
What a blooming flower you are! The horror!
You need to get married so that you can listen to someone.
Of course, it will be difficult for you to explain yourself to Galya.
But never mind, I'll go right now and bring her here.
I'm begging you, don't.
You don't want to marry Gala anymore?
I met another woman.
"Where?" - In Leningrad.
"When?" "Tonight.
Oh, my God!
And that's why you're breaking up with Galya?
Yes.
Mommy, what's wrong?
"Mommy, what's wrong with you?" "Wait a minute.
Has it passed?
You're a womanizer. A womanizer.
Oh, Mom, I'm an unhappy person.
Why am I so unlucky in life?
And I don't need to get married.
What for? Really?
Not necessary.
No one will look after me better than you.
The sly one!
Imagine if we have a strange woman here.
It remains to be seen how you'll get along.
And whether you'll get along.
I'll get annoyed.
No, that's all.
Everything! To hell with it!
Let everything remain the same.
My poor child!
Lie down.
Lie down, everything will work out.
Lie down and rest.
What's her name?"
She has an amazing name.
Nadia.
And most importantly, it is rare.
You forgot your broom.
How did you find me?"
You're an impenetrable dumbass.
My God, this is where the same thing starts!
I hope it's not Hippolytus.
Hello! Happy New Year!
Happy New Year!
Happy New year!
Where is he?
Wake him up.
Hello.
How could I have made a mistake? I never get drunk.
I'm glad that you, Zhenya, and...
Galya.
That we are your friends, and Galya forgave you.
Zhen, stop hugging.
We can't stop. We haven't seen each other in too long.
It doesn't bother me. Does it annoy you? Not me.
Zhenya, we are glad that Galya forgave you.
We are glad that you finally found Galya.
Mother!
My Nadia has arrived.
Do you think I'm frivolous?
We'll wait and see.
"Do you understand anything?" "Is that you for me?"
It seems to me that this is not Galya.
Say something, you're the smartest one.
I can say that one of them is Zhenya.
My friends!
I am grateful to you for making a big difference in my life.
And that fate threw me to Leningrad.
And that in Leningrad there is the same street, the same house
and the same apartment.
Otherwise, I would never have been happy.
We would never be happy.
.
I asked Ash,
Where is my favorite?