[soft dramatic music]
- Hi, I'm Michael Stevens,
but who are you?
Do you even know who you are?
Are you your memories?
- I don't remember that.
- I don't remember that at all.
- Are you the choices you make?
The focus tester
is actually a magician.
- That's scary.
[chuckles]
- Or are you your past?
- I hit the back of my head
and I forgot my entire life.
Just like you hit
a delete button on a computer.
- [quietly]
Wow.
[electronic music]
♪ ♪
Have you ever looked
at a photograph of yourself
and thought,
"That's what I look like?
Ugh."
We often think we look bad
or not right in photos
because photos show us
what we really look like
to other people.
The you that
you're used to seeing
is mirror you.
Every mirror you look into
reverses your face.
Most selfie cameras do this too,
so we tend to prefer
that version of ourselves.
If you wanna see yourself
in a mirror
the way other people see you
in real life,
take two mirrors
and position them
at a 90-degree angle.
What you see won't be
yourself reversed,
but how you look in real life.
So who would you say
you are really?
Is it how you look?
Or is it how you dress?
Or are you the atoms
that make you up?
Because all of those things
change throughout your life.
Ah, maybe
the real common thread,
that which doesn't change,
is your history,
your memory.
But what if we remember things
differently
from the way
they actually happened.
Does that mean
we don't know ourselves?
False memories are
frighteningly easy to create.
Today, we're gonna make some,
and we're gonna have
a little fun doing it.
We have created a fake game show
called "Who You Were."
We're gonna bring contestants
down memory lane
and have them tell us
about their past.
Some of which we're going
to completely make up.
We're gonna plant a few
little seeds in this mind field
and see if we can grow
some fake memories.
[cheers and applause]
Hi, I'm Michael Stevens,
and welcome to the show
that takes you on a trip
down memory lane
from who you are
all the way back through...
"Who You Were."
Please welcome
today's very special guest,
Timothy DeLaGhetto.
- How's it going, man.
- Thanks for coming in.
- Thanks for having me.
- Excited to kinda
dive into some memories?
- Yeah, I don't really know
what to expect.
- To begin, though,
let's give the audience
a taste of your life.
- Oh, my God, let's take a look.
- So Tim was raised
in California
where he and his parents
owned and operated
a Thai food restaurant.
- [laughing]
- Tim found popularity
as a rapper,
comedian, actor,
and Internet personality,
and has attracted
over 3 million subscribers.
In order to--to kind of see
how you became who you are today
let's go back to who you were.
- Let's do it.
- We spoke to your parents...
- Mm-hmm.
- And they told us
some of their favorite memories
from when you were very,
very young.
- Okay.
- I'm going to start
with some true stories
before I slip in
the false memory.
When you were seven,
you were pretty much
held prisoner
by a very controlling
school girl.
The girl took control
of your life
and always wanted to know
what you were doing.
- I remember her.
Like, she was,
like, my--my best friend,
sort of,
but then she was also very,
like, possessive of me.
- But you guys aren't
together still.
- No, we might be
Facebook friends.
- Okay.
Here's a memory.
You weren't a crybaby
on the first day of school...
- Yeah.
- Until you noticed that
all the other kids were crying
and then you joined in.
- You know,
I empathize with people...
- Right.
- And, uh, I was just kind of,
like, helping them feel like
we were all a team.
- Now here's the fake story
we made up out of thin air.
Here's another memory.
- Mm-hmm.
- When you were about
four or five years old...
- Mm-kay.
- You actually took a ride
in a hot air balloon,
but you dropped something
from the balloon.
- I don't remember that at all.
[laughs]
- Really?
- Yeah, like, at all.
- We're going deep--far back.
- I didn't even know
I've ever been in
a hot air balloon
until you just reminded me.
- It was in Echo Park.
- Was it?
- Yeah.
- No clue.
- Timothy is not accepting
the story as truth yet.
Time for our second subject.
[xylophone trills]
[upbeat music]
- Dylan, how are you?
- I'm doing great, man.
- You were, uh, inseparable
from you Superman cape
when you were young.
Once, you even tried
to use your super powers
to stop a car
driving down the street.
- Yeah, try to stop a car,
like, with my--with my hand
and everything.
- Did you succeed?
- You know,
the dude hit his brakes.
- Okay, next memory.
So when you were about
four or five years old,
you took a ride
in a hot air balloon
and you dropped something.
- Huh.
Uh...
I'm not sure
if I remember that to be honest.
- Sometimes enriching
the false story
with a realistic detail
can trigger the brain
to begin filling in the memory.
Here goes.
Did you have a favorite toy
or anything
that maybe you had brought?
- Oh, I mean, I had, like,
some action figures, I think.
Um, I do remember,
like, losing one.
I'm not sure, like--that was,
like, the--what happened.
If I, uh, was
in a hot air balloon.
That's a crazy adventure
if I actually,
like, did something like that.
- Hi, Victoria.
When you were around
four or five years old,
you took a ride
in a hot air balloon
and you dropped something.
- I don't remember that.
- Four or five years old?
Up in the air?
- No.
- How many times you been
in a hot air balloon?
- None.
- Of course
none of the subjects
remember the balloon ride.
It never happened,
but we are not done
with them yet.
24 hours from now,
we'll take our subjects
to Echo Park...
- Okay.
- The site of their supposed
childhood balloon ride,
to see if any of
the seeds I planted today
have taken root.
This is where you took
your first hot air balloon ride.
- Are you serious?
- I'm serious.
[soft dramatic music]
We might not be able
to remember our past accurately
all the time,
but at least we have
direct insight
into our own mental states.
We know how we feel,
what we like,
and why.
Except we don't.
Psychologists call
our tendency to overvalue
how we explain our own behavior
while distrusting
that other people
truly understand their own...
An interesting manifestation
of this bias
is something called...
It is surprisingly easy
to fool someone into believing
they made a choice
that they never did,
and the amazing thing is that
they'll also defend
that fake choice
as if it were
what they had always wanted.
[film reel humming]
We feel like
we know ourselves pretty well.
We know why
we like the things we like.
We know why we decided
to do the things that we did.
But do we?
[dramatic music]
Today, we'll be showing
our subjects sets of photos
and asking them
to choose the photo
of the person
they'd prefer to work with.
But this isn't exactly
what it looks like.
The focus tester
is actually a magician
who will be using
slight of hand
to swap
some of the faces they choose
for faces they've rejected.
Will they catch the trick?
Or will they justify
and explain a decision
they never actually made?
- Thank you for participating
in this study
of first impressions
in the workplace.
You will be shown sets of faces
and be asked to select
which person you would prefer
to work with.
Are you ready to begin?
- I am, yes.
- Cool.
So would you rather
work with person "A"
or person B?
- Person B.
[soft dramatic music]
That's as complex as it gets.
- [laughs]
I can do this.
- Person "A" or Person B?
- Uh, B.
B.
"A."
- Perfect.
So we've made a pile of
your ideal workplace colleagues.
Effectively.
- Okay.
- Uh, now part two is to--
if you could fill out the
"women in the workplace"
segment of the questionnaire.
- All of this business
about filling out a survey,
it's just to distract them
from what's about to happen
because our magician
is gonna make a swap.
There it is.
Two of the eight photos
have been swapped out
for pictures
our subject rejected.
What will she say
when presented
with photos of people
she didn't actually choose?
- Now, on their own merits,
I wanna ask you
what it was about them
that made you pick them.
- Okay.
- We'll start with a picture
that she did pick
before we slip in the rejects.
- So why did you want
to work with this person?
- She looks nice.
She looks really nice,
but I think the person
I compared her to
didn't look very friendly.
- Gotcha.
- Here's another pair of photos
where she had
a clear preference.
- Person B.
- Now we're going to show her
the picture
she actually rejected.
- Why did you want
to work with this person.
- Um, she just looked nicer
than the other one.
[laughs]
- Yeah.
- That was one
where the other girl
didn't look very nice at all.
- Is she just misremembering
this one choice?
How about another photo
she rejected?
- Why did you prefer
to work with this person?
- She looks super sweet.
- So that was
what you were thinking
when you chose that--chose her?
- Mm-hmm.
I feel like she would be
one of those girls
that would, like,
on the birthdays
get you the card and...
[laughs]
She just looks really sweet.
- This isn't just
simple misremembering.
This is fabricating
a past that never happened.
Will any of our other subjects
justify choices
that they never made?
- Person "A" or Person B?
- "A."
- Now we'll present him
with the photo he rejected.
- So why did you choose
to work with this person?
- She gave off the appearance
of a genuine person
who would be easy to work with.
- People are
completely fabricating
justifications
for things they never even did.
I think we could actually
up the ante.
We've been swapping
two of the eight faces,
now we'll swap four.
Let's see if she justifies
the photos
that she actually rejected.
- I liked her--her look.
I like to work
with confidant people,
so, to me, she looked like
a confident person.
As a woman,
I wanna, like,
help other women
grow and succeed
and give them advice
and I gravitated
towards that picture
because of that reason.
She looked like a type of person
you could confide in
and ask advice and learn
from her experiences.
So I think she had
that type of look.
She looks like she might be,
like, a wise type of person.
She looks confident.
So I think that's
why I picked her.
- She seems so sure
of her decisions,
but let's give her
one last look.
- In particular,
I'm curious about how you feel
about these four.
- You know,
there's the confidence
and, um, kindness,
and somebody young.
I feel like that would be
people I could work with, so...
I-I stand by my decisions.
- Cool.
- Yes...[laughs]
- Perfect.
- Yes.
- The interesting thing
about this study...
- Okay.
- Is they are not actually
the ones you chose.
- No?
- These ones were.
- Oh.
- They were switched
while you were filling in
the questionnaire.
It's this phenomenon,
what's known as
choice blindness.
If we think we made a choice,
we will find a way
to justify that choice...
- Ah.
- Even if we don't know
that's what we made.
- Okay.
I was trying to justify
these four...
[laughs]
'Cause I forgot
that I picked those four.
- It's like a debate.
Like, no matter what--
what side I was on,
I was gonna give reasons
for that.
I'm, uh, I'm not happy
that I did that,
but, um, that's the reason why.
- You pulled this
complete switcheroo on me,
and I wasn't even,
like, conscious about it.
That's scary.
♪ ♪
- You may think you know
why you do the things you do,
but, in a pinch,
your mind can replace the truth,
that actual past
with completely new explanations
that you will
confidently believe
to be exactly what happened.
But what if fabricating the past
is all you can do?
That may be the case
for someone with...
When you can't
remember your life at all,
what happens
to your sense of self?
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
So, Scott, you have
retrograde amnesia.
- Correct.
- Tell me what that is,
how it happened.
- I walked into a restroom
at my office building,
but I slipped on
an oily substance,
and hit the back of my head
and suffered, you know--
it was, like, four-
or five-inch laceration,
and that gave me
retrograde amnesia,
which means everything
autobiographical
and historical in my life
were completely erased.
- Erased?
- Just like you hit
a delete button on a computer.
I've forgotten my entire life.
I had no idea who my wife was.
Her name...
my children.
It was absolutely horrifying.
- Wow.
So this happened
eight years ago?
- Mm-hmm.
- What memories did you have?
You still knew English.
You still knew things
like how to ride a bike.
That's a totally different
kind of memory.
both: Right.
- Well, when I handed him
a toothbrush,
he didn't comb his hair with it.
He put it in his mouth,
but he didn't know
what it was called.
- And you didn't remember
ever using one before?
- Correct.
- But you didn't have
the autobiographical memories
that involved toothbrushes,
but you knew how to operate it
'cause that's
a procedural memory.
- Right.
- Exactly, exactly.
- Wow.
- Things like that,
you know, are stored in
a different part of the brain.
- So it was almost like
you were--you were born
into this person's body
you didn't get to choose.
You have a name,
you have a wife,
you have a house,
you have a past...
- Mm-hmm.
- And you have to just accept
that all of those
are what you've been dealt.
- Right, 'cause that's exactly
how I felt.
Like I stepped
into somebody else's life,
and...
a lot of it I didn't believe.
I just couldn't picture that,
you know, I flew airplanes
or--or was in the NFL.
I just--seemed like
nothing I would ever do,
and a lot of it, you know,
she had to prove to me.
She put together
a whole album full of pictures.
She kind of put my life
in a chronological order...
- Wow.
- And that kind of, you know,
filled some of the gaps
of who I was,
and I-I've heard that,
you know,
you are who you are
from the things
you've experienced
and your memories,
and when I hear that,
it's like a knife in my heart.
'Cause it's like,
"Then who am I?"
- So, Scott, when you're asked,
"Who are you?"
what do you say?
- It's hard to answer
that question
because I haven't
figured out who I am.
I'm developing every day
my personality and who I am,
but inside of my brain,
I don't know who I am.
♪ ♪
- You are the collection
of all of your memories.
Right?
I mean, that's your story.
Those are things
that happened to you
and they're in the past.
They can't be changed.
But it can be created.
[film reel humming]
An illuminating Harvard study
found numerous examples
of seemingly sane people
who believed
they had recovered memories
of past lives
and alien abductions,
and there's no deceit.
These people actually believe
that these events occurred.
- And I remember I was
just literally scared to death.
- Once people have decided
that a memory is real,
the brain can fill in details
that never happened.
Especially
if the clues you're getting
or what people are telling you
isn't entirely accurate.
Leading cognitive psychologist
Elizabeth Loftus
made that point
in a 1996 experiment
where she convinced
over 25% of the subjects
that they had been lost
in a shopping mall as a child.
Your brain will just take
those untruths and run with them
and fill in details
out of nowhere.
Completely changing
your personal history.
♪ ♪
When we last saw
our Who You Were subjects,
they did not recall
the false memory we planted.
When you were about
four or five years old...
- Mm-kay.
- You actually took a ride
in a hot air balloon,
but you dropped something.
- I'm not sure
if I remember that to be honest.
- You took a ride
in a hot air balloon,
and you dropped something.
- I don't remember that.
- We've let the memory
sink in over night,
and today we're gonna see
if physical stimuli
will help solidify this story
in their minds.
Today is all about you...
- Mm-hmm.
- And a little drive
down your memory lane.
- [laughs]
- This is where
you rode over
in a hot air balloon.
- [laughs]
In a hot air balloon?
- That's right.
- Maybe my parents mistaked me
for, like, a--another kid.
- Some other kid?
- [laughs]
- We'll get out and walk around
and see what can come back.
Let it all soak in,
and tell me
if anything's
coming back to you.
- Hmm.
I don't know, man.
It's not--it's not popping up.
- You dropped something...
- [breathes deeply]
- When you were
in this hot air balloon.
Will this be the detail
that pushes Tim
to remember the event?
- What could I have dropped?
What did I walk around with
back then?
♪ ♪
- I spent another 15 minutes
attempting
to kick-start Tim's brain
with details
of the false balloon story.
Has anything come back?
♪ ♪
- No.
- Hmm.
- [laughs]
- Tim's brain
doesn't seem susceptible
to the false memory.
Let's check in
with our other subjects.
This is where you took
your hot air balloon ride.
- Really?
- Yeah.
This is Echo Park?
- And--
- It was about 15 years ago.
- Yeah.
- You don't remember any--
anything from this.
- No.
- Of course he doesn't.
It never happened.
This is where you took
your first hot air balloon ride.
- This is?
- This is it, yeah.
- Are you serious?
- I'm serious.
Does this bring back memories?
- Um...
♪ ♪
- You don't remember anything
from this?
- Um...
I do remember,
like, something as a kid.
I-I dropped something.
- He dropped something.
Now how do you suppose
he got that idea?
You dropped something.
Dylan's mind
is gradually taking
an idea we planted
and adopting it
as his own memory detail.
- I could have been around here
riding my bike,
then we took
a hot air balloon ride,
and possibly dropped
a Superman cape.
♪ ♪
- For some people,
physical sensations can be
an effective trigger
to bring back real
or imaginary memories.
What about smells and sounds?
- Well, when I was
four or five when I was here,
I remember it smelling...
fresh.
- This sensory memory
may be a jumping off point
to begin accepting
the false memory.
You remember looking down
on the park from above?
- I might remember, um...
♪ ♪
Being able
to overlook the water.
Um...
I remember, like, standing over
and squatting,
and, like,
just, li--
being so happy to be up there
and the wind
blowing my hair back,
and my dad kept
telling me to sit down,
and I wouldn't sit down.
- Yeah, you weren't scared.
- [laughs]
- How high up were you?
- Probably, like...
800 feet.
- No kidding.
- Yeah.
- Wow.
Victoria's false memory
is beginning to take hold
with the help of her
imaginative subconscious brain.
What do you remember seeing
from up in the hot air balloon?
- The water fountain,
for sure...
- Yeah?
- And I could have been crazy,
but I think
that I could have felt,
like, almost a little bit
of mist hit my skin
from the water fountain.
- What color was the balloon?
- I wanna say it was red.
- Red.
- Yeah.
Let's see if
the seed I planted earlier
has taken hold.
You took a ride
in a hot air balloon
and you dropped something.
- I don't remember that.
- You dropped something.
- I did.
At that age,
I was a huge Barney fan...
- Ah.
- And I just, like, remember
just, like--and looking down
and him just being gone.
- [laughs] About where
did it fall do you think?
- Um...I would say
six or seven blocks away.
- Oh, really?
So not in the water?
- No.
- By now,
it seems Victoria's brain
has turned our suggested memory
into a complete
childhood experience.
- I remember
waking up at, like,
9:00 in the morning,
getting in the car,
and then my mom and I
being in the car
having no idea
where we were going
'cause he loved to do that.
Just put the family in the car
and just go somewhere,
and just, like, surprise us.
- Victoria is personalizing
this false memory
by merging it
with pleasant details
from her childhood.
- And next thing you know, like,
we're just, like, flying over,
like, the whole,
like, greater Los Angeles area.
- So who do you think was
in the basket with you?
- Well, definitely
both my parents.
I know we got something
to eat afterwards.
Almost I wanna say, like,
a churro or something like that.
- Post-balloon churro.
- Yeah.
[laughs] Yeah.
- It's a classic.
- Now that
our subjects are convinced
that the balloon ride
happened...
- [laughs]
- Oh, shit.
- It's time
for a reality check.
Tell your mom, uh, the memory.
- We went, like,
on a hot air balloon ride,
and I dropped,
I think, my Superman cape.
Why you looking like that?
- [laughing]
No, Dylan.
That never happened.
- Wait, what?
- There was never
a balloon ride.
- We made the whole story up.
Well, you made most of it up.
- Oh, wow.
- But isn't that amazing?
Because, remember,
we planted that story.
- No, that is.
That's actually really crazy.
I-I was actually having these--
these, like,
weird, faint memories
of me, like, looking over,
like the pond,
and, like, you know--
I don't even know.
- Has Dylan been
to Echo Park before?
- Oh, wow.
- And now it's Victoria's turn
for a rude awakening
from her father.
- Hi.
- The story is not true.
- What?
- You've never been
in a hot air balloon.
- What're you guys
talking about?
Why would you make that up?
- Did you truly believe
that you'd been
in a hot air balloon?
- Yes.
- You remembered
so many details...
- Yes.
- Of something
that never happened.
- Yes.
- How many times you been
in a hot air balloon?
- None.
- So what were you remembering?
- I'm not entirely sure
because I really do
feel like I have a memory.
- We all are susceptible
to this.
- I really felt like I had
experienced that experience.
- And what about our YouTuber,
Tim?
- Well, Tim, I'll tell you what.
It's not surprising
that you don't remember
anything from it.
- Mm-hmm.
- 'Cause it never happened.
- I knew it.
[laughing]
I was like, "Dude..."
- Tim wasn't susceptible.
But false memories are common
and can have
real-world implications.
The innocence Project
of the United States claims
that faulty
eye-witness memories
account for 72% of convictions
overturned by DNA evidence.
♪ ♪
So who are you?
Well, how could you be
any one thing?
You are always changing.
If you can lose track
of your past,
and your memories
can be altered
or implanted,
in the end,
who are you really?
Maybe...
you're the stories
you're telling yourself,
and as always,
thanks for watching.
[electronic music]
♪ ♪