Hello!
First of all, this video, of course, is of a historical and philological nature:
how the Old Russian names were arranged.
But I also want to tell you some autobiographical nuance:
why my name is Mikitka, the son of Alekseev.
According to my passport, I am Nikita Alekseevich, but I came up with the idea of calling myself Mikitka, the son of Alekseev, back in the tenth grade, this
s one of the forms of the Russian folk name.
That was the name of all our ancestors two hundred, three hundred, four hundred years ago.
Well, all our humble ancestors.
Since I don’t have an aristocracy in my family at all, such a name just suits me.
The first reason why I abandoned the name Nikita and took Mikitko
is that now we have become painfully cool, and almost all of us have
Church Slavonic forms of our names in our Soviet-era passports.
For everyone in Ancient Russia, and among the people until the 20th century,
full church forms of names were used very limitedly.
A person could have two completely different names: one - a pagan, Slavic, for example, household name:
Tretiak, Bazhen, Nechay (hence such surnames as Tretyakov, Bazhenov, Nechaev);
and another name - baptismal: Timothy, Boris, George.
And it is clear that at first the church name was left for special occasions, for religion;
he was often hidden from strangers, and in ordinary life everyone knew the person under his popular name.
If a person already had only one name, a church one
(well, in the later era it was more often the case),
then he still had many forms:
one of them was Church Slavonic in appearance, others, a large number of them, were
Old Russian, that is, folk.
Let's say it's just nonsense for some peasant woman to be called Elizabeth:
only Lizaveta, Liza, Lizanka, and so on;
or Elena: only Alena, Lena and so on;
or the potter's name was Daniel: only Danilo, Danil, Danilko and so on;
or Theodore: only Fedor, Khvyodor, Fedko, Fedya and others.
An interesting story already from the 20th century: my grandmother had two cousins, and they lived in Klintsy,
and their parents moved from the village to the city.
So, everyone - all relatives, all friends, acquaintances - all of them were called only
Lyolya and Talka.
Grandmother says that she found out the real names of the sisters only when she was already over twenty,
well, she saw some documents there,
and they were called by the passport - what do you think?  -
Elena and Natalia.
Grandmother said that it just shocked her then, it didn’t even occur to her
that Talka and Lyolya - well, these are some kind of colloquial forms, and it just seemed to her that, well, such rare names, yes ...
Please note  that in ancient times, folk forms did not sound childish, rustic, insulting, dismissive;
they were also often used by adults and respected people.
Names such as Gavrilo, Sudilo, Yanko, Milko, Miloshko, Fedko could be used in letters
in relation to a merchant, a boyar, and even a bishop.
So, in the Nikon chronicle under 1171,
the death of the posadnik Vasily Buslaev is mentioned,
and he is called "Vaska Buslavich".
There were other posadniks, for example, Peter and Miroslav, who are named Petrila and Miroshka.
And even Prince Vsevolod is sometimes mentioned in the annals as Vsevolodok.
Or, pay attention, the well-known Old Russian text is called
"Questioning Kirikovo", well, or a variant of "Kurikovo",
and Kirik is not Kirill!  - it was a respected person, a
mathematician, a thinker, a monk.
Exactly the same thing happened with other Slavs:
some diminutive forms completely replaced the original names.
Take that South Slavic - Ivanko, Mirko, Branko, Goiko, that Polish - Leszek, Jacek, Frantisek, Marek:
everywhere we see diminutive forms.
The name of the first Polish prince, the baptizer of Poland, for a minute!  - Meshko.
That is, it is a folk form from the full name "Mechislav".
It's the same as if we called our baptist
Volodya.
A radical change took place in Muscovite Russia.
On the one hand, in the culture of the then society,
there was a demand for such linguistic means through which one class
can show dominance over another.
On the other hand, it was also necessary to show Christian humility.
This is how the oldest Slavic tradition was represented by meanness and self-abasement.
Then it became obligatory for a superior person to call himself the so-called "half-name".
The superior himself was honored to be addressed in full, ecclesiastical form.
This rule was canceled by a special decree only by Peter in 1702,
and before that, the serf peasant Andrei was Andreika for the clerk,
but for the tsar, the boyar Andrei was also Andreika.
In turn, the superiors themselves eventually began to call the niello
only folk forms,
but for people equal in their position, the
diminutive form was not offensive or derogatory.
On the contrary, she sounded friendly and familiar,
ordinary people always communicated with each other like that.
Although for a person of a different status, this would sound familiar:
"He is not Dimon to you!"
Russian folklore also often uses diminutive forms
in such a good-natured, positive meaning.
So, in epics, the heroes Vaska Buslaev or Dobrynushka Mikitinets are often sung about,
or in songs about Stepan Razin, the forms "Stenka" or "Senka" predominate.
But, on the other hand, you can also meet negative characters, for example,
Kudrevanko, Tsar Kudrevanovich.
Why at the end "o" and not "a"
Now Slavic names with "-o" have become very rare in Russia,
although they are still common in Ukraine:
Gavrilo, Petro, Yurko, Pavlo and others.
We have them, if they exist somewhere - well, at least in the culture of the last centuries -
this is mainly in the Russian north, where there is an okane.
The same Mikhailo Lomonosov.  Or also connoisseurs of North Russian folklore
know the old "Vavilo and buffoons" for sure.
Suppose Gavrila Ardalionovich in Dostoevsky's The Idiot is written through A.
Or the impostor Grishka Otrepyev.
We also just have names Yurka, Sasha, Petka, and not Yurko, Sashko, Petko.
Danila Cross through A, although the older form is on O,
compare: BG has the song "Ivan and Danilo",
or Letov's song in the text says:
"How blind Ivashka ran after the sun",
but the name of a linguofreak known to many of our viewers is  Ivashko.
But in the 18th and 19th centuries, probably because of akanya, all masculine words beginning with "-o"
began to be declined like words beginning with "-a".
That is, it also affected cities, such as "Vilna", "Kovno" became "Vilna", "Kovna";
This also affected Ukrainian surnames,
that is, if earlier they were "Shevchenko", "Shevchenko", "Shevchenko",
then they became "Shevchenko", "Shevchenko", "Shevchenko",
at the beginning of the 20th century, in general, their declination became non-literary,
well  and the same process happened with names beginning with "-o" like Mikhailo, Mikitko, Gavrilo.
That is, the spelling "-o" remains, and the word is inclined differently for a long time.
The second reason why I abandoned the name "Nikita"
For most foreigners, including Poles, it sounds feminine.
Male names with "-a" for other peoples are generally rare,
so all our Pashas, Sashas, Petyas, Yuras sound very feminine for most foreigners, and the nam
"Nikita" is doubly unlucky: it does no
t have a full form for a consonant,  this is on
and two - in the West it is well known precisely as a female name,
this was facilitated by the film "Her name was Nikita".
I once asked a Pole who did not know about my channel
what his associations are with two names:
Nikita and Mikitko.
He immediately said to Nikita that it sounded feminine,
and to Mikitka he replied that it sounds strange,
it seems that this is the name of someone from the east (meaning - from the Eastern Slavs),
moreover, it seems somewhat outdated,
he added that  he would not be surprised to come across such a name, let us say, in a novel by Sienkiewicz.
Well, I thought that this is probably one of the most successful associations
that can arise for my name,
so, at least for the Polish audience, it is well chosen.
Yes, yes, I also heard that there is something Japanese in the name
Mikitko, but I have already decided to close my eyes to these associations.
Why M and not H at the Beginning
These two sounds often change into one another in Slavic languages,
because both are nasal consonants.
Hence such a form of the name Nikolai as Mikolay or Mikola,
in Novgorod letters there are such forms of the name Nikifor as Mikifor or Mikiforko,
in the northern Russian epic one sings about the hero Dobrynushka Mikitinets.
Why a patronymic and not a surname
Firstly, I didn’t want to shine with my full name, and now I don’t want to,
secondly, my surname is quite common,
I personally met in my life as many as two of my namesakes by name and surname,
it is obvious that in  there would be even more of them on the Internet, and it would be quite difficult to find me.
And thirdly,
before most people, except for the nobility, did not have surnames, there
were only patronymics and nicknames.
Well, just as until now, suppose, the
Icelanders do not have surnames, a country with a population of more than three hundred thousand;
at this point, globalization has not affected them.
It’s not without reason that my patronymic sounds like a surname,
because most of our surnames come from ancient Russian patronymics:
whose son?  - Ivanov, Petrov, Fedorov, Vasiliev, Dmitriev.
Please note that this naming was also not purely common people
, even the princes used it.
For example, in one chronicle of the end of the 12th century it says:
"... repose Mstislav son Rostislavl, and grandson Gyurgev".
This refers to the Novgorod prince Mstislav the Brave.
Or in another chronicle, later:
"The Great Prince Vsevolod, the son of Gyurgev, the grandson of Volodymyrov Monomakhov, his son Yaroslav, sent to Pereyaslavl."
As historians now call this prince, I think it’s understandable,
because the grandfather’s nickname is presented.
The full title of "The Tale of Igor's Campaign" is
"The Tale of Igor's Campaign, Igor's Son of Svyatoslav, Grandson of Olga."
So, I remember, I once amused my art history teacher,
then, in the tenth grade, when I had just seen such a name format in the annals,
I signed my test work
"Mikitko, son of Alekseev, grandson of Ivanov, great-grandson of Vasiliev."
There are also ancient princely charters with such signatures, let's say, a
charter around 1130, and
"Behold everything gave Varlam Mikhalev son", a
charter around 1192.
At the same time, many scribe books with such forms of names
were kept until the 18th-19th centuries, well, of course, mostly
people of simple origin were already recorded there.
Suppose, "Marchko and Fadeyko Nekrasov's children; Miroshko Tretyakov's son;
Danilko Menshikov's son; Kornilko Bazhenov's son" and others.
Many of the people we know supposedly by last
name didn't actually have a last name.
So, for the first printer Ivan Fedorov, Fedorov is a patronymic, not a surname.
He also often signed "Ivan Fedorov son Moskvitin",
that is, his first name, patronymic and nickname.
Also, patronymics, but not the surnames of the traveler Afanasy Nikitin or the militiaman Kuzma Minin.
Why "son of Alekseev" and not "son of Alekseev"
As you can see, I also had a choice of word order.
Moreover, the second type - Alekseev's son - nevertheless met in real texts much more often.
But this is not surprising: this word order is natural for the Russian language.
And then, imagine, it would be like the Irish:
McCarthy, McDonald, McGrath ...
But I chose "son of Alekseev", and here's why:
firstly, if "Mikitko Alekseev's son" is written,
then it is more likely that the latter  the word will simply be discarded, they will
say "Mikitko Alekseev", as this, in fact, happened in general in the history of the Russian name,
and ... then all the flavor disappears.
Secondly, the word "son" in fluent speech often loses emphasis,
and if it is "Mikitko son Alekseev" - this is normal,
but if it is "Mikitka Alekseev son", then with fuzzy pronunciation the question involuntarily arises:
"Who-who-who  "Alekseevson?"
Well, then two associations:
either this is a Scandinavian surname, which is unlikely in our area,
or, God forbid, Jewish!
[irony]
And thirdly, if the word "son" is at the end, then we get a rhythmically uneven combination:
"Mikitko Alekseev son" - well, three unstressed syllables at the end is a lot.
Results
Despite the fact that I used to call myself "Mikitka son of Alekseev" for quite a long time,
this old Russian flavor is no longer so important for me,
as it was at the age of 17,
I still think that the choice of the name was successful.
This sounds unique;
you can just call me by my name, and it's immediately clear who you are talking about.
It's called a mononym.
That is, when a person is known exclusively by name and there is no need to specify his
last name, patronymic, nicknames, origin, profession, and so on.
And who in our Russian culture can even boast of such a thing?
Ermak, Nikon, Avvakum, Nestor
(unless you mean the author of this moronic channel on Youtube, which has recently been hyped),
or - the female names are mostly singers -
Zemfira, Pelageya, Alsu ...
well, perhaps that's all.
Game I
suggest you, brothers, dear sisters, think about
what your name would be if you lived only three or four hundred years ago.
Write the resulting options in the comments, maybe someone will come up with a very beautiful combination.
First you need to take your name in folk form.
If you don’t know, see how it looks in Ukrainian,
or check Wikipedia, there are different options.
Remember: there will always be many options, and that's okay.
Then you can add the diminutive suffix "-k", and for the masculine ending
, "-o" is preferable, for the feminine - "-a",
however, if you don't want it, your name already sounds very dashing,
then you can not do this  .
Then add the word "son" or "daughter"
(depending on your gender).
Next, take your middle name according to the type of surname on "-ov", "-ev", "-yn", "-in".
Please note that since this is your father's name,
there should not be a diminutive suffix
so that the endowment suffix does not change in the end.
So that from Sergeev you do not become "Sergeikin",
and from Timofeev - "Timofeykin";
let's leave such amusing forms to the
clerks of Muscovite Russia.
Well, some examples:
Alexandra Kirillovna - Sasha, daughter of Kirikov,
Gleb Petrovich - Glebko, son of Petrov,
Philip Sergeevich - Pilip, son of Sergeev,
Maria Fedorovna - Marya, daughter of Fedorov,
Nikolai Georgievich, Mikolko, son of Gyurgev,
Daria Alexandrovna, Dasha, daughter of Alexandrov,
Mikhail Alekseevich, Mikhailo, son of Alekseev  .
And on that, brothers, dear sisters,
goodbye for now.