Is there a border we will never cross?
Are there places we will never reach,
no matter how hard we try? It turns out,
there are. Even with sci-fi technology,
we are trapped in a limited pocket of the Universe
and the finite stuff within it. How much
universe is there for us and how far can we go?
If you look at the night sky, you
might assume it will be there forever.
Stars are born and die again in a cycle that
feels endless. But it is not. Take the milky way:
Up to 200,000 light years in diameter,
containing some 100 to 400 BILLION stars.
How many stars do you think are born
here each year? Thousands? Millions?
The answer is around three. Three new stars per
year. 95% of all the stars that will ever exist in
the universe have already been born and we live
at the tail end of the age of star formation.
We are at the beginning of the
end of the universe as we know it,
the formation of new stars
will continue to slow down.
But there is more. It turns out the
universe is rushing away from us.
The Milky Way is not alone - together with
the Andromeda galaxy, and more than fifty
dwarf galaxies,it forms the Local Group, a
region of space about ten million light years
in diameter. Our galactic neighbourhood.
Hundreds of galaxy groups like the local
group make up the Laniakea Supercluster, which
itself is only one of a myriad of superclusters.
In total there are around two trillion galaxies
that make up the current observable universe.
Unfortunately, even if we could travel at light
speed, around 94% of the galaxies we can see
are already unreachable for us forever. Let this
number sink in for a moment. The simple fact that
there is a limit for us, and that there is so much
universe that a human will never be able to touch,
is kind of frightening. Why are all of
these galaxies out of reach already?
Well, it all has to do with why there are
galaxies in the first place: the big bang.
We are simplifying here, but in a nutshell
about 10^-36 seconds after the big bang,
the young universe was a very small bubble of
energy. It was not completely uniform though,
some parts of it were a tiny, tiny bit denser
than others, which had massive consequences.
In a process called cosmic inflation,
the observable universe expanded rapidly,
from the size of a marble to trillions of
kilometers, in a trillionth of a second.
This was so fast that all those tiny differences
in density were stretched from subatomic distances
into galactic distances. Which is why the whole
universe consists of more and less dense regions.
Pockets of the universe, filled with a bit
more stuff than the space around them. After
that short but powerful inflation ended, gravity
began trying to pull everything back together.
Inside the denser pockets gravity emerged
victorious and so over time, they grew into
groups of galaxies, like the one we live in today.
The Local Group is our pocket of the universe.
But at the larger scales, outside the
denser pockets, the expansion of space
never stopped. This means that our Local
Group is surrounded by a lot of stuff,
but none of those structures and galaxies
are gravitationally bound to us. The more the
universe expands, the larger the distance between
us and the other gravitational pockets becomes.
Even worse for us the expansion of the universe is
accelerating. We don't know why this happens so we
came up with the concept of dark energy. You can
imagine it like an invisible effect that speeds up
the expansion of the universe. We will explain
these concepts in more detail in another video
though, for now all you need to know is that
the universe is expanding faster and faster!
This expansion means that there is a cosmological
horizon around us. Everything beyond it, is
traveling faster, relative to us, than the speed
of light. So everything that passes the horizon,
is irretrievably out of reach forever and we
will never be able to interact with it again.
In a sense it's like a black hole’s event
horizon, but all around us. 94% of the
galaxies we can see today have already
passed it and are lost to us forever.
Wait, if we can’t interact with
them, how come we can still see them?
Well, the way we are able to see something is
via light. And although the speed of light is
the fastest way to travel through the universe,
it needs time to get from one place to another.
Every second light reaches us from
trillions of galaxies that have
passed the horizon because when their light
was emitted, they were much closer to us.
We are looking at their ancient past
and see their ancient positions.
So the observable universe is much larger than
the universe we can actually interact with. In
a sense, the universe is pulling off a great show
for us, showing us things that are out of reach
forever. We have no idea what these galaxies look
like today and we will never know. But we will be
able to observe them for a long time as their
light hits our telescopes. Interestingly this
means that currently the observable universe still
appears to be growing as more and more light,
released by super distant galaxies billions
of years ago is arriving at our doorsteps.
Still. All the pockets of the universe outside
the local group will one day pass our cosmological
horizon . Once they do, their light won’t be able
to reach us anymore and from our perspective,
they will fade away into darkness. Every second
of your life 60,000 stars pass the horizon.
Since you started watching this video around 22
million stars have moved out of our reach forever.
Ok, but if 94% of the observable universe is
beyond the cosmic horizon and gone forever,
that still leaves us with 6% that is technically
in reach, which is still a ton of stuff:
All the galaxy pockets that are less than 18
billion light-years away. They are still moving
away, but slow enough that we could physically
reach them, although chances are shrinking with
every second that passes. Everything that is
more than around 5 million light years away
is moving away from us. But the closest galaxy
groups are receding the slowest so there is a
time window to jump galaxy groups. The challenge
is extreme though even for type 3 civilizations.
Even at the speed of light, a trip to
the Maffei Group, the closest pocket of
galaxies outside the local group, would take 11
million years. If some sort of super motivated,
super advanced civilization
takes this challenge on,
its potential sphere of influence could
expand to hundreds or thousands of galaxies.
Although as time passes and the universe
grows, they would be separated forever.
It is pretty safe to assume that
humans will not make this journey,
at least not with technologies that
are even remotely on the horizon.
For us, the Local Group is most likely the
largest structure that we will ever be a part of.
Just traveling between the stars would
be an achievement of epic proportions.
We would already be incredibly successful if we
colonize our cosmic backyard. Which accounts for
0.0 0 0 - 0 0 0 - 0 0 0- 01%
of the observable universe.
As dark energy pushes the rest of the universe
away from us the Local Group will become more
tightly bound. All its galaxies, big and
small, will merge together to form one
giant elliptical galaxy with the unoriginal
name „Milkdromeda" in a few billion years.
This process might even smash huge gas clouds
together and respark star formation for some time!
And this new light will be very welcome because
at some point, the galaxies outside Milkdromeda
will be so far away that they become too faint
to detect. Once this happens, no information
outside of the Local Group will reach us ever
again. The universe will recede from view.
A being born in the far future in Milkdromeda
will think that the universe consists of nothing
but its own galaxy. When they look far into
empty space, they will only see more emptiness
and darkness. They won't see cosmic background
radiation, and they won't be able to learn about
the Big Bang. They may have no way of knowing
what we know today: the nature of the expanding
universe, when it began, and how it will end. They
might think the universe is static and eternal.
Milkdromeda will be an island in the
darkness, slowly getting darker and darker.
Still, with its trillion stars, the Local
Group is certainly a big enough playground
to entertain humanity for a while. After
all, we still haven't figured out how to
leave our solar system and we have dozens
of billions of years at the very least,
to explore our galaxy. And we have the incredible
luck to exist at the perfect moment in time
to see not only our future, but also our most
distant past, just by looking into the night sky.
As isolated as the Local Group is it is our
home. And it really is a spectacular place.
Time for some behind the scenes content.
You might have noticed that we sorta already
made this video a few years ago. But the original
had a regrettable mistake. In it, we said it
would be physically impossible to ever leave
the local group to reach other galaxy groups.
But our travel limit is actually much larger,
as we showed in this video. It's not
physically impossible to go further
but just extremely unlikely that it’ll ever
happen. So why did we leave the video up?
Well it has to do with the nature of the
mistake. We talked to Astrophysicists
and they thought it didn't matter.
The parts they considered important
were correct and they thought
we should just leave it and move
on. Which is one of the funny things about working
with astrophysicists. Rounding up or down a few
billion is not too important to them, as long as
you’re kind of in the right ballpark, because of
the humongous numbers they work with. So with
that feedback, we decided to spare the video.
But since 2016, and really thanks to you
birbs, we were able to grow Kurzgesagt and add
fact checkers to the team and develop an in
depth process with experts and our detailed
sources documents to avoid these sorts of mistakes
and also to make our work transparent. We can’t
avoid making mistakes from time to time,
but we can work hard on getting better.
And this video kept bugging us. So we finally
decided to replace it, not just reupload,
but remake it better and longer and add
fun universe facts to make it worthwhile.
Sorry for taking so long. We’ll leave the old
video up but pin a comment and change the title.
If you want to support us and our sometimes
exhausting but hopefully worthwhile methods,
you can watch, share and click the
bell and get something from our shop.
Inspired by this video’s topic we created a Milky
Way Poster and a Local Group Poster and we are
working on a series about the entire universe.
Visit our shop for more science-y and kurzgesagt-y
products designed with love and produced with
care. In any case, thank you for watching.