Kurzgesagt is lying to you, in every video,
even in this one. Because our videos distill
very complex subjects into flashy ten minute
pieces and unfortunately, reality is, well,
complicated. The question
of how we deal with that,
is central to what we do on this channel
and something we think about a lot.
What we mean by lying is the
concept of “lies to children”.
The idea that on the path to explaining something
complicated you start off with a little lie,
a useful oversimplification, that makes it
easier to grasp a concept. For example as a
kid you learn that the earth is a sphere orbiting
the sun with planet buddies. But it's not actually
a sphere and the buddies are super different
in size and not close to each other at all.
By beginning at a place of oversimplification
you are building a framework,
a foundation that you can then build upon
and add nuance and complexity later on.
Step by step you are getting towards the
real gist of the complicated subject.
Science communication has to use
“lies to children” to some degree
or it turns into science education. And getting a
proper education in all of the scientific fields
would take years of intense
study to become fluent in them.
As a species we have a major interest in
summarizing science and its advancements
and educating as many people about it as
possible, because we all benefit if more
people have a fact based, scientific world view.
We will discuss what science is and how it works
in different videos in more detail, but for
now let's just say it's a process to advance,
organize, predict and test our
knowledge about the universe.
If you understand the current
state of scientific knowledge
then you can make better decisions,
based on facts and testable ideas
rather than outdated belief systems or
our intuition that evolved to protect
our ancestors from lions but is no longer
suited for the complexity of our modern world.
Our brains are comically ill prepared to
navigate the fast moving world we happen
to live in today – a world ironically created by
science. A few hundred years ago it was possible
to be knowledgeable at an expert level in
pretty much every field of study. In the
information age this is a futile endeavor since
knowledge and data are increasing exponentially.
So to even have a chance of grasping the world we
live in we need summaries that give us, if not a
true understanding of all the details, a solid
overview. Explaining science to many people is
not about enlightening the ignorant but necessary
for the progress of our species at large.
To make this possible we need to find
metaphors and stories that capture the
true nature of things as much as possible while
using a language that our brains can deal with.
A great example here is physics.
Quarks are often depicted as blue,
red and green, with different spins. But just
saying spin and using colors forces our brain
to imagine colorful spinning balls. Which is
great to visualize the different types and the
relationships between quarks, but also creates
a very wrong image of reality in our heads.
Molecules are nothing like the neat
diagrams that we're taught in school
but buzzing and vibrating entities held
together by something we call “charge” that
describes how certain things want to be close
or escape each other for some unknown reason.
We are describing phenomena that we are pretty
sure exist in some form or another because the math
works out and we can do real world experiments
and predict their results before we do them.
In reality these are models,
tricks to summarize what we know
and make up a coherent story and prepare
the ground for more in depth explanations.
Don’t confuse the description
of a thing for the thing itself.
Simplifications like these are
not just meant to dumb things down
they are actually useful for
experts themselves. For example
chemists who use “wrong” electron shell models
to work out chemical bonds or scientists using
simplified models as the basis of discussions with
colleagues across different scientific fields.
But the simplification of science can also
be problematic for a bunch of reasons.
Finding the true nature of reality is
super hard because our brains did not
evolve for this job and the universe
does not care if we understand it.
Science is a process to work towards gaining
knowledge and not an absolute truth generator.
The answers it provides are multi-layered and
nuanced and that complexity can get lost when
it is simplified. Especially when it is done
so for headlines. An interesting cancer study
turns into a potential cure, a healthy
food becomes the basis for a new diet.
Such simplifications give a misleading
definiteness to science which goes against its
process-like nature. When cures don't materialize
and diets don't turn out to be magical,
we lose confidence in science and start to think
of all science communication as misleading.
Then there is the opposite effect:
If a simplification is too engaging, if the story
it tells is too good, it can distort the true
complexity of a subject and give you a false sense
of security and an illusion of deep knowledge.
A gut feeling that you understand the science
better than you actually do, which can lead
people to ignore actual experts over their
dangerous superficial knowledge and gut feeling.
And this can have negative consequences for all
of us because in the worst case overconfidence
in your own understanding of science can
lead to bad decisions made with confidence.
Just think of the surge of people that
confidently disavow vaccines or climate change
without truly understanding the subject matter.
So considering all of this and the fact that we
at Kurzgesagt reach millions of people
with our videos, how do we handle this?
Well, it has been a journey, especially the
research. When we started we just read articles,
then moved on to books, peer reviewed papers, then
to conversations with experts. We began to collect
our sources. With every step we realised that we
were still not doing enough. Nowadays we try to
read as many primary sources as possible, talk to
multiple experts and document our simplifications
and give further reading in our sources doc.
But this doesn’t make our process flawless.
What do you do if experts disagree with each
other? What do you do if you find an amazing fact
that perfectly fits a narrative but just can’t
find its primary source? How do you deal with
the reality that many scientific results have
huge error bars or “maybes” attached to them?
How do you handle complex
systems that defy easy answers?
In the end, we make ten minute videos, so we
need to make decisions about what details and
explanations can fit, which aspects need to be
simplified and which parts to cut.There is no
single best answer for how to do this and so we
weigh the different options every single time.
It can be painful for experts
to see their field simplified.
Some are happy with us, while others don't like
it. This is fair but also impossible to avoid.
We are still trying to improve and want to be
transparent about what we are trying to do.
For example we are taking part in the TRESCA
project about science communication to learn more.
All of this brings us to
the purpose of our videos.
The most important thing we want to do with this
channel is to inspire you and spark your curiosity
for science and the amazing universe we live in.
Learning often doesn’t feel like fun, but with the
right story, it is one of the best things and
we hope to provide that to you. Ultimately we
hope that we light a fire in you that motivates
you to read books, pay more attention at school
or university and just get interested in a
scientific field or two and learn more on your
own. Not because you have to, but because you want
to know more about how the world really works.
Because the universe is beautiful and science
is a way of seeing this beauty more clearly.
And we hope that knowing that we have to simplify
a bit does not make you enjoy our videos less.
We are trying to build something with
Kurzgesagt and while we are not 100%
sure yet what exactly, hopefully something that
gets people to think about their own life and the
context they exist in today, as well as the far
future and the potential we all have as a species.
And of course how big things are and what happens
when we blow stuff up, because it is fun. Thanks
for watching and sharing and supporting
us – we really can’t do this without you.
Running a science communication business
is a balancing act that we take extremely
seriously. On the one hand we need to
be responsible and look out for the team
and be able to grow responsibly on the other hand
we have to protect the integrity of our videos.
You are enabling us to stay independent
because while we do things like sponsorships
or commercial work, the majority of
our income comes directly from you,
the birbs. Kurzgesagt is fundamentally
funded by its community. By you. Because
of you Kurzgesagt is able to invest as much
time in our videos and try to become better.
You get our calendar every year, support us on
Patreon and get your personal birds, watch our
videos without adblock or with Youtube premium
.Our favorite way to keep the channel running are
our sciency products from our shop that hopefully
add additional value to the world. We love
bringing little pieces of knowledge into your home
or classroom that inspire you to learn more about
the universe in a little more detail. Especially
with our carefully researched infographic posters.
Our latest one teaches you about the night sky and
showcases the stars in our night sky and
their special significance for humanity.
With every purchase you directly support
what we do on this channel. Please don’t feel
obligated to do so though! Watching and sharing
is already helping us out a lot and we are just
grateful that so many of you care about what
we try to do here. Thank you so, so much.