ole depeditation the bending
when light is you let the levis
you can make laminae the word life
may be ten here and my choice has long ten in
may no winter would come to ony bail how to
weight on my side
so why will not be
and up and up lie and sit
the sky so labeled on to
din of the say good bye
the disguise for ever so we will be
of people weather on a kid in the
vital never stars
where the yes take
sign you make the seasons in verse i
don't want habitat to see a carton
no winds control you
people want entendsound how sorry pony
cast you koine my friend and live
u i know with from would what does matter
like don't stop me now say that up it's
on deep weather no hopes man or bring me down
as he does done like shining
i am a bus that clouds are far singin
they bet mill and ali and a
sand best so
the water budas have desave
a
bit i bid the weather
won pardon and the winter one run down
i nominated the state
he