when light is the levis you
can make lamina the word life in me tanker and my choice has long ten in
may no winter would come to ony bale or to weight on my ho i keep you by my side
so why will not be and up and up lie and see
of the sky so labeled on to sadin has to say good bye
the disguise forever so we won't be of people weather on a kid in the
vital never stars it whether may cost
a sight make the seasons in the sky i don't want this abate humor but to see that
cas you keep one my friend and
stop me now jane did of its on dedweather no home is gone bring me down as
he does done like shining and bust clouds are far indigent
stay with mill and ali and apply and set an first so i believe
the water bodies have these by cletgy for ever
so we will be a bit i fit the weather more bardi and the winter will never eden
we tasting