When life gives you lemons
You can make lemonade
But life gave me Tank here
And my choice has long been made
No winter will come to Ponyville
I'll do it on my own
I will keep you by my side
So I will not be alone
And I'll fly, and I'll fly
Until the end of the sky
So I'll be the one who doesn't
Have to say goodbye
I'll clear the skies forever
So we won't be apart
I'll keep the weather warm for you
And the winter will never start
Weather-makers Pegasi
You make the seasons in the sky
I don't want to sabotage you
But you see, I've got to try
No winter can come here now
I'll keep the warmth and the sun somehow
I'm sorry, ponies, this has to be
For I need my friend and he needs me
I know it's wrong, but what does it matter?
'Cause nothing's gonna stop me now
I'll change it all, it's only the weather
And nopony's gonna bring me down
I'll keep the sunlight shining free
And I'll bust the clouds apart so you can stay with me
And I'll fly, and I'll fly
Until the end of the sky
So I'll be the one who doesn't
Have to say goodbye
I'll clear the skies forever
So we won't be apart
I'll keep the weather warm for you
And the winter will never start