Ivan Vasilyevich Changes the Profession (HD)
Oh, shit!
Listen, what is it? The lights are out again.
What a mess! Timofeyev blew the fuses again!
- Comrade Timofeyev, when will it end? - I'm finishing it now.
I'm asking, when will your irresponsible experiments,
...which is resulting in de-energizing our whole building, do you understand?
If you only knew, Ivan Vassilyevich, what a most useful invention
what experiments I've been conducting, you wouldn't be talking like this!
Experiments with electricity, my dear comrade, should be done at work,
and at home electric energy should be used for peaceful, domestic purposes!
I am on vacation, so I work at home. My experiments are absolutely safe.
As a member of the public I declare to you: Stop it!
Today you burned the fuses, tomorrow you will burn down the whole house!
Well, we'll have to increase the voltage. Is it dangerous? Of course it's dangerous,
but the risk, as they say...
It's a hard problem to meet love.
The planet goes round and round, round and round,
The planet is flying away Through the turmoil
It's not easy, it's not easy To love on it
The January blizzard is ringing and the showers are whipping hard
And stars rush in circles And cities make noise.
People don't see each other, they pass each other by.
People lose each other, and then they never find each other.
And somewhere there's my heartfelt love
Unrepeatable, eternal, eternal...
I've been looking for it, but in the hustle and bustle of days
It's not easy, it's not easy to meet her.
The January blizzard is ringing And the tide is whipping hard
And the stars rush round and round And the cities rumble
People don't see each other, They pass each other by
People lose each other... And then they never, never find them,
And then they'll never find each other.
I can't imagine what's going to happen now! I wish it wasn't a scandal!
They're exhausting, these scandals.
I've been divorced three times. I don't count Zyuzin.
I've never been so worried.
All right, let's go.
Oh, Shurik! Shurik! Your machine will ruin you.
My machine, Zinochka, will make me famous! And you, too! - Yes.
I'm sorry to disturb you, but I have some terrible news to tell you.
My gloves were stolen from me at the cafe today.
And I fell in love with someone else. Do you understand me, Shurik?
- What gloves? - Not the gloves, but I fell in love with someone else.
But here it is! Don't contradict me and don't make a scene!
What? You're asking who he is? And, of course, you think it's Molchanovsky?
No, I don't. Zupperman? Wrong again. Well, all right! Let's not play hide-and-seek.
It's director Yakin! - Well, well, well.
This is weird, though. This is the first time in my life.
"They tell him his wife is leaving him, and he goes, 'well, well. It's not even polite."
- He's, what's his name, blond, tall? - Well, that's an outrage.
Not interested in his wife like that! The blond one is Molchanovsky.
And Yakin, Yakin is talented. What? You're asking where we're going to live?
Today we're going with him to Gagra, to choose a place to shoot,
and then they should give him an apartment. Unless, of course, he's lying.
He's probably lying!
Ah, how silly! Out of jealousy to insult the man!
I pondered for a long time during sleepless nights and came to the conclusion,
that we weren't right for each other. Understand, I'm all about movies, about art!
I'm amazed at your calmness! And you know, Shurik,
it makes me want to have a scandal! - Don't. - You think so? - I'm sure.
Well, goodbye, Shurik.
Just don't discharge me yet. You never know what might happen.
Alexander Sergeyevich, tell Zinaida Mikhailovna...
I can't tell her anything, she's gone away.
- Gone where? - With her lover in the Caucasus. - What do you mean, with her lover?
And you speak so calmly about it? You're an original man!
But you have character! If I were your wife, I'd go too!
If you were my wife, I'd hang myself!
Rude!
Dental clinic? Hello? Extension 3-62.
Could you please call Anton Semyonovich Shpak?
- Anton Semyonovich, for you! - Who's asking? - Some woman.
Don't shut your mouth! I'm listening!
Anton Semyonovich? Hello. What time do you work today?
This is an artiste speaking. No, I don't know her, but I'm dying to meet her.
So you'll be working till four? I'll call you again. I'm very persistent.
I'm waiting.
That was my lucky entrance!
Citizens, keep your money in a savings bank, if you have any!
But what business is it of yours what happened to my wife?
Whether or not we divorce her is our own business!
It's a public matter. With your divorces, you're lowering our numbers drastically.
I'm asking you to hold off on getting a divorce until the end of the quarter.
And then divorce as much as you like.
When you talk, Ivan Vassilyevich, it's as if you're delirious!
And again about your suspicious car. I beg you, report it,
or we'll report it ourselves.
There's nothing suspicious about this machine. I just invented a time machine.
In short, I can permeate space and go back in time.
- Go back in time? - To the past.
Such experiments are only done with the permission of the proper authorities!
The apparatus would be of unheard of benefit. I'll explain everything to you now.
Well, everything!
And now we will experience my time machine in action.
You are witnessing a historical event.
We will now pass through space.
- Did you see that? - What? Did you see? - What is it? What's the matter? What's the matter?
Where did the wall go? - What's the matter? There was a wall here just now!
Comrade Timofeyev, you'll answer for the wall according to the law. Did you see what machine was invented?
- Half of the apartment has disappeared! - Nothing has disappeared!
I've seen wonders of technology, but this!
- Excuse me, who would you be? - Who would I be? - Yes!
- I'm a friend of Anton Semyonovich Shpak. - And what are you doing in his apartment?
Waiting for my friend. What did you think?
How did you get into his apartment if he's at work? - What a vulgar question!
You see, I got through time. I got what I wanted!
- So it's any wall you can take out? - The wall!
- Your invention is priceless! Congratulations! - Thank you.
Why are you looking at me like that, Father? I don't have any designs on me.
I have my doubts. You're wearing the same suede jacket as Szpaka.
Jacket? Suede? Isn't there only one Shpak in all Moscow who has a suede jacket?
- What's your last name? - I'm an artist of big and small academic theaters!
And my last name is too famous for me to mention it.
Perhaps you'd like to go back to Shpak's room? I'll open the wall for you.
No, no. I'd rather look at your car. I like it very much.
I'm very glad! You're the first to see it. You're the first witness, so to speak!
I've never been a witness before!
She's looking! You'll wipe a hole on me.
- Can you imagine what you saw? - You bet!
And in the store you can lift the wall? Ah, what a useful invention!
- And you came to Shpak with a tape recorder?
You see, bypassing all these walls, I can pierce space.
- I can go back 200, 300 years! - Yes, yes, yes.
- You ignored my question about the tape recorder. - Yuck on you!
Oh, what a machine! It really is a new word in science and technology.
Blast you again.
We're about to go back in time to see ancient Moscow!
Come to your senses, Comrade Timofeyev! Before, you understand, to see the ancient Moscow
without the permission of the proper authorities! - Wait a minute! - What is it?
- You interfere in the academician's experiments one more time, and you'll stand in the way of progress... - Understood.
Go ahead.
- I'm worried. - Courage, I'm here!
To the heavenly village... ...to the Reverend Abbot Kozma...
- Kozma... - The Tsar and Grand Duke of all Russia... ...of all Russia... - Cheers...
Write further!
- Look! This is Ivan the Terrible! - You go!
Demons! Demons!
Go away! Go away! Gone!
Alas for me, a sinner! Woe to me, the wretched murderer!
- Wait! Get lost! - Wait! - Go to hell! Evil force!
- Where are you going to call? - The police! - Put the phone down! - What?
- Put the phone down! - What? Hang up what? - Put the phone down! - I won't put it down! - Put the pipe down!
- Why not? - Hang up the phone, I'm telling you! Hang up the phone!
- I'll kill you, hat!
Where are the demons? Hit the demons!
Get down!
Wait! Wait!
Locked up, locked up, demons!
That's what the life-giving cross does!
Where is the tsar?
We need a snack!
Hurry up!
- Oh, how they scream! - They can't scream. They've been dead a long time!
- Have you ever seen a dead man shoot? - Open up, dog! - Who's he for?
- You! - Me?
Oh, this is hard for me! Tell me again, aren't you a demon? - I've told you a hundred times what I am!
- I am not a demon! - Oh, don't lie! You lie to the tsar!
Not by the will of man, but by the will of God, I am the King! - Very well!
I understand perfectly well that you are a tsar, but... - Alas for me, Ivan Vassilyevich!
- Alas for me, sorcerer. Send me back! - I can't! Because of that damned golden eagle!
All the transistors have burned out, and until I buy them, I can't send you back!
Then buy them!
- Stores are closed, it's lunchtime. - Oh, woe is me! Oh, woe is me!
- Calm down, Ivan Vassilyevich! Oh, woe is me!
- Do you drink vodka? - Anise. - That's it!
Anisova, unfortunately, no. Stolichnaya.
- Drink up. - Taste from my cup! - What's that for? - Taste it!
You think I want to poison you?
We don't do that. And in this age it's easier to be poisoned by sprats than by vodka. Drink up!
- Cheers, boyar! - Bless you!
- Did the key-keeper make vodka? - Let it be the keywoman. Have a bite!
Did you make a car like that? I had one of those, too.
I made the wings. - Well, well? - Well? I put him on a powder keg.
Let him fly. - Why so cool?
- I don't drink, Ivan Vassilyevich. Thank you. - Do you respect me?
- Jesus, Ivan Vassilyevich. - Then drink! - Just a little! Stop, stop!
- Well! Cheers! - Cheers!
So this is where you live? It's a small room!
- It's certainly no tsar's palace! - Yes, of course it is!
- And where is your noblewoman? Is she in church?
And my noblewoman ran away to the Caucasus today with her lover Yakin.
- You're lying! - By heavens! - Caught? - Ha. - If they catch her, I'll stake Yakin!
- Why, Ivan Vassilyevich? Why? They love each other and let them be happy.
Oh, you're a good man!
My God, why am I here and the Swedes took Kem?
Boyar, send me back. Go and buy those transistors.
I'm busy! Call me later.
- I'll go with you. - Down the street? No, that's out of the question. Wait for me here!
- Only you, boyar, hurry up! - I'm in a hurry myself, I have to bring those two back too!
- What will happen to them there? - They'll cut off their heads and that's it.
- That's all, eh? - To hell with them!
Take demons alive!
Stop!
Eureka! Czar's clothes. Get dressed! You will be king!
No way!
Get dressed, I'll kill you!
Talk to me, my seven-stringed friend,
My soul is full of you, And the night is so moonlit.
Oh, one more time, one more time, Many, many, many, many more times.
One more time, and many, many more times.
Cornflowers in a clear field, A long way off.
My heart is torn with longing, And in my eyes there's anxiety.
- Well, how? - Oh, it doesn't look like it! Oh, hackneyed!
Let me at least tie my teeth. My misfortune!
- You see, that one has a smarter face! - I'll ask you not to touch his face!
Sit down! Mind your state business. Take the stick. Dictate!
- Dictate what? - Well... The Tsar and Grand Duke... repeat.... All Russia...
-Tsar and Grand Duke... repeat, All Russia. - Yes... Don't repeat it! Repeat! Quiet!
So you say... The Tsar and Grand Duke. I did, comma.
Where's our secretary gone? What's the matter, comrades?
I'm asking you, precious ones, what's the matter?
What parasite dared to break down the doors to the tsar's room?
Weren't they hung for you to break them?!
Go on, Your Majesty! He's beating his head in. Semicolon.
So I'm waiting for an answer to the question I asked.
The tsar, the tsar is here, the tsar is here...
The tsar is here!
Sit! And where should he be? The Tsar is always in his place!
Don't order execution, Great Sovereign, hope! The demons have seized thee.
We've been chasing them all over the chambers! And there are no demons!
There were demons. We don't deny it. But they self-destructed.
So please stop this silly panic. Who are you?
- Theophanes, clerk of the ambassadorial office. - All right, Fedya. Stay here,
and the rest of you, please clear the tsar's office. In short, everybody out.
- Bark at them! - Wo-o-o-n!
- Do not execute, Great Sovereign, hope! - Yes, that's enough tumbling!
I did it once, I did it twice, that's enough!
What's the matter with you, Your Majesty?
Have you got an ailment?
Don't be silent like a stump! I can't work alone!
- My teeth hurt. - He has periostitis, flus. Don't pester the tsar.
- Fedya! Stop bowing. You'll be falling down till tonight.
- Let's meet! - Don't be angry, Boyar, I don't recognize you. Are you the Prince?
Я? I guess I'm a prince! What's so surprising?
Where did you come from in the tsar's chamber? You weren't there?
- My dear tsar, who is he? - He's a friend of Anton Semyonovich Shpak.
Oh, you fool!
The tsar says I'm Prince Miloslavsky. Does that suit you?
- Dibs... Get lost! - What is it? It's not good again! What's the matter?
- You were executed the other day! - That's news to me!
They hanged you at your own gate on the third day by order of the king.
Oh, thank you! They hung me on your order. Help me out, or we'll fall asleep.
Why don't you say something, you bastard? А? You remembered! It wasn't me who was hanged.
- What was the name of that hanged man? - Vanka the robber.
- Yes. And I'm the opposite, Georges. That bandit is just my namesake.
- Am I right? - Mm-hmm. - There you go.
- What are they yelling about again? Run, Fedya, find out! - Yes, yes!
Tsar, Tsar, Tsar...
Puck, puck...
The men of the service want to see the Tsar saved. They're rejoicing!
No, that's out of the question. There's no time. We'll rejoice later.
Send them away immediately, understand? The damned man won't say a word.
- Why, Fedenka, there's no war now? - Of course there isn't, fedya!
The Swedes are really jamming, the Crimean khan is outrageous on the Izyum road.
- How could you let this happen?! - Don't order an execution!
Stand up, Fyodor! I don't blame you. Sit down.
"Write: 'The Tsar's decree. "
I order to send an army to dislodge the Crimean Khan from Izyum Road.
Sign it, Great Sovereign.
I have no right to sign such historical documents.
Tell them not to hurry back. Let them take Kazan on the way back.
So they don't have to go twice. - How can it be, father,
Kazan is ours. We took it long ago. - Yes? You were in a hurry.
- Don't order an execution! - All right, then. Once we've taken it, it's all right. We can't give it back to them.
Well, go! And be out of here in five minutes.
In the green springtime Under the old pine tree
Vanyusha bids farewell to his beloved.
He tinkles with his ring and speaks softly:
"Don't cry, don't cry, beautiful Marusya.
Marusya is silent and tears are shed, Her soul is aching with sorrow.
Drop, drop, drop From Marusya's clear eyes
Tears drip on the spear
Drip, drip, drip, drip, drip, drip,
Drip, drip, drip, drip.
In cold winter, again under a pine tree.
Vanyusha meets his sweetheart.
He rings his ring again, and says softly:
I've come back to you, my beauty.
Marusya sheds tears of happiness, Like a psaltery her soul sings.
Drip, drip, drip, From Marusya's clear eyes
Tears drip on the spear...
Well, let's get on with it. Why isn't the inventor spinning his time machine?
- Oh, my God! What a scandal waiting for me at home! - What's the matter?
- I didn't tell Ulyana Andreyevna where I was going! - Oh, yes, of course. - That's just it!
Excuse me for disturbing you during your family drama,
tell me, is Ivan Vassilyevich not with you? They're looking for him all over the place.
Oh, what a scoundrel! And why did I open up to this holy man?
Shurik, are you home?
What's that, huh?
Oh, my God! It was me who took that scoundrel Yakin's suitcase.
Not only did that hysterical woman make a scene at the studio,
she got our suitcases mixed up. It's an hour before the plane.
Karp Savelyich! I can't believe my luck.
Wait for me and I'll be back.
Hello! Anyuta? You can't imagine! I'm going to Gagra! With Yakin himself!
I think, Zinaida Mikhailovna, you know very well that after what you did at the studio,
what you've done at the studio, it's all over between us!
- Karp Savelyevich, you scoundrel! - I'll ask for my suitcase back.
I hope all my things are in one piece.
You scoundrel! Scoundrel!
I'm leaving my husband, this holy man with all his comforts.
The ingenious inventor. I'm going to that... scoundrel!
- My God, what text, what words! - You don't know the real words yet!
And two hours before I leave, I find him with some kikimora,
He grabs her hands and behaves like the last bastard!
I had a scene with her! Hysterical woman. It's my professional duty.
Professor de fois! - That's enough! I've had enough.
"I'm leaving you for director Budimir Kosoy's production of Boris Godunov."
- Kosoy is a hack. - And you're talentless! I'll play the tsarina with him.
Kosoy has no one for the role of John the Terrible. - What? No John?
- I've already rehearsed with him. - Where did you rehearse? - Here!
- Who's playing Boris, the Tsar? Who? - Boris the Tsar who?
Boris the Tsar?
What, are you really rehearsing?
So he, the wicked one, paid the wicked one for the pre-tribulation?
He himself wanted to reign and rule everything? He's guilty of death!
My God, what a type! Bravo, bravo!
Please, go on!
Why have you offended the boyarina? Smerd!
Wonderful! Amazing! Genius! Look, I don't recognize you in your makeup.
Who are you? Sergei Bondarchuk? No. Yuri Nikulin? No, no...
My God, Innokenty Smoktunovsky!
Kesha!
- How could you hide this from me? - Oh, you pikey death pimple!
- Are you crazy? - Here, you son of a bitch! - Kesha! That's not witty!
Oh, my God!
Scoundrel, son of a bitch! You wretched adulterer!
That's the real tsar!
Help! Help! Help! Militia!
On your knees, you worm!
I got you, you adulterous son of a bitch, Yakin!
Say your prayers, son of a pike! Say goodbye to life.
- Oh, are you rehearsing, Zinaida Mikhailovna? - Re-pe-pe-pe-ing...
What kind of rehearsal is this?... Call the police. - Where? - I'm here, I'm here.
Just like you play! And the tsar is so typical...
He looks like our Bunsha!
And me, Zinaida Mikhailovna, I've been robbed. The dog and the police promised to come!
Who do you belong to?
Excuse me, comrade artiste, but what's this - whose?
- Whose peasant, I ask? - Excuse me, but I don't understand you!
You stupid peasant!
- Why are you always a smerd and a smerd? - It's the role he's playing. Well, that's the role!
It's a scolding role, I beg you not to apply it to me!
What a house - now they steal, now they call me names,
and we're fighting for the honorary title of a house of high culture of life. It's a nightmare!
- Well, you pimple, ask the boyarina for a belly or a death. - Stomach.
- Belly, belly. - Have mercy on him, Your Majesty!
Belly? Have it your way!
Hear me out, Karp. Only, I beg you, be calm.
This is the real Ivan the Terrible!
Remember what I said about the time machine? Well, Shuriku has had this experience!
- He could have stabbed me! - And by the way, he would have done the right thing!
Bullshit! Who's John the Terrible? He died a long time ago.
- Who died? - I'm not talking about you! It's the other one who died, who...
- Did you seduce the boyarina? - Я. I am. My life.
What is your life, you stinking dog! Look at yourself! Vita!
- Tell me something in Slavonic. - Paki...
Paki, Paki... And the cherubim! Your Excellency, have mercy.
By the way, you misunderstood me!
How can I understand you if you don't say anything?
I don't speak languages, Your Excellency.
- Do you love the boyarina? - I love her! Madly!
Oh, boyarina, she's beautiful, she's inky with her lips, and her eyebrows are all alike.
- What more do you want, dog? - Nothing. - So wait, bury the dog. The Prince is letting her go.
I ask for your hand, Zinaida Mikhailovna!
Hello! Galochka? You're going to die. That's wonderful news! Yakin has abandoned
his kikimora, so he persuaded me to fly to Gagra with him.
Well, you sinful beard, if I find out anything bad about you!
- Don't interrupt the tsar! - Yes, I will!
- I give you a fur coat from the tsar's shoulder! - Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you... I'm very grateful to you!
Your Majesty! You can't stay like this.
There's no telling what they might think.
God Almighty! I've forgotten where I am. Lord! I forgot!
- Change your clothes, John Vassilyevich! Oh, the devil's clothes!
My thoughts are confused: a fur coat, Tsar John the Terrible...
Stop fidgeting! John the Terrible, what's the big deal?
- You'd better go and help the tsar change his clothes. - Yes, sir!
Hello! Vava? You're going to fall!
My God! He looks just like our Bunsha!
Not at all! It suits you very well. My dear tsar, we must be going.
- Since we're very late for our plane. - Good riddance!
Let me thank you for everything! You're a very temperamental man!
Hello! Shurochka? Imagine, Yakin fell in love with me like a boy,
proposed to me and we're going on a honeymoon.
Touch it!
Oh, what a beauty! It's beautiful.
It's soooo good!
A smoke break!
- The Swedish ambassador... - What is it, Fedya?
- The Swedish ambassador's been asked to accept!
Bring in the citizen ambassador!
Move your eyebrows! Move your eyebrows!
Der großer könig, das swedischen königreich, zande mich.
Seinen trayen diner, zu inen, tsar i feliki kneze
Ivan Vasilievich usarussa.
- Intourist, speaks well! - What does he say exactly? - The devil knows!
- We need an interpreter! - We had an interpreter for him to translate, but he doesn't know a thing.
We boiled him in boiling water. - That's no way to treat interpreters!
- Answer something, you see, the man's tiring himself out. - Hitler kaput!
Go on, Mr. Ambassador. We absolutely agree with you!
- Kemska volost! - That's right, absolutely...
Listen, comrade! Comrade, can I talk to you for a minute?
I'd like to understand, so to speak, in general terms, what he needs.
You can understand him, my dear tsar, of course. They want Kemsky parish.
We fought in the war, they say, so bring it here! - What, what? Kemsk parish?
- Let them take it away in good health! I thought, Lord! - How can it be like this, fed?
The tsar knows what he's doing! The state won't be poor! Take it away! Take it away!
Don't execute me, Your Majesty! Speak your word!
Are you a son of a bitch, an impostor, squandering the lands of the state?
There won't be enough parishes to go around!
What shall I tell my king?
- Give your king my warmest regards. - And Kemsk parish?
Such matters, my dear ambassador, are not resolved from the blink of an eye. We must consult
with our comrades. Come back in a week. By the way, a little souvenir for you from me!
Here you are.
Well, auf Wiedersehen! Goodbye! Au revoir! In short, ciao!
Everyone is free.
Yes, the convoy is also free. Convoy free!
- Why are you crawling, Father? - The ambassador has lost his knighthood from his chest.
You can't be so absent-minded. You should watch your things when you enter a room.
- Why are you staring at me, Fedor? Don't you think I've taken it? - You didn't!
You didn't take it?
Or maybe you rolled up behind the throne?
Well, no, I didn't. - What a woe!
I'm having second thoughts again, Shpak has the tape recorder, and the ambassador has the medallion.
What are you hinting at? I'm asking you, what are you hinting at, tsar's face?
The Tatar prince Yedigey to the sovereign!
The reception is over. Lunchtime.
The king desires to dine!
- This is some kind of dream! - Wait a minute! Who's paying for this banquet? Who's going to pay for it?
Not us, anyway! Fedya, what's in there?
Ah, hare's kidneys, pike heads with garlic.
Black caviar! Red caviar! Yes... Foreign caviar...
Eggplant caviar!
- It's beautiful! Well, tsar, shudder! - Shudder.
- It's beautiful! - Hello! I'm looking for him all over the house, and he's sitting in someone else's apartment.
Why are you turning your back on me? - Look how my apartment has been cleaned!
It's all that was earned by hard work, it's all ruined!
What do you look like, huh? You've gone crazy from drinking! You're unrecognizable!
- What are you wearing? - An imported tape recorder... - He's drunk!
A gold cigarette case, domestically made, there's nothing.
He can't stand on his feet! Where are you going?
What the hell is this? Go home, alcoholic!
- Leave me alone, old lady, I'm sad.
Old lady? You're a jerk! I'm 5 years younger than you. Come on, let's go now!
- You're a witch! - Guard! Guard!
- Ooh, a witch! - Honestly, yes!
- What do you want? - Dear Ivan Vassilyevich,
I ask you to testify. Here's a list of stolen things:
Two tape recorders, two movie cameras, two cigarette cases. Please!
- It's like filing a petition to the tsar! - Allow me! You're not hooliganism!
What kind of drunken tricks are these? I'll file a complaint against you - a collective complaint!
I can see you, peasant, won't give up!
A psychiatric hospital? My husband's got delirium!
He attacks people with a knife.
- Stop, put that knife away! - Knife!
Look at our activist! He's an armed bandit!
- A peasant! - I hear from a peasant! - A peasant!
Now the police will decide which of us is a peasant!
- I beg you, wait! It's not Bunsha! - What do you mean it's not Bunsha?
It's John the Terrible, the real one!
I'm busy, call me later!
I told you a secret, you're a decent man. I beg you, promise to keep quiet.
- Not at all! I give you my word of honor. - Thank you, thank you.
Militia? That's the talk of today's stolen Spak.
I'm not talking about the theft. We've got a cleaner case here.
Engineer Timofeyev summoned a living tsar to his apartment.
I'm not a drinker. With a dagger. A cold weapon. You have my word of honor. Waiting.
- I can imagine what a fight is going on at Izyumskiy Shlyah right now! - That's all right!
Fedya, why are you huddling by the kidneys? Come here, don't be shy.
Here. Let's have a drink.
Listen, old man, do you take jewelry at your jewelry store?
- You got it! - Shudder.
The tsarina is here to see you, Your Majesty! She wants to see!
You shouldn't have taken it off! You don't have a tsar's face.
What? But I'll ask you! Who are you talking to? You lackey!
Dear Tsarina, I'm very glad to meet you! Very glad to meet you.
Very glad to meet you. Hello. Tsar... Pleased to meet you, Tsar.
Pleased to meet you. The tsar, the tsar, how do you do? Hello, tsar, how do you do?
Please, please come to our table.
- I think we've met somewhere. - What are you talking about, you bastard?
A human being! Waiter! Kidneys once to the tsarina.
- Excuse me, your name and patronymic? - I'm Marfa Vasilyevna. - Wonderful!
Charming! Marfa Vasilyevna!
- A shot of cardamom? - Oh, not at all! - Why, don't refuse. Bless you.
You say you're a tsar, a tsar. And you think it's easy for us tsars? Not at all!
All workers have two days off, we tsars work without days off.
Our working day is irregular.
Have a bite, Margarita Vasilyevna, it's all paid for.
If you want to know, we tsars should be given milk for free!
"Health magazine says so directly: nerve cells are not restored."
And yet you work hard, great lord, like a bee!
Margo, you're the only person who understands me.
- Another drink with a pike head? - Oh, no, no, no, no!
- Tell me, don't you have a separate office? - You, your nobility, you've had your fill!
Why don't you maestros say something? Come on, give us something!
It's not a big cloud that's drowned out. A cloud!
It wasn't the big thunders that rumbled.
Thunder!
Where's the Crimean Khan going, dog?
Dog!
What dog is that?
I won't let you sing such songs about the tsar! You've gone wild here without me.
What's your repertoire?
We should sing something massively modern. How's that? Tilly, tilly, tilly, tilly,
Tili-tili. We're not tili-tili, we're not tili-tili.
Calm down, Vanya! It'll be done.
- Excuse me, what's your patronymic? - Marfa Vasilyevna. - Well, Marfa.
Eh, Marfusha, should we be in sorrow?
- You, Father, just tell us how it is, and we'll take it. - Stop! Quiet.
Suddenly, in silence,
Knocks at the door.
You've come to me, haven't you? I do and I don't.
The snow was falling, the dawn was breaking, Autumn was drizzling.
So many years, so many years, Where have you been?
Suddenly, like in a fairy tale, the door creaked, All is now clear to me.
So many years I fought with fate For the sake of this meeting with you.
I've been freezing somewhere, sailing across the sea. I know it wasn't for nothing.
Everything in the world was not in vain. It was not in vain.
You've come, you've come true And don't wait for an answer.
How could I live without you in this world?
He who waits Will bear it all, No matter how hard life beats him.
Just as long as it's not all in vain.
Everybody dance!
The army is in revolt! They say the king is not real!
- Dear Autocrat, we are lost! - I demand a continuation of the banquet!
Missing how? Why?
Here!
- Hurry, Prince, bring me back! - In three minutes it will be ready!
Right away, Ivan Vassilyevich. In the meantime, you'd better change into your czar's clothes.
Do you smoke? Don't smoke? You're doing the right thing.
I don't smoke either. Who are you, anyway?
- I am the king. - A nickname! - Quiet. Surname?
- We are Rurikovich. - Name, patronymic? - Ioann Vasilievich. - John.
- Year of birth? - 1533 A.D.
- We're joking. - So much for Tarapunka and the plug. - Quiet. Where do you live?
- In the wards! - What wards?
Your address, your address!
- Tell me, what's my fault, boyar? - The wolf of Tambov is your boyar!
- Did you take Shpak's apartment? - Shpak's? - Yes!
I took Kazan, I took Astrakhan, I took Revel, but I didn't take Shpak.
Here he is! We've got you, my dove! You've waited, drunkard?
- Who are you? - Comrade Lieutenant, I'm that alcoholic's wife.
Liar! You're not my wife, old woman!
He's drunk out of his mind. He doesn't recognize his wife. We had to call a psychiatrist.
That's it! I see he's talking nonsense. He took Kazan, he took Astrakhan.
- He calls himself Tsar - Ivan the Terrible. - White fever. A typical case.
- What's the patient's real name? - Bunsha Ivan Vasilyevich.
- Liar! You witch! - I can't see him!
Attention! Get ready, Ivan Vassilyevich!
Take the impostors alive!
Black caviar!
Red caviar!
Caviar from overseas, eggplant caviar!
Comrade Timofeev! Alexander Sergeyevich! Save me! Save me! Save me!
Ivan Vasilyevich, hurry! Farewell!
- Alive? - Alive! No one will believe it if I tell them! - The police will believe it!
Your Majesty! Just a moment!
Interesting movie! Why do you have, comrade scientist, police on duty at the site?
- Oh, it's your friend, Shpak, who was robbed today. - What are you saying?!
- Another one was detained, Comrade Lieutenant. - No, they didn't. I came to you myself.
I want to confess to you wholeheartedly. I'm delighted to surrender to the police.
- Who are you? - Ivan Vassilyevich Bunsha.
- So you claim to be Ivan Vassilyevich Bunsha? - Well...
- Your papers! - I left them at home.
- And who can confirm your identity? - Anybody! At least ask my wife.
Did you want to confess something?
I confess that not of my own free will, but under the compulsion of Prince Miloslavsky,
I was temporarily acting tsar. - What tsar? And you're the tsar?
- The Tsar, Ivan Vassilyevich the Terrible. - You lie, you dog! I am the Tsar!
Everything I've gained by hard work is gone: three tape recorders, three movie cameras,
three cigarette cases, a suede jacket - three jackets.
And they're still fighting for the honorary title of home of high culture of life!
Tell me again, who is he?
- My God, I told you, my husband is Ivan Vassilyevich Bunsha.
Now you'll be cured, alcoholic. - Wonderful! And who's he?
- An impostor! - An impostor, that's what I hear!
- Well, who's he? - My husband, Ivan Vassilyevich Bunsha. And you'll be cured!
- So you have two husbands? - That's right, two husbands. - And both are Bunshas?
Both!
And you will be cured! They'll cure you, too!
And I will be cured!
What you told me is grandiose! As an eyewitness, you're priceless!
If I were you, I'd start my doctoral dissertation right away.
There's no hurry. I'll always have time to sit down.
Are you coming to me? I do and I don't. The snow was falling...
Ulyana Andreyevna, I was a tsarina, but I didn't betray you! I was tempted by the tsarina,
but I didn't give in. I swear it!
- Damn it! Miloslavsky himself was in our hands!
- Georges Miloslavsky? - Nada! Stop him! Quickly! - Now!
Stop! Hold Miloslavsky! Hold him!
I was pretty sure I sent you back.
- Hurry up, Prince, spin your car. - Where have you been all this time?
The militia got you. They're making a case!
The chase, Prince! The chase. Hurry! Hurry, hurry, God!
Run, Ivan Vassilyevich! Run!
- Hurry, Ivan Vassilyevich! - Run, Lord, my grave sins!
- Farewell, Prince! - Farewell! Don't say goodbye, Ivan Vassilyevich.
- It's an outrage! - You've blacked out the whole house again, you know!
Mind you, we'll complain about you to the proper authorities!
What, they let you out of the asylum already?
- What? What is it? Oh, you hooligan! - What rudeness! And you're wearing glasses!
You'll be tried, you bastard!
What was it, was I imagining things or was it really happening?
Ivan the Terrible? Miloslavsky? Ah, because Zina left me!
Delirium, that hit me hard!
What if I'm not delirious?
Oh, my God! What's going on with you? I got high, I got high. And, of course, I haven't had lunch yet.
- You didn't go to Gagra? - What Gagra? You're going crazy with your car.
Oh, where did you plant such a lump?
- Zina, tell me honestly, where were you just now? - At the rehearsal. - All right.
I'll ask you straight out: "Do you love Yakin?"
- What Yakin? What's wrong with you, Shurik? - Don't pretend! He's your film director!
- We don't have any Yakin as a director. - Really? - Honestly.