Every language is constantly changing.  But what will be considered
“the clearest example of
illiteracy and ignorance”, and what will not be noticed at all, is a matter of fashion.
What the media will promote, in popular books, in public, they will notice.  What will be branded a hundred times as a
“mistake”, “half-literacy”, “colloquial”, will be considered as such in society,
even if until recently the intellectuals said so.
And the accent “call” is the clearest example of such promotion and fashion.
Speech nuance
NUANCE 2 - Y
“HE CALLS”
AGAINST
until the
1930s of the forties, both forms existed, the
old form was more usable, but the new one was perceived calmly, and
many even
highly educated people said so, but after the activation of the Soviet norm creators, Stalin’s time,
variability from something  one form is pressed, both are the only correct one, and all the rest are a
mistake, damage to the language, and so on, another and so on you call, he calls,
such famous people of the past as sergei yesenin, zinaida gippius boris pasternak, david samolov andrey platonov, most conveniently say
history  donations over the past two hundred and three hundred years to show on examples from poetry, I analyzed all the example from the corpus of texts of the
Russian couple there is a poetic corpus, that is, poetry and there is a logical accent, that is, not necessarily
poetry, maybe prose should be, it means that the original was stressed for the
first time  stress on the root of the word to call in any  of its forms
is found in
1910 and in general most of the use in the corpus is from
1910 to
1000 forties
out of 78 the use during this time
15-17 were with an emphasis on the root
1517 because there were two cases where you
seem to want to read in size just call but  if you say call, it will be a little
but a little out of size, but still, on the whole, it’s coherent,
however, most of the poems still have accents and friends, please note
17 out of 78, this is actually
21 percent,
you also need to remember about the
specifics of the corpus if something  didn’t get into the corpus before, this doesn’t mean that it didn’t exist before, and in general the very fact that
new stress is already appearing in poetry, that it is generally acceptable in print in
written speech and from says that even this stress was already clearly in speech
long accepted, that is, most likely it arose around the end of the nineteenth century
parsnips for the tenth year
again one full flat empty drop ringing post again a birch tear on further winter furrows of
springs  In 16 years, gently under the trembling of angelic wings, the crosses of the nameless graves of
Plato are ringing.
Samoylov 44 years old do not ring bells in Russia and whether it is necessary to ring the bells,
note that they do not ring, but whether it is necessary to call, we will talk about this a little later, the fact is that in modern
Russian this verb may not have 2 stress patterns, but as many as three  and
after the forties, new stress is less and less common, a
new surge is closer to perestroika, when the language
democratizes,
and in poetry, most likely, it deliberately democratizes literary norms to the evil of the Soviet dictatorship and
across censorship,
although of course for 50 years, but the stress has not disappeared anywhere, but thanks to  school and
propagandist of the correct Russian language in the mass consciousness, the connection of this stress with ignorance was fixed,
for example, in Soviet cinema  you can’t meet this accent, but it’s another matter, but who says
that,
it’s all simple people from the village who
obviously know a little about science,
so spin around, run around on the phone name to enter all the papers all these people all go
work
really can stop
right away I want to say that that  an
hour and a half lecture by Andrey Anatolich Zaliznyak is devoted to the same topic as the next part of the video, an episode from the history of Russian stress,
therefore, those who want to become proficient in the survey from all sides, I invite you to watch this
fascinating shiva video,
so
all Russian verbs in it have only one of three schemes  accents in
red we will designate the shock base on the diagram about the green shock ending,
let's call these diagrams for memory shirks not 1 2 3 so as not to get confused, but using
your usual words with a similar meaning, do not think that I want to scan the fuselage of their
listeners or cause bewilderment in  viewers of
venerable age, this is just a
mnemonic trick, the
emphasis is always on the roots  for example, the verb limonite, the
emphasis is always on the ending, for example, the verb to pick a pea, a bean, etc., and an
accent from a mixed scheme, a verb to masturbate
nothing reprehensible
friends, we even read a text behind the glacier with ourselves where our
wives taught with his hands three fields fool
science above prejudices that our perceptive viewer who  I watched the fourth video conversation,
to which I will also leave a link of the
possible already guessed that the three
stress patterns in the modern language are explained by the fact that
in the Old Russian language there could be three times accent markings about the root,
but the vast majority of our viewers, as I guess, did not watch this video
and therefore they do not understand  how the very accent markings work in general, what is it,
therefore, for simplicity, we will simply take it for granted that
there are 3 schemes in the modern language and that’s all, and
so in the Russian language from the 15th and 16th centuries
there has been a tendency
that the verbs of the scheme to pull begin to turn into the scheme to masturbate,
for example, to  16th century they said only to drown the drowning
tapes  load sollers just turn it on turn it on turn it around and of course it’s variable and the jargon is
hanging out hanging out stupid stupid stupid posting and there are
so many words that it’s impossible to even fit them on the screen
some examples from old literature or from folk dialects
from kulaks and do not last hundreds of different times before  but thousands of them lie
on the
floor
on
but why doesn’t the teacher give the student a deuce when he says mom with a face
why flax catering intellectuals don’t curl their ears into a tube when they hear the phrase Santa Claus gives gifts to children
why why are journalists not under the carriages articles with names in the spirit
the new dictionary of the Russian language resolves the stress you smoke what is it
new  the norms of the Russian language or the crab of the education system, an
astute viewer should certainly note one nuance
all these verbs in which the stress has changed are
transitive verbs, that is, those after which you can put words in the accusative case
cook soup salt potatoes stew a cigarette butt smoke a cigarette roll a cigarette
thus stress in verbs  it’s a way to designate the
grammatical meaning of transitivity, not transitivity,
but after the verb call you can’t put a direct object, we don’t say
call who we say call who the dative case
can be assumed that this is why the Soviet norm of the palaces disliked the verb call because it, they say, is
out of the general  regularities but not everything is so simple
there are three explanations why the verb to call has changed its gift and personally I am more inclined to the latter the
first explanation is the
influence of Western languages
e in English I stuck samvadas in Fr
nch apple kol ken in German on roof elena d everywhere we have transitive verbs
additionally  The
question arises why, at least until now, mostly calls say no, experts in
Western European languages are not intellectuals, but people, well, in my opinion, mainly from the south of Russia or from Ukraine, the secon
explanation is th
Ukrainian-Belarusian South-Russian influence of th
s very point of view  Andrey also adhered to Zaliznyak his
lectures, the fact is that in the Ukrainian and Belarusian languages the stress has shifted not only for transitive verbs, but also for intransitive ones, for e
ample, Russian please and Belarusian you take away or Russian you call, but Ukrainian you drive
away or co
pare some forms may fluctuate in Russian  they may not hesitate, but in Ukrainian and Belarusian, the
accent is only new, say Russian, they wrote send salt but paint only 100, or
it means Russian voice but Belarusian hair h or Russian
produce but Belarusian catch and,
accordingly, say in Belarusian
you pay or in Ukrainian
you call  it will be out of the norm
in this way in Ukrainian Belarusian  In English,
transitivity is not the transitivity of the verb, this is no longer the feature along which the
distinction between different stresses occurs in these languages, some of
their own patterns operate,
although
the same patterns under the influence of fraternal Slavic languages \u200b\u200bmay appear in Russian and there
are already the first swallows, for e
ample, in the second half  In the 20th century, when I couldn’t establish exactly
, the stress appeared, he’s friends instead, he’s friends, the stress shifted and the verb to is
intransitive, then I’ll eat off the tank of respect where to call whom to contact whom to complain about the
inaction of philologists on the face of
3 spring until the middle of the twentieth century, the verb to call was transitive
I myself fell  to this thought, when I studied an example from the corpus of texts,
now we mainly ring the telephone, but also the bell, the bell, all sorts of other similar objects, as well as the tram,
before the telephone appeared and, in general, the telephone became available to everyone,
in fact, the bell rang most often, and the bell
rang part of everything for my husband  not only does it make a sound, and the bell also does not just  then calls in this way a person wants to either inform about
something or call someone,
therefore, in the language of the 19th century, it was possible to call a servant
girl, post an alarm,
morning or evening, his eyes fell on martha, then on crying Zosima again on martha, call
vyacha and aunts do not  they could see the disorder that the flowers would spread out in Asia whimsically Anna Vasilievna entered
called the girl in the cap
ordered her brothers symmetry,
however, the dream did not go away and the artist began to frantically ring the dresses
compare this whole situation with the word to bring down
there is a meaning to throw something and then the transitive verb
to bring down together on the ground  he knocks the bag down there is a
meaning without addition and here the emphasis does not change the same there were not a single line
that he was a training ground for us
and the
third meaning, it seems to me, for modern people, at least for my peers, the
most basic most frequency is to leave to leave despite the fact that  already the verb does not have a direct object,
it changes its stress in the same way as any other
transitive verb from e  of that group, for example, he brings down abroad or we bring down gas spore,
so it can be assumed that in the Russian language of the future the
first or second meanings will become completely secondary;
and
I remember that the verb and go from the scheme to finger the scheme to masturbate on them the scheme of a lemon,
that is, one option, the
regularity of the point of view of the language is the stress call I call you call, but you don’t call evil, you don’t always call the roots,
but even here the question arises why the creators must have opposed both forms  they just don’t have this last
answer, I have a feeling that the
accent
call, call, call, this odds are more common among those for whom these forms are
native since childhood, for example, my grandmother says so,
call, call, call, I hear mostly and those who
deliberately speak in defiance  the norm, or who, with their own lips, voice for themselves a deliberately wrong
option, such is my em  If I'm wrong, please write me about it in the comments. The
emphasis he calls is the best example of how a
natural phenomenon in the development of a language
becomes the main target of the struggle for the correctness of speech. It becomes a
canonical example of
illiteracy.
funny
, firstly, we know that many educated people spoke like this at the beginning of the 20th century; secondly,
hundreds of words with the same linguistic change by native speakers are not recognized as something new, much less as something bad,
what are dear friends and now aufiderzein