Hut, hut, stand back to the forest and front to me.
О!
Kolyvan!
I recognized you, Mother. Will you invite me in, or what?
Come in, if you're here.
I'll join you for a couple of days. Do you mind?
Actually, my sister and her husband are coming to visit me.
What do you got there?
Oh, hold on.
Here, a present for you.
I'm thinking of setting up a shop.
Your merchandise is... so-so.
Average merchandise!
It's rubbish, in a word.
Even so. But it's not just any product, it's European.
Straight from China itself.
Such goods will be ripped off with their hands and feet.
Yes... Well, if they recognize you. Aren't you afraid..,
that the prince will take your head off for your past deeds.
He will, you say?
And so?
Well, pure Basurman. It's like a von baron.
That's it.
and Lyubava says: "Go," she says, "learn Latin."
What do you think?
It's strong.
That's a tough wife you've got.
Ilya, I'm here for you!
And before that, she was pestering me with Ancient Greek.
What?
Well, yes! He says it's a shame not to know languages nowadays.
Go and learn it, she says.
Well, Alyosha! Have you learned it?
No, I haven't. Not very much.
I'm thinking, maybe I'll take Yulia as a tutor.
Yulia's a great teacher.
That's what Lyubava says.
Yeah, there aren't many of them.
Are you in cahoots with her?
Lyubava said even worse things about Julius.
I'm the only one who stops her from talking.
That's it, brothers, coven.
That's it! Give it up!
We've lost again.
How are we going to live?
I'll tell you how. Now he'll promise you eternal peace.
And in the fall he'll attack again.
Sorry, Dobrynyushka, Ilya's telling the truth.
I can't help it.
I understand.
So, until the fall, then?
Till autumn.
It's a mess. Such a heavy load. How do you manage? I can't imagine.
By the way, I'm just finishing my report on gender equality.
Would you like to hear the main points?
We could have a good time.
We could, for instance, spend the evening at my place.
Souvenirs from Europe! Come on!
Oh, souvenirs, you hear, souvenirs. Would you like a souvenir?
The best present ever. Go for it! It's cheap!
Kittens. How much for pussycats? A foreigner.
"Pstsieku, pstsieku, please, lady."
Я... Я...
Oh, German! I knew it!
Allow me to introduce myself, Gaius Julius Caesar. A pleasure.
Just Julius to my friends.
I am archivist and cultural attache,
in terms of foreign relations.
and foreign public relations.
Heartfelt gratitude.
How I adore Germany.
Especially London. How's Montmartre?
How is it? The old man's chipper.
He's chugging along, even though he's not strong enough anymore.
You know, there's no one in the middle of nowhere to talk to.
How much for chocolates?
2,50.
Let's go. I must introduce you to the Prince immediately.
No, I can't. Busy.
Expensive and stiff.
Come, come. First of all, as a foreigner.
you have to sign the prince's address anyway.
And secondly, the Prince loves stories.
Let him hear about foreign countries, that's all.
And they also have toilets all over the street.
You pay the money, you do your job, and then you go on your way.
How? And they take money for that?
Prince.
Pardon me. How? It's a relief for you and a profit for the treasury.
Is that so?
I-I.
Interesting. It's a clever idea.
I found it, Prince.
Well, a book of titels. What titels? What have you brought, you fool?
Book of honorary visitors.
There! You've got a lot of tithele, tithele, tithele. Write it quickly.
Okay, let's start with the red line here. What do you want me to call you?
Basurman, I mean, Baron.
Von, then. It means Baron von Kurdyuk.
Duke, that's Duke in German. It's a famous name.
Well, please, scribble here as a memento.
That's how they do it. And they also say that in Europe,
if a king or even a duke comes out,
and God forbid he should fall at his feet.
Not my God!
Yes, how?
Here's how. All you have to do is nod your head and smile politely.
It's called human rights.
They have a lot of nonsense, of course, but there are also useful things.
Thank you, Baron, for the interesting story.
I think it's time for us to introduce all sorts of Europe.
Otherwise we'll spend the rest of our lives as fools. What do you think?
It's time, it's time.
Baron, could you teach us a lesson?
Teach us how?
You know, your Europe.
Yeah, we can do that. That, as they say, with our pleasure.
Well, here's the deal. We'll start tomorrow.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
No, I won't. He'll pull my head off.
Relax. I'll take care of everything.
Be brave. He'll thank us afterwards.
Guten morgen, guten morgen. How did you sleep?
Oh, you. Take that!
No need, dear Prince.
I'll give it to you, guten morgen.
Oh, don't.
But scientists in Europe have calculated that...
That one bucket of cold water prolongs life by three months.
Really?
I-I.
Stop. I'll explain again. Look at me.
There, there, that kind of casual smile.
And no bowing. My lordship, one more time.
How many times?! We've been here for an hour, and it's no use.
You, you, you! Even I've already understood. And you!
Well, that's it. Come on, Baron, take care of them here.
When you wake up, you'll be ready to call. I've got enough to do.
Julius, follow me!
You are our merciful man, accept the gift, do us mercy. This is the way it's supposed to be.
If you don't give a little bit of this, what's it called, corruption, they will laugh at you.
Uh, why all at once? Come on, let's all get in line.
Yes, Mother, I've got such power, that it's like a wow.
Tomorrow I'm going to put everyone in the oven mitts, all of them.
Well, hold on!
What about the palace?
Is it beautiful?
Yes, beautiful, beautiful. I was...
At school they called me Kurdyuk. So I just blurted it out to them:
"Baron, I'm Kuryuk.
And this one started whispering to the prince: "Kurdyuk, that means Duke in their language."
You're a dust in front of him, he says.
Tell me, in this palace of the prince,
are there a lot of girls?
Well, ladies, I mean.
Dames? What ladies?
You, mother, must be full of hen's porridge.
Who's going to let them in?
That's why everything goes wrong with you men.
That's what?
Because you don't let us in.
Fools!
Come on. Let's go to bed or something.
There's a lot of work tomorrow.
Guten morgen. Guten morgen. How did you sleep?
Well, Baron, thank you, as they say, for the science.
By the way, we learned a lot of useful things.
It's a pity I won't be able to get to your Europe.
How? They won't.
That's it. We've learned and that's enough.
Tomorrow my bogatyrs are coming from the outpost.
We have a military review as planned.
Hey, are you offended, or what? Come here.
I want to reward you. It's valuable, by the way.
Smuggled all the way from Europe. Here.
That's it. Resignation.
What?!
You're deaf, aren't you? I said resignation.
It's all gone.
It's ruined! And you're glad.
You're all sulking now.
I'm telling you, you men,
you can't do anything serious without us.
All right. Let me show you something.
What is it?
You like it?
I sewed it myself.
I don't get it at all. Where's it going?
Ouch. Where, where?
It was my dream. I wanted to be a maid of honor.
A maid of honor...
Yes, a maid of honor... And I will be! Look what I've got.
Why is that?
None of your business. I wonder who would agree to be a prince?
Well... it's... I can do it!
You can... Oh, yes.
You've taken great power over the boyars. All right,
you'll be a prince. Just watch out for me.
Do everything my way. All right?
It's all right! Only tomorrow the bogatyrs are coming back.
What about them?
No. We'll save you for another time.
Here's what we'll do with the bogatyrs.
Well, here we are at last.
Yes, what a beauty.
So I tell Lyubava too, why go somewhere?
And she kept saying: vacation, vacation. What for?
I'll do some exercise, walk three or four versts, and that's my vacation.
Eh, Alyosha, sometimes the soul also requires rest.
And strength, in general, should go to the mind.
If the head weakens, it's not long to lose strength.
Look what I've lost? Did you see that?
I haven't lost anything.
Well, that's the way it is.
Let me pass, good man.
Come on in. Come on in, Grandma.
Gone. Gone. Gone!
Ope.
Ouch. Thank you so much. You helped out an old lady.
Why, Grandma, are you going far away?
No, I'm not far away. And you, my dear, if you're not too weak.
won't you help me again?
Gladly, Granny. Tell me.
What do you want me to do?
Look at my barrel, it's a fine one.
But it's a little rusty.
It needs a little shake on the inside. Can you do that?
What are you talking about? Yes, we can!
Well, that's good. I'll put some water on it afterwards,
and the water will swell it up, honey.
Hush, you wicked one, don't lose the barrel!
Why, brothers? The old dandelion lady tricked us good and proper.
Oh, my shoulder's open.
No, did you see that?
She fights.
Careful, careful, Kolyvan.
Give me an answer...
You're a bastard and I'm not.
Give me an answer... Ah, here!
Whose living portrait do you keep? Let him go free,
Let him come to my captivity.
Look...
Taste the strength of a bogatyr.
You fell down and did your push-ups.
Just like alive. Really?
Well, that's how it is.
It's the third hour of the show for the troops.
Let them just show up - I'll give them a good time.
It must be Alyosha again.
Where's the painting gone?
It's bad luck.
There's plenty of space.
This is where I'm going to fix it.
All my things will fit in here.
Why is it so low, it doesn't go any higher?
We'll put the fridge in the corner and the flowers here.
Okay, a broom... We'll hang the broom here.
And that's all for the garbage.
This... how did you get... Guards!
Get them!
Come on, you two unpleasant-looking men from the box,
come out and use your cudgel to teach the insolent man a lesson.
Hey, why are you so small?
That one over there in the crown.
Uh, uh. What's that for? Where are you going? I've got a posse built over there.
You think you can handle my posse?
This is ridiculous. Isn't it, Julius?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. I think there's been a misunderstanding.
I think the Baron is just a little offended.
So, first, I propose we form a conciliation committee.
Second, we should definitely invite foreign observers.
And finally, thirdly, we'll kill several birds with one stone...
One last warning,
the three bogeymen will be here literally any minute now.
Julius!
Horses and hares - friendship forever.
Let's go! The fatherland is in danger!
Come on, get him out of there.
Quiet! Quiet!
Friends! Faithful defenders of the city of Kiev, here!
You all saw it for yourselves.
Our prince, before... appointed me supreme ruler.
Liar!
Prince, don't push so hard, my hooves are slipping.
The hooves are slipping? Do you know what's going to slide now?
Well, wait. Let me just get to you.
There's a piece of iron sticking out here, maybe it's a ladder, what do you think?
Let me show you, Duke...
I'll make you emperor, I'll make you Caesar.
Well, go.
Oh, look. Look, bogatyrs. Hush, hush.
Taste the enemy's mighty strength.
If your elbow itches, it's a good thing.
There's an omen.
Do we understand?
Bogatyrs, tell everyone if the Prince has named me his successor.
Yes!
Hooray!
Hey, wait. Where are you going? Julius, come on, quickly get down.
Immediately, I said!
Where am I going to go?
I don't know where. Hurry up, the men are leaving.
What is it?
Prince, I don't want to upset you, but now we're going down.
And not quickly, as you wanted, but very quickly.
What's going on up there?
Mom! Aah!
Everyone turn in their silver spoons and forks.
Oh, look - Prince Kurdyuk.
Well, have you sat down? Let the others sit.
All right.
You know what, Kolyvan. I don't want to be a maid of honor.
A maid of honor. I'll become a tsarevna at once.
Did you catch the prince?
Why did you come, then? Go look for him!
Yes, all over the city.
And when you find him...
...you'll throw him in jail.
No! Oh...
Oh, finally. Are you awake?
Were we the ones who were sleeping?
Yes, we were. I've been up a long time.
I'm so hungry.
Let's get out of here.
It's... what is it? Is that... where are we going?
Holy shit, it's the sea.
The sea.
The sea! Yay!
Well...
Yeah...
You know, Nastasia keeps telling me, too:
"Let's go to the sea. Let's go..."
And I say to her: "What haven't I seen there?"
And here it turns out to be nice.
Yes, consider that you were sent on vacation.
I don't need a vacation without Nastasia.
Me and Alyona, she's on business trips, I'm on exploits.
Eh!
No, I can't do that.
I have to eat first, and then go on vacation.
You lie here for now, and I'll go and have a look around.
You don't have to show your tongue to good people.
Hey, that's nice.
Ow, ow, ow.
You'll know how to deal with the Russian bogatyr.
Oh, there's food.
Dookey Speak...?
All right, then.
I'll be off then.
Oh, thank you.
See what I can show you.
Eh, when we get home, I'll take Alenka in my arms and we'll go away.
I don't know, to the lakes or somewhere else.
Well, or mushrooming as a last resort.
That's right. I'll take mine somewhere, too.
To her mother, for example, she's been asking for a long time.
Let's go, what's there, for two weeks.
No, two weeks is a lot. A week. Or three days, at least.
You hear that?
Yeah.
Isn't Aleshka weird?
Alyosha, what are you doing here?
And these are my students.
Bow, bow.
Well, Alyosha.
Wait, actor.
What are you doing, brothers? I'm trying for everyone.
Look how much food I got.
Here. To eat the worm.
Raw fish.
Yes? I hadn't noticed.
All right, guys, stand back.
Eh, now we can go to bed. I hope it doesn't rain tonight.
Look how fast they put the handkerchiefs up.
At least we'll get some sleep.
Here you go, old man, I give you this.
What is that noise?
Sleep, Alyosha.
Yes, what the oligarchs have brought the country to.
What are we supposed to do?
Get out of here! Go home and be as quiet as possible.
I'll call you when I need you.
Yeah.
The prince has not much money.
Well, that's all right. I'll just draw up a decree.
A ball.
What?
A ball! Money later.
Right now I want a ball.
With musicians and everything proper.
What a ball! An edict first. And then...
Kolyvan, I think you've forgotten who's in charge here.
Not at all, Mother.
I'm just sitting here thinking about...
About money.
You have only money in your head.
What money? I'm thinking about the ball.
Well, the cooks are more or less clear.
But which artists should I invite?
Eat, Alyosha, eat. You must have been hungry during your march.
No. I'm not asking about the service. I understand.
It's a state secret. Well, at least tell me,
Maybe you met something interesting on the way.
Did you get there by a shuttle bus or what?
Oh, and how are Dobrynka and Ilya doing?
You're silent. Don't you like me now, Alyosha?
You're running around like a squirrel in a wheel. And he comes and doesn't say a word!
At least once cleaned the floor, or the dishes.
If you say so, I'll do it.
Well, I'm giving you an order. Wash the floor now, aspirin!
Oh, Alyosha, what are you. I was just kidding.
Yes, you must be sick from me. Well?
He is not reflected in the mirror.
Wake up, brothers, wake up.
What happened?
A butterfly in the plague, trouble in the dumas.
There's an omen.
You said it yourself - vacation.
No, brothers, we must hurry home.
I smell trouble in Kiev.
I agree. There's a reason we were crammed into a barrel.
I thought it was suspicious at once.
The great ones are awake!
May you have a good morning.
And it turns out they can talk.
Oh, we great ones live in fear.
And we try not to make unnecessary noises.
Something does not seem.
Yes, wait, Alyosha, let the man speak.
Go on, old man.
Life isn't easy. But it's going to be different now.
Because at last the heavens
has sent us great fire-giving kings.
Please accept these signs of a higher power.
What kind of joke is that?
It's not fitting for a Russian bogatyr to dress up as a tsar.
Wait, Dobrynya. Old man, why do you need tsars?
You seem to be a free people.
It's written in our ancient book.
They can also read.
Alyosha, give you a break at last.
It is written that only great kings can protect us from Gamu.
What else Gamu?
Yes, some kind of monster, which in ancient times invented.
So that children wouldn't go into the woods. And those poor souls still believe it.
We have to help out. Listen up, everyone!
You don't have to be afraid of Gamma anymore.
There is no Gamuma!
That's why nobody's going to eat anybody. Don't worry.
The word of a great man.
The word of a great king.
The great kings said that Gamuma is no longer feared.
Thank you, as they say, for the bread and salt. But they're waiting for us at home.
How will we get back to Kiev?
By swimming, of course.
By swimming? No, you can't swim, it's too long.
Well, how then?
By ship.
Well, you're giving, Alyosha.
Where could he come from here?
Yes, exactly, brothers, the ship.
Hey! On the ship!
We're here! Swim here!
Look, that's right.
We'll soon be in Kiev.
Look, they've come to see us off. Goodbye!
What's that?
Isn't that Gamuma?
I thought you said there was no Gamuma.
Well, my mistake.
Ilya, Dobrynya.
You shouldn't offend ordinary people.
Yes. And if you are.
Hey, big guy, whoever hurts my friends has to deal with me.
Taste the strength of a bogatyr.
Well, that's the way it is.
Is your name Gamumu?
Okay. Well, Gamumu,
you're going to promise us that you'll never
you'll never do anything naughty again.
If we hear one more time...
Well, you know.
Gamumu won't hurt anybody else.
Gamumu's word.
Hooray! Hooray!
What are you so happy about? We lost a ship because of you.
And your book doesn't say when the next ship will be.
A hundred years from now.
How long?
Are we going to be here forever?
I've got Lyubava there. I mean, she's, you know.
She doesn't know.
Yeah, what's up, brother? We're not staying here. We'll think of something.
Right, Dobrynja?
We'll think of something.
Oh, he's not reflected in the mirror!
He doesn't cast a shadow. Look.
What about you?
Not reflected in the mirror.
Dobrynyushka, what happened to you?
It's no use. I've already tortured him.
Well, what did he say?
"Fell down and squeezed" and laughs.
He doesn't remember anything.
Witchcraft.
Exactly.
Where are our real husbands?
Let the prince give us the answer.
Where and why he sent them. Let's go to him.
Prince! Julius!
Prince, where are you going?
Julius, stop!
Severe punishment.
An edict from the supreme ruler:
that all silverware be surrendered by tomorrow.
Severe punishment.
Everyone surrender their silverware by tomorrow.
Hey, who's the supreme ruler?
What about our prince?
There's our prince running to turn in the silverware.
Yes. I guess something bad happened.
And you just guessed? Of course it happened.
It happened to our husbands.
It happened to the Prince.
With Kiev, at last, it happened.
Oops.
See, here comes another hero.
Now they're all going to shake and run
like cockroaches with those dishes.
I'd just like to punch him in the forehead!
Gorynych!
Yes, it's us.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to.
Come on, what's the big deal.
We were told to turn in the dishes.
So we went. Who knows, maybe they really need it.
What's going on here, anyway?
Oh, Gorynch, my dear.
We're in trouble!
Tikhon, are you home?
Yeah, I think I am.
Stop. You stay here for now. Check the tail, report back.
Go, go.
Prince, maybe we'd better set fire to Kiev and retreat in an orderly fashion?
A tail like a tail. What's there to check?
And what the bastards have come up with. They put toilets everywhere.
And they charge workers three times the price for this very thing. What's it like?
It's an outrage. Everything is getting more expensive:
and buckwheat and grits and butter.
Exactly. Well... Here's the thing, brothers.
It's important for us to hold out until the bogatyrs come.
In the meantime we'll organize a partisan unit with the traitor.
With the chairman. A cell, so to speak, of resistance.
I report: the tail is checked, all clean, no fleas.
Well, go, go, hero.
Dobrynia!
He fell down and did his push-ups.
That's not Dobrynya.
There, and you didn't believe it.
What are you staring at? Come here, you rascals.
Nothing came out.
They said only the prince knows. He personally sent the bogatyrs on a mission.
And where to, no one but him knows.
That's it! Let's go to the palace.
A prince, not a prince. Let the authorities answer where our husbands have gone.
They won't let us into the palace. There will be a ball there.
Only musicians and entertainers are allowed. I saw it myself.
Everyone turn in their gold coins by tomorrow.
Gold money is going out of circulation
and will be replaced by wooden rubles.
The population will not suffer.
Everyone to the palace by tomorrow with gold coins...
Yeah, I know how it won't hurt.
If you say that the population will not suffer. Then that's it...
...save yourselves!
Yes, yes!
And remember we had a case, too,
when they swapped the gold ones for half-gold ones.
Oh, there was a lot of noise.
I don't remember! Bloodsuckers! Despots!
Well, you won't have long to feast.
Tikhon, attack. Julius, let's go.
I'll take the pigsty first. Then this object.
And from here we go straight to the palace.
In brief, comrades, this is our strategic task.
But the main thing, of course, is to hold out until the arrival of bogatyrs.
The whole barn, that is, all of us. Julius, give me the next poster.
Don't make me laugh.
Julius!
This is... Atas.
I'm not allowed in!
You must be going to the ball.
To the ball, to the ball.
Well. Come in.
But I won't let you in!
Only young people and artists are allowed in.
We are artists. Do you want me to sing?
Cheer up, cheer up. Well, why are we sad?
Let's go quickly. Come on. Well, what are you standing there for?!
Dance, dance. Spin, spin, spin.
Move it!
Who dances like that, huh?
What are you playing? Come on... mine!
Will you dance with us, Granny Yagusya, you bony leg?
Kolylivan! Here's the clue.
Gorynych, he's running away.
Stop right there!
Grab her!
Where are our husbands? Give me your husbands! Catch them!
Do-loy of the oc-ku-pants. People's Avengers.
People's Avengers!
Hooray! Did you see that? People are already recognizing us on the street.
Yes, yes. People's support, that's worth a lot.
Exactly.
You remember the plan?
No, I haven't. First, get the guns. And then...
And then...
And then the stable, the cowshed and the library!
Why are you yelling?!
What's the matter, honey, are you ashamed?
What is it?
They gave up their prince to be mocked, the bastards.
We're men of the service. We do as we're told, we do as we're told.
Servants... Give me that.
What are you, uncle?
Uncle? Uncle, you say!
People, people!
Oh, oh, oh!
Don't believe that blabbermouth baron!
He slandered your Prince. Here I am.
Alive and well.
Oh, the Prince is back alive and well. Hurrah for the prince.
Hurrah!
What are you doing?
The prince is back.
We people's avengers will not allow anyone, ever.
We demand the immediate return of all silverware.
Down with autocracy! Down with the occupiers!
And our Julius will not be harmed.
And our prince will not be harmed.
What are you digging for?
It's jammed. Can't you see?
Where the hell have you been? Well!
I think I got it. This way, this way, hurry up.
You see? Quick, all of them. Can you do it?
The main thing is to catch the prince.
And don't let Gorynych get away.
Victory will be ours. Hooray! Take Baron alive.
Taste the might of a bogatyr.
Alyosha!
Ours.
Ours?
Hooray!
And I said, I knew it would be.
Taste how strong bogatyrsky.
Not ours.
I fell down and did my push-ups.
Oh, why, why?
Exactly, we were told to sit still and wait for us.
Well, that's how it is.
They were saving us.
You traitors! Who did you raise your hand against?
Well, that's it. I gave birth to you, I'll kill you.
Ilyushenka, Alyoshenka, Dobrynyushka.
Brothers, look, it's me.
Wow.
Well done, Dobrynya. Hurrah!
Taste the strength of a bogatyr.
The cows have always shown an interest in me.
There you go. There you go. That's forward, and then you bend it a little bit.
All right, come on. Watch closely there.
You will be king for a reason. Don't shame us.
You see, we have a state council right after the farewell.
And then... I have to look at the diary.
Oh, you know what. I'll send you my schedule by jaeger mail.
Where can I find you? In the barn. Great. You got a deal.
Dobrynya, put your scarf on immediately, you'll catch cold.
The wind on the river is cold, and his throat is weak.
We'll see each other for sure!
Goodbye!
Greetings to Gamuma.