We live in a universe
where, statistically,
disorder is king.
As time moves forward,
things fall apart.
Stars burn out.
Energy spreads out.
Entropy conquers all.
But humans, life, fights
that trend.
We build things.
We organise things.
We add information.
So why is it that we love
destroying things?
Exploding fireworks.
Fights and crashes.
Even popping bubble wrap.
Ugh!
Tiny, cute things can make us
want to just squeeze 'em to death.
Ugh!
Why?
The power to destroy is a delicious one.
Even just holding this here,
knowing I can drop it.
I am in control.
I can exert my will in a
dramatic and irreversible way.
Ready?
Ready.
Ugh.
Beautiful.
Why does that feel so good to do
or even just watch?
For me, throwing it to its death
was almost relaxing.
Like, I feel calmer now
after being destructive.
Like I've vented some pent-up energy.
Or anger?
Why do we like
breaking things when we're angry?
There's a growing trend
of businesses called
anger rooms
that are popping up in places
like Texas and Toronto.
People pay to visit these anger rooms
and let off steam by smashing
mock-ups of workplaces,
kitchens and more.
Catharsis Theory proposes
that such acts of destruction
reduce our anger.
But do they?
Sometimes,
but sometimes they don't.
This is what makes studying
the mind so difficult.
Researchers are still looking
into the specifics
and the variables involved,
and I want to see first-hand
and in person what it's like
when people get angry
and then break things.
Will they be more or less
violent afterwards?
To demonstrate
Catharsis Theory
we set up our own anger room
to see whether or not breaking
things will help calm down
some angry people.
Our subjects think
they're participating
in a study about opposing
political views
so we've asked them
to write an essay
on different polarising topics.
- Come in.
- Kashona? Hi.
How are you?
I'm Michael.
Hi, Michael.
It's nice to meet you.
I was just with your
co-participant Clint.
He's in another room.
I'm gonna give your essay
to Clint
and he's gonna critique it
and you're going
to critique his.
- Okay, thank you.
- See you soon.
He wrote a lot.
I didn't write that much.
Okay.
Each of our subjects
has been paired with a man
named Clint
and they will be critiquing
each other's essays.
"Police officers have
a very difficult job.
They have to protect us mainly
from people of colour."
The thing is...
Okay, here we go.
I'm actually Clint.
Overblown, un-American.
Get over it.
My job...
or rather, Clint's job...
is to make our subjects mad
so they can test
our anger room.
[BLEEP]
"You should be ashamed."
"You deserve what's coming to you."
What an asshole.
Ha!
Changed it to black.
That's better.
Oops!
Okay, Kashona, I'm back.
And you were with Clint.
Okay.
Let's go through what he wrote just quickly.
He wrote...
- Did I put that that way?
- No, you didn't.
- Did you turn it around?
- I did turn it around.
He seems like a bigot
or somebody.
I didn't want to
keep looking at his face.
He's responded to your essay there.
We can't tell people where
to go to eat for lunch,
what car to drive,
that just really irritates me.
This is a person that is making arguments
that are not based in any fact.
He's clearly someone who thinks
that the people
who are on social programmes are lazy.
I was like,
"What the [BLEEP]?"
Getting fired up, mother...
ooh, I'm getting fired up.
It's disgusting.
I got an F-plus?
Oh, I hope I don't see him
in the hallway.
He's a dick.
And that is why, he is part
of the reason
why our country [BLEEP] sucks
right now.
Because he's stupid.
Well, I think that was pretty effective.
We've got a lot of angry people
on our hands,
so will demolishing things calm them down,
or will acts of destruction
throw fuel on the fire?
Let's explore Catharsis Theory
with an expert.
The modern view of catharsis
is that by acting out
we release sort of like
a pressure valve,
and that releases that energy
in order for us to sort of build up again
and handle everyday distress.
People who are angry and aggressive
who then act that out, what
would they feel afterwards?
What many studies have found
is that it's a short-lived release
it feels good,
it feels really good to release...
but what happens in the brain is
the brain enjoys that.
There's really a reward to
build up that pressure again
and then release it again.
It's a temporary fix, as far as we know.
I didn't realise it was so complicated
and still being researched.
I thought it was black and white.
You do this, and you release the emotion
and it's gone.
Yes, not as much.
We don't have this
perfect definition
of catharsis,
where everybody agrees,
here's how it works,
here's how it ends up.
Well, let's see if catharsis
works for us.
Now that Clint has sufficiently
angered all of our subjects...
He's more like a [BLEEP]
pussy, as far as I'm concerned.
It's time to put
Catharsis Theory to the test.
Some subjects will be allowed
to actively take out their anger
on all of these beautiful art objects.
You have completely free reign
to break anything in this room.
- What?
- Okay?
Other subjects are instructed
to sit in the room passively.
I want you to reflect on
the essay, the arguments,
the critiques
and also on the objects in this room.
Am I going to meet Clint, or no?
- No, you are not.
- Okay.
That's not part of this study.
Okay, gotcha.
Will these subjects feel less angry
after their violent acts of destruction?
Only one way to find out.
When we are angry,
the body's adrenal glands
release cortisol and adrenaline,
readying the body and mind for fight mode.
But Catharsis Theory hypothesises
that letting it out relieves
feelings of aggression.
Will these subjects feel less
angry after their violent acts
of destruction?
Okay, I'm done.
Before we move on to the final step
of our anger-room demonstration,
maybe we can gain insight
from someone who makes
a living by hitting.
Not objects, but other people.
Mark Smith, aka "Rhino",
is a champion bodybuilder, boxer
and UK gladiator
who knows a thing or two
about how to destroy an opponent.
So, when you're going into a fight
you know that you're going to get hurt.
- Yes.
- You know that you're gonna
hurt someone else.
How do you psych yourself up
to be good at that?
When you're goin' into a fight
you want to stick to your game plan,
stay focused and be relaxed.
Relaxed...
Because I would have thought
you'd want to go in angry.
No, because if you go in too angry
all you're doing is...
and you're not thinking straight
it turns into, like, a school brawl.
- It's a very tactical game.
- Right.
The eye of the tiger,
like Rocky.
But this is fascinating to me
because you would think that to
physically outfight someone
in nature, we would have evolved
to run off of anger and fear.
That's like two lions,
I agree with you there.
Two lions attack and go
full out, don't they?
There's no pace in that fight whatsoever,
like animals, but you have to
know when to be an animal
and at what point in the fight.
- Bang!
- Oh!
– So there's no point in...
– I'm a very jumpy, flinchy person.
It's knowing when to pull the trigger.
If you ever find yourself
angry in your real life,
do you find it helpful to punch
a punching bag...
- Definitely.
- Yeah?
I will get angry, like,
I'm on the phone
with my bank,
and I might think slamming a door
or just hanging up
and throwing my phone on the bed...
No, don't throw your phone,
and don't slam doors.
Just come and exercise and hit the bag.
You'll feel so much better.
What's the difference though?
They're both active things.
You're not doing something spontaneous
and acting on impulse.
It's premeditated.
You know you'll go: "Okay,
I'm gonna pack my bag,
go to the gym...".
You're releasing endorphins,
you'll feel more relaxed
and you'll be able to assess
the bank manager
who's been irritating you
for the last hour.
Can I... can I try hitting some things?
Definitely.
You can try hitting me.
- Can I really?
- Yes.
- Are you gonna hit back?
- I will...
...I'll let you know I'm there.
Okay.
Awesome.
Do I look scary?
Oh, yeah.
Is Rhino correct that
violent acts of rage
won't calm you down?
But the controlled aggression
used in boxing
will actually relax you?
I guess I'm about to find out.
Yes, like that.
No, no.
No.
Come on!
I'm tired.
Well done!
Good work.
I came out of the fight
having learned two things.
One, I'm a wimp.
And two, Rhino was right;
when physical violence is channelled
in an organised sport like boxing,
it can actually
reduce feelings of aggression.
I had this weird combination of feelings.
- As tired as I am...
- Yep.
I'm very amped-up.
- So now you feel it.
- Yeah.
I don't feel aggressive.
You feel relaxed?
I wouldn't say I'm relaxed here
I would just say I'm clearer here
and I feel more in control.
Eye of the tiger, Rock.
Yeah, well,
maybe it's the eye of the kitten
who is in a bad mood
but, man, that was great.
It's time for the final part of
our anger-room demonstration.
All of our subjects
will be taking part
in what they think is a reflex test
against their opponent Clint.
In reality, of course,
there is no Clint
and what we're really looking at
is the Catharsis Theory.
Have our subjects' levels
of anger been affected
according to whether they committed
violent acts of destruction?
Or not?
Stage three is going to be testing
how your reflexes are working
at this very moment.
Okay?
So, this right here
is a static-electricity generator
that is going to provide
a little bit of a shock.
We're putting one on Clint as well
and he's in another room
but you both have the same setup.
Once our subjects are fitted
with the shock bracelet
they're introduced to
the test's control panel.
Look at this.
Yeah, it's very simplified
but that really helps keep
the variables low.
So both you and Clint will be
competing in a bit of a game.
The yellow light is going to
come on at some point,
and as soon as you see it come on,
hit that orange button.
And if you hit this button
before Clint does
you'll see the green light come on.
And that'll mean that you won.
And Clint needs to receive
a small shock, okay?
And you can set this to a level
of your choosing.
So... okay.
Light goes on, if I hit this
the green one comes
and then I'm allowed
to work this contraption.
- Correct.
- Which controls how
high the voltage and for how
long the voltage.
- Correct.
- Okay.
If, however, Clint pushes
the button before you do,
the red light will come on,
indicating...
My red light and I'm about to get it.
You'll get a shock,
yeah, correct.
We'll get a sense of our
subjects' level of anger
by how they respond to the
chance to administer pain
to Clint.
Remember, this subject just sat
in the anger room passively.
Did I get him?
Oh, all right.
The green light means our subject wins.
How hard will he shock Clint?
I'm gonna give you
a little low one, buddy.
There you go.
Just a kiss.
Ah, got me.
The red light means Clint won.
How will our subject respond
to getting shocked?
Ahh!
You son of a bitch.
Not only does this subject
not seem angry, he's actually
enjoying the game.
All right.
How about that?
I'm not gonna harm you, man.
I'll give ya a little low one.
He actually seems
relatively calm.
Will our other passive subject
follow suit?
Clint gave her a painful shock.
Let's see how strongly she retaliates.
Even after getting a shock from Clint,
this subject is still hesitant
to give him a shock in return.
Okay, Clint and Drea,
this is just a reminder that you are...
...you are allowed to change that dial
to what you think would be appropriate.
Yeah, I just don't want to,
like, hurt him or anything.
I'm just gonna keep it at low.
So the angry subjects who sat passively
seem to have calmed down.
Now it's time to check on the
subjects who acted violently
in the anger room.
Did letting out all of that aggression
relieve their anger?
The experiment will begin now.
Take it, take it, take it!
Kashona.
That's... that's fine.
What level is your dial at?
Um...
Low.
He cranked that all the way up
and he's laying on that button.
This subject was one of
the most aggressive people
in the anger room,
but that doesn't seem to have
calmed him down.
Among our subjects
it seems that those
who physically vented
their anger are still pretty angry
compared to the subjects who sat quietly.
So at least in this case
catharsis therapy was not effective.
In fact, in some cases
the subject seems even angrier.
Ow! [BLEEP]
You know what?
That's too hard.
You [BLEEP] dick...!
Why don't you come in here and
[BLEEP] talk to me in person?
Oh, my God.
We're all familiar with
the concept of rubbernecking.
It's hard to look away from a car crash.
Oh, my God.
But why?
There are surely a myriad of reasons,
but one may be that at a primitive level
witnessing danger allows us
to learn and prepare for it.
Activities where danger
and destruction are likely
are exciting.
Starting in our childhood,
physical aggression is encouraged,
even in games.
Take a piñata for example.
As a special birthday treat
we are told to beat up
an effigy with a baseball bat.
And when we hit it hard enough
we are rewarded with candy.
What parts of a child's urge
to destroy are innate
versus learned?
Well,
there is a groundbreaking experiment
that shed light on this.
In 1961, Albert Bandura conducted a famous
and controversial study
called the Bobo Doll Experiment.
He had adults act violently
to an inflatable clown doll
in the presence of children.
Then left the children alone
with the same doll
to see if they would mimic
the destructive behavior
they'd observed.
Disturbingly, the children
did indeed copy the adults,
and lashed out at the doll,
often getting very creative
with their aggression
and destruction.
Aggression comes in many
unexpected forms.
Why is it so hard to resist
popping bubbles in bubble wrap,
for instance?
Do we like the sound?
The destruction?
Or both?
It's like we're naturally drawn
to destroying
these harmless plastic bubbles of air.
Destructive tendencies
seem to be so engrained in us
that we even respond
to positive stimulation
with urges to destroy.
One of the strangest things
about destruction
is how people want to hug things to death,
especially things that are extremely cute
like a puppy.
We don't know exactly why this is
but there is a study
that demonstrates the effect
by using bubble wrap
and our desire to pop these bubbles.
Oh, yeah.
Can sweet, adorable stimuli
really incite aggressive behavior?
We're about to find out.
Thank you for participating
in our focus test.
No problem.
Please make yourself comfortable.
We've recruited subjects
who think
they're taking part
in a motor-skills test.
Are you familiar with
this product?
- Yes.
- Have you popped the bubbles
in bubble wrap before?
Yes.
But really, what we're testing
is their aggressive response
to cute stimuli.
So you will be viewing
a montage of images.
Please pop bubbles
in the bubble wrap.
You may pop
as many or as few as you like.
Just be sure to start
when the images begin
and stop when the images end.
Popping bubbles is like
squeezing a stress ball.
It's a great way to express aggression.
The question is, will
the subjects pop more bubbles
when watching
neutral images, or cute ones?
First we showed our subjects
these basic landscapes,
which are not designed to
elicit an emotional response.
And we tallied
the total number of bubbles popped.
Okay, great.
I'll take those.
All right,
we're gonna do part two
where you'll be viewing
another set of images.
We also showed them
images of...
... puppies.
Oh, look at that one!
Don't you just want to
hug them and squeeze them...
okay, look, you get the point.
To keep things even,
half of the subjects viewed
the landscapes first
and half viewed the puppies first.
But either way, they seemed
to pop a lot more bubbles
while watching the puppies.
Except for this guy.
So-called cute aggression
is a universal
psychological phenomenon.
Researchers believe the brain's response
to both cuteness and aggression
results in the release of dopamine
implicated in reward and pleasure
If we are unable to
physically touch cute stimuli,
the desire to do so can be regulated
by substituting aggressive
physical behavior.
Will our results reflect this theory?
How did you feel
about the images that you saw?
They were cool.
How did you feel about the puppies?
I love them.
They were very tiny and adorable
and I wanted to hug them.
And how did you feel about
popping the bubble wrap?
I felt like I wanted to
play with the dogs, or...
I wanted to play with the bubble
wrap with the dogs.
In our simple test, our
subjects popped an average
of 33% more bubbles while
watching cute puppies
as opposed to boring landscapes.
So was the bubble wrap
a stand-in for the puppies?
I guess so.
In fact, the majority of our subjects
popped more bubbles
while watching puppies.
But not this guy.
Remember him?
So how did you feel about
seeing the dog pictures?
I've always been more
of a cat person.
It seems sometimes cuteness
is a matter of perspective.
Our relationship with
destruction is not a simple one.
It can release endorphins
and relax our minds.
It can amp us up
and make us even more aggressive.
It can even help us regulate
our emotional reactions
to cute things.
Destruction can be useful,
it can be dangerous
and it can be a lot of fun.
And as always,
thanks for watching.