What would happen if we detonated a very powerful nuclear weapon on the moon?
Will it blast its orbit towards Earth, causing a huge tsunami and disaster?
Could it be that after the moon was blown up, countless debris bathed the earth in a deadly meteor shower?
The moon has been the main space exploration site since the cold war, you know, for more military bases
so the US Air Force commissioned  A neglected study was conducted to understand
the effects of nuclear explosions on the lunar surface.  But just quotes are boring
so let's do a very important science experiment with a 100 megaton hydrogen
bomb that will be twice as powerful as the most powerful bomb ever detonated
and will also find a few curious  Hearty astronauts to act as observers
Let's hit the detonator button and slow down.  For the first few milliseconds from the outside,
nothing happened.  But at the same time, the high explosives inside have sent shock waves to the radioactive metal,
compressing it to a critical point, so that the chain reaction of nuclear fusion can begin.
In this first stage, a plasma of up to 100 million degrees is generated, which also triggers the second stage.
At this time  Nuclei fuse as in the core of a star.
For a split second, our guys encapsulate one of the hottest places in the universe
and now, just 10 microseconds later, the whole universe notices
something is happening.  Planet Is Born
So far so good!  But everything that starts to happen now will be very different from what we know on Earth
for one major reason: the moon has no atmosphere and
as the fireball unleashes flashes of X-rays and fiery photons, a silent wave of heat rushes outward towards  In all directions
on Earth, this heat wave will burn anything within a 50-kilometer radius beyond recognition
. Not only on the moon, there is no such thing as burning without an oxygen-filled atmosphere, and nothing can burn the
moon's crunchy topsoil.  Silicate rock and metal composition.  These metals have been smashed into dust by countless meteorites for many years, and mixed with a small amount of water
. At the same time as the explosion brings high temperature, the X-rays emitted by the fireball will evaporate a layer of thin rock on the surface of the moon,
and the poor dust inside the fireball will be melted into glass.
Any astronaut who sees a good show within 50 kilometers
will be fried to a crispy crunch with furious fire.
Now, we can witness the most striking difference compared to the explosion of the
earth. The atmosphere on earth resists that giant plasma bubble
Atmospheric pressure would violently and violently prevent the explosion from expanding.  But this is not good news.
While the fireball slammed back into the atmosphere, it also created the most destructive part of a nuclear explosion on Earth: the
compressed air around the shock wave explosion would rush outwards at supersonic speeds and
smash buildings.  Shattered physical organs
but no shock waves on the moon.  No atmosphere means nothing to stop the explosion from expanding
on the moon, because there is no atmosphere to hinder or a fireball that produces a sound
explosion just grows in a weird and quiet way
. It can be very impressive to watch from a safe distance.  The
surprising thing is that there is almost no "safe viewing distance" for a lunar nuclear explosion. There is
no lethal ionizing radiation that can disrupt DNA in a weakened atmosphere.
Anyone seeking a great viewing position will be exposed to lethal amounts of radiation.  Down.  And of course, the good drama was just about to kick in
when the explosion hit the moon like a giant hammer.
About one-tenth of the energy was converted into seismic waves, which produced powerful moonquakes.
The moon is much smaller than the earth, so no matter where the astronauts stand, they will feel a violent shaking that cannot be ignored. If you
compare the earthquake with a magnitude of 7 on the Richter scale,
such an earthquake will seriously damage our infrastructure on the moon.  Even razed to the ground.
Those hiding on the far side of the moon wouldn't realize that it all stemmed from an explosion. The
shaking felt like being hit by an asteroid the size of the Pyramid
of Guf.  Local soil splattered like a splash of a stone thrown into water.
When the explosion pushed the surface, up to 100 million cubic meters of dust and rock could be excavated to
form a one-kilometer-wide crater.  The rock is smashed into rubble
and the wreckage shoots into the sky in all directions.
Similarly, without the interference of the atmosphere, the wreckage rushes out as if it were no one.
Many sparse wreckage will never return to the moon.  The high speed of escape velocity flew far into the distance. A
series of snowflake-like micrometeorites flew out to start the journey of the solar system.
Many of them will fall to Earth like rain, but few are larger than ordinary pebbles.
Anything blocking the flight direction of these debris  Satellites, astronauts, or space stations are likely to
be shot at different velocities and angles.
This makes them scatter like bullets on the lunar surface
, no matter where our curious astronauts are.  In the
end, the explosion came to an end.  On Earth, the fireball takes off like a hot air balloon and turns into a stalk.
When it reaches a certain height, the surrounding cold air is continuously sucked in, and the top becomes a mushroom cloud.
But on the moon, well...you  Also got it: no atmosphere, no mushroom cloud.
As the plasma ball gets bigger, it cools down, which means less energy for it to pull off some fun or scary tricks
after it all starts.  Within a few seconds, this huge bubble turns red and then disappears from view.
What can be seen on Earth, like a twinkling star, then immediately disappears
. It flashes quietly, and nothing happens.
The myriad of tiny debris fragments that reach far from the lunar surface
will be gleaming in the sun for a few minutes, bringing an eerie aesthetic to anyone who stays to watch the spectacle.
How's the moon's orbit now?  Basically unaffected.
Delusions of moving the moon with nukes are like blowing air on a truck and expecting it to go.
Maybe a nuclear explosion is big, but the universe is bigger.  Our powerful explosion left only a single crater.  one in millions.
Anyone who is on the moon next will have no good fruit to eat
. The material that ends up falling back to the moon is radioactive.
If there were no natural processes to wash it away or bury it, the lunar surface would still be contaminated.
Fortunately, the worst radiation would be  Attenuates
to levels comparable to natural levels of cosmic rays in about a year.
In conclusion, we can say with confidence that while the Moon simply doesn't care about being dropped a nuclear bomb or even notices
using the Moon as a test site for a nuclear bomb, right?  It's going to cost everyone who wants to do some research or build something useful on the moon
so maybe we just...
don't do that.
Translator: Louis Tsai