Food is arguably the best thing about
being alive. No other bodily pleasure is
enjoyed multiple times every day and never
gets old. It is an expression of culture,
our parents' love and a means
of celebration or comfort.
That’s why it hits a special nerve when we are
told we should change what and how we eat to
fight rapid climate change. One of the most
delicious foods, meat gets the worst press.
It doesn’t help that the topic is really
hard to properly research yourself
and debates get emotional quickly. But
clearly science can give us an answer!
The reality is, well, it’s complicated.
Let’s take a look at three
climate arguments against
meat that are used a lot and see what happens.
#
1. Does our Diet REALLY play that
big a role in climate change?
Feeding billions of people is impossible without
causing emissions. Even if someday we have
zero-carbon tractors, refrigerators and cookers
running on renewable energy and electric trucks
to move our food, there are still unavoidable
emissions. Rice emits methane. We cut down forests
to make room for pastures and crops. And we emit
nitrous oxide when we use fertilizers and manure.
Worldwide food production is responsible for about
26% of all human-made greenhouse gas emissions.
Which is unfortunate, since food is not
optional. While 26% doesn’t sound THAT bad
it means that even if we extinguished
all other sources of emissions today,
the emissions from food alone would still
use up our entire carbon budget by 2100.
So no matter how we twist and turn it,
food is a real driver of climate change.
Still, emissions from different
food items vary a lot.
How do things look when we compare
their footprints separately?
Foods’ climate impact is most often
based on “life cycle assessments”:
an analysis that looks at all the emissions
of a product throughout its existence,
from production to transportation,
packaging, use and waste management.
In the most detailed meta analysis of life
cycle assessments to date, beef emissions
stand out at the top. On average, a kilogram
of beef emits 71 kilograms of CO2 equivalents.
Lamb is also high, at 40 kilograms. Pork emits
12 and poultry 10 kilograms. At the bottom we
have lots of plant-based foods: Potatoes, for
example,emit around 150 times less than beef.
The most important aspect of food isn’t weight
though,it’s nutrient density. A kilogram of beef
would keep you alive much longer than a kilogram
of potatoes– so how does the ranking change
if we compare emissions per calorie or protein?
Not much. Animal protein is still the most
costly for the environment and beef and lamb
are also outliers in emissions per calorie.
But is this fair? After all, not all beef is the
same. There are all sorts of ways to rear cattle,
from pure grass fed to factory farming.
The worst beef comes in at 105 kilograms
of emissions per 100 grams of protein –
the best at only 9 – a tenfold difference.
In contrast, most other
foods, especially plant based,
have a much narrower spectrum. Still, the
best beef is worse than the worst plant.
Ok but this seems promising – can we buy
the right beef and lower our emissions?
Maybe by buying locally produced
beef to minimize our footprint?
# 2. Does Buying Local Food Actually Matter?
Let us stick with beef
since it is such an outlier.
By buying locally, you are trying to avoid
emissions from transportation and packaging.
But it turns out these only account for
0.5 to 2% of beef's total emissions.
Actually, transport and packaging combined
are only about 11% of all food emissions.
Nearly all food transport emissions
are produced over the last few miles,
the regional travel on the road supplying
the markets and shops in your area.
International food transport happens mostly on
freight ships, which are insanely efficient.
For example, shipping one kilogram of
avocados from South America to Europe
generates about 0.3 kilograms of CO2
equivalents in transport emissions
and around 2.5 kilograms overall – while one
kilogram of beef from your local butcher will
come in at 18 kg in CO2 equivalents at least .
So even when shipped great distances, emissions
from almost all plant-based foods cause lower
emissions than locally produced animal products.
Ok, so if transport doesn’t play a big role,
what causes the vast amounts
of emissions from beef then?
By far the largest share of beef emissions
consists of methane released directly by the
animals. While CO2 hangs around for centuries,
methane only stays in the atmosphere for decades.
But in these short periods, it is very powerful.
All in all, methane has already caused 23 to 40%
of human-made warming so far. There is controversy
about how bad this is exactly and we don’t want
to dive in too deep here – but the way things
stand, any kinds of extra emissions are not great.
Still – all cows burp and fart to similar degrees
– what explains the spectrum of beef emissions?
There are a couple things:
It makes a difference if the beef comes from a
dairy herd or one dedicated to beef production.
44% of the world’s beef comes from dairy cows,
sharing its footprint with dairy products. Dairy
cows tend to get higher quality feed, which
makes them grow faster and emit less methane.
Geography also plays a role, because it
determines which farming methods are possible.
The worst factor by far is the destruction
of forests for farmland. Not only does this
release the CO2 that was bound in the
flora, it sets free carbon that was
stored in the soil and destroys its
ability to store it in the future.
This aspect accounts for much of
the range of emissions in beef:
the worst emitters are farms burning down
rainforest for farmland, especially in Brazil.
There is a sinister truth hidden here: The
more animals suffer, the better they are in
terms of climate change because they are way more
efficient. They use less land and their food is
brought right to them, and so they grow faster
and don’t expend energy on things like walking.
Cattle in a factory farm that never get to roam
pastures can sometimes be less destructive for
the climate than cattle grazing peacefully
on a formally lush piece of rainforest.
But isn’t it a bit out of touch with
reality to demonize cows so much?
Some of the land these animals are grazing
on isn’t suitable for crops anyway.
By grazing on pastures they
can turn things we can’t digest
into food. Isn’t farming animals just a smart
way to make the best use of unused resources?
#3 Don’t Cows mainly use Land that we
can’t use for agriculture or other things?
About half of the world’s ice- and desert-free
land is used for agriculture, an area the size
of the entire Americas plus China. Half of all
agriculturally used land is dedicated to animals.
Most of it is grassland, 65% of which can not be
converted to cropland, so pasturing animals is
actually a very efficient way to use those areas,
since we can’t grow human food there anyway.
There are a couple of catches here though.
While the idea of cows turning useless grass
into steak is nice, it is a marketing lie.
Even though it is so massive, pastureland
alone can’t support the ruminants living on it.
Globally, grazing systems sustain only 13% of
beef production. So if we were to switch to 100%
grass fed, we’d simply have to
eat much less beef – in the US
beef production would crash by some 70%
if it were to exclusively rely on grass.
The only way to sustain our high demand for
meat is by growing crops and feeding them to our
cattle. And we haven’t even talked about chickens
and pigs, who exclusively eat feed crops .
Because of this feed demand, less than half of the
world’s cereals are used directly as human food.
41% is fed to animals. The same is true for
soy. There is a lot of talk about Amazon
deforestation for soy production, which makes
us think of soy milk and tofu. But only 19%
of global soy production goes towards products
for humans. About 77% is used to feed animals.
Besides, land without food crops isn’t
automatically ecologically useless.
A beef free diet would free up around
2 billion hectares, a vegan diet would
free up around 3 billion hectares of land. We
could use this land to grow forests or restore
wild grasslands – basically anything that could
suck carbon out of the atmosphere. If we spared
3 billion hectares of land, it could remove about
800 billion tonnes of CO2 from the air over 100
years. By comparison we emit about 50 billion
tonnes of CO2 equivalents per year at the moment.
Ok to summarize.
Food is a huge driver of emissions. Meat
but especially beef is the worst food in
terms of emissions. Buying locally does
not have a big impact on food emissions
compared to the type of food you are
consuming. When it comes to beef,
cattle that are grass fed can sometimes even
be counterproductive because they just need
much more land. Even if you find the most
environmentally-friendly beef in the world,
your burger still comes with a significantly
higher carbon footprint than a veggie pattie.
You can decide for yourself what you
want to do with this information.
In fact, you are always only one
decision away from making a change.
You could start learning a new skill or dive into
a new interest today – it’s up to you. If only
that first step wasn’t so hard to take. We have
something for you to make it a little easier.
We are big fans of Skillshare, an online
learning community that offers thousands
of classes for all skill levels in tons
of creative disciplines like Illustration,
Animation, or Film and Video. There
is something for everyone really.
Unlimited access to all the classes
is less than ten dollars a month with
an annual premium membership. The
first 1,000 kurzgesagt viewers to
click the link in the description will
get a 1 month free trial of Skillshare.
Since we started working with Skillshare, you,
our viewers, have taken over 100,000 hours of
classes – including our own three Skillshare
classes on how we make our animations!
In them you will learn all the basics like
how to set up your project and layers,
but also more details about how we work with
tools and timing. You will get to re-create
typical Kurzgesagt scenes with our very own
illustrations and get a sneak-peak into the
work process of our animators. If you’ve always
been curious about Animation, give it a try.
But anything that makes you feel excited
and sparks new ideas is a great first step.
If you want to get creative with new skills
and support kurzgesagt, give it a go.