Timer makes sense in small pieces
But when you look at huge stretches of time, it's almost impossible to wrap your head around things
So let's start small, with minutes hours days
You probably spent the last 24 hours of mostly sleeping and working and you probably wasted a good chunk of
yesterday on the internet
Days become weeks weeks become months and then we have a year
Let's look at 2017
France started to Train Eagles to hunt terrorist drones. paycheque nuclear power plant held a bikini contest to pick their new intern and
People on the internet made a challenge out of eating bleach. You know ,the usual stuff
let's go back further...
A kid born in the first year of the 21st century is 18 years old now
But the century is still young even if you're not
It was largely shaped by the attacks on 9/11 which led to the war in Afghanistan and the invasion of Iraq in
March 2011 the Syrian civil war began and is still ongoing after seven years
Most of us were born in the 20th century
Which had the two most devastating wars in human history and the Cold War for
The first time ever we could destroy ourselves with the nuclear weapons, and we almost did
But we also had a space race and left earth for the first time
The internet was also invented which led to memes but also to Facebook and Twitter
So all in all we're not sure if this was a good development
The average human lives about 79 years, which covers a good chunk of recent history
The oldest living person on earth is currently Celino Jaramillo who was born in 1896?
Which means that his birth was closer to Napoleon ruling Europe than to the current day?
Only 250 years ago the Industrial Revolution
Turned the world into a progress machine the farmers became workers and knowledge became easier to distribute
Around this time we started the progress that is causing climate change today
Not that long ago actually
The theory of evolution changed how we saw ourselves and the world we live in
Newton wrote down his theory of gravity we discovered distant stars and very close bacteria
The 15th century was very eventful
Columbus's discovery of america and the fall of Constantinople marked the end of the Middle Ages
War was all the rage in the Middle Ages
But the number one killer was disease the Black Plague killed every third European in just six years
Around 2,000 years ago we set the arbitrary year one of our calendar that most of the world follows today
But to a Roman the world was already ancient
the great pyramids were constructed
4,500 years ago so to a Roman the pyramids were older than the Romans are to us today
so long ago that there was still living mammoths on earth a
Lot of history happened before that even around 7,000 years ago humans began writing things down
about 12,000 years ago human organization exploded
We built our first temple and around the world mankind began farming
Which enabled the rise of larger communities our dominance over planet Earth really begins here?
Homo sapiens sapiens the modern human evolved at least 200,000 years ago
50,000 years ago the cognitive revolution expanded our minds and innovation back
Then we shared earth with at least five other human species that either died out or were killed by us
at least 2 million years ago our ancestors already had control over fire and constructed tools from wood and stone
And six million years ago the last common ancestors of chimpanzees and humans existed
So this graph is all of human history
Our close relative Homo erectus survived 10 times longer than we have existed
This tiny part is the human era. We have to zoom in a lot to even see your lifetime
Still all of human history is not that long
65 million years ago the age of the dinosaurs ended in an enormous explosion
The dinosaurs ruled the earth for over 165 million years
27 times as long as all humans
That's so long that it means a t-rex that lived at 65 million years ago is closer to us today
than to a live Stegosaurus
Dinosaurs in the form of mighty chickens are still around today
Animal life on this planet started 600 million years ago
the earliest animals were fish and other small simple sea creatures then came insects that wrapped ours and
Finally around 200 million years ago mammals joined the party
Life itself began much further back. There is evidence that it appeared up to 4.1 billion years ago
for at least 3.5 billion years life consisted only of single-celled organisms
4.5 billion years ago the Sun was born from a gigantic imploding gas cloud 60 million years later earth formed in
In those early years frequent bombardment by comets and asteroids supplied the earth with large oceans
But as far as the whole universe goes how solar system is pretty new
Thirteen point seven five billion years ago the universe was born
And about half a billion years later our own galaxy formed from billions of stars
But what came before the Big Bang the truth is we don't know and maybe we never will.
And there you have it the past
Now let's take a look at what we know about the future.
In roughly 1 billion years the Sun will be so hot that life on Earth becomes impossible the death of the Sun 4 billion years later
Marks the end of life in the solar system
If we want to have a chance to survive we need to have ventured to the Stars and what happens after that in
The next 100 billion years most of the biggest stars around will die the universe becomes dimmer and dimmer
illuminated only by smaller red and white dwarfs
But they too will eventually burn out and one day the last star in the universe will die
The universe will turn dark and at some point even black holes will evaporate and die
When they do our universe will reach its final stage heat death?
Nothing changes anymore the universe is dead
forever
Now you're feeling some pretty weird feelings right now aren't you we are - it's only natural
The good news is this is all far far away
The only time that actually matters is now
That cute girl or boy you like ask them out time is precious
Make it count
One of the questions we get asked the most is how we make animated videos
The short answer is with Adobe After Effects and years of training
But if you'd like to get a glimpse we now have something for you
we made Skillshare tutorials explaining in detail how we animate scenes from our videos if
You aren't already familiar with it Skillshare is an online learning community with more than 18,000 classes in things like writing
animation and video editing
Their premium membership gives you unlimited access to high-quality classes from professionals working in their fields so you can improve your skills
Unlock new opportunities and do work that you really enjoy
It's also extremely affordable the annual subscription is less than ten dollars a month
The first 1,000 people to sign up get their first two months for only 99 cents
So if you want to learn new things and support cuts cos øx. Give it a try
How did you like this remake. We're thinking about redoing a few of our older videos in the next one or two years
Any videos you would like to see redone?