Once upon a time,
...when the forests were full of mushrooms and berries,
...and the ponds and rivers were full of fish,
...the people of Mother Russia lived...
...and they had no trouble.
And then all of a sudden...
...bad things began to happen.
Out of nowhere,
...a villain appeared,
...the Bandit Nightingale.
Not a horse,
...or a foot soldier.
He burned and plundered...
...the Russian villages.
Ilya!
Well, help me,
...mother of the earth.
Nice horse you have, Ilya!
Why don't you sell it?
It's not a horse at all,
...but my faithful friend!
Well Ilya, my time will come, wait!
Relax!
Oh, thank you, Ilya Ivanovich!
Don't leave us, bogatyr!
- Come back! - Don't forget us, Ilyashenka!
Bon voyage and good luck!
We're waiting for you, our defender!
I'll be back.
What did he say?
"I'll be back!"
So... This is for social needs...
This is for the vigilantes...
And this is for other expenses.
That's a lot of other stuff.
Yeah, that's right.
What if we raise taxes?
Let's say they don't pay a tithe,
...but let's say a quarter?
What... what do you think?
How about cutting "other things"?
But-but-but! Aren't you, by any chance..,
...not a democrat?
Dibs on me! God be with you, Prince!
That's right!
Look at me!
Isn't it true that they say you let Nightingale go again...
...for a hundred coins?
It's state business, it's none of your business.
Why, I'm like a dog..,
...I'll chase after every bandit..,
...and you let him go free again?
What's the matter with you? Are you out of your mind?
Mind your own business!
I'm a prince, I do what I want!
I'm acting in the interests of the state!
Oh, yes!
There's a lot to be done that way.
That's it! I've had enough!
Look at you! You've gone crazy!
Get out of here!
I'll go, Prince,
...only for the service henceforth...
...don't call me. Period!
Go, go! Without you, there will be some heroes in Russia.
Don't forget to leave your horse!
What do you mean, leave it?
Burushka?
- How could I, Prince! - How?
It's on the balance sheet, it's government property.
No, you can pay, of course,
...if you have money.
Did you see that?
What's up?
Prince, there... ...there's...
...that chronicler has come to see you!
Again?
I told you not to let him in!
They're getting attached...
Don't let them in, Prince...
...they'll scribble nasty things again!
So what do you want me to do?
Oh... Well, of course I have to ask!
Why do you ask, you fool!
Don't grieve, Burushka,
...I'll definitely buy you back.
I'll make some money!
Why..,
...I can plow the land,
...sow bread...
Well, don't be clever.
Hey, Stepan!
You comb his mane, but watch out,
...don't cut it!
You'll reduce his strength,
...you'll take grief for yourself.
You got it, Ilya Ivanovich!
A star fell from the sky at night.
Good omen!
I made a wish.
Before you know it,
...we'll be together.
We've come a long way, haven't we?
In the old days, I would have written these
...in no time at all!
Shackles! To the dungeon!
And now, you see, people want to know the truth.
What will say in the West!
О... Baba!
Mmm, pretty.
How did you get in here, honey?
I'm not a broad, I'm a chronicler!
Of the weekly "New Birch"!
You're a... A chronicler?
Yes! And I want to know by what right I'm not allowed into the palace!
By what right am I barred from the palace? What on earth is this?
Do you confirm the resignation of Ilya Muromets?
They say he accused you of conspiring with Nightingale the Robber?
That's not true!
Let him prove it first!
That's true. The law is that if you're not caught, you're not a thief.
А... э... Metaphorically!
Get him out of here! Take him away! Sketching in the palace is forbidden!
You know what?
What is your name?
- Alyonushka... - What a wonderful name!
Well, Alyonushka,
...they won't let us talk to you here.
Let's go to my office.
Don't let them execute you, soul of the Russian land!
Did you see that?
What happened again?
The treasury, my dear prince!
What - the treasury?
The bandit nightingale, the damned bandit..,
...has stolen the treasury!
What will be your further actions?
Did you make it? I need a close-up!
Having gathered my spirit,
...and having come to a wise mind..,
...the prince began to think and decide,
...how to catch the thief,
...and steal the riches.
Catch them!
A bogatyr in pursuit!
Don't order the execution, Prince,
...but where to get a bogatyr?
Ilya Ivanovich went home in anger.
I hold a grudge against you, fair Prince!
And Nightingale also took the horse..,
...of Murom!
Listen, fair Prince..,
...what if Ilyushka doesn't say a word about the treasury?
And tell me about the horse!
He's sick before the horse,
He'll go to help him out,
...and at the same time help our treasury!
That's right! We must urgently go to Ilya.
Don't say a word about the treasury from the chest!
Listen, Prince, can I go with you to Ilya Ivanovich?
I'm writing a chronicle.
"Weekdays of Russian Heroes" is called.
Right. Who let her in?
You yourself, Prince, ordered it.
I used to order it. And now I don't!
That's it! Take her away.
The opal.
This is an outrage!
Violence against the press!
Freedom to the pen and the word!
And Ilya Muromets plows the earth,
...and knits his shoes.
We have only one thought,
...to redeem his friend from the prince.
Come, mother,
...I'm not tired yet.
Don't argue with your mother! You look completely gray.
Skin and bones.
I think it's time for you to get married, son.
To whom?
What difference does it make? To this one or that one.
For example, Varvara, our blacksmith's daughter.
Her cheeks are red, she's strong...
...ugh!
That's why she's red,
...because she won't leave the blacksmith's furnace.
All right. Let's have a look at Glasha.
I've got a lot to look at.
I don't like that girl.
Ugh, not to my taste!
What do you want to make cabbage soup out of her?
Well, mother!
A fly in the milk...
Wait for visitors, Mama!
It's an omen!
An omen...
Are you going to look for a wife by omens too?
Why not?
You can't escape fate!
It will show you a sign..,
...when I meet my soulmate.
Ehhh!
Oh, you're too much, someone's really galloping!
The prince has come.
It's no wonder something happened.
It can't be that the Prince himself has done the honors!
Oh, you, naked, not cleaned up!
Trouble! Oh, trouble!
Oh, you dark yoke!
Good health to you,
...bright Prince of Kiev..,
...the hope of Russian cities!
Mother!
Ilya Ivanovich! The bandit nightingale is on the loose again!
What's it to me?
These are matters of state..,
...and I have nothing to do with them.
Ah... Ilya Ivanovich,
...ah... You have stolen a sacred thing.
He stole your horse, Burushka..,
...our falcon, from the stable!
What do you mean he stole it? When?
Last night.
Don't abandon your faithful friend!
Follow him! Keep up!
Good day to you, my hostess!
Can you tell me where I can find a hero, Ilya Muromets?
He was standing here, plowing the land,
...and when the prince arrived, he jumped on his horse,
...and rushed away in the wind.
I'm late! And you yourself, who will be Ilya?
I'm his mother, of course!
Oh, great!
And tell me how the hero's mother feels,
...- pride for her son, anxiety, confusion?
Ah... You're right. Anxiety!
Ilyusha forgot to take his cherished little bundle!
And I didn't even remind him!
Oh, so give it to me!
I'll meet him now, of course.
Come on, come on! Don't doubt it.
They shaved it off!
A tribe of Basurians!
Aya-ya-ya-ya-ya, what a misfortune!
M-m-m!
You, Prince, tell them to give me my armor,
...and let them find a stronger horse!
- I'm leaving tomorrow. - Hey there, what are you waiting for?
...equip the Russian bogatyr for the dangerous journey!
For this righteous cause I decided to go with you, Ilya Ivanovich.
I'll help you in your difficult feat.
No way!
I'm not taking a wagon to the campaign!
Ilya! I'm really embarrassed!
It seems to be my fault...
...that Burushka was stolen...
I say no.
And I say yes.
I say no!
And I say yes! After all, the honor of the state is affected!
Damn you to hell!
Ha! Good omen.
Well! Your luck, Prince. But be warned,
...the two of us will go. Quickly, but lightly.
Good?
Come on. А!
Come on! Don't be afraid!
Come on!
She doesn't want to go. She's stubborn!
She's... afraid of heights!
So you've got her stabled!
How on earth did you get her on the road?
I did! And I didn't notice.
Oh! Aren't you Ilya Muromets?
That's the one!
Do you know me?
Who doesn't know Ilya Muromets?
Thank you, you've helped me out.
It's nothing.
It's no accident that we met, Ilya Ivanovich!
How so - not by chance?
Here, I'm writing a chronicle, "Weekdays of Russian Heroes"!
My dream is to go on a hike with you!
To save Burushka...
To the campaign?
Well, yes. And I also have an errand for you!
From your mother.
Ouch. I don't know where I was going with that!
An errand from my mother...
(in the background: No, that's not it...) Stop talking to me!
What about the hike, Ilya Ivanovich?
How the hell did they get wind of the treasury?
It's our competition. Nothing is sacred to them at all.
That's freedom of speech!
- Ooh! - You don't say!
Tomorrow all the morning chronicles will mention the horse and the treasury...
What if Ilya Ivanovich accidentally reads it?
Ugh! Hey, get the executioner over here!
Wait, Prince! The executioner is no help here.
What is written with a pen, you can't chop with an axe!
Yes? He's such a virtuoso...
And what will the people say?
That's just it!
And I can easily fix it,
...if you take me camping with you.
Camping?!
I'll write a chronicle about your courage!
Material for me, respect for you!
About courage?
Well... Why not?
It's a deal!
And Ilya Ivanovich won't mind?
Ilya?
Who is he? I've got dozens like him!
Hundreds of them! After all..,
...am I or am I not a prince?
What's that?
Where?
- The posse! - What brigade?
What did we agree on?
Are you crazy, Ilya!
What kind of a prince goes without a retinue!
So... That's it!
- Kar! - What's "kar"? - Kar!
Ah! Almost too late.
Are we moving?
Are you all..,
...conspiring?
Why? Let her come with us.
It's more fun on the road.
They took the sour cream. Thieves.
We will walk from the edge of the forest.
What do you mean on foot? I'm not going anywhere on foot!
Shouldn't we send you back to Kiev, Prince?
What do you mean, send you back to Kiev? Who are you?
To send a prince!
"...to send a prince?"
You know, Ilya,
...I'm an easy-going person by nature.
I have a temper sometimes, but otherwise I don't hold a grudge against anyone. Uh-huh!
What now?
Shh! The birds have fallen silent.
What do we need birds for? We're not out hunting.
A beast and a bird can always sense trouble.
We're not the only ones here.
Ah! Oh, no!
There's a cone over there, fallen on the trail!
Expect snow for supper!
People have been noticing omens for centuries!
They always tell the truth.
What am I, a little child, listening to fairy tales, ha! The omens!
Ilya Ivanovich!
Ilya Ivanovich! I have an errand for you.
From your mother...
Ilya Ivanovich!
Tell me, is Nightingale ,
...is that your first or last name?
What made you take the slippery path of robbery and robbery?
Not us! Life is like that!
- That's a good devil! - Tie her up, boys!
We'll spend the night here.
Here?
Look around you! The tree is dry, and the owl isn't screaming for good.
It's a dead place.
What's it to you? You don't believe in omens.
Well, you know! You said it yourself - people have been noticing omens for centuries!
- In general, it's not quiet here somehow. - That's it. We're done discussing.
Time for bed.
You're on watch till midnight.
- Me? Yeah, you.
What's the big deal? Then I'll take over for you.
Everyone is equal here, okay? Democracy!
Here you go.
- Democracy will lead you to turmoil! - Prince!
Don't sleep a wink!
Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah!
Well, well, well. What kind of fish got into our net?
- Probably a merchant. Or a boyar. - What's the matter with you?
You're so dark! Can't you see - the Prince is standing in front of you!
Or rather, you're standing in front of the Prince!
Behead!
You uneducated bastard!
You mock pheasant!
Listen to me! The Bandit Nightingale himself put me in charge here,
...so tell me now who I am,
...or we'll take your head off your shoulders right away.
I told you, the Prince is before you!
Order me to untie him at once,
...and fall at your feet!
- Maybe the Prince will forgive you. - Ah!
Oh, Ilya, you won't believe it,
...I'm so glad to see you!
And you, Prince, well done,
...you're not afraid.
You say, "Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Of course!
What the hell is that?
Where did she come from?
They're conspiring behind my back!
No way, Ilya! Here's your cross!
And in general, a woman in a campaign is always useful.
I mean, cooking..,
...or do the laundry! My sleeves are dirty.
No! We'll leave it here.
It won't be a problem.
I am! Yes you!
Yes... How dare you!
I didn't do it for nothing!
I wanted to publicize the everyday life of Russian heroes!
А... And you...
Thus, the operation, code-named "Vengeance"...
...was led personally by the Prince of Kiev.
Did you write it down?
From the first steps luck smiled on the prince.
And-and-and...
...and his entourage!
Luck has nothing to do with it.
It's just military cunning,
...nothing more.
How so? Can you be more specific?
It's not difficult. I've got a sign of an outlaw place,
...and then I took them as bait.
- You know, like fishing. - So that's it,
...that I was your live-bait?!
Easy, Prince, easy!
- I'm telling you, it's just a military trick. - You!
You endangered the life of the head of state!
That's... of... treason!
Look! He's awake...
So, are you going to tell me where Nightingale is?
...or shall I write you a second invitation?
He's gone over the sea.
He went to Tsargrad.
As soon as the treasury of the prince... у... м...
To Tsargrad? Are you sure? To Tsargrad?
Wait, Prince! You have to open his mouth.
How will he talk?
- Well? - That's what I'm saying,
- ...as soon as the treasury... - You'll talk in substance..,
...answer in substance!
- About Tsargrad! - Well, Prince,
...let him speak.
The Nightingale told him to wait for a sign,
...took the knight's horse and the prince's treasury..,
- ...and left. - He's delirious!
Your hand, Ilya, is heavy!
So...
So you say..,
...you took the treasury of the prince?
You thought you'd use my hands to settle your affairs?
- Not your own! - Listen, wait! - Not your own, but the state's!
You told me yourself, I had nothing to do with them!
Look, Ilya, remember what I told you about the errand? You know, from your mother?
You should say something in a good time and keep quiet in a bad one! Don't interfere!
- And don't you dare shout at me! I'm not your saddle mare! - I'll tell you...
...say hello to your mother!
After all, I am a prince!
And what's more, it's his duty to serve the Prince! And he's giving me a hard time!
And me... My sleeves are dirty! And I'm a prince! In case he's forgotten...
And the Prince and Ilyushka are probably in tears. Ah-ha-ha!
"Where's my money! Where's my horse, where's my Burushka!" Ha-ha-ha!
What? Is it hard without a magic mane?
Don't you cross the Nightingale, don't you cross the Nightingale! Where's my gold?
The Nightingale needs gold... Ouch! With gold the Nightingale will start a new life! Ouch!
Zanrani!
And I'll sell you to the first man I meet. Understand?
Or not? I'll order to make two drums out of your hide!
I'll play one myself, and send the other to Ilya!
You rebellious, thug! You parasite!
I thought I'd do the right thing!
A horse for him, a treasury for me, and now here you are! Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah!
Here! My horse, my treasury, my treasury, my horse!
It's all mine!
- I don't want to see him! - No, Prince, it's not right. We must catch up with Ilya!
- What's that? - My mother told me to give it to Ilya.
- She said that his native land gives him strength. - So what of it?
We don't need Ilya the rebel now!
You can't do that! And if trouble happens to him?
It serves him right! Eh!
Good! How can we beat Nightingale without Ilya? Have you thought about that?
How? How...
Vasilius! We... will help us.
Who can compare to Ilya Muromets? And what kind of a bogatyr is that - "Vasilevs"?
Oh, you! Chronicler!
The Vasileus is... Emperor.
Byzantine. He's my brother by blood.
If I whisper to him, he'll get Nightingale out of the ground for me!
While the prince and his companion were reaching the port,
...Ilya was halfway across the border...
...to Tsargrad.
And the Bandit Nightingale, celebrating his victory...
...to the great city.
Three!
Two!
Take it!
It's a good horse, isn't it?
- It's a good horse! No pity? Why don't you play it back? - Hm!
I'll buy me a hundred of them! A thousand!
I don't need a horse! For that money the whole of Tsargrad will be mine by today!
Do you know how many there are here?
You shaitan scum!
Uh, no! That's my horse now!
Get out of my way!
Well, merchant, let's see if your legs are strong!
You're lying, you won't get away with it!
Look what I found!
- Wow! Look! - Wow! - Wow!
Where did the horse go?
Who saw it? Hmm?
Well, we're almost there. We'll get on the ship,
...and we're done. You got any money?
Heh-heh-heh-heh! That's what I said. Why do we need money?
Am I a prince or am I not a prince?
Oh, what a beauty, a figure of a vine, a face of a berry!
- Would you like to go to Tsargrad? - What's it to you?
I can help you. And besides, I can offer you a job.
High pay, accommodation, insurance...
How so? As what?
In show business! Exotic dancing!
I can already see it: "Star of Tsargrad!"
No, no, it doesn't fit. Tell me something,
...a tall, handsome man. A bogatyr, in a word!
Are you talking about Ilya again?
Who are you writing the chronicle about?
There are heroes around, and you have a deserter on your mind!
We have two tickets to first class. Payment - at the expense of the host party!
And serve tea! With baranki!
You don't have to write it down in the annals!
I am the prince! I am you!
Wait! You'll come to me for a license!
Oh, Prince... I am... Wait for me here!
And in Constantinople, life went on as usual.
The Byzantine emperor, the emperor, was working hard,
...thinking night and day about the affairs of state.
Well, that's about it. It's beautiful.
Isn't this where the Duchy of Kiev is located?
Isn't it? Curious, heh-heh-heh...
So what of it? What are we feeding the army with? А?
So... The Great Emperor... Brothers! By faith...
Don't you get it? You want to upset the emperor.
Where is he? Where is the executioner, I ask you!
It's his day off! The great emperor...
Hmm?
As they say, I impregnate you! Bye...
I'm so tired!
No! Do not ask, do not beg, all to the executioner...
I will execute... And pardon...
...And so Tsargrad has managed to preserve itself over its more than thousand-year history.
Immediately upon arrival we will give you a guided tour, and you will see everything with your own eyes.
And now we offer you a taste of fresh tea with baranki.
Boorushka!
Don't you get it?!
Who let the horse into the emperor's garden?
А?! Hey! Somebody! Bring the executioner here!
- It's his day off! - He'll finish it later!
A Roman chariot...
- It's not ours, it's the horse's. - Gold?!
Curious...
God's grace has descended on your head, great emperor!
The magical horse is not just in your hands, but for the deeds of righteousness!
Glory to the great emperor!
- Hail! - Well done... Well done!
And where... Where, I ask you, is the magic horse?
...mine. А?
Missed it... Missed it!
- Right! All of you! Move it! Search! My horse! - Ah...
- M-m-mo... - Go away, go away!
- Hey, somebody get him out of here! - Can't we try it from the air? Ouch!
Curious!
Well done... good boy... Come here!
- Do you know how to parachute? - Mm... ah... э...
Oh... St. John...
All built up... Oh...
There's the palace of the emperor. It's so far away.
Let me sit down for a minute, or else... I feel dizzy!
Look! How cultured they are here!
They even have chairs outside!
Oh, it's nice here!
Cultured...
Cultured, I say! When I come back, I'll have them put chairs like that in Kiev too!
In Kiev!
Oh, it's convenient.
- And the money? - What money?
- Here's to a wonderful rest in my wonderful chair! - What?
Are you out of your mind?
Here's to sitting on that crappy... stool! You want money?
- Quiet, quiet! Better pay, Prince. - Where from?
I told you, I don't have any money!
They'll let you go to hell! You're a bad trip...
Silver! Silver, I say!
- A foreign wonder! What kind of a prince is that, eh? - It's a balloon!
- Did you steal a fork from the ship? - No way! This is payment.
It's not every day that they have a prince to serve.
I don't see anything yet...
Nothing...
W-w-w-w-well... There!
Well done! Good boy.
Boorushka!
There he is! There he is, my little dove!
And who's that?
Who dares to catch my horse?
Seize them all immediately and bring them to me!
I'll have mercy and beheading.
Perhaps only execute...
Oh, they won't make it in time.
I wish he could shorten his way here.
Well done! Good for you.
Show him a shortcut!
Did somebody tell him to pull the ring? А?
Open your eyes! I almost didn't let trouble get ahead of me.
Thank you! You saved me from the fierce beast.
That's right! It wouldn't be a bad thing to say thank you.
Thank you, Grandma!
Thank you!
I hear what you're shouting for!
They're in a hurry, they're in a hurry... There's no time for thanks.
I don't think we'll make it tonight. It's a long way to the palace.
And the emperor has a short working day.
I work from dawn to dawn, but emperors, you know...
Here you go!
Ooh! That's the kind of animal I'd get.
Doesn't bite?
Would you like a ride, sir?
I know you! You'll t-o-o-o-o-o-o-o-o... you'll rip off your underwear!
Ah-ah-ah-ah! No, sir,
...you don't have to pay for riding.
- Are you sure? It's free? - I swear on my mother!
Prince, he's lying, it's his business!
- And we'll lose time. - That's all right. We'll use it. Get in.
I'm not going anywhere! Ilya may need help, but we...
- No, like a child, honestly! - You're talking about Ilya again?
That's it, I told you! I'm not interested in him anymore!
Let's go to the emperor! And you stay here, since you're so clever!
You think you can defy the prince!
- Despot! - I heard everything!
Aaah! A vine with a figure, a berry with a face!
- You're still looking for a big man, aren't you? - Why? Do you know where to find him?
Of course I do. Please, my dear!
That's my horse!
- Get out of my way! - Ha-ha-ha!
What's the matter with you? You want to whistle in here?
Don't whistle, I said!
Don't whistle!
There'll be no money, it's an omen!
Hey! What are you doing here?
I'm late for the king.
It's... is a walk... not a cab.
All right, that's it! Stop right there, brother! Get me out of here!
Harasho. Give me the money.
You swore you wouldn't take money!
I don't take money for the ride,
...but for the fact that you...
...to get off the elephant.
- Got it, huh? - Oh, you foreign crooks!
Wait, I'll come down!
Oh... I'll be right down!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Boorushka!
Where are you, Boorushka!
At least give me a sign, send me word!
Burushka!
- Prince! Ilya! Ilyushka!
Get me out of here!
Ilya! My dear knight!
Thank God! We have met!
I'm by nature... an easy-going person. Well, you... you know.
I guess we should stick together after all,
- because it's a foreign land. What... what do you think? - Hmm!
What's that... foreign beast?
Are you still here? Get out of here! You stupid bastard!
You're so clumsy, Prince!
How can you talk to an animal like that?
She, like a human being, likes affection.
Oh, you, good, good!
We won't hurt you.
Where did such a strange animal come from?
They call it business! The damned chaser shrouded me in deceit!
...and said, "Get in! Take this despot for a ride! I don't want any money!"
I knew right away what was going on. And he said, "Take a ride, prince, do me a favor!"
You stole my elephant!
Ilya Ivanovich! There he is! The damned bandit.
Where's my money? Give me my money!
What money?
Shut up, you stupid brute!
He who is weak in spirit, the beast is in disgrace!
Why are you tying the beast?!
I wanted my elephant. I wanted to take my money. He's a crook!
- He's a crook! - I'll show you now!
Leave him alone, Prince!
- Better tell me, where did Alyonushka go?
Nobody knows how to use a parachute!
How are we going to live? А?
Well, as long as they catch my horse, we'll train. Come on. Get in.
Come on!
To the Great Emperor I dare to offer a foreign maiden!
A vine with a figure and a face like a berry!
Wow! Interesting!
By what right was I captured and brought here against my will?
I like it!
No, I do! I like it!
Even better... this... the one before that!
Untie me at once! I was coming to you!
You came by yourself? Ah... What's your name?
What's your name? Alyonushka!
What a wonderful name!
That's it, Alyonushka,
...let's go to my private office!
Caught!
Caught it, Great Emperor!
The parachute has opened after all.
Caught your precious horse. They've put him in the stable.
And the bandits who were chasing him?
- Ah... We only caught one! - What do you mean one?
Do you want to upset the emperor? Well...
- The hangman to him, my horse to me. Now! - May I see the hangman?
- The hangman? - No! At the horse. I'm very curious.
Come on, prince, don't lag behind!
Look! Look! Another Vasilius!
No, he's alive! Honestly!
When we come back, I'll have them put up, too! A dozen of them!
- What a beauty! - Let's go, Prince!
I told you, Burushka's running around here somewhere! I feel it in my heart...
Don't worry so much!
He'll help us find the treasury in no time... I mean, save Burushka!
- He's my brother, by blood... - Aha!
Well, did you get caught?
Well? Take a bite! Know our people! Aspies.
And you, my dear friend, have not reduced your strength one bit.
Why would I reduce it?
Well, what about it? And the Russian land, from which you take strength..,
...it has nothing to do with it? Oh, sly one!
How could I have forgotten!...
Hey! What are you doing? Get up, Ilyushka!
Get up! I was joking! About the land!
I'm going to the emperor, Ilyushka, to the emperor! For help...
Well, servant, report immediately to the emperor that his old friend, the prince of Kiev, has arrived!
Well! Do I have to wait long? Let me through!
The Vasilevs! The Vasilevs!
What are you doing, smerds? Let me through!
Your Majesty! Vasilius! Vasya! Vasya! Vasilievos!
Damned Russian! You didn't want to do it the right way?
Let them pay the ransom for you now!
Thank you, foreign wonder!
I couldn't have done it myself.
Ah... How can I help you?
Well, what a nuisance... Aah!
I've lost all my strength...
Listen!
Here's Burushkin's horseshoe! She walked on her native land!
Come on, honey, help me out! Come on!
Look at that! The strength is really coming back!
Come on... Oh!
It's coming back!
Hello, girls!
Well, that's how it is!
- Ekem... Biru... - What?
Phew, thank God! Hello, orthodox!
- Who are you? - Huh? A prince!
- Will you have some tea, Prince? - Come here, Prince! - Have a seat!
Hello, servants!
I've come with the Prince of Kiev.
Has he appeared here?
I understand, the service... It's not allowed to talk to outsiders at the post!
What's the matter with you guys?
You must have me confused with someone else!
So what's up?
Was the prince of Kiev here?
So he was! And where did he go?
Here you are! Stupid brute,
...but she's more useful than all of you!
I'm curious, how much more does he have inside?
May I ask you for an interview? What an unusual story!
I don't have an interview!
- There was a horse, and that one was taken away! His name is Burushka! - What?!
Burushka?
Don't order his execution, O wise emperor!
- Don't you understand?  - Your good horse... - What horse?
Stop spewing gold!
Well, get ready, Prince!
Ah, the dinner has just arrived...
- Pasta! - Well done, Ilya, you remembered your prince!
Let's go, shall we?
Do you know what the brothers say?
It's as if they delivered a beautiful horse to the emperor.
They say it's spewing gold!
What nonsense! What gold?
This kind of gold! And along with the horse they also brought a foreign girl.
If it wasn't Alyonushka...
And where... Where's my treasury? I'm so worried about the treasury!
All right, Prince, don't get excited. We'll sort it out.
Why isn't the horse spewing gold anymore?!
Answer me!
Have you sent someone to fetch the executioner?
Don't!
And the innocent prisoner told of the intrigues of Ilyushka of Murom.
How the heartless villain had robbed him of his honestly earned wealth,
...robbed him to the bone..,
...and hid all his gold...
...in his horse...
...magic horse!
Great Emperor! The Russians have destroyed the bridge to the palace!
- Now, Burushka, now! - Great Emperor! The Russians have destroyed the city prison!
Come on, dear land, help me out!
Great Emperor!
The army for the march on Kiev is built!
Here you are, Prince, a brother by blood!
There must be some mistake...
- Russians, surrender! - Russians do not surrender!
Where are the Russians?
Are these the ones?
You and Business go ahead,
...and I'll cover your rear!
Ilya! Where are you going?
Ilyusha, hold on!
Eh... Not the same power as in Mother Russia!
But it seems to be the same!
Na-shee! Na-shee! Na-shee!
You, Emperor, are no match for the Russian bogatyr!
And you didn't believe me! I wanted to take Kiev!
- We need a special warrior here. - What do you want? What do you want?
Toothmaker! For starters...
Well, that's how it is.
Alyonushka!
Hold on, Ilya! Hold on! Here, Russian land!
Here we are... Now we'll never part!
Ilya... Russian land...
Your mother told me to tell you. Remember?
Thank you... But you're a little late.
The mountain and the mountain don't add up, Ilya!
Don't whistle!
I told you, you wretched fool!
Where is my treasury! You damned scoundrel!
Answer me at once! Before I deal with you myself!
Hello! Hello, my brother!
Ah... No, really... I didn't recognize you.
As you say, you'll be rich!
The king returned the treasury of the prince,
...which the prince could not rejoice in for a long time.
And so they walked and rode, and so they reached home,
...where honor and honor awaited them..,
...and glory awaited them!
He's back!
And Ilya Muromets regained his former strength and power,
...and then Ilya Muromets beat the countless hordes of his enemies,
...and grabbed the main villain by the belt..,
...and threw him over the sea! Since then, Ilya Muromets has been honored not only by the Russian people..,
...but also in other foreign countries! And when there's trouble, they call...
...Ilya Muromets immediately! And the people live in peace..,
...as long as Ilya Muromets!... All right, that's enough! All right, then,
Alyonushka has written well! Fresh and believable. Give me that chronicle!
Yes... You, my dear man, here and here...
...in short, everywhere! Replace Ilya Muromets with the Prince of Kiev, and it'll be fine!
Well, that's it!