"If anyone dares to drink tea from an Orthodox Christian, he shall be anathematized by the Lord God Himself this hour.
And let him be anathematized three times.
If any man dare to drink coffee from an Orthodox Christian, he will be anathematized three times,
That man will be an evil coffee, and he must be anathematized four times.
"About Tobacco, about Tea, about Coffee"
Old Believer doctrine of the 18th century.
*(music plays)
The word coffee was first used as early as 1665, and immediately in the middle genera
"Boiled coffee, which Persians and Turks know and customary after dinner, is a great cure for insults, runny noses and major ailments."
But the only thing is that when coffee could only be drunk
Very noble people like the tsar or his retainers.
You couldn't just walk into a store and buy coffee.
So before Peter's time, the word was never found anywhere else, but in Peter's time.
both the drink and, consequently, the word itself becomes widely used.
As you know, at his assemblies Peter himself ordered everyone to drink coffee.
And in 1720 the first coffee house called "4 frigates" was opened in St.Petersburg
During the eighteenth century, coffee in the neuter gender occurs in as many as one-third of
Accordingly the remaining two thirds are coffee in the masculine form.
And it should be noted that this has nothing to do with the situation, the education of the author of the text, his knowledge of foreign languages,
or his knowledge of foreign languages, or his style, or anything like that.
Example
Karamzin. 1793.
Unknown. 1783.
Note here both the middle and the masculine gender at the same time
"If a particularly weak coffee is brewed for children, the harm of it is only that it laxes the stomach unnecessarily, as any lukewarm and watery drink does."
Examples of masculine
Radishchev
"Imagine," my friend once said to me, "that the coffee poured in your cup, and the sugar dissolved in it, deprived you of the peace of a man like you,
that they were the cause of his labours, the cause of his tears, lamentations, executions and scoldings."
Fonvisin
"I asked for coffee, which they immediately served me. I have never seen such vile filth - just vomit".
In the nineteenth century the neuter gender is used much less frequently.
Всего лишь в 6% случаев
Тургенев.
"После обеда подали кофе, жидкий рыжеватый, прямо немецкий кофе"
Пример среднего рода
"Шахрудцы, как и вообще персы пьют только чёрное кофе, то есть без сливок и притом очень редко"
Как это часто бывает при вхождении иностранного слова в язык, поначалу оно существует в большом количестве вариантов.
Особенно если слово запоминалось со слуха. Так, наряду со словом кофе, долгое время использовались и такие слова как coffee
"Кофей", "кофий", "кохей", "коф", "кофь", "коф", "кефа" и даже "кафе".
Повезло только трём из этих слов. Первые два: "кофий" и "кофей" нашли свое прочное место в языке XIX века,
а последнее - "кафе", на французский манер, "le café" стал обозначать собственно место где этот самый кофей пьют.
Причём обратите внимание что это слово сразу стало словом среднего рода, хотя во французском языке его вообще нет и артикль там мужской - "le".
Все остальные формы слова уже в XIX веке считались просторечием, и хотя некоторые из них прочно нашли свое место
в старообрядческой среде, ну взять что того самого "кофъ лукавого" что, скажем, такой пример:
Немирович-Данченко. 1874 год.
Одна тысяча десять рублёв на дорожку изволили пожертвовать
— А коф пить грех! — вставила пожелтевшая и высохшая странница
Although in the middle of the 18th century a serious author could still write "kov" or "kof".
Tatishchev. 1742.
... daily he with a footman covers the table and collects, and after dinner he makes coffee and distributes it.
As we have already noted, the words "Coffey" and "Coffee" are unprecedentedly widespread.
I looked up the statistics on ruscorpra.ru for 150 years
from 1750 to 1900, and I found that the word "coffee"
was used five times less often than "coffee," but still "coffee" was three times less often than just "coffee."
Coffee, sugar, millet, candy, and the like, imported from Persia,
against the imported ones through European merchants to consider, which trade is more useful, those and goods to facilitate.
Example from Chekhov.
He generously forgave me with tears and advised me to use acorn caffeine for my catarrh.
But since the nineties, both words, as well as "coffe" and "coffee," with an "E."
Begin to decline in usage.
Their frequency declines until the
1950s, until it becomes about the same as it is now.
That is, the word can be found, but it
is recognized as somehow clearly obsolete.
As for the gender of the word "coffee" in the twentieth century, the middle gender returns again and we again come to the indicators of the
of the eighteenth century - one third of all uses.
For example, "coffee" in the Neuter gender was used by Alexey Tolstoy, Bulgakov, Bunin and Brodsky.
In the latter it occurs in two variants:
"Coffee in a cup stood on the desk."
"I was sitting in an empty ship's bar, drinking my coffee, leafing through a novel..."
The items exported were marijuana, base metal, mediocre coffee cigars called Corona, and folk art trivia.
Now let's see if the word "coffee" has ever been declined
The answer is yes, but there is only one case form, the instrumental case -
"Kofem."
Imagine - even Tsar Nicholas II himself said so
From his diaries:
"She received the presents before the coffee downstairs at Alix's."
Philologists began to pay attention to the word "coffee" in the middle gender even before the Revolution
For example, in the book "Experience of a Dictionary of Irregularities in Colloquial Speech," by Dolopchev, 1909
The word "coffee" in the middle gender is mentioned explicitly as incorrect
The author of the other book is Chernyshev.
"Correctness and Purity of Russian Speech."
1911.
does not mark this word in any way, but the text itself contains two such very
very contradictory passages. On the one hand, the word "coffee"
is mentioned among the words which
"used generally in the middle gender," but it goes on to say that it is used
"chiefly in the masculine gender."
Now go figure it out.
Soviet normativizers did not radically change anything this time-they simply reprinted old recommendations.
No Soviet dictionary gave precedence to the Neuter gender, but it was mentioned everywhere as colloquial.
So the fact that since the 1980s they regularly say that they supposedly
"introduce new norms" are nothing more than newspaper ducks.
The last time this happened, I remember, was in 2009, when Act 195 was passed, with this
long name.
This law instructs us to use a dictionary in which the word coffee is marked as a neuter word
"Oh, there was an awful racket! Once again it was said that the era of the beautiful Russian syllable was over,
Education is ruined, and our children won't understand Pushkin.
It is not so much deplorable that someone writes such things, but so much that someone listens to this gibberish.
But news of this kind achieves its purpose.
It turns a linguistic phenomenon into a distinctly sociolinguistic one.
That's how "coffee it" became the clearest indicator
of illiteracy in the late Soviet era.
Look at this. Along with the neuter gender of the word "coffee,"
normative dictionaries also do not advise, say, such accents as znaemye, apostrophe, you need znaemye and apostrophe, respectively, and many other things,
but if someone says so, they won't even pay much attention to it, on the contrary.
rather be surprised when they learn that the dictionaries advise otherwise.
But to say in polite society.
"I had a good cup of coffee" is like stepping in shit and then
and then not washing your shoe - everyone will say:
"Ew, you're so illiterate!"
And those sons of bitches correct me, like.
"Remember, my friend, how to do it right! Or else you'll spend the rest of your life handing out keys!"
*music*
The word "coffee" in the 17th and 18th centuries
was borrowed in several forms from several foreign languages.
but in all languages the word was masculine
German: "Der Kaffe".
In French: "Le café"
Dutch: "Koffie."
This is why the pair "caffee"/"coffee" appeared - evidently from the Dutch sounding.
And the masculine gender was further supported by both the analogy with these words "koffie"/"coffee," and perhaps by the fact that most
of the authors of texts of the 18th and 19th centuries and the coffee drinkers themselves were educated people.
They knew foreign languages one way or another and may have had all these examples in their memory.
In Soviet times, when there were fewer connoisseurs of foreign languages, they found it expedient to use another explanation
that coffee is masculine because it's a drink.
This, of course, is a totally useless explanation, it only makes things worse.
and the discerning person immediately has a question:
"Well, okay, if coffee is a beverage and therefore is masculine, then why the middle gender of 'beer,' 'brandy,' 'sake,' 'cocoa' ?"
The reason the language doesn't want to contain such an exception and sort of
pushing us to use the neuter gender
is quite trivial - analogy, because if this exception doesn't have any semantic or grammatical function, we can get rid of it.
Since in Russian "E" words are exclusively Neuter words, we have two choices:
Either we keep the gender but change the ending and then we get "kofiy".
or we keep the ending, but we have to change the gender.
And that's how we get the inflected tasty "coffee."
Compare a similar example, where we get words that are feminine but
ending in a consonant, and there's no such thing in Russian.
The Soviet hippies had "gerla" in their jargon, because she's a "girl", which is not inflected.
French "madame" became "madame" in Russian,
and there's a Scandinavian name like "Ingeborg" which became "Ingeborga" on Russian soil.
And so did the Lithuanian language, which also doesn't have the corresponding types
consonantal declension of the feminine gender, but we call "Ingeborga" not only Lithuanians, like, well, the most famous one is probably the actress
Ingeborga Dapkunaite
We also call all sorts of Danish women Ingeborga, who actually have a name ending in a consonant.
At the beginning of the 20th century, "blinds" was a neuter word in the singular.
So Chernyshev writes:
"Open blinds."
Later on, however, it became a plural according to the Russian types of declension.
That is why there is absolutely no surprise that it is possible to celebrate the New Year "in Helsinki".
and the Olympics in Sochi.
That's what my dad says, and I often say it myself.
A curious example from the Polish language:
In Polish, the ending "e" is also a plural ending.
That's why "Google" can be understood as a plural word.
"Szukaj w googlach" - "Search in googlach".
Just as coffee was masculine in the past so were many other nowadays only neuter words
"cacao," "jabot," "coupe."
"piano," "piano," "auto," "coat," and others
Tolstoy
"This short man was wearing a white, leather apron that covered his chest and part of his legs,
around his neck was worn something like a necklace, and from behind the necklace protruded a tall, white jabot, which bordered his elongated face, lit from below."
Herzen
"It was a lean, tall man, much older than the first; he was almost all the same color, wearing a light green coat."
Discerning viewers will remember that there was such a video as "Conversation Three" on our channel
And so there was this girl Masha,
Who played the role of...
The student in the movie.
There's a funny story about her.
Many years ago she found out somewhere that the word "piano" used to be
and so, they say, it should be said until now.
Indeed, we find such a thing in old texts
Leskov
"Do you recognize it or not, our old piano?"
And everyone wondered then, how aristocratic it sounds.
"Black Piano."
But still, it's kind of weird.
I even found this unique photo
Where I'm on the right, Masha is there, you see, looking out in the distance. Between us stands the black piano in question
I, of course, started noticing that she talks like that
and I myself began to speak to her as another old dictionary, Nikolai Grech's "Reference Place of the Russian Word" of 1843, advises
He requires the words to be declined and says "playing the piano .
...but being able to play the piano, puts them to music worthy of their subject.
I must say that after a while Masha finally gave in to the nobility of her tones and began to speak as before
And one last example that is on many people's lips:
The word "subway" was once a masculine word, too, because it's short for
"Metropolitan."
There was a newspaper called Soviet Metro.
And it was even sung in a song:
"But the subway shone with its oak railings, at once it bewitched all the riders".
The word "coffee" has always been in the neuter gender. Moreover, it first entered the language in this form
There were periods when the neuter gender almost disappeared, but after a while it began to spread again
And it is the middle gender that is the future of the language.
If there's no public opinion.
of the mass-media and constant conversations at school, it will take a generation or two for the masculine gender to perish.
But, by the way, it is hardly possible in the next decade, and now all the literate people have already managed to teach masculinity.
Well, I personally lucky - I very rarely have to choose between saying "hot coffee" or "hot coffee".
I personally don't drink coffee or tea and I don't smoke tobacco.
And it's not even that I'm afraid of being attacked by the evil one, or that I'm desperate from God; no.
I just don't like it. That's all.
Well, brothers, sweet sisters.
Adieu!