"If anyone from Orthodox Christians dares to drink tea, this hour will despair the Lord God himself
and be anathematized three times.
If anyone from Orthodox Christians dares to drink coffee,
in that person there will be evil coffee and let him be anathematized four times"
"About tobacco, about tea  , about coffee"
Old Believer teaching of the 18th century
*music plays*
For the first time the word coffee was used back in 1665 and immediately
neuter "Boiled coffee, known and common by Persians and Turks after dinner, is a fair remedy for arrogance, runny noses and headaches"
But  the only thing is that only
very noble persons, like the king or his entourage, could drink coffee.
It was impossible to just come to the store and buy coffee.
Therefore, until the time of Peter the Great, this word was not found anywhere else, but in the time of Peter
I, the drink and, accordingly, the word itself became widely used.
As you know, at his assemblies, Peter himself ordered everyone to drink coffee
And in 1720 already  Petersburg, the first coffee house called "4 Frigates" was opened.
During the 18th century, coffee in the neuter gender was found in as much as one third of cases.
Accordingly, the remaining two thirds are coffee in the masculine gender.
Moreover, it should be noted that this has nothing to do with either the situation or  education of the author of the text, neither with his knowledge of foreign languages,
nor with style or something like that.
An example of
Karamzin.  1793.
Unknown.  1783.
Pay attention here to both the middle and masculine gender at the same time
"If especially weak coffee is brewed for children, then the harm from it consists only in the fact that it weakens the stomach unnecessarily, as any warm and water drink does"
Examples of the masculine gender
Radishchev
"Imagine  , - my friend once told me, - that the coffee poured in your cup, and the sugar dissolved in it, deprived a person like you of peace,
that they were the cause of labors surpassing his strength, the cause of his tears, groaning, execution and desecration "
Fonvizin
"I asked for coffee, which was immediately served to me. I have never seen such vile swill - just emetic."
In the 19th century, the middle gender began to be used much less frequently.
Only in 6% of cases
Turgenev.
“After dinner, coffee was served, liquid reddish, directly German coffee”
An example of the neuter gender
“Shakhrudtsy, like Persians in general, drink only black coffee, that is, without cream and, moreover, very rarely”
As is often the case when a foreign word enters a language, at first it  exists in a large number of options.
Especially if the word was memorized by ear.  So, along with the word coffee, for a long time such words as coffee
"Coffee", "coffee", "kohei", "coffee", "coffee", "coffee", "kefa" and even "cafe" were used.
Only three of these words were lucky.  The first two: "coffee" and "coffee" found their firm place in the language of the 19th century,
and the last - "cafe", in the French manner, "le café" began to denote the actual place where this same coffee is drunk.
Moreover, note that this word immediately became a neuter word, although in French it does not exist at all and the article is masculine there - "le".
All other forms of the word were already considered vernacular in the 19th century, and although some of them firmly found their place
in the Old Believer environment, well, let's take that very "sly coffee" that, say, such an example:
Nemirovich-Danchenko.  1874
One thousand and ten rubles for the track deigned to donate
- And it's a sin to drink coffee!  - put in a yellowed and dried-up wanderer.
Although in the middle of the 18th century, a quite serious author could write "kov" or "coffee".
Tatishchev.  1742.
... every day he covers the table with the attendant and collects it, and after dinner he brews coffee and delivers it.
As we have already noted, the words "Coffee" and "Coffee" have gained unprecedented popularity.
I looked at the statistics on the site ruscorpra.ru for 150 years
from 1750 to 1900, and it turned out that the word "coffee" was
used five times less often than "coffee", but still "coffee" was three times less common than just "coffee"  .
Coffee, sugar, millet, sweets and the like, imported from Persia,
against those imported through European merchants, consider which bargaining is more useful, those goods to facilitate.
An example from Chekhov.
He forgave me generously with tears and advised me to use acorn coffee for catarrh.
But since the nine hundredth years, both words, as well as "coffee" and "coffee", with "E".
Starting to decline in use.
Their frequency decreases until the
1950s, until it becomes about the same as now.
That is, this word can be found, but it is
recognized as somehow clearly outdated.
As for the gender of the word "coffee" in the 20th century, the neuter gender returns again and we again reach the indicators of the
18th century - a third of all uses.
For example, Alexei Tolstoy, Bulgakov, Bunin, and Brodsky had "coffee" in the neuter gender.
The latter has two versions:
"Coffee in a cup was on the desk"
"I was sitting in an empty ship's bar, drinking my coffee, leafing through a novel ..."
Export items - marijuana, non-ferrous metal, mediocre coffee cigars called "Crown"  and trifles of folk craftsmen.
Now let's see if the word "coffee" was ever inclined. The
answer is "yes", but there is only one case form - the instrumental case -
"Coffee"
Imagine - even Tsar Nicholas II himself said so
From his diaries:
"She received  gifts in front of Alix's coffee downstairs"
Philologists began to pay attention to the word "coffee" in the neuter gender even before the Revolution.
The author of another book - Chernyshev
"Correctness and purity of Russian speech"
1911 This word does not mark in any way, but the text itself contains two such very
contradictory passages.  On the one hand, the word "coffee" is
mentioned among the words that are
"usually used in the neuter gender", but then it is said about it that it is used
"mainly in the masculine gender"
So go and figure it out.
This time, the standardizers of the Soviet era did not radically change anything  - they just reprinted old recommendations
Not a single Soviet dictionary gave preference to the middle gender, but it was mentioned everywhere as colloquial.
So the fact that since the 80s they have been regularly saying that they are supposedly
"introducing new norms" is nothing more than newspaper ducks
Last time  this was, I remember, in 2009, when law No. 195 was adopted, with such a
long name.
This law requires us to use one dictionary in which the word coffee is marked as a neuter word
"Oh, there was a terrible hype! Once again they started talking that  the era of the beautiful Russian style has come to an end,
education has been destroyed, and our children will not understand Pushkin. It is
regrettable not so much that someone writes like this, but so much that someone  then he listens to this rubbish.
However, news of this kind achieves the goal.
They turn a linguistic phenomenon into a clearly sociolinguistic phenomenon.
That is how "coffee is it" became the clearest indicator of
illiteracy in late Soviet times
. Look.  Along with the middle gender of the word "coffee",
normative dictionaries also do not recommend, say, such accents as a sign, an apostrophe, you need a sign and an apostrophe, respectively, and a lot of other things,
but if someone says so, then they won't even pay much attention to it  , on the contrary, they are
more likely to be surprised when they find out that dictionaries advise the opposite.
But to say in a decent society,
"I drank delicious coffee" - it's like stepping into the [ __ ] with your foot and then
not washing your shoes - everyone will immediately say:
"Fu, what an illiterate you are!"
These sons of [ __ ] will also correct, they say,
“Remember, my friend, how to do it right!  Otherwise, you will be giving keys all your life!”
*music*
The word "coffee" in the 17th-18th centuries was
borrowed in several forms from several foreign languages at once, but i
all languages this word was masculine In German:
Der Kaffe" In French:
Le café" In Dutch:
"Koffie"
That is why the pair "coffee" / "coffee" appeared - apparently from the Dutch
sound.
of the 19th centuries, as well as the coffee lovers themselves, are still an educated public.
They somehow knew foreign languages and all these examples could be in their memory.  coffee is
masculine because it's a
drink. Of course, this explanation is completely stupid, it only casts a shadow on the wattle fence
and the astute person immediately has a question:
"Well, it's good if coffee is a drink and therefore it is masculine,  then why then the middle gender "beer", "brandy" "sake", "cocoa"?
The reason why the language does not want to contain such an exception and, as it were,
prompts us to use the neuter gender is
quite banal - an analogy, because if this exception does not have any semantic or grammatical function, then it is quite possible to get rid of it.
Since in the Russian language  words on "E" are words of exclusively neuter gender, then we have two options:
either we keep the gender, but change the ending and then we get the word "coffee"
or we keep the ending, but we have to change the gender
And so we get the inflected delicious  "coffee"
Compare a similar example, when feminine words enter the Russian language, but
ending in a consonant, and there is no such type of declension in Russian.
So in the jargon of Soviet hippies there was the word "gerla", well, because she "girl" is like-  you can't decline the
French "madame" became "madama" on Russian soil,
and there is also such a Scandinavian name as "Ingeborg" which became "Ingeborg" on Russian soil. By the
way, he also made Lithuanian  th language where there are also no corresponding types of
consonant declension of the feminine word, but we call "Ingeborga" not only Lithuanians, for example, well, the most famous one is probably the actress
Ingeborga Dapkunaite.
We also call Ingeborga any Danes who actually have a name  ends in a consonant
At the beginning of the 20th century, the word "blinds" was a neuter singular word.
So Chernyshev writes:
"Open blinds"
However, later it became a plural word in accordance with Russian types of declension.
Therefore, there is absolutely nothing surprising in the fact that you can celebrate the New Year "in Helsinki"
And the Olympics can be held "in Sochi" I can,
for example,  dad says, well, I myself often say so too.
A curious example from the Polish language:
In Polish, the ending "e" is also the ending of the plural,
so the word "Google" can be perceived exactly as a word in the plural number
"Szukaj w googlach" -  "Search in Google"
Just like masculine coffee in the past, there were many other now only neuter words
"Cocoa", "jabot", "coupe",
"piano", "piano", "auto", "coat" and others
Tolstoy
"This short man was dressed in a white, leather apron that covered his chest and part of his legs,
something like a necklace was put on around his neck, and a tall, white frill protruded from behind the necklace, fringing his oblong face, lit from below"
Herzen
"It  there was a thin, tall man, much older than the first;  he was almost all the same color, he was wearing a light green coat "
Insightful viewers remember that on our channel there was such a video as" Third Conversation "
And so there was a girl Masha,
who played the role of an
entrant in the film.
She is associated with such a funny  history
Many years ago, she found out somewhere that the word "piano" used to be a masculine word,
and so, they say, it must still be said today.
Indeed, in old texts we find such
Leskov
"Do you recognize him or not, our old  piano?"
And then everyone was surprised, they say, how aristocratic the
"Black Piano" sounds.
But still, it's somehow strange.
I even found such a unique photo
where I'm on the right, Masha, you see, looks out in the distance.  the black piano in question
I, of course, began to notice that she spoke like that
and I myself began to speak to her as another old dictionary advises - “Reference place of the Russian word” 1843 by Nikolai Grech
He requires to decline words and speak  "play on  piano "
... knowing how to play the piano, he puts them to music worthy of his subject.
It must be said that after a while Masha nevertheless gave up the nobility of her subtlety and began to speak as before.
And the last example that many people hear:
When-  then the masculine word was also the word "metro", because it is an abbreviation, as it were, from
"Metropolitan"
There was such a newspaper - "Soviet Metro"
And even in the song it was sung:
"But the metro flashed with oak railings, it immediately bewitched all riders"
Word "  coffee" has always been neuter.  Moreover, it first entered the language in this form.
There were periods when the neuter gender almost disappeared, but after a while it began to spread again.
And it is the neuter gender that is the future of the language.
If there is no public opinion, the
media will not pay special attention to this  constantly speaking at school, then a couple of generations will pass and the masculine gender will perish.
However, in the next decade this is hardly possible, and now all the literate people have already managed to teach the masculine gender to everyone.
Well, I personally was lucky - I rarely have to make a choice between how to say: "  hot coffee" or "hot coffee"
I personally don't drink coffee or tea,
I don't smoke tobacco.  No,
I just don't.  That's all.
Well, brothers, dear sisters
Adieu!