[Loud TV]
[doorbell rings]
I'm not available, get out please!
Gee! Brother, don't you understand the word? Who at this hour?
-Who is knocking on the door? -I stole it bro.
-Did you steal it? -Yes brother.
Is your height enough for this bell?
[laughs]
-Brother, it's a shame. -What a shame?
-Why do you bother? -You have a letter, brother.
Throw it out from under the door, son. Neck is closer to there.
"Fate" Aha! It's from the community!
It may be something important, let me open this, stop. Take it.
"The organization of our Black Warehouse Truckers Association..."
-What's up? -What did they write, brother?
What the hell, what did they write to you?
My special, special letter, son! Don't make the man mad, I'll put it in your mouth!
You are right bro.
"Our Black Warehouse Truckers Association
at the Sixth Konya Dried Bean Festival, organized by
We will be happy to see you among us." he tells me!
Good news, I guess.
There is no better news, son, let me tell you so. I put it in your mouth!
There is no better news! Nurullah! Nurullah, I want my good news!
I want my good news, Nurullah!
I want my good news, Nurullah! I want my gospel!
[female] Recep is coming!
No! Please back off, please! I will not eat!
-Take one. -Please! It's okay!
Ok, leave it alone! Oh really!
Nurullah!
Pop my balloons! Why are you blowing up?
[laughs]
Nurullah!
What are you doing?
Come on, walk!
Nurullah!
[car tires chirp]
[plays traditional Turkish music]
Nurullah, Nurullah! I want my good news, Nurullah!
God! I want my gospel, good news! Nurullah!
-Brother, how many? -Two two.
Selamunaleykum, let's see.
Nurullah, I want my good news Nurullah!
I want my gospel, sit down. Sit down, sit down.
[grunting]
I swear I'm going to have an infarction huh!
Oh brother, why are you tiring yourself so much?
I bring you great news. I want my gospel.
Read it!
"At the Sixth Konya Dried Bean Festival,
We are honored to see you, our valued member, among us."
-Dried Bean Festival? -He, the Dry Bean Festival.
-Where is this? -In Konya.
-Is it Konya? -Hey, Konya.
The city where time stops, Konya. An awe-inspiring city.
The city with thousands of shades of green.
My grandfather was a Mevlevi during the Ottoman period.
He was interested in Sufism. I always want to see Konya, Nurullah.
That's great then!
You will hit two birds with one stone.
You will both visit Konya well and bury the dried beans.
We will bury, we will tour.
I assume you mean second person plural. Because we will go together.
-No, brother, I can't come. -What do you mean I can't come, Nurullah?
Will I go alone? Aren't you my homie?
-What do you mean I can't come? -Who will I leave the coffee to?
Whoever you leave it to! what about me? Did you ask me while opening the coffee?
Your friend has been invited to the Baked Bean Festival.
-How are you bro? Of course you will come. -Ya Recep, I can't come!
[sniffs and spits]
God damn you! If you don't come, don't come!
Do not come if you do not want to!
With you right now, my whole bromance is over!
I cut off all my bromance with you.
If you don't come, don't come, let the devil see your face! -Oh okay, I'm sorry.
-I'm coming. -Don't come, don't come!
Don't come, who are you? Like please! If you don't come, don't come, is it up to you?
But you are like a child. OK. I'm coming, I'm coming.
-Are you coming for sure? -I'm coming, Recep.
Handle those tickets too, come on, coach.
Why am I handling the ticket business?
You're the one who invited, why are you burying the ticket for me?
I'll probably bury you! Who else should I bury? Aren't you my homie?
Bros bury each other. Gee! You probably have a mite, we bury you.
You pass it on to everyone here.
The man drinks eight, you get 35 at the end of the month.
I have a salary of 325 TL from my grandmother, should I take it with her?
Almost half left, I bought bitcoin with them too.
Damn it sank too. I bought it from 17 thousand, it went down to 3-4 thousand.
Everything is going wrong already. Isn't your nephew a tourist?
Search this. Call, maybe he'll give you free tickets. Search!
My mother, my mother, my mother. We will go to Konya.
It will be a festival, Nurullah... My mother, my mother, my mother.
Is it ringing?
[phone rings]
-Hello? -How are you, nephew?
-How was it? -What about the good uncle?
We also work at work, work is power, you know.
I'm fine, it's fine. We will have a trip.
Well, uncle, you have your order, let's arrange it right away. How many are you?
-Two people. Recep... [line cut] -Hello? How many people uncle?
-My two nephews, two. -Hey, two.
-Hey, two. -Huh. Two people, two people.
-Well, uncle, what do you think? -Konya.
-What did you say uncle? -Konya.
Hello, I can't hear your voice uncle. I love your eyes...
-Hello? Don't I hear? -Look, is there no network?
-There is a mains, two teeth. -I'll put it in your line!
Uncle, I can't hear your voice, for God's sake go to a place that attracts you.
-What about my nephew Konya, Konya... -[line cut]
I'm getting my uncle "ya" but I can't get his head. What or"?
-Ya Konya, Konya! -Konya, Konya!
Ya Konya, Konya!
-Huh, Kenya... -Alo?
[line cut]
-Kenya, it's beautiful. Okay uncle. -Hello?
-Okay uncle, it's very beautiful. - Huh! thank you!
So do you know the date?
-When do you think? He says when.
-The festival is on Sunday, the 15th. -On Sunday, 15 of them are gone.
Uncle, it would be a little expensive, only one way, let me tell you.
He says it will be expensive.
I swear there is no one coming in and out of me, it's exploding at you.
Uncle, I have a terrific tour of 13 departures and 16 return tours.
just for you.
There are 13 outbound tours and 16 return tours.
-Okay, take the tour. -Okay, the tour is ideal for us.
-Wonderful. -Does the tour tour everywhere?
- So where are you traveling? -The plain or something?
Do you tour the plain?
Plains, natural beauties, historical beauties,
You will visit all of them one by one. They were traveling everywhere.
There will already be special vehicles in front of your door,
they will take you and show you all over the place, uncle.
You pick us up with special vehicles.
-Perfect. Accomodation? -How is the accommodation?
You will stay in four-star hotels, uncle.
-It's four stars. -Four?
I was expecting five, my expectation was for five, but it would be four.
Sure. Okay. Accept, accept, take the tour.
Ok nephew.
Only uncle, these places are not like our places. Look, it's very hot.
Be careful, take clothes with you accordingly.
It would be very hot there.
No? I thought it was cool too. The heart of Central Anatolia!
It takes the sun like a mirror, of course it's hot.
This is the Konya Plain, death valley!
Either your brother Recep knows the place already, he knows it's hot.
Is there anything else?
You have e passports, don't forget the passports.
Bring them to me and I'll deliver them back to you on the plane.
It says passport?
Where does the passport come from? Do we show a passport when we go to Konya?
-Not for safety? -Hee, maybe.
There is a state of emergency, a state of emergency. It could be because of passports, it makes sense.
I already have Salih Abi, you can buy it from him.
Ok nephew, I'm bringing all the paperwork to you.
E super uncle, we got a deal.
-Okay? - He said okay.
If it's ok, close it, close it directly, close it without giving up.
Cayar, mayar now. Shut it down now, shut it in your face.
I'm so excited huh! We're going to a great festival, hit it!
[makes a kissing sound]
Slow on the side...
Selamun aleykum.
Take good care of the Red Devil, got it, jack bro?
Don't leave the car alone. Let's.
Selamunaleykum my nephew. Here are the documents.
-Goodbye, uncle. -Selamun aleykum brother.
Aleykum salam. Hello uncle.
I just told you to wear clothes suitable for that place.
Is there anything better than this bro? These are my great-grandfather's clothes.
We wore them because they were wearing them in that region.
Ok brother, if you say that, I will not be rude.
I mean, people hang around there anyway.
The important thing is to breathe the same air.
hey. It is important to live that mysticism, that theology, that spirituality.
That's right, my brother.
Now we have to catch the plane, the convoy.
- Let's get our vaccine, let's go from there. -Is it a vaccine?
Where does the vaccine come from? No, wait a minute!
-The vaccine has not been tried. There is no vaccine. Where did it come out of? -My brother, it is compulsory by the state.
It has nothing to do with me.
Yahu bro, are we primary school babies?
Should the state make vaccination compulsory for us?
Then the state should also look for mumps and chicken pox.
Let's celebrate Domestic Goods Week. What is this?
Either we will go on a trip for three days, the state did not come after us.
What about my nephew, is there anything you can do?
Unfortunately, my uncle.
What if it were up to me, would I bother you here, for God's sake?
I say, God forbid, in case something happens to you there,
I mean, not because it will happen, but because we said it happened, you understand?
Not like this, Nurullah. Can you excuse me for a second?
OK. We have five minutes, we'll catch the plane. OK?
Let me tell you something very clear Nurullah, I did not catch my eye on this baby.
There's definitely something wrong with this baby. -What is it, Recep?
Ya, I'm also getting hairy because he's your relative anyway.
Your whole family is smugglers, swindlers. This is her own father at the wedding,
Didn't he take his mother's gold and run away with the wedding officer?
Okay, I say give this kid another chance,
Let's not convict him for his father, but...
"Look, passport," he said, bristling.
We come here, he says vaccine. There's two.
God forbid the third.
What if the government says something, it's true.
If the subject is the homeland, the rest is details!
We know too! Don't stop shouting slogans here!
We know it too! I call you a vaccine, a vaccine!
Walk! Walk!
[inaudible conversations]
Selamunaleyküm, my teacher.
-How can we do it, sir? Shall we go like this? -Here you go.
Sir, let this friend be the first.
-You first! -You are the first, my son.
-I'm scared! -I'm scared too, son!
-Be you, does it hurt? -You're big, sit here.
-Come on, come on! Get over there, son. -Oh, Recep!
Oh, please sit here.
So you're both going to get it done, after all. If you want, go first.
God damn you! Take it.
Hold this too.
Which arm should I roll up, sir? Should I graze my right arm or my left arm?
-We don't do it from the arm alone. -How can you not do it by arm alone?
-We don't do it by hand. -Where are you from, ma'am?
From the hips.
-How from the hip? -From the hip. Rough meat.
When I say rump, I mean... Ass, we know.
[cakes] So...
We were never told such a thing.
We are victimized over and over again, but not at this airport.
Is it this way?
-What vaccine is this, sir? -Malaria.
We are going to Konya, my teacher.
What is malaria doing in Konya, Central Anatolia Region?
Konya? Beautiful!
Look at the triples! All these doctors are getting head burns,
they work for seven or eight years.
They cut a cadaver, a corpse, a kidney splashes in your eye or something.
Peel it off please.
my mother! My mother, my teacher! You're getting to the point very quickly, sir! Not that way, but that's it!
Can you look at what you have, sir? Do you peel it?
You haven't specified your preference yet. Right or left, sir?
-It does not matter. -How does it matter, sir?
Just like the arm, there are two separate parts there.
Should I scrape the right lobe or the left lobe? Which one should I scrape?
So it doesn't matter to me.
[sighs] Sir, then let me shoot from the right,
they usually hit me from the right when I was a kid. My mother, Nurullah!
-Sir, is this stripping enough? -Enough is enough.
Ah! It hurts it hurts!
-Sir, I haven't even touched it yet! - All right, sir.
-Ah! It hurts it hurts! -The needle is in my hand!
Please let me know before I do, I want to prepare myself.
Alright. Take a deep breath!
God! I'm on fire, God!
-What number are we at, Nurullah? -Eight, bro.
-Eight? -Yup.
The girl who threw us back again.
-Nurullah? -Yes bro?
Are you sure we're on the right plane? -Yes, brother, the people of our tour.
We passed together. Hello aunt.
What aunt? Have some manners!
You will say sister, sister! Shame, shame!
Excuse me ma'am, what did this boy say to you?
Did he say old man? Did he say kartoloz, what did he say? Aunt said!
Do not exaggerate so much, let me love your eyes! You are already your aunt.
-It would be an insult to say sister, you're an aunt. -Ill mannered!
Late Nurullah, walk. Give it, give it.
Give me the bag too.
Have a nice flight.
[sighs]
Do you feel any difference when you look at the plane in general?
-No. -How do you not feel?
-There are too many blacks. -That's right bro.
-Why is that? -I do not know.
Activate the flower pot.
-I couldn't find it. -This is the power of Konya, the power of Konya.
What did Mevlana say?
"Get out and come." said. -Oh, god damn you! Ignorant!
O Seda Sayan lan, Seda Sayan o!
Mevlana said, "Whatever you are, come." said.
Look how, flock from the world,
The whole world is flocking to Konya. How does it migrate?
[hostess] Please fasten your seat belts.
Oh, notice.
Please open your sunshade and put your belongings in the pocket.
Did you fasten your belt? Is it plugged in?
-Did you wear your belt? -Yes.
-Where in Konya are you from? -Yes.
-He? -Yes.
You say yes to every shit, I don't get it.
Come on, bismillah, give your hand Konya.
Have a nice trip, captain, lift the plane.
-[the plane shakes] -My mother!
Allahu Akbar! What's going on Nurullah?
Nothing bro, calm down. We got into turbulence.
Look, look, look, look at the comfort of this.
"Nothing bro, calm down, turbulent..."
It's as if he flies 45-50 thousand miles every year, giving me turbulence lessons.
What time is it?
-13.37 bro. -How 13.37?
-So it's been three and a half hours? - That's right, brother.
How about Nurullah?
-This work is being weird. -How is it, brother?
-How many hours is it from Istanbul-Ankara? -One hour.
er? Below Ankara is Konya. One and a half hours from Istanbul-Konya.
It's half past three, there's definitely a problem here, Nurullah.
-Brother, no air traffic? That's right, air traffic.
It gets very tight just after work,
There is a bridge, the Istanbul-Konya bridge, right? You idiot!
What traffic in the air? Null. You are flowing.
What traffic? The traffic happens on landing and taking off.
I have to ask this, Nurullah, it is not a good sign.
It shouldn't be three and a half hours.
[beeps]
Hostess? Hostess? Do you believe?
Come on girl. Come on. I pressed it.
You you. You come.
Where did this come from?
Here you go, sir.
Did I call you bro?
No, my friend is interested in the service. Let me help you, please.
I pressed the button here,
We came face to face with the lady from there, she is coming, you came from behind.
You're going to make a haircut. Is this your district? You just delivered sandwiches.
-What are you doing here? -I did not understand but...
Anyway... Look, we just checked our watch, we were stunned.
This plane has been in the air for three and a half hours, and it doesn't seem like it will land any further.
Yes sir, we only have three hours of flight, so we don't look like we're about to land.
Hey bro, how can there be three more hours of flight?
-How many hours is Istanbul-Konya? -Istanbul-Konya...
So I'm not entirely sure, but...
-Probably about... -Oho! We have business with you!
What kind of host are you? The host will be friendly to the customer you call.
You became a post, not a host.
It's a place I fly, not a track, that's why.
What's wrong with me bro? Anyway... We've been in the air for three and a half hours.
You put in three, it's half past six.
Fall one and a half, five hours. Tell me the difference between these five hours bro.
Gentleman, the distance between Istanbul and Konya is one and a half hours. But this is not the Istanbul-Konya flight.
-What plane is this? -Kenyan sir.
-Is it Kenya? -Kenya.
Isn't that a Konya plane?
How is Konya? This is the Kenyan plane, sir. You must be kidding. [Laughs]
A minute! Is this plane going to Kenya right now?
-Yes, this plane is going to Kenya. -What does this Nurullah say?
We boarded as Konya. This plane has to go to Konya.
-Sir, this is Istanbul-Kenya. -You are kidding.
-No dear, why should I joke? Tell me it's a joke, son.
This is not a Kenyan plane!
-You tell me this is a joke! - Sir, will you leave?
-Can you quit? -Are you kidding me?
-I'll talk to the pilot! I'll talk to the pilot! -[groans]
- That pilot will tell me, he will! -Stop, sir!
I will go to Konya! To Konya! Not to Kenya, to Konya!
Leave us to Konya, just go to Kenya!
I will go to Konya! To Konya!
-Get out, get out, I'll knock you out! -What's going on?
This man had to pass out! Why didn't he faint?
-[grumbles] -Is it not working?
[traditional African music]
[elephant voices are heard]
Look at this situation! We came to Kenya as Konya.
Does one letter change that much?
Does the environment change that much when you put "E" instead of "O"?
Brother, if you look less positive. Look, we came to Kenya, not Konya.
We are on vacation. Let's savor it.
Why should I think positive, son? I ate 7,000 volts at 30,000 feet.
I still can't feel the left cheek of my ass right now! Why should I be positive?
[camera click you]
Pull pull, pull like this! Take it like this!
-What's going on, Recep? -Hey, what's going on?
Look, if I miss that bean festival in Konya,
then I will ask you, then you will see what happens.
Welcome! Welcome sir, welcome!
You are all welcome. Welcome to our beautiful Kenya.
It's me, your tour guide Ersin.
How was our journey? Are we tired?
-No, brother, were you with us too? -I do not understand?
Were you with us too? "Are we tired? Have we?" Are we a group together?
No, I'm just talking about.
The plane shook a little, so sorry you're nervous.
I understand. Let me take you to your tents, rest.
Tent? Where does the tent come from, Nurullah?
No tents! It was a four-star accommodation?
-We were not called that, Ersin Bey. -But sir, that's our concept.
Look at this, look at me.
How can we stay with this in the tent?
Will it work in the same tent as this? What if tonight he snores, farts,
truck rolls over, does something.
-Are you very different, Recep? -Shut up!
Don't worry, our facility is already four star rated.
Trust me, you will love it. Here please.
What happened to us because of you? Walk, walk!
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Well, how did you find it, sir?
What can I say, it's more beautiful than my house.
I told you. Have a good rest, tomorrow will be a tiring day.
-I'll see you at 6am for breakfast. -Is there breakfast at 6, bro?
What did our ancestors say? "An early riser gets an early start."
Have a nice day!
My eye is stinging from somewhere, but Nurullah... Hold on, for the best.
Which bed?
-Brother, let it be. -No?
I will sleep in it, you will sleep here. You will be close to the door.
You will face the danger first.
When the animal mayvan comes, it will attack you first. LAT!
[sighs and puffs]
Nurullah.
[horuldar]
He brought us to the middle of Africa,
snoring like glass, you bastard dog!
It's so bad that I'm awkward about my place. [sighs]
It seems like everyone is watching me, I see eyes everywhere.
What is it?
my mother! It moves too. Ayy, that's a bug!
Aha! God damn it! He went and stuck to the bottom of it.
Oops! He is very afraid of this insect.
What are we going to do, an insect as much as a calf's eye.
[gags]
I swear I'm going to vomit now!
Alas, let me see...
[continues to snore]
Look where the animal is standing, damn it!
When we say let's kill the insect, we will castrate Nurullah.
But there is nothing to do, Nurullah, I have to hit the insect.
Come on, bismillah. [spits]
[sighs]
my mother! It moves, goes, goes! It came to his face, God dammit!
I swear I'm going to vomit!
[gags]
He had a hideous face, made even more disgusting by the bug. God damn it!
Let's see... One, two, three.
Oh!
my mother! It got in your mouth! Cough Nurullah! Nurullah, cough!
Cough, Nurullah! The man is dying! A man is dying in Kenya!
[Rep shouts]
Take it out Nurullah! Nurullah take it out!
[cries continue]
-The man is dying! The man is dying in Kenya! -Output!
-Is it out? Are you sure? -Output!
-Is it out? -It's out!
Ah! Jamboo-Jamboo! Jamboo-Jamboo! [kahkaha atar]
No no, no cambo mambo, no cambo. Bitch, bro.
my bro. Not Cambo, bro.
Ah! Bro-jamboo. [laughs]
Go away! Go go! I swear I'll hit the slipper in your mouth from here!
[laughs]
[elephant voices]
Good morning to you too, brother.
Both your brother and you... I'll fly you out of here with my head, huh!
-I think you got up backwards today. -No, I got up from my beautiful side!
I'm super happy!
I was going to go to Konya to eat dried beans, I eat this in Kenya. Very nice.
It was perfect!
Outside in the 55 degree heat of the savannah, all the wild animals staring at me,
I woke up perfectly this morning!
Do I want it like this, Recep? There was a mistake.
Shut up! Shut up! Don't be upset with the man!
-Did you call your nephew? -I called bro, I talked.
What is he saying? When is the return flight?
Unfortunately, three days later, there are no planes.
-I made a backup. -God damn you!
God bless you and your nephew!
You know, the midwife who gave birth to you, I'm screwed!
Two organisms like you were supposed to perish,
How did you come into the world?
-Why are you insulting? -Shut up! Speech!
Everyone who sees me since morning bursts into laughter.
They think you and me are lovers because of yesterday's incident.
Could such a thing happen? You disgraced us.
[they chat]
Jamboo-jamboo! [laughter]
All because of this bastard.
I got you boy, I'll catch you in the savannah...
I'll cut your head off!
Jamboo! [laughter]
Do you understand why I'm angry now?
Oh brother, you're angry, you're irritable, but your appetite is good.
It's not like our breakfasts, be careful! By Allah, you will feel nauseous.
Hey! You know a lot!
You lived in Africa for seven years as an expat,
You know very well African culture! You are so dominating! Look at what you eat.
God's idiot! They did it very well, it's like a gullac. will you buy it?
-Oh brother, is it edible? -I swear it's edible, it's perfect.
-I'm nauseous. -By God, eat it.
Well done! Are we serving sweets to each other?
Good morning sir. I hope we weren't too tired last night, huh?
Because we're going to watch the Great Migration soon. [chuckles]
Look, here's the thing I told you about.
-What's your name bro? -Ersin.
Ersin, you will take my beating. Look, be smart. What are you implying to us?
No, astaghfurullah sir. Cambo cambo... [laughs]
What boy cambo cambo? What are you trying to say son?
The watchman saw it for us, when the event came to life in my eyes... Ay got upset. [Laughs]
What did he see brother watchman? What are you trying to say?
You mean chorolo? What are you talking about?
Any client can come to us. It's your personal preference after all, isn't it?
Oh, of course it's my choice.
And I will give you a choice, which will be your choice.
Should I say A or B, should I say C or should I say D? What can i say?
-Sorry? I say choose one.
Should I say A or B, should I say C or should I say D? Which one?
-Get it. -Good choice.
[inler]
If you had chosen B, C, there was no slap there, you chose A. This is your choice.
Brother, I swear, I will cut you in the savannah, Tarkan will perform the funeral prayer, do you understand?
-Get out of here! -Go go!
-Go go! Why are you provoking us? -Don't be idle either! Don't be empty!
All this happened to us because of you.
I swear I'll stab you! I swear my knives.
I hang it from your feet to the ceiling, I inflate it with a hose and I skin it.
No matter what we do, we can't help you, Recep!
We are ready to go too, huh, our safari is starting!
God... Are these left in our car?
It would have been better if we had gone before they arrived.
Captain, you start the car a little bit, maybe we can get away. Here you go.
Hello! Wait, where are you going? Ho!
Oh!
Oh! Oh!
Oh! [lip smacking]
Be heavy, slow down! No, that's right, brother, where are you trying to go as if you were running away?
Sir, we're a little late, so many people can't wait for you, in that sense...
No!
So many people will wait for me bro! It will wait!
Since you broke my order,
Since I'm in a place I don't want right now,
since I'm in Kenya by force,
-Then you will wait for me. -Yup.
What if I were in Istanbul, I would have my breakfast at 10 o'clock,
around 11 o'clock my bowel movement begins,
Excuse me at 12, I'll take a good shit. Here you have breakfast at 6,
my bowel movement has not started yet, my poop has not come.
I don't want to start the day like this! That's why you wait bro.
-Of course. -Open the door.
-You were so needed... -I don't understand?
Well done, I say you came, we are not deprived of you. [chuckles]
Brother! Know your guide, guide like a man, okay?
Don't bother me. Let me see you.
Selamun aleykum. Have a nice tour
I'll tell my master, I hope we see lots of animals.
WL.
[traditional African music]
This is the land where humanity was born, dear friends.
The habitat you see around us,
It is home to 500 kinds of animals.
-Take a look, please. - I remembered how I met the friend.
-Do you recognize? -Look, watch well.
-Guide, will you look? -Here you go.
You mean 500 kinds of animals, count!
[chuckles] I'll count if I have to, so what?
- Say it right now, it's necessary. I asked, say. -I'll count.
Rhino, elephant, gorilla, lion... Did I count the rhino?
What happened man? You know, there were 500 kinds of animals here?
What happened, why can't you count 496 of them? Stupid! [Laughs]
Do you remember me?
Sir, it's you again, all kinds of jokes, right?
Anyway, sir, in a moment everyone in this car is what we call the Great Migration ,
He will witness the Great Migration.
An announcement will come over the radio, and we will go to watch.
-Sir, what is the Great Migration? -There is only one immigration that I know,
the Turkish tribes who migrated from Central Asia to Anatolia.
[chuckles] What does that have to do with it, sir?
Are you taking it lightly? If it wasn't for immigration
you were selling water on the Great Wall right now, idiot!
Sir, this migration is an influx of herds to more wetlands.
Oh okay! Every morning in Istanbul
there is a migration to work in droves.
Sir, this is an animal migration.
Partly the struggle for survival, partly brutality! The journey of hope!
Ok, we're talking about the same thing.
People are already struggling to survive every morning.
People are biting each other's arms and legs for an empty seat.
What are you saying? Already inside the animal-filled public transport.
There is a pervert, there is a molester, there is a rapist, sir. He has a fort.
I mean, it was the last one who even fingered himself and made him vomit.
Do not interfere with the guide and let him tell! Will we listen to you dear?
Is it hard, sister? My tontik, are you having a hard time?
What's hard?
-I say menopause, is it hard? -Ill mannered!
Sir, please let's be calm. Let's be calm.
Dear guests, take a look at this vast plain.
Everything, everything started here.
What happened, Recep?
I have a very bad pain in my stomach, Nurullah! I'm terrible!
I said don't eat those dishes, brother!
How do you know it's about food?
-[his stomach growls] -Are you okay?
I swear, guide, I'm not good at all, my poop is very bad. I have to jump.
-No, you can't get out of the car! -Should I shit in the car?
No sir, don't! Don't jump...
It's dangerous, we're in the field! It's full of wild animals, it's dangerous!
By Allah, it is more dangerous for me to stay in the car, let me tell you so.
I'm going to have such an explosion,
It will jump on everyone. I am in such a situation.
-Flow will flow, output will come out. -[his stomach growls]
I didn't know what to do. At least don't go away, go somewhere soon.
Let's get down! Go far!
Are you talking to gene? I swear I'm going to shit at your feet now huh!
I'll let go, I swear!
-Ill mannered! -Damn woman!
[his stomach growls] Mom! I'm going to that bush.
Don't go anywhere, I'll fuck that bush and come.
[woman grunts]
Hay Allah... [inler]
[distance elephant sounds]
[sighs and puffs]
[inler]
[distance elephant sounds]
-Does it take too long for your friend to work? -Takes. He likes to hang out long.
[walkie-talkie öter]
[speech voice from walkie-talkie]
-God! Migration has begun! -What did you say? Did you say emigration?
- Migration has begun! -Act immediately!
I've been waiting for this moment for a year.
I can't miss this migration for a shitty reason!
My husband is the most famous lawyer in Istanbul.
I will destroy your company! I'll take it from your feet to your panties!
We are disgraceful with our money! Refund our money! We are going to emigrate immediately!
Or where are we going? We can't go anywhere without the man coming.
my god! I was confused as to what to do. Migration has begun!
But if everyone says let's go, there is nothing you can do. You!
Get off at least and stay with your friend, but don't move.
Get into the bush, stand like this.
Let's watch the migration, we'll come back and get you. Okay?
I will not leave my friend anyway. I'm getting out of the car!
-Of! Get in quick! -Don't move, don't move.
We'll be right back, don't move.
Come on, hurry! Go! Go! Go!
-Recep! -Don't come, don't come!
I'm pooping!
OK, I'm waiting here.
Friend, there is no comfort even when taking a shit.
[Receiving]
-How have you been, Recep? -I'm fine, why did you come?
The vehicle had to go urgently,
I got out of the car so as not to leave you alone, I came, my brother.
-Did you get out of the car? -Yes brother.
-Where is the car? -Brother, the vehicles are gone.
The announcement came, the Great Migration has begun.
Man, why are you letting the car go?
Why are you letting the car go before we get in the car?
Brother women made a big deal!
Damn, I'm going to pass it on, I'm going to bring you the big event!
Are you stupid son? Are you retarded? Is your head not working?
Is it okay to get out of the car just because two or three wives made a scene?
This is Africa! Predators everywhere!
How do you get out of the car?
Brother, calm down. They're going to pick us up from here, don't go anywhere,
They said wait in the bushes. -You idiot!
I just fucked up here! Here's the smell of hot shit!
In Africa, the smell of hot shit spreads fast. It will spread all over now.
It was all jackal, jackal, cheetah, leopard, lion coming here!
-Should we wait here? -What are we going to do, brother?
Call that camp quick! Quickly call the camp, reach the camp, quick!
-Brother does not draw a line. -What the hell is pulling on you anyway?
-What attracts you? Brother, let's call with your phone.
No, I did not take my phone.
I left it at camp. I left it in the camp because it is closed abroad, data roaming is in progress.
I didn't get it, I don't have a phone with me.
-What are we going to do, brother? -[sighs] We have only one way, Nurullah.
We will find the camp by following the tire tracks left by the cars, there is no other way.
Of course, let's check the lions, for example, they went to the gazelle there.
There's a surplus of lions on that side, we'll go this way.
Brother, what if the lions come there too?
Here's what we're going to do, stand side by side, look at the lion and run in different directions.
The lion will be stunned, one of us will follow, the other will be saved.
If my brother comes to the place where I go, lion...
Hopefully! I hope they choose you.
If they come to you, run as far as you can.
Where you can't run, kneel, lie on your side, fold your hands, open your neck,
Say "Ashhadu en la ilahe illallah" and say salawat.
They're already doing the rest after that.
You die in three or four hours, they will eat you in four days.
-Brother, open your mouth for goodness! -Walk, go!
It's like my midwife got out of the car! Walk! Go away!
[shouts]
You will always follow the driveway...
Why is that? Because what you call this driveway is going to go somewhere.
This is the car, is it gone?
[ofs]
-Nurullah? -What happened, Recep?
-Dead end. -Is it a dead end street?
-We're fucked right now. -What?
-The driveway is over. -Are we in the wrong direction, Recep?
No. We couldn't have come in the wrong direction.
All my calculations showed that the camp was here.
So it definitely has to be there. We've come this far.
Ah, the driveway. It ends here.
No! Cars came from the air, landed here, started here!
We're in the wrong direction, Recep!
Can you excuse me? Will you let me run this crisis? Move aside!
Here, Recep.
[coke]
-What are you doing, Recep? -I'm smelling the air.
If you were smelling the air, knew where the camp was, you would have done it all over again!
Go away, go away! Wherever you go yourself!
You've got all the way to hell, get out!
Where will I go, Recep?
The lions, who will smell your sweaty ass soon, will come here.
You make me talk, they will eat us because of you.
-Your ass stinks! -Sorry.
Just let me!
I've spent my life finding direction in open field and land.
I studied until primary school 3, I was a scout for three years.
-My name was Kurt Recep, the cub, let me! -Okay okay.
Yes, based on all my experience, I'm telling you right now Nurullah,
If the direction we came from is cut off here, there are two options left.
We will either go left or right.
-I think we should go right. -Let's go, Recep.
It's always good to have common sense. Let's go right.
[roars]
[meerkats shout]
[lion roars]
Nurullah, let me tell you clearly and unequivocally that
We got lost clearly and precisely.
-Are we lost? -Hey, I swear we're lost.
I have no idea where the camp is.
So what are we going to do, Recep?
Surely we will do something, God!
We're not in the mood to sit here and cry like a girl!
I'm the alpha male, it's my job to survive!
When I was a kid they used to drop me off in the city seven or eight kilometers away,
From there I would find the village at night, sniffing, in the dark. Barefoot.
What are you talking about?
Now, the sun will set.
We need to find a formula to spend the night in the open.
Will we stay outside?
Yoo, I'll stay here, I got you a hostel. You idiot!
We are in the forest, we will stay outside!
But not in open space. We have to turn our backs towards the forest.
Therefore, we will go to places where the trees are denser.
Our back will be closed, our front will be open. Come on, let's walk like this.
OK, very nice.
It's perfect now, Nurullah.
No one can touch us here. The woods behind us
Our fire is burning in front of us. Our field of vision is free,
Our angle is clear, we dominate the enemy.
We can sleep soundly here now. -I hope, Recep.
I hope he doesn't have a salary. Predator does not come to the place where the fire burns.
The animal is afraid when it sees the fire. For example, did you see a fire, would you go?
-I won't go, Recep, this is an animal. -You are an animal too, Nurullah.
I mean, you're a kind of animal, too, so I can't say that you're human.
Are you closer to a human or an animal? Take a look at yourself, make a self-criticism.
Evaluate yourself. Which type are you closer to?
I think the animal. Hey, don't get me wrong, I'm an animal too.
I'm more domestic, I'm a cat person when I raise my curtains.
I'm separating myself. Anyway.
I don't go to the fire, you don't go to the fire,
The predator does not go either.
Don't exaggerate by saying it's a predator, don't make it that big.
What is a predator? After all, cat family, cat ya, kitty kitty.
kitty kitty! No, sir, the lion attacked,
no sir leopard chased, no sir cheetah clawed.
What is this? No such thing! Lion maslan, never climb.
The cat is, after all, kitty, meow. Did you say good bye?
-Brother! -What?
-Wow, your father! -[roars]
What are we going to do, Recep?
First of all we will be calm, first of all we will be calm!
The predator has arrived now! Is there any food in your bag?
-Son, nothing. good boy. Calm down. -There is!
-What? What? -Sausage!
Is it sausage? What is the sausage doing in your bag?
It's very good, the sausage is very good. Look, my son lion, look, look.
That's all, that's the content of all animals. This is the sausage, come.
Come on, kitty kitty. Come on, come on.
Nurullah snatches our hand, let me give it with this. Get!
Here you go, horse meat, donkey meat. Take it son!
-[homurdanır] -Hop!
How he shakes it! Look what a mighty beast!
-Take it, take it son, take it! -[roars]
Look how he claws!
-[Recep moans] -[Lion grunts]
Get it, get it! Nurullah, look, he will go now!
Hop! Here you go! Sausage, sausage. Here you go, run!
Run there! Go back! Go to the sausage!
I threw sausage, go away! It doesn't go to the sausage.
You need to give me a deterrent immediately. Look for it in your bag. What?
No no!
God damn you! There is sausage, is there no deterrent?
Something comes to my mind, we have a salvation, Nurullah. Come.
We're going slow, arm behind my back. Approach, approach, approach ...
[yellenir]
How many how many! My mother, my mother, run! Did he get animal gas?
Did the animal get the gas? Aha is coming!
[winters]
[sighs]
Safe, secure, safe...
♪ If I hadn't landed, I wouldn't have gone to shit out of that jeep ♪
♪ Come on, I'm retarded but why did you come after me lad ♪
♪ Nurullah! Mal Nurullah, mal Nurullah ♪
♪ We're two lovers, confused ♪
♪ We looked right, we looked left ♪
♪ How did it happen, we were surprised too ♪
♪ We were going to Konya, we stayed in Kenya ♪
-Good luck, daddy. -God bless you.
Come on, take the caftans out of that bag and lay them out, let's sleep.
Good morning, good morning Nurullah.
-[remote animal sounds] -Ah!
[live traditional African music]
[choruses]
-Nurullah? -Ha...
- Take that arm off. -Ha?
- Pull that arm, that arm. -I'm in front of you, Recep.
are you ahead of me
Uh...
You are truly in front of me, Nurullah. Then who is behind me Nurullah?
[shouts] My mother! get up!
-[gorilla grunts] -[shouts]
-Damn! -This one was missing!
[shouts] Don't worry, calm down! We will show him our strength!
Don't show weakness! What's up, what's up!
[shouts] If you're crazy, we're crazy too!
[screams and whistles]
[continues shouting]
Do you see these? Three gorillas just stand in the middle of the forest.
It's really incredible. I guess it must be some kind of mating ritual, don't you think?
-[groans] -[Recep shouts]
[groans and shouts]
Damn, knock it out!
-Wow! -Them
We need to knock him out and take him to the lab.
Absolutely I agree.
Stun it! I'm out of power!
Blow out the first one, please.
Why are you hitting me, idiot! You will hit this!
Wrong, Recep!
[gorilla grunts]
What happened to it?
Oh! It was a great shot!
What happened to this animal, son? Did this animal have a heart attack?
Oh?
Nurullah, they hit him with a needle.
There must be people here. They shot it with an arrow, with a poison arrow.
Next, knock out the second one.
-[gunfire] -[groans]
my mother! God! Nurullah! [groans]
I was shot in the ass! my mother! They shot me too, Nurullah!
God! They shot me in the ass, it comes to my leg. Look, the leg is wasted!
Uh! Look at this! Falling, falling!
My leg is free! Look how my leg is bouncing!
Nurullah! Nurullah! I saw it in a documentary,
Take out the needle, suck my ass, take the poison!
-Take the poison Nurullah! -Your ass?
Hey, my ass! Suck my ass!
-I can't suck, Recep! -Suck my ass, suck!
-I can't suck, Recep! -Suck my ass Nurullah!
Suck my ass before the poison spreads!
-[silah session] -God!
-What happened? -I've been shot, Recep.
Forgive me...
Did you get shot too? Damn everybody got shot, god damn it!
I'm left all alone here! my mother! Well, my mother...
[groans] It's starting to affect me too...
I was paralyzed on my left side. [groans]
I still have one eye playing...
It still hasn't worked on me... And my eye...
[inler]
-Hey! -Really...
-High five. -Oh my God!
-That's it! -That was incredible.
[inler]
Let's get them and take them to the lab.
-Let's go. -Lets go.
[nonsense]
-I swear I'm just sobering up huh. -Where are we, Recep?
I don't know him either, Nurullah.
They brought this with us. I guess we are in a place like a laboratory.
[gorilla grunts]
-Did you pee under it? -I pissed, Recep.
Look, you're the big guy. Does it suit you?
-I can't feel my feet. -Aha, they came. Teacher?
Sir, can you see? You're doing it wrong, a lot.
Get us out of here. Why are we being treated like gorillas, are we gorillas?
We are human! Human human!
Human! Man, man. Man, man like man.
Man, man like man.
The most interesting species I've ever seen. Especially the two on the right are very unusual.
Are we one with it?
Homo sapiens sapiens.
A wise man, a wise man, a wise man.
A wise man
I think let's start the tests now.
Get us out of here, quick.
-Me and my friend, please. -Test one, please start.
What happened? He said start, start start.
What is this complicated thing? How do we do this?
Take the purple, give the orange.
Like.
[joy sound]
You don't show a way! How did the animal end?
Test two, please start.
What are we going to do here, sir? What is this teacher?
Aha, I have the numbers gone. I don't remember where it is.
It's not going to happen!
[sighs]
[ring tone]
God damn it! It was something like that, sir.
Oh my god, that one is a complete idiot!
[beeping sound]
[groan of joy]
-Is it finished again? - Pretty smart.
-Yeah, he's really smart. -That's not all!
It came out very easily.
It is torpedoed as an animal. What's wrong with this?
[groan of joy]
-I'm going to hit you on the head, huh! -Test number three, start please.
What is this, teacher? What are we going to do about it?
[sighs] I'm out of hand! My hand!
[sighs and puffs]
Look. Look, it detected sugar, my teacher, it detected sugar.
[gorilla grunts]
Oh my God!
That's it. You're dealing with a stick.
Stupid, stupid, smart.
[spits]
[Recept lip smacking]
Look what happened to us! Look what's happened to us.
Aha.
Nurullah.
-Yes bro. I thought of a terrific escape plan.
-Are we going to dig a tunnel, brother? -Hee, we're going to dig a tunnel. Is the spoon with you?
Like El Chapo... Idiot! What a tunnel!
We will get out of here with a collective effort.
-The ones on the wall are the keys to the cages? -Yes brother.
-Are you sure? -Yup.
-There's the doormat over there. -Yes brother.
-Let him come to you. -Brother, is it the time to joke?
[chuckles]
All right. Can you reach him?
-I'll try bro. -Try it.
Try it, try it.
Is it taken?
-Did you lie down? -He's reaching out, brother.
-Are you getting? Slow down, be quiet. -I got it bro.
Do not make noise.
-[Recep] Did you get it? -I bought.
Watch.
OK. We have completed the first phase.
Now the second stage, we will work with the gorilla.
-[gorilla grunts] -[Recep whispers and lip smacking]
Look here. Come on, be quiet. Take the stick.
Take the stick, take the stick. Take the stick. Now turn the stick. Turn the stick.
Look there, look there. There is the key, the key.
It's their lock. It's the lock, the lock.
They locked you in there, that's his lock. If you get the key...
We will run away, we will go together. Key.
What was the key ? The key is hanging on the wall! Look there! Pass the stick.
Bring the stick, put it on it, get it.
It's kakdir.
Don't worry! Bring the stick. Take the key, reach for the key.
God damn you! You knew how to hit the damn lights.
You knew how to choose a picture, Eşşoğlueşşek. Learn to use tools, to use tools.
You idiot, you just can't get out.
You splattered, you splattered the whole escape.
No, it's not possible. He doesn't understand this is a fucking idiot.
[sighs]
-I guess he's doing it. -[groans]
[whispers] He does! Come on son! Come on son!
Pass the stick! Well done!
Well done! Come on son, get it out of there.
Al! Al!
Take it son! Take it son! Take it son! Get! Well done son!
Well done to you, well done. Well done to you, give me the key.
Give me the key. Give.
You are Adam. I swear you are a man, well done for you, you are a man!
We took it, I swear we survived. Let's open that lock before that idiot wakes up.
[sighs]
What are you doing? Give me the keys!
-Go away! -Give me the keys! Give...
I swear he hit the man's cerebellum, knocked him out! Well done son, bravo.
[gorilla grunts]
Go this way, go that way.
-Come, come quick! Come on! Come man! -[groans]
Are you going there? Wow...
-So it's time to part, huh, Charlie? -How do you know his name, Recep?
- Usually their name is Charlie. -Charli?
Hey, Charlie. Come on, Charlie, go on your way.
Maybe you have two babies waiting for you too.
Maybe they're watching your way.
Don't make them need a dry branch or a dry eucalyptus. Run, come on go.
Maybe your aunt is waiting for you too.
He made a nice sautéed banana for you in case you're coming tonight.
You go, wash your feet, eat your food. Here you go.
You are poor too, brother. We are poor too. We'll understand it.
Come on, go on your way, goodbye to you. Get on your way.
How is he moving, dummy! We are talking to you emotionally here.
What kind of move is that? If it moves, we have it too.
-Here's your move! Stupid. -[groans]
I didn't say you can't be a gorilla, I said you can't be a man! Get out!
Coward, get out! Go go! Stupid gorilla, go!
From here.
-I'm very thirsty, Nurullah. -I'm thirsty too, Recep!
Should we drink each other's urine?
-Is it drinkable? -He's been drinking, son.
It replaces water, I watched it in the documentary.
By urinating, the man survived. Maybe it will benefit us too.
Oh!
Nurullah, do you see what I see?
-[Nurullah] I see it, Recep! -Is it a village?
-Yup! There is a village there, Recep. -Is it our village, Nurullah?
-We survived! Nurullah we are saved! -We're saved, Recep!
Mom, we survived! Thank God we saved my book Nurullah!
There is water, look, Recep, I am very thirsty!
I'm thirsty too, let's drink water first.
Selamunaleykum sisters, let's have a drink of water.
[women scream]
What did we say, did we say something? Never mind. Come, come brother, come.
Come brother come, come, come.
[man shouts]
[sighs]
[groans] Here you go, take it... Take it, let it touch the dead.
Recep! Someone is coming.
[sighs]
Selamun aleykum brother.
What if we got lost but we have to find it, city by city.
We need to talk, phone, city, plane.
We will go, we will go to our hometown.
He doesn't understand this.
If we had come to one normal, Turkish village
They gave us the buttermilk and buttermilk. What is this?
I'm going to die for Anatolia! Look at these!
They're all different from each other.
Ya brother, we are with this, tourist tourist, photo photo, tourist.
Safari, photo, tourist. You understand?
We got out of the car, I was going to shit, I got out of the car,
gone, when the car left, we stayed in the middle.
[shouts angrily]
[they shout together]
What's going on!
[screams]
my mother! Nurullah! They're going to cut us crunchy!
God help! They will kill us, Recep!
Nor will they kill Nurullah, nor will they kill!
Look at that move. damn! The Turkish government will not leave this to you.
You're making a mistake, let us go, look, we are good people, son, let me love your eyes.
Shut up Recep hush! You're pissing him off even more!
It is not clear what it does!
-Look at these situations! -[shrill screams]
Without God, without books, these are Recep!
Look, they're worshiping this.
Oh! Nurullah!
That man looks like me!
-Yes, he looks like you, Recep! -I wonder if this is someone important?
-May be important since it's on the top. -I thought of a plan, Nurullah.
I'll take a chance.
He held it, he did not hold it hakuna matata.
What does Hakuna matata mean, Recep?
Hakuna matata, meaning Nurullah!
[screams]
That's enough!
Look over there! Look, look, look over there. what's in there?
Hey, look at me now. Look at me, look at him.
Behind.
See, it's the same me. It's mine.
Street?
-Ha? What does Sokaçu mean? -I think his name is Recep.
Hey, if his name is Sokaçu, look.
I'll do better if you untie my hand, untie my hand.
Untie my hand. Sokaçu Sokaçu. Untie my hand.
-[speaks native language] -He topyanabu. Open Open open.
Now look. Ah! Did you see?
Ah! [nonsense]
Do you see? It's me, Sokaçu!
-Street? -[curious murmurs]
[Recep] Sokaçu, I am Sokaçu.
I am Sokaçu, I am Sokaçu.
-[curious murmurs] -Street, me, same me.
Alley!
They believed, Recep, we are saved!
I hope Nurullah. No, get up. Estagfurullah, get up.
Lie! This is not Street!
[excited hum]
How is it not? I'm Sokaçu, I proved it!
-[nonsense] Look at the same job, I'm Sokaçu. -No! No!
-According to legend, Sokaçu has an animal! -[curious hum]
OK, I have a pet too. Ah, you animal.
Chief, this is my special animal. humanoid body, animal body
It's a creature, it's my animal.
-It's a shame, Recep! -Shut up!
Any shame left? We will die here. You're an animal!
It's a trust relationship like that, but I mean... I've proven I'm Sokaçu, look.
You're lying!
Street wonders! If you Sokaçu, prove it.
All right, I'll prove it. I have proof to you, what is it?
Tomorrow, until the sun goes down!
Otherwise, you will die! [screams]
-[excited hum] -What's going on? damn!
Take my animal too, my animal!
[excited hum]
damn! Slow down, slow! It's like you're treating an animal.
Look at this situation, Nurullah. They threw us into the hardware and garbage dump here.
Anyway, thank God we're alive. I swear they were going to cut us!
If you don't find a miracle by tomorrow, they'll cut it anyway.
Shut up! Shut up!
Don't be upset with the man! Get something to eat so let's eat, quick.
-There is no bag, Recep. -Where is your bag?
-E stayed where they knocked out. -Why don't you own it?
-How do I take care of myself when I'm unconscious? -My God!
Thank God I have a mobile phone and a charger with me.
Well, plug it in and charge it. Is there electricity here, idiot?
There is no network anyway, and your phone is turned off. Well done taking them.
Do you remember? When we were in middle school, we were generating electricity from potatoes.
Son, I didn't go to middle school. I'm a 3rd primary school dropout.
I learned to read and write, I left education. Enough.
I said enough there. The only thing I know about potatoes is the potato press.
I was working with the counterfeiter,
forgery of documents, that's all. I don't know any other.
Go look over there.
A place like Ardiye. There are definitely chickpeas, chickpeas, legumes, something.
-We can even gnaw dried lentils, look. -Let me see, Recep.
Come on, bismillah. [sighs]
-Rep, come on. -What happened?
-I found food, food! -Don't make a sound!
-Come! -Don't make a sound, don't shout.
[pigeons crow]
-What is it, son? -Look.
-What are these? -Did we turn two of them into one in the fire...
Son, are you an idiot? Are these edible?
This is the messenger pigeon, my son.
Get one of these now and come immediately.
Did you understand? Come on in.
Come. Now, this bird will save our life, Nurullah.
And you say let's cut it and eat it, will it be cut?
We will tie the note to its foot, we will release it.
Thanks to this, they will find our place.
Hopefully, Rex.
They will find it, how are we going to write a note about it?
If only we had a pen and paper like this.
Paper pen? I have it, Recep.
Wow, live a thousand lives with your mind! Let's take it out.
-Give me the bird. -Keep.
Okay girl calm down, okay, nothing, girl.
Oh, thank you, don't be afraid, my bird.
Write. I got lost with coffee maker Nurullah and my friend Recep İvedik.
-We are lost. -Stop.
We're in Africa, stop. around Kenya.
- Around Kenya. -Find us, stop.
-Stop. -Help.
-Help. -OK.
Roll it up, fold it up nicely. Roll it.
Now tie it well, let me see, tie it up.
-Is it OK? - It's okay, brother.
OK...
This bird will go, convey our message and they will find us, Nurullah.
-Brother, how will he find the address? -Hee, I swear you said it well.
They find their way through scent. We need the smell of those places.
What are we going to do bro?
We need to show something that belongs to Güngören, Nurullah.
-I have an idea. -What?
-What hangs the most in our neighborhood? -I do not know.
What is your lady hanging outside?
-He is chasing so that the birds don't get on him. -Washing.
He hangs laundry, but hangs your underwear.
Everywhere is your underwear, in the neighborhood!
There's frost on it too, did we give it a sniff,
I swear he finds your underwear like a fly that clings to shit.
-Take off your underwear quickly. -Does the frost come out?
-Go take off your underwear! -Impossible!
It's a matter of life and death. Go take off your underwear over there!
Bring your underwear. I'm not too keen on your filthy pants!
Stickers around. God forbid, what kind of body is this?
Late, late, late, quick. Give me your underwear.
Give me your underwear... God damn you, look at that underwear! Look at that donut!
Smell it girl, smell it girl, smell it.
That's where you'll find the center of it.
You will go to Güngören, you will give our message. smell it.
Kokla, kokla, kokla.
Take your panties, take them!
Come on, beautifully set us free, deliver our message.
I'm throwing you, taking shelter in the Creator, come on, bismillah!
Bravo, so the animal died because of your shitty underpants.
The animal's lungs were cauterized, the animal could not bear the smell.
Is there anyone?
Uh? Someone came.
Selamun aleykum.
Alaik-Salam, brother.
No, you gave it until tomorrow. Why did you come?
Brother, I brought you food. Eat, eat.
Thanks.
One can also bring a drink.
Our mouths and tongues stuck together. Take this, Nurullah.
Thank God, we were hungry.
I believe you, you are Sokaçu.
-But prove it to my father, do a miracle. -What do you mean your father?
The chief is my father.
-Are you the chief's son? -Yup.
If you're the chief's son, talk to your father and let us go.
We are good people.
Let you go, but show a miracle.
Come on talk, let us go! Come on, I ate your life.
I swear I'm a victim of the necklace, come on.
Come on attack us. Talk to your father.
-Can I tell you something? -Let me check.
You eat, just eat. Let's.
God damn you!
He ate... Don't we know? Stupid!
Rich baby! That's the rich baby. There is money, there is everything, there is no head.
Recep! What are you doing? Why are you making noise, brother?
-What do you say jackass? Stupid. -What is this, brother?
To charge that useless cell phone in your pocket,
I made a charger.
I also made an electric coil on the back.
There is mechanics, there is mathematics here.
Give me the phone.
Sit here, sit down quickly. Quick!
Wait for news from me, don't press anywhere! Don't mess with it, got it? It's a mechanical tool.
Mm.
OK, turn it over now.
Turn it, turn the coil. Damn son, turn it stronger!
-I can translate that much! -Turn it over, quick.
Didn't move, let go, let go. Leave!
-Take this, hold the phone. -[they]
Let's do that too. Let's do the translation.
Let us invent it, let us do the translation.
-Are you going to kill me? -Speech!
Speech!
-I can't, bro. -Cut, cut!
-Look at me. -Sir, my brother.
- Let me know as soon as the electricity comes. -Okay, brother.
-I will adjust the voltage accordingly. -OK.
-Did you understand? -Understood.
-Don't make me pedal for no reason. -OK.
Let's see, bismillah.
Come on, strength to your waist, Recep. I'm starting Nurullah.
-Start, brother. -Here you go.
[Nurullah] Translate, translate bro! Translate translate!
Did he come? Did the electricity come?
He didn't come!
How is it not coming?
-Go on, Recep, go on! -No electricity, son?
Came now! Now bro started charging!
-I'm increasing the voltage, I'm Nurullah! -Go on, brother!
-I did the tempo, I swear my spleen is out! -Slightly faster! Tempo!
-Tempo, Recep! -Is the phone turned on?
It will open bro, it will open! Keep going, keep going!
What a phone that won't turn on, what brand is it?
Bro opened, opened, opened!
- Now send a message to the first place you come across. -[phone rings]
-Brother, the embassy message came. -Send Nurullah, position the embassy immediately!
-I'm sending, I'm sending location! - Position the embassy immediately, Nurullah!
I'm posting, man!
Something happened to the phone bro, I think he's confused!
-God damn you! What happened? -He's doing something on his own.
-Oops! The camera is on, too! -What's the deal with the camera?
-Something happened to the phone! -Why did you open it? Stupid!
-I don't understand, he's confused! -Did you send it?
-I'm taking pictures, brother, I don't understand! -Send it now!
-Send! -Oops!
Brother is going but I don't know what's going on bro!
-Screen locked! -Send it!
-Send this! -Oops!
Alas, I can't hold the phone! God!
-What are you doing? -My hand burned bro, the phone got very hot!
Let me get you to work, you idiot!
I did not like you at all, Ersin Bey.
How can you leave Turkish citizens alone in the forest?
It was as I intended.
Sir, this bag related to missing friends was found.
Most likely, this bag is theirs, and these items are theirs, sir.
Yes, their bag.
This bag was always on this short man's back.
They camped near the western natural border of the savannah.
- They found it there in the morning. - Any chance they're still alive?
Yes, I hope so!
Most likely friends with wildlife knowledge.
-Mm. -[door clicks]
Dear Ambassador.
-There are encouraging developments. -What?
There were messages on the embassy line last night. Signals, close to Uganda
taken in a wooded part, west of Kenya.
We think that these signals belong to our disappeared citizens.
Our friends are working to locate the place.
He is alive.
Let go!
Joyful! Perform a miracle or you will die!
Bah!
[Recep] Oh my God! What is this nerve?
Didn't I say I'll show you a miracle?
I'll show. Why did you gather so many people here? Let it be the miracle you want.
What will you do now, Recep?
There was a trick or two I learned in primary school, Nurullah. I will make them.
They do not know whether they live in the forest or not. I think they're going to drop.
If you're ready then let me begin.
Look now, you see my fingers. Well watch now. Oh look.
[slaps tongue]
-Did you see? How miraculous? -[screams angrily] It's not a miracle!
Look, my hand is in my pocket. Look, this is in my pocket.
-Did you see? -What's this?
Here, let me do something else. Look are you watching?
[rhythmic sexual grunts]
[faster grunts]
[screams angrily]
Show miracle!
I will disappear from behind the cover you see in a moment.
How will it be? It's a miracle. God's work, miracle. Now look.
A.
İki.
Three!
[inler]
[groans and grunts]
[everyone laughs]
[screams angrily]
I have not met our friend before. Do I know you? I do not know.
He doesn't know anyway, he doesn't know our language. Look now, watch well. Miracle!
Ah egg! Where did this egg come from? How did the egg come out of his head?
[screams angrily]
Like a shit too!
Look, get ready for a miracle now. Remove, remove.
Are you watching well? Now look.
[screams angrily]
[crowd grunts]
[irritable speeches]
Niye bırakıyorsunuz lan? Ben size bırakın dedim mi?
Ağzına sıçtıklarım! Bırakın dedim mi?
Hazır mısın? Bak.
[kızgınca bağırır]
Ne var ya? Olmadı mı? Ne oluyor ya?
Mucize yoksa, öleceksiniz!
Ya şefim, gözünün yağını yiyeyim ya. Biraz insaf et ya.
Sana ben beş on tane mucize gösterdim burada ya!
Hiçbirini kabul etmiyorsunuz ama! Olmaz ki bu şekilde.
Ayrıca da, sen bana dün ne dedin? Sen bana, "Yarın güneş batana kadar." dedin.
Güneş batmadı ki şu anda. Battı mı güneş? Havada güneş.
Laf ağızdan bir kere çıkar. Siz nasıl delikanlısınız oğlum?
Sözünün arkasında duracaksın.
Benim hâlâ mucize göstermeye şansım var.
Doğru mu, değil mi? Öyle "öleceksin" e bağlama hemen ya!
-Bir bekleyin ya! -Ne yapacaksın Recep?
Aklıma bir şey geldi, şu iki büklüm adamı görüyor musun?
-Evet, Recep. -Onu bizim Mehmet Abi'nin
I'll fix it with technique. At least I will try.
Chief! I'm going to show you a miracle now, okay?
I just need a friend. I'll take this.
Come here. Come here, come.
Look, this friend is bent like this, like this,
I'm going to do it upright like this, okay?
What is its mission? This must be the magician.
Did I make this wizard upright, do you accept the miracle?
-No! Not allow! -Cut it, cut it!
Don't jump all the crap! Don't give them such a say, my chief.
Have your authority, do you accept or not?
Did I have this sewn up, do you consider it a miracle?
OK. Last chance.
Yes, chief. We are here now for the miracle that will prove to you that I am a scavenger.
Our friend, as you can see, is the magician of the years.
-Are you okay? Ha? Look how she's fading. -[they]
She's fading like glass right now, she's in pain, she's in pain. I will take them all now.
Lie here, lie down like this. Okay, look now chief.
-Take a check! OK, fix it, fix it. -[groans]
Yes chief, now this is your friend, look,
here, there is slippage in the vertebrae in the lumbar region.
These are compression and contraction. How do we open the contraction?
We'll take advantage of gravity,
We're going to take advantage of Newton's discovery of gravity. Look at my asthma friend.
Relax, relax.
OK, very nice.
Now look, I'm going to open this up nicely with my friend.
Are you ready? One two Three. Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Mehmet Abi, I hope your technique is good.
-[groans] -[gasps]
We're going to shoot a little from here. We're going to take it for a little while, sir.
[bones crackle]
[murmurs]
-Download, download, download. -[man groans]
-Get up, come like this. -[groans]
Stop son, don't fall. Stand up.
How's your waist? Nothing in your waist, recovery?
Son, has your back not healed? One two Three. Bismillahirrahmanirrahim!
-[bones crackle] -[gasps]
-[bones crackle] -[sighs and groans]
[breath held]
-[groans] -[bones crackle]
[crowd grunts]
-How? -[cries of joy]
[a confused hum]
[man screams with joy]
Did you see?
[cries of joy]
That's it!
Alley! Alley!
[cries of joy]
Joyful! street
Welcome to the Nahu Tribe, your homeland, your first home.
This necklace is a necklace of courage.
Keep it and don't give it to anyone.
Dumb necklace, tin.
This title shows your strength. You are one of us now!
Welcome to the club!
[tribal unison] Sokachu! Alley! Alley!
-Street man! Alley! Alley! -[roars]
Alley! Alley! Alley! Alley!
[mute sound]
[spits]
God bless you! Where does this come from? Where does spit come from?
God damn you!
-[clears his throat] -Is there such a thing? No no! Beware!
-[clears throat] -Don't! Go away!
The incoming spit, the outgoing spitting. What kind of Sokaçu is this?
Oh, my brother, spitting is a sign of love.
It means welcome.
Are you welcome like this? I'll get you into Sokaçu like this!
Do you welcome like this? Damn, am I not Street?
After that, I banned the damn spit.
"Welcome" will no longer be spit. My first act.
[drum rhythms]
Take this, eat it. Nice meal.
Thank you, thank you. We just ate, thanks. Let's not eat.
No, this is holy food. Good, eat, eat.
My God, what is this? What's this?
This is good food, eat.
Look, I trust you.
Let's have a taste, it's a shame if we don't look anymore.
Hadi bismillah.
Oh this thing, okay... Okay okay, this thing, take a look.
Take it, you will understand immediately. This thing...
It's on the tip of my tongue, what was it?
-This is a rhino, a rhino. -Okay, rhino!
All right, rhino.
Rhino. I was going to say, I was going to say, I was going to say an ethnic animal, a rhino.
So is his meat, ethnic.
It tastes ethnic. Rhino, that's right. Beautiful.
-Where is the rhino? Delight part, back? -It's a rhino organ.
Which organ? Internal organ?
Large rhino organ.
-Antrikot? Where? - Rhinoceros dick organ, dick.
Mm-hm.
-The dick? - His dick organ.
Your rhino?
-Good, eat. -Beautiful.
[spits] Whoa God damn you!
-Take this, take it! -[laughs]
I wouldn't mind this Street! Give me a drink.
Stuck on my neck, rhino's dick stuck! Give it!
[laughter]
[clears throat and gags]
I swear I'm going to vomit now! I'm going to take it out. This is beautiful, what is it?
Bu, you say you say.
-Oh, ugamba mugamba. What is its content? -Ugamba, the white bat.
Mm.
So you named the drink white bat, good.
No, ugamba mugamba. Ugamba, the white bat. Mugamba, his piss.
I mean, white bat piss.
Puh God bless you! Take this!
-What kind of tribe are you? -[laughs]
Doesn't your animal have any other place? You're stuck there.
No sir, no rhino's dick, no piss, no bat's poop.
Give, give fruit, let the taste of my mouth change.
I don't eat anything other than these, I only eat fruit.
-Fruit. [laughter] -I only eat fruit.
[drum rhythms]
[screams]
That's how the story started. We were going to Konya, then it ended in Kenya.
This is the result. Look, see if we look alike.
-[grumbles] -[laughs]
-Oldu mu? -Hop hop hop!
What are you doing, Recep?
You blew my mind, idiot! What are you doing there?
Ya Recep, let's get away from here when they think you are Sokaçu.
Hey, let's go! Let's go and feed the wolf. Let's go and let the lions cover us.
-We have to stay here right now. -Why Recep?
-Didn't you send a message from here? -I sent.
If those messages reach the addressee, they will detect us from the GSM network.
They will find our place, our homeland.
We have to stay here so they can find us.
- That's right, brother. That's why we can't move anywhere.
Ok bro.
By the way, I pee a lot.
I'll take a pee here. Wait.
Ya Recep, be careful.
I can't take it anymore Zouya, when will you talk to your father?
I can't talk to my father, Songa. Nahu says no.
-Then I will talk to your father. -No way, Songa!
My father will kill you.
-I love you. -What is it?
-I can not stand. -Who is he?
-I love you too, Songa. -Psst!
Lan! Songa!
No, son. Who is this girl?
-No, brother, there is no one. -How is it, son?
I saw it with my own eyes.
Did you throw a girl over the damn fence? Damn you, you're a big man!
Oh man, this girl is my lover.
-Darling, are you serious with this girl? -Yes brother.
Hey, I got it, it's done now.
-Who is this girl? -This girl is the daughter of the Hunkutu.
Who are the Hunkuts?
Ya brother, our enemy is the tribe.
-So, what are you doing with this girl? -I love it, though.
I'm in love with him.
You said love, you melted all my fat. Blind love.
I understand your situation son.
Okey brother. But please don't share it with anyone. With no one.
Medicine, pit, medicine! Did you understand?
OK, I trusted you.
Don't worry, it's between us. Trust in me.
No! No! I said no!
A Nahu cannot marry a Hunkut, Songa!
Thanks bro, you burned me! You wouldn't share it with anyone?
Who did I share it with, son? Did I put it on Twitter?
Did I share it on Instagram?
-What have I done? -Hunboxes are my enemies!
Nothing like this will happen while I'm alive! Never!
What should I do, dad? I love it though.
-Let's go, let's make up then! -Hush, I said shut up!
[speaks in native language]
Finished!
-Oh dad! -Look, you're talking wrong to your father too.
I mean, you're stepping on the man's vein, too.
It's not like "Oh daddy" or something like that. Please.
What did I tell you? If my father hears, it will never happen, this love will never happen!
You finished me, brother, you destroyed me!
okay man! Don't whine here. Do you love this girl son?
-Go on, bro! -Do you like it or not, son?
-A lot! -Since you love this girl so much,
Then we will go, we will ask his father.
If he gives, he gives. If he doesn't, we will kidnap the girl and come, okay?
-How will you do it, brother? We're going to do cross-border operations.
Take the man you trust the most with you.
And I'll take my humanoid animal,
We will go to Hunkutu village with the first light of the morning.
Okey brother.
My name is Sokaçu. I will not let the lovers stay apart!
-Okey brother. -I'll take it out, I'll take it immediately!
-Did you understand? -Understood.
Gentlemen, we had a very good transfer. You stay here
You are scouting.
If we do not come, immediately run to the village and bring the Nahu.
-OK. -Joyful,
You go ahead, Songa, you show the tent.
You are following too.
-Okey brother. -Come on, have a blessed war, lions.
Let's go back and start the transition. Slowly, squat, keep going.
[sound of surprise]
[native language conversations]
[curious conversations in the native language]
Twin axles you! Keep going, keep going.
Yup. We have successfully completed the transfer, my friends.
What we have to do is figure out which tent it is.
Oh brother, I don't know him.
-How do you not know? -I don't know bro.
-Damn! damn! Go go! -[nodding]
-Which one? Which tent? -I don't know, brother.
The cow is attacking until you know it, idiot!
Brother, the girl stays in the big tent.
I think he will stay in the big tent.
Then let's try this tent. Let's see, transfer two.
[native murmurs]
Oh, Mahmut Hoca.
We are very sorry, we entered your tent by mistake.
We were looking at one woman, in that sense. I'm sorry, my aunt.
[screams]
[Thunder]
You broke into my house without permission, huh? Nahus!
Nahular!
I will kill you!
What about my friend, did we enter your tent on purpose?
We entered your tent without knowing it.
How do we know it's inside?
If we already knew, be sure we wouldn't go in!
Shall we go to your tent to see this bet face?
You are a disgusting man! Look at me,
Don't kill like that, don't go there!
Don't come in, you'll get hurt.
Look, this is it, this is the chief's son. Songa is the chief's son.
What about you, touch our hair here,
I swear I'll pile up two trucks of men here huh!
Be smart! You will not harm our hair.
There is a man behind us son, what do you think?
[murmurs]
Ah, they came! What happened?
-Now the color has changed, coach! -[buzzing]
[lip smacking]
Be heavy!
What happened son? You were just throwing, holding. What happened?
Look, they came like lions.
We're Nahu, we're God's men, do you understand?
Be smart, come on!
What's happening in here?
Ya chief, we came here for a good cause,
friends are also acting badly, but I'll handle it. Beware.
Yes, Hunkutu chief. Listen to me carefully.
My name is Sokaçu. Streets from Nahu! Come here.
This is my animal. Humanoid animal huh. We didn't come here on our own terms, son.
We came here with legend! Everyone will be smart! Instead of late.
Me and my tribe have come before you for a good deed.
By the command of Allah, by the word of the prophet, to our son Songa, your daughter...
-What was the name? -Zouya brother.
Hey, we want Ziya.
-Will you give? -Zouya!
[Zouya] Baba.
[they speak in the local language]
[screams in native language]
I have no daughters to give to the Nahus!
-Why? -Nahu, cowards!
Nahus are brave!
[tribe shouts]
Don't yell! I swear my head is swollen!
He's yelling, and you're yelling. Wait a minute! Let's talk like a man!
-Sokaçu, let's go. -One second, chief.
I'm not going anywhere until I finish this job.
If the Nahus are cowardly, the Hunkut are brave,
since we don't know how to fight, you are great warriors,
come on then! Is he eating, is your spade boring?
[smacks mouth]
I openly challenge you to a duel here at this time.
The Hunkuts versus the Nahu. Are you there or not, son? Accepted or not?
-Acceptance! But there is one condition. -What is your condition?
If we win, you forget the girl
And that necklace is mine!
No, Streeter! This necklace is ours.
This has been our necklace for 200 years. "The Soul of the Forest."
Boy, this is the crappy necklace, the crappy tin necklace you know.
You think it's shit, it's not. Look, it's fake. I'm with you at the Grand Bazaar
I have a man, I will do the same, I will send. Calm down, let it go.
Okay, okay, okay! If you win, I will give this necklace.
But even if we win... What was his name?
-Zouya brother. -We'll take Soy. Accepted or not?
Acceptance!
Then tomorrow, in front of the village
-I'll wait for you in the meadow, all of you. -[groans]
See you tomorrow. Be smart! Let's go.
[buzzing]
Yes, today is the big day.
We are now at the place where the tail of the calf was cut off. After that, it's either hero or merro.
This is Songa your friend's love mekk, marriage,
It's not a question of giving or taking girls anymore, we're past that.
Now it has become a matter of dignity, of honour, of honour, of pride.
We'll get out there, a real Nahu how
We will show all our strength, all our courage, all our fighting!
[murmurs of approval]
Fighting until the last drop of our blood, until the last drop of our sweat,
We will raise our flag and come, God willing.
Oh brother, our village doesn't have a flag.
No? You think so, Songa lord. Take out the Nurullah flag.
Yes, friends, this is our flag from now on.
What sign is this? "Nah" sign.
What is the name of your village? Nahu. There is no better symbol than this.
Let me show you how it's done. Let's make a ball like this, let's click.
Try it, do it.
Yeah nice. Yes, try it.
Yes, it does, nice.
It will, it will. We also had a hard time at first. Yes, good, it will, it will be more beautiful.
-Who are we? -[warriors] Nahu!
-Kumiss? -Nahu!
-I know! -I know! Nahu! Nahu!
-Let the duels begin! -Let it begin!
The first game is the slap game. Let's see who is strong!
[cheer]
[groans and shouts]
-Oh god damn it! -[groans]
-Hadi Songa, hadi! - [homurtular]
Ohoo ...
[homurtular]
[inler]
-[Recep] God, God... -[cheers]
Come on Nurullah, let me see you, coach. Come on, show him the power of the Turk, Nurullah.
Fine, stick it.
[moaning]
God damn you.
[cheer]
You couldn't catch the man yet! You couldn't catch the man!
We are three or four people, look at this situation.
Let's see, bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
-Selamun aleykum brother. -[groans]
-[fake kiss] -[grunting]
Did you understand? huh? Here you go.
Are you ready? Shoot me over there. hit hit hit.
[sighs]
[groans] Good.
You are fundamental, you are firmly seated.
But now you're getting an Ottoman slap mixed with Nahu, are you ready? Look good.
[spits]
[cries of joy]
[cheer]
-[tribe] Nahu! -[kiss imitation]
-[tribe] Nahu! -[cheer]
What happened man? It has been short.
-That's it! -[tribe] Streetmen! Alley!
[shouts angrily]
[cheer] Streaker! Alley! Alley!
Next game, walk on fire! Let it begin!
I swear they have been walking on the chord since they were born. Look at this.
Brother, they already put it so that you won the competition.
I am aware of that too, but is it the place, Anatolian child?
We are prepared for anything legal or illegal, Nurullah.
Keep the mix I told you on my feet.
-Will it work, brother? -It will work, son, I watched it in the documentary.
It creates a layer of air under the foot.
The air layer blocks the fire.
I'm doing stretching, drive it off.
[Rep sighs]
[cheer]
-[groans] Yeah. -Sokaçu, Sokaçu! It's your turn.
I'm stretching, I'm stretching.
I'm doing body stretching. Did you drive?
-Okey brother. -Did you drive?
WL...
Hadi bismillah.
my mother! Nurullah!
-What happened, Recep? -My feet are stuck, it's on fire! God!
[cries of pain]
[laughter]
[cheer]
Load it, load it! what are you doing?
Stop, let go! Go away! I don't need any of you! [groans]
[screams]
[screams wildly] That's it! That's it!
my mother! This is slipping, son! Look at the man, he looks like a mih Nurullah!
Mom, I'm running out of strength!
[shouts]
I swear it's over. No more strength in my arms!
WL!
[cries of joy]
Oh god damn it!
[inler]
[cheer]
God bless you!
Hunkutu will not draw!
Hunkut brave! Marok, the lord of the forest, solves this!
-[kabile] Marok! Mark! -Nahu?
Do you have the courage?
Nahus are never afraid!
-Marok, it's accepted! -[tribe] Marok!
-Look at me, what's Marok, son? -The largest snake of the Marok forest.
-Anaconda. -Anaconda?
Yes, Sokachu, anaconda.
No one has lived up to this time trying to get his egg.
No, chief, not anaconda. No, don't accept it.
-Do not accept. -Alright. Who will go from the Hunkuts?
-We dig! - [kabile] We dig!
Who will join the Nahu?
Let's go to the street and see.
Why am I leaving, idiot? I go to every shit.
I'm not going, no! Pack up your own ass.
Sokaçu to everything, Sokaçu to everything.
Anaconda says chief, I cannot go to anaconda.
I'm having a hard time dealing with that many cobras, please. Anaconda does not come to me.
-Street man! -[tribe] Streetmen! [cheer]
Street will go!
From the two villages, until the sun goes down...
The bravest man will go and bring Marok's egg!
Whoever gets it first, wins!
Acceptance! The Hunkuts will win!
[tribe] Hunkutu! Hunkut! Hunkut!
-Nahular kazanacak! -I know! Nahu! Nahu!
-Lan Songa, where is this Marok? -Be careful bro, it can happen anywhere.
What I know is that the snake is like this under a stone or a log. It happens in a cool place.
Brother, this is a very big snake, anaconda.
Brother, shall we look at the riverside?
What do we have to do with the river? We are in the forest right now!
Anam, Marok!
I joked, I joked.
What is it? Whoa!
-Are these eggs Marok's? -Yes brother, it's too big
Hoot! It has eggs as big as Nurullah's head.
If its egg is like this, how is this animal?
Brother, this big snake is anaconda.
-Nurullah. -Yes bro.
-See those eggs? -I see it, brother.
-Come on, take two, run and grab it. -I can't go, brother.
I swear I'll spend a day with you! What are you for? What are you for?
-Come on, Songa. -Brother, I can't go.
God bless you! Why did you come with me then?
Have you come to take a walk in the meadow? Am I going to all the shit?
Give it, give it!
Look at me. I went there,
If you sense danger, you will come to help immediately!
-Okey brother. -Okay?
-Okay, Recep. -Look, don't leave me alone.
-Okey brother. -Look, I'm in danger of life.
Let me love your eyes, when you see the danger, come running.
-OK. -Do you promise?
-Promise. -Promise, promise.
Come on bismillah... [sighs]
-No, my son is here, that's not it. -Brother, come, come, come.
Come on bro, come get the eggs.
No, not here. The animal is not here.
My brother can be anywhere, come here.
-Dangerous! -Nurullah. Do you look at the egg? Look, look!
-Let me love your eyes, brother, please! -Look at this Nurullah.
It's literally like this...
butter, in a pan, it makes a good menemen.
Oh! You will dip the bread like this, you will stretch it like this...
-you will eat, full menemenlik. -Let go of your menemen!
There is nothing to be afraid of, but you exaggerated the animal.
She left her egg here, she's gone.
Who knows which snake is doing something?
Did you understand? He got the job done here, too.
Come on, get the eggs, bro! This job is no joke!
This is obviously her waitress. Did you understand? It's not his home.
-It comes once in a while. -It's home, brother, come!
Huh?
There was a snap.
-Come on, brother, please! -I'm coming.
Please, come bro, come!
-Marok. -Abi al gel, al gel.
-Marok, come on, son. [lip smacking] -Brother, please come.
-Please! -No, not here.
[shouts]
-[gasps] -[shouts]
Help me! [shouts]
damn! Help me son! Help! Help me!
[nonsense]
[inler]
-Oh! -God help me!
Help me! Damn, help me!
[panic screams]
[inler]
Help me! Damn, help me!
Help!
Pulled, pulled!
[shouts]
[groans and cries]
[buzzing]
-Arrow! -[Cheer]
[native language calls]
[cry]
[cries and chuckles]
Songa!
Where is Sokaçu?
Dad, we took the egg, but Marok attacked.
He pulled Sokaçu into the hole, we couldn't save him, he left.
Is alley dead?
He pulled the big man into the hole. We couldn't, we couldn't!
-Ah be Sokaçu! -[homurtular]
Forgive me Zouya, I will always love you.
[inler]
Nahu, there are no warriors.
Hunkutu, there is an egg.
-The winner of the duel, Hunku... -[cry of invitation]
Alley!
-[tribe] Streetmen! -[cheer]
[tribe] Streetmen! Alley! Alley!
Get off!
[homurtular]
You said eggs, eggs, gentlemen. Take Marok himself.
Hey, I brought eight or ten eggs in case you want eggs.
You can make nice sausage eggs with them, you can break them.
Well then, the Nahus were the winners!
Well, Hunkut's chief, I did my part.
It's your turn. Will you give your daughter Ziya?
Hunkutu honest, Sokachu won.
My daughter Zouya can get married!
You will say, "My daughter Ziya can marry Songa, from the Nahu",
let me hear.
- Of the Nahu, she can marry Songa. -Hah, it's done now!
Then if both of our chiefs approve, I say we'll have a wedding tomorrow. What do you say?
-It's possible. -Joyful?
It's possible.
I invite you all to the wedding tomorrow in the village of Nahu!
[cheer]
[tribe] Streetmen! Alley! Alley!
[paced African music]
Isn't it too much, man?
No, that's what happens. Not much, that's the groom's shave, son.
[ahlar]
You're ready!
[native laughter]
[native language conversations]
[laughs]
[speaks in native tongue and chuckles]
-What is this, son? -[murmurs]
-What's this? -[murmurs]
Is there a game with it? What does it say? Dynamite writes. Go go, come on!
Is there such a thing? Is there such nonsense?
Anam! Anam! Anam!
-[cries of horror] -[panic sounds]
Where should I put this? God damn it!
This is going to explode in my hand! Nurullah! It's going to explode in my hand! my mother!
[sighs and puffs]
Damn, there was only one dynamite left in my ass that didn't explode, it exploded too!
Does such a thing happen? You're running away like a freckle puppy!
Where are you! Where are you!
Yes, my brothers. I will speak harshly.
What if you see the dynamite here, all of you.
How is it?
Were you a warrior? Where were you squabbling at each other?
One of dynamite?
The village would blow up if there were no wells here.
It became a well, if I didn't cover it, it would fly again.
I sat down and popped it in my ass. I got all the pressure.
Do I have to?
Anyway, I won't hurt you any more in front of the kids.
We have met here today for a happiness.
We're going to celebrate these two young people getting married.
Now I ask, Chief of the Hunkutu, do you have your approval?
Where.
Chief of the Nahu, do you have your approval?
Then I too
As Sokaçu, by the authority the tribes gave me,
I declare you husband and wife.
[cheers]
Hah, let's make it official, let's name it.
[man calls from afar]
Ah! Nurullah, do you see what I see?
I see it bro!
-The Turkish flag? -Turkish flag!
God! We are saved! We are saved Nurullah, our people are coming!
Turks are coming, Nurullah!
my mother! By Allah, Turkish soldier.
Chief, these are ours, we'll handle it, don't worry.
Come on Nurullah! Come on Nurullah!
By Allah, Turkish Army Nurullah! I swear by the Turkish Army!
God bless you commander! God bless you.
Recep İvedik and Nurullah Sağlam, right?
-Yeah, that's right. -We are Turkish soldiers in the peacekeeping force.
By the order of our embassy, ​​we send you to the land of the homeland.
We are here to repost.
God bless you, I swear! Only commander,
we've been here for a long time
We have a job to complete, let's get it done.
Ofcourse. We wait, we found you, that's enough for us.
Lions! Turkish army! Good luck to you!
Come on, Nurullah, come on.
[homurtular]
[smacks his lips]
Dear brothers and sisters, I will explain something very important to you.
-I'm not a street runner! -[murmurs]
My name is Recep İvedik.
We are not who you think we are. That you will tie us there and cut us off,
We made up such a lie. But good thing we made it up.
Did we do bad? Look, two villages that have been fighting for years have made peace.
two young people who love each other got married.
How beautiful. The important thing is not being a Sokaçu, friends.
The important thing is to be human.
Now, this beautiful necklace that was entrusted to me the first time I became Sokaçu in the village,
I want to give it to the right owner.
Can I have the bride and groom?
This is the Soul of Jungle necklace that was given to me...
I always hide it...
Saying that the female bird will make the nest, I present it to the bride. Here you go dear.
Here you go.
Own this necklace. You give it to your children and grandchildren. Okay?
-Thanks bro, you are really a man. -Thank you bro.
You're a man too, a real lad. Claim your home, let's see.
-Okey brother. -Here you go.
Chief, it's time to leave. Guys, he's from the peacekeepers. Turkish soldier.
These are the sons of the homeland, they have come to get us.
We have to go.
Your name is not Sokaçu!
But you are the real Streetman.
A brave man.
You and your friend are good people.
Thanks.
-Thank you, God bless. You are like that. -You are brave, you are the big man!
God bless you. You are like that.
Then I would like to bid you farewell with your customs.
-[spits] -No, no, no!
[laughs]
God bless, take care of yourself! Come on Nurullah.
Street...
[tribe] Streetmen! Alley! Alley!
Alley! Alley! Alley! Alley!
Alley!
Look now, is this going to work?
Let's make ours for them, Nurullah.
[laughs]
Take care of yourselves. Come on, entrust it to God.
-Nurullah. -Yes bro?
-What did we forget? -What did we forget?
-Is there a wedding without halay? -No, bro!
No bro!
-[traditional Turkish music] -Come on!