you can often hear that there is no word supposedly
no
, what those who say this really don’t have is a linguistic instinct,
so let’s free our native language from the prison of Rosenthal
and find out why there is no better word no, how it was used in the past and how it  they use now
and most importantly - why does the language even need such long denials as no or even netuti
against the background of genuine knowledge, it’s a bit ridiculous to hear that no is a distorted word no,
and this knowledge lies in the fact that no no comes from no, but vice versa,
but we  we won’t understand today’s speech nuance if we don’t also consider other denials in the history of the Russian language,
let’s start with the simplest, it’s the shortest,
this negative particle “not”
this word goes back to the Proto-Indo-European times, if not even more ancient
and it is approximately the same  sounds in most European languages, then from there there is this root, but
then the word appears in the Proto-Slavic do not
pay attention here already long voices  nye "e"
then it became the sound "ie" in the Old Russian language, that is, "I team"
which was reflected in the old spelling until 1918 and then again just a short "e"
now such "not" as a separate word is no longer used
but  we can still see in the composition of other words,
pay attention again to the spelling in the old spelling of
someone, some, and so on,
and in all such cases, "not" will be a stressed syllable,
where did this "not" come from?
it comes from the combination of the Proto-Slavic nas, that is, there is literally no there is no
word indicates the absence of something in some place
compare similar phrases in other languages
xample of such an independent text not from Old Russian, others may
bject to us, well, how can you  sometimes say in colloquial speech let's say you have some business for tomorrow, not
what is possible, and so, but for some reason it seems to me that this is rather such a situational neoplasm, an
abbreviation for no or no, but in this second it is more likely  there really is an ancient “not” of everything,
then
finally we’ll talk about the word “no”
it comes from a combination of the same “not” and “tu”
that is in Old Russian “here”, “here”
compare, this word still has  such a form in the Polish language
in this way, although the word "no" did not yet exist in the Proto-Slavic, at that level it would be decomposed into three words
no no no
and, as you might guess, in the early Old Russian period no sounded quite redundant
as if m  you just said instead of “I don’t have time” “I don’t have time here”
and it wouldn’t be about a specific place where exactly I don’t have time
now about the word “no”
I repeat once again that not “no” comes from  “no”, but on the contrary,
that is, at some point, the final vowel began to fall off the word,
and this happened, which is why
in the late Old Russian language there was one
phonetic change;  but some other grammatical indicators of the remaining elements changed their appearance
was enough to show the corresponding morphemes
also for the word no, the final "tъ"
allowed us to maintain a difference with the word "not"
if we look into the corpus of Old Russian texts, we will see that there strongly prevails over no
of course, the historical corpus of Roscorporation is very small, but still it can give some relative figures,
so in ancient Russian texts it doesn’t meet 15 times, but no, I
only
have two  the assumption that by the end of the Old Russian period they already said
exactly no,
I will later explain why
but no is more common in texts because it was supported by some kind of written tradition,
but, as you understand,
this is not known for certain; nevertheless, here are some examples of the word no from ancient Russian texts
here is an example for the word no
further the development of negations on the word no does not end
there is one word that now seems terribly rustic to us
although it also arose in the early Old Russian language
this word is
netuti or netut
as perceptive viewers could already guess
it was the words netuti that first appeared which then  abbreviated to netut
according to the same rule, according to which there is no in no,
here it is, at the end, this is another amplifying word, an amplifying particle
that was also once used separately, for example, in birch bark it
turns out that the word netuti at the Proto-Slavic level was laid out as much as  four words ne je tu ti
examples of its use in  Old Russian texts
here in this example do not exist at all, but a thread with such a dialectal reflex.
So, what happens closer to our time,
well, the word netuti is almost never used by the 18th century, wherever it occurs later
it is such an element for conveying the speech of highly illiterate characters and  here are the words no and no, live and live,
yes, the
word no is much less common than no,
so in the dictionary of the Russian Academy of 1789 the
word "no" is not written out at all, but there is the word "no" and it refers us to the dictionary entry "is"
that is, “no” is considered there as a form of the verb “to be”,
and if we look in the same corpus, we will see
that during the 18-19 centuries the word “no” appeared in texts about 3700 times,
while there are only 390  occurrences, that is, no, it was used almost 10 times more often than none,
but 390 occurrences are not jokes and, of course, we should not forget about another 1700 occurrences in the 20th century,
now let's talk about the meaning of the word a
curious moment that in the modern language the word no can have  to be consumed in two meanings
as the absence of something and as a negative answer to the question, the
word "no" in the second meaning already sounds strange
- Are you busy tomorrow?
-
No, we don’t say that anymore,
but earlier it could be said that
I looked through the corpus and such a meaning of the word disappears completely only in the 1930s and 40s,
however, it was quite rare even before that,
now let’s talk about the style of the word no,
as for  its meaning as a negative answer,
then there can be no doubt that even in the 19th century such a meaning was not neutral;
it was somewhere lower in the stylistic register
, because wherever it is used, this is the speech of some not very literate characters,
but  we don’t observe the absence of such a picture for the word no,
yes, you can find various examples, including stylistically colored ones,
but there are also examples where the word no is generally neutral, it is used in the speech of clearly educated people,
here is an example from Herzen, only here it is  the direct speech is not of Herzen himself, but of his colleague revolutionary Kelsiev.
Soviet dictionaries in fact were not so much against the word no,
it was simply attributed to the colloquial style
that is, it was still within the framework of the literary language,
it is much better for the fate of the word than if it were called
vernacular or dialectism
, that's what Ozhegov writes in his dictionary,
so all these radical statements that you probably all heard
that there are no words in Russian  no,
it’s just the chatter of those who decided to become more adept at literary norms,
but they didn’t do it clearly enough,
or it’s just such an unsuccessful pedagogical technique for Russian language teachers
, because it can be easier to make a schoolboy once and for all
throw out of his head some such word with a trick
that  he, God forbid, did not give it away in the exam rather than explaining the various subtleties of its use,
now let's talk about the word "no" now quite in our time, that is, in the 21st century,
Gramota.ru and other reference resources are still reprinting Soviet dictionaries,
where  it is said that no this is a colloquial word and that's it,
but the corpus shows us that now the word no can be called colloquial only with very much  For the
sake of brevity, we will omit examples from written texts by a big stretch, we will cite a lot of them,
only something from the multimedia corpus
about biology, nothing is the same.  There are no two identical individuals,
there are no two identical people, it’s impossible, they are somehow different now that there is no alliance of right-wing forces, the
business trip is over and there is no
fundamental limitation on agricultural productivity, even with doubling
the world’s population, these are very small black holes,
microscopic black holes that arise in quantum theory  gravity, that is, whether they are unknown or not,
they do not reflect what I say, the syntax of the language, that is, there are faces here,
but there is no complex, there are no contexts in
which this gesture is realized by
sergey udaltsov and has been under house arrest
and for the last few months that he has been under it
Google doesn’t, email doesn’t,
we use different sources, we naturally search in the corpus,
but it’s still too small for these needs, there are no solutions for many words,
and in general, there are no prospects and evolution within this paradigm
within Georgia, we have very few contacts, unfortunately, and  in practice, they can be said to be absent.
We have no ideas and a stereotype that life  it’s wonderful
why the word no has not yet gone away and has not been completely replaced by the word no,
on the one hand, the word no has a
specific meaning: the subject is absent, the word no is ambiguous in this sense,
therefore sometimes it may be better to say no for greater accuracy,
but with  on the other hand, I have one more suggestion
why no has not yet left the Russian language,
it explains well why the word no seems to be more ancient than no
is still kept precisely in the colloquial layer of the vocabulary,
and not somewhere in the high,  and why it is now just expanding its use
and the answer is simple
no, it’s one syllable, but no - two
the longer the word, the more expressive and usually more expressive it is,
and when it comes to expressiveness and expressiveness of
negations, a well-known general linguistic pattern comes into play
you've been like that.  that a person says “I didn’t like it”, and you hear “I liked it”
and then you ask again whether you liked it or didn’t like it in
order to avoid this, speakers strive to say so that they understand unequivocally, and for this we need expressive amplifiers
what we saw in the history of the Russian language
at first was  just “ne”, then it began to be missed, they began to say “nee”, it merged into “not”,
this also began to be missed, they began to say no, no, then it began to be missed, they
came up with such words as netut or netushki,
that is, expressive is added to the word  amplifier, then its expressiveness weakens
, one more word is added, then already in this neoplasm the
general expressiveness weakens, a third word is needed, and so words can be strung on top of each other indefinitely
examples from other languages
in there is a word non which is translated as Russian no non o
curs  from the abbreviation ne eounum "none"
hence the Italian negation e.g. io non dico
In the English language, there was once a normal-looking negation, I say in modern pronunciation something like
je ne sais, that is, I don’t know,
then it began to be perceived as
insufficient, not too expressive, and therefore so that the interlocutor would understand for sure that you didn’t understand something at all  you know, the
French at some point began to add pas (step) to the end
in the modern language, I don’t know it will be je ne sais pas, as if “I don’t know a single step”
well, compare with Russian “not a drop”
then such a construction completely became  obligatory and omitting this pas in modern French is no longer a mistake,
but you can omit ne, and you get je sais pas, such a good construction of the spoken language
and a similar process when the amplifier completely replaces the negation and the previous negation can generally disappear from the language
is called the Jespersen cycle  about this you can read one interesting article
another example, perhaps the most breathtaking
in the German language, the negation is made by the word nicht, which comes after the verb
in modern  German German still has the word der Wicht with a similar meaning,
but the word nio itself never consisted of two words ni and io
ni, this is just the usual Old High German negation as Russian, not
but io meant "always"
that is, if you lay it out at a very ancient level  then sie wartet nicht will be "she does not always wait for a creature"
what words were used at different times to enhance the
expressiveness of the expression and
we see how these words did not really change its meaning
and the last: the English word not completely shares the history of the German nicht
in the Middle English period the word not  it was written like this, and in Old English it was noht from the older
nowiht,
and as astute viewers already guess, when modern English speakers say nope instead of no,
they are driven by the same linguistic process
as we have seen in a variety of languages, denials over time acquire different
expressive amplifiers  these are either individual words or some just sounds like in English nope or  in Russian, no, the
word no comes from the word no, and not vice versa, as many people think,
all long negatives no, no, netuti arose in the Old Russian language instead of the usual
word no, the word no used to have two meanings, just like the word no now the
first meaning is preserved until  until now (there is something missing) and the second, the answer in case of denial, we no
longer say that you want to drink no, but we won’t say that, this second meaning of the word no already began to disappear at the beginning of the 20th century
and apparently it always had a colloquial connotation, but the first  the meaning for the word no has never been vernacular; the
word no is simply used in the first meaning ten times less often than not
, and even Soviet dictionaries give it only a colloquial mark,
that is, it remains within the framework of the literary language,
although now the word no is expanding its use by registers and  it’s probably not very correct to say that this word is purely
colloquial and one of the reasons why this happens is the long length of the word is not present, and therefore its large expressive
perhaps greater expressiveness,
well, brothers, dear sisters, but on that, goodbye for now