One often hears that the word "no" is allegedly
no
what those who say that really don't have is a sense of language.
so let's free our mother tongue from the Rosenthal's prison
and find out why no is better than the word no, how it was used in the past and how it is used now
and most importantly, why language needs such long negations like no or even no-ti.
it's a bit ridiculous to hear that no is a distorted word, no, against the background of real knowledge.
and the knowledge is that it's not no that comes from no, but vice versa.
But we won't understand today's speech nuance if we don't consider other negations in the history of the Russian language, too
Let's start with the simplest one, which is the shortest.
it's the negative particle "not."
it goes back to Proto-European times, if not even older.
and it sounds more or less the same in most European languages.
and then in Proto-Slavic there's the word don't.
you notice there's a long vowel "e".
and then it became the "e" sound in Old Russian, which is "I tim".
which was reflected in the old orthography until 1918, and then again with just a short "e".
Now this "not" is no longer used as a word.
but we can still see it in other words.
Note, again, the spelling in the old spelling.
some, some and so on.
and in all such cases the "not" will be a stressed syllable.
Where did this "not" come from?
it comes from the conjunction of the pre-Slavic nyy e, i.e. literally no is not there
the word indicates the absence of something in some place
Compare similar expressions in other languages.
here's an example of such an independent not from the old russian text
others may object how can we sometimes say in colloquial speech you have some things to do for tomorrow not
that it's possible, but somehow it seems to me that it's more of a situational neologization.
short for no or no-ah, but that second one probably has the ancient "not" in it.
next
finally, let's talk about the word "no."
it comes from a combination of the same "not" and "tu"
tu is Old Russian for "here", "here".
compare, this word still has this form in Polish
so, although the word "no" did not yet exist in Proto-Slavonic, at that level it would be arranged into as many as three words
ne et tu
and, as we can easily guess, in early Old Russian no-tu sounded rather redundant
as if now instead of "I don't have time" we say "I don't have time here".
and we wouldn't be talking about a specific place where I don't have time.
Now about the word "no".
Again, it's not "no" that comes from "no", it's the other way around.
that is, at some point the final vowel of the word no began to fall off
and that's why it happened.
there was a phonetic change in the late Old Russian language
the rule of it was.
that's why our case endings didn't fall off.
eye eye about eye, but some other grammatical indicators changed their form
the remaining elements were sufficient to show the corresponding morphemes
Also in the word no, the final "t"
allowed us to keep the difference with the word "not".
if we look at the corpus of Old Russian texts, we see that there no strongly predominates over no
of course the historical corpus of Roskorpora is very small, but still it can give some relative figures
so in the Old Russian texts there no occurs 15 times and no
only two
I have an assumption that by the end of the Old Russian period more was spoken
Exactly no.
I'll explain why later.
and no occurs more often in the texts because it was supported by a certain written tradition.
but this is not known for certain, as you understand.
nevertheless, here are some examples of the word no from old russian texts.
here's an example for the word no
the development of negations does not end with the word no.
there is one word which now seems terribly rustic to us.
although it, too, originated in the early Old Russian language
this word
netuti or netut
as discerning viewers may have already guessed
it was the word netuti that first appeared which was later shortened to netut
by the same rule as no in no.
the ti on the end is another reinforcing word, a reinforcing particle
which was also once used separately, for example in birch bark writings.
it turns out that the word no-ti at the Proto-Slavonic level was divided into four words: pe-e tu ti
examples of its use in Old Russian texts
in this example it is not netut' at all, but nitut with this dialectal reflex.
So, what happens closer to our time
well, the word netuti is hardly used anymore by the 18th century.
it's an element to convey the speech of highly illiterate characters, but the words no and no are alive and well.
It's true.
the word no is much rarer than no.
So in the Russian Academy Dictionary of 1789.
the word "no" is not written out at all, but the word "no" is there, and it refers us to the dictionary entry "is."
so "no" is treated there as a form of the verb "to be".
and if we look in the same corpus, we see
that in the 18th and 19th centuries, the word "no" was used about 3,700 times.
While no has only 390 occurrences, that is, no was used almost 10 times more often
than no.
but also 390 occurrences are not a joke and of course we must not forget about 1700 occurrences of the 20th century.
Now let's talk about the meaning of the word
The curious thing is that in today's language the word no can be used in two meanings
as the absence of something and as a negative answer to a question.
the word "no" in its second meaning already sounds strange.
- Are you busy tomorrow?
- No.
We don't say that anymore.
but we used to be able to say that.
I looked through the corpus, and it was not until the 1930s and 40s that the word disappeared altogether.
but even before that, it was quite rare.
Now let's talk about the stylistics of the word no.
Well, as for its meaning as a negative answer.
there can be no doubt that in the 19th century it wasn't neutral.
it was somewhere down in the stylistic register
because everywhere it's used, it's the speech of some not very literate characters
but for the word no meaning, we don't see that pattern.
Yes, you can find different examples, including stylistically colored
But there are also examples where the word "no" is neutral in general, and is used in the speech of obviously educated people
here is an example from Herzen, only here it is direct speech not by Herzen himself, but by his fellow revolutionary Kelsiev
The Soviet dictionaries weren't really so much against the word no.
it was just classified as colloquial.
so it was still within the literary language.
which is much better for the fate of the word than if it had been called
colloquialism or dialectism.
this is what Ozhegov says in his dictionary
so all these radical statements that you've probably all heard
that there's no word for "no" in the Russian language
is just the chatter of those who have decided to learn literary norms
but haven't done it enough.
or it's just an unfortunate pedagogical technique of Russian teachers
It might be easier for them to make a student once and for all
to get him to drop some dirty word out of his head once and for all.
that God forbid he didn't spit it out at the exam than to explain the various subtleties of its use
Now let's talk about the word "no" in our time, in the 21st century.
Gramota.ru and other reference resources still reprint Soviet dictionaries,
which say that "no" is a colloquial word and that's it.
but the corpus shows us that nowadays we can hardly call "no" a colloquial word.
We will omit examples from written texts for the sake of brevity.
We'll only give something from the multimedia corpus.
About biology, nothing is the same. No two individuals are alike
No two people are the same, it is impossible that they are different now that there is no alliance of right-wing forces.
the business trip is over and
the fundamental limit on agricultural productivity even with a doubling of
of the world's population there are very small black holes
microscopic black holes which appear in the theory of quantum gravity, whether they exist or not.
we don't know
they don't reflect what I'm saying is the syntax of the language.
but there is no complex no context
by which this gesture is realized
Sergei Udaltsov is under house arrest
and for the last few months he's been under it, he's gone.
There's no Google, there's no Mail.
We use different sources. We naturally search the corpus.
but it's a little small for these needs, a lot of the words aren't there.
there are no solutions and no prospects for evolution within this paradigm.
Unfortunately, we have very few contacts inside Georgia and practically none.
We have no ideas and no stereotype that life is beautiful.
Why hasn't the word no gone away and been completely replaced by the word no?
on the one hand, the word no
has a specific meaning: there is no object, but the word no in this sense has many meanings
so sometimes it might be better to say no for accuracy.
But on the other hand, I have another suggestion.
why no is still in the Russian language
it explains well why the word no seems to be more ancient than no
is still in the colloquial vocabulary,
and not somewhere high up there, and why it's now expanding its use
and the answer is simple.
no is one syllable and no is two.
the longer the word, the more expressive it is, and usually the more expressive it is,
and when it comes to the expressiveness and expressiveness of negatives.
there's a general linguistic pattern that comes into play.
You've ever had someone say "I didn't like it" and you hear "I liked it".
and then you ask them if they liked it or didn't like it.
to avoid this, speakers try to say things so that they can be understood unambiguously, and for this we need expressive intensifiers.
what we've seen in the history of the Russian language
at first it was just "neh", then it was no longer enough, so they started saying "neh" and it merged into "not".
that also became insufficient. They started saying no, no, and then that also became insufficient.
they invented words like no-tie and no-touchy.
That is, they add an expressive amplifier to a word, and then its expressive power weakens.
they add another word, and then this new formation
the overall expressive power weakens, a third word is needed, and so the words can be strung on top of each other ad infinitum.
examples from other languages
Latin has the word non, which translates to Russian no.
non comes from the abbreviation ne eounum "not one".
hence the Italian negation e.g. io non dico I don't speak
another example, in Old French there used to be a common-looking negation say in the modern pronunciation of something like
je ne sais, that is, I don't know.
then it came to be understood as
insufficient, not too expressive, and so that the interlocutor understands exactly what you don't know at all.
the French at some point began to add pas (step) to the end.
in the modern language I don't know would be je ne sais pas, as if "I don't know a step".
compare it to the Russian "not a drop".
later this construction became compulsory and we can't omit this pas in modern french anymore - it would be a mistake.
but you can omit ne and you get je sais pas, it's such a good construction of colloquial language
and a similar process where the amplifier completely replaces the negation and the former negation can disappear from the language altogether
it's called the Espersen cycle, you can read an interesting article about it.
Another example is perhaps the most mind-boggling.
in German, negation is done by nicht, which comes after the verb.
in modern German there's still a word der Wicht with a similar meaning.
but the word nio itself was never made up of two words, ni and io.
ni is just a common Old German negation, like the Russian not.
but io meant "always".
so if you break it down on a very ancient level, then sie wartet nicht would be "she's not always waiting for a creature".
which words were used at different times to reinforce
the expressiveness of the expression and
see how these words didn't really change its meaning
one last thing: the English word not shares completely the history of the German word nicht
in Middle English the word not was spelled like this, and in Old English it was noht from the older
nowiht
and as discerning onlookers will already guess when modern English speakers say nope instead of no
they are driven by the same linguistic process.
as we've seen in all kinds of languages, negation over time grows into different
expressive intensifiers, either individual words or some simple sounds, like in English nope or in Russian nope.
the word no comes from the word no, not the other way around, as most people think.
all long negatives no, nooo, neti arose as early as in Old Russian to replace the usual ne
the word no to has two meanings, like the word no now
the first meaning still remains to this day (no something) and the second, the answer to the negation, we no longer say
we don't say you want to drink no, but we won't say it that way. This second meaning of the word no has already started to disappear at the beginning of the 20th century.
and apparently it's always had a colloquial connotation, but the first meaning of nooo has never been colloquial.
the word no was just used in its first meaning ten times less often than no.
and even Soviet dictionaries only give it the label colloquial.
that is, it stays within the literary language.
although now the word no is extending its use in registers and it is probably not very correct to say that the word is purely
colloquial and one of the reasons why it happens is the great length of the word no and therefore its great expressiveness
probably more expressive.
Well, brothers and sisters, goodbye for now.