Matter, as we know it;
Atoms, stars and galaxies, planets
and trees, rocks and ourselves.
Only 5% of our universe
consists of this matter.
About 25% is dark matter
and 70% is dark energy.
Both are invisible.
That is quite strange because it suggests
that what we experience is
only a very small part
of reality.
But it gets worse.
We have no idea what dark matter
and dark energy are, or how they work.
We're pretty sure they exist.
So what do we know?
Dark matter is the stuff that
allows galaxies to exist.
When we calculated why
the universe is the way it is
, it quickly became clear that there simply is
n't enough normal matter.
The gravity of visible matter
is not strong enough
to form galaxies and complex
structures.
Stars would then be scattered everywhere
and would not form galaxies.
This way we know that there is something different
in and around galaxies.
Something that does not emit
or reflect light.
Something dark...
but in addition to being able to calculate
that dark matter exists
, we can also see it...
well... sort of.
Places with a high concentration of dark
matter bend passing light.
So we know there's something
that acts on gravity.
We now know a lot more about what dark
matter is not than what it is.
We know that dark matter is not
clouds of ordinary matter without stars,
because that would emit particles
that we can detect.
Dark matter is not anti-matter,
because it emits unique gamma
rays in reaction with normal matter.
Dark matter is also not made up
of black holes,
very compact objects that
drastically change their environment,
while dark matter
seems to be everywhere.
We know three things for sure;
1. There is something beyond normal matter.
2. It acts on gravity.
3. There's a lot of it.
Dark matter probably
consists of a complex, exotic particle
that doesn't interact with light and matter
as we would expect it to,
but at the moment,
we simply don't know.
Dark energy is even stranger
and mysterious.
We cannot detect it, we
cannot measure it and we cannot taste it.
But we clearly see the effects
of dark energy.
In 1929, Edward Hubble observed
how the wavelength of light
emitted from distant galaxies shifts
toward the red part of the
electromagnetic spectrum
as it travels through space.
He found that galaxies
that are further away appear redder;
galaxies that are closer
do not appear redder.
Hubble explained this by stating that
the universe is expanding.
The shift to red occurs
because the wavelength of light is
stretched as the
universe expands.
More recent discoveries show that
the expansion of the universe is accelerating.
Before that, it was as if
gravity would cause the expansion
to slow down or even collapse on its
own.
Space doesn't change as it expands;
there's just more of it.
New space is constantly emerging everywhere,
galaxies are dense clusters of matter
held together by gravity,
so we don't notice this expansion in
our daily lives.
But we see it all around us.
Where there is empty space in the universe
, more and more are created.
Dark energy is thus a kind of energy
intrinsic to empty space.
Energy stronger than
anything else we know
and it just keeps getting stronger
over time.
Empty space has more energy than all the
other things in the universe put together.
We have multiple ideas about
what dark energy could be.
An idea: dark energy is not a 'thing',
but a property of empty space.
Empty space is not nothing,
it has its own energy.
It can create more space
and is quite active.
By expanding the universe,
more empty space is created
which causes the universe
to expand faster.
This idea is similar to Einstein's idea
in 1917,
the concept of
a cosmological constant,
a force that opposes
gravity.
The problem is that if we try to
calculate how much of this energy there is,
we get an erroneous and weird result
which only confuses us.
Another idea is that empty space is
actually filled
with temporary, virtual particles
that spontaneously and continuously
arise and disappear from nothing.
These particles could be dark energy
.
Or maybe dark energy is
an undiscovered type of energy field
that permeates the entire universe
yet has the opposite effect
on the universe
than normal energy and matter.
But if it exists, we don't
know how and where to detect it.
So there are still many questions
to be answered.
Our theories about dark matter
and energy are just that: theories.
On the one hand that is quite frustrating,
on the other hand it is the front line of
science which makes it very exciting.
We see that as much as we
think we're in control of everything,
we're still primates
with smartphones,
on a small, fragile island
in
space looking up and
wondering how the universe works.
There is still so much to learn
and that is great.
This video is supported by
the Australian Academy of Science.
They promote and support science.
Learn more about this topic
and others at nova.org.au.
It was great working with them
so go check out their website.
Our videos are also made possible
by your support on patreon.com.
Visit our Patreon page to
support us and be part
of the Kurzgesagt bird army.
Subtitles submitted by the Amara.org community