Tiffany, is a very neon 80s name, and not
without reason,
it exploded in popularity during the decade.
But despite Tiffany's modern sound the name
wasn't born in the 80s.
Tiffany is at least, 80 decades old.
["OMG that's like, positively medieval." "How
is that? And then why is this?"]
Well, let me tell you the tale of tracking
Tiffany through time.
It starts in the year 300, with this guy,
Eusebius.
A historian and bishop in the Holy Land.
He wrote a treatise *On The Divine Manifestation,*
and the word for that in the Greek he wrote
was *Theophania*.
In ye olden days religious virtue names were
totally a thing
and Theophania became a name given to children
born on the feast of The Epiphany.
Though no five syllable name can go unnicked,
so for some rhyming sage a Tiffany Epiphany
was inevitable.
The name, thus born in the Holy Land,
then spread with the Greek language.
The most famous example appears in 972
with the Empress of the Holy Roman Empire,
who's name is written this way and
probably pronounced *tay-off-ahnu*.
Ancient pronunciation is…
a whole other thing that we are going to skip
(becauseit'sunknowable)
and it doesn't help that the Empress's name
is listed in different ways,
so it's impossible to know if she want by
[Tay-off-ahnu or Theophania, or Tee-o-phania]
which are all close to Tiffany, but not quite.
Who knows. Maybe she shortened it and her
title was
[Tiff, Empress of the Empire. The top Tiff.]
But that's just speculation.
When this word first became a Tiffany name
precursor
isn't exactly known.
[Spoiler for History]
Pre-printing press, there's not a lot of written
evidence, for anything
and lot's of documents that did exist got
lost.
So to tell the totality of the tale takes
trusses of trust
betwixt islands of evidence.
It's time to try to find the true old-time
Tiffs.
By working backwards through hundreds of years
of census books,
and if you did that in English, you wouldn't
find much,
thanks for nothing *Doomsday Book*.
But if you also looked in French you could
find Tiphaine Raguenel,
born 1335, about whom all information is delightful.
A noble lady astrologer who lived in
France's fairy tale castle Mont St Michael
and used her astrological powers to predict
the outcome
of her husband's knighting battles.
[Hey honey, maybe don't go to that one.]
And she was righter than wronger
because he survived to ascend to become the
[Grand Constable of France, First Officer
of the Crown.]
On the island there's still a little museum
to her, and her husband.
Though the one thing you won't find in that
museum is her skull,
which was turned up just a few years ago
in a reliquary box in town of Dinan
with a note on it saying *this is the skull
of Tiphaine Raguenel*
and given anonymously to the local library.
So, that's a thing that happened.
Wait, why are we talking about this?
Oh right, because this is oldest Tiffany,
that's pretty much spelled Tiffany,
and about whom details of her life are known.
But were you to keep going backwards through
the census books
you'd also strike a Trio of Tiffanies in Paris
in 1313,
but all that is known about them is their
listed professions:
wax maker, washer woman and spinster.
A woman who spins wool into thread.
Thus this foursome of French Tiffany's written
records are the proof
that Tiffany is totally neon medieval.
Though you might be wondering exactly
how did a Greek name from here,
end up on a Fancy French Tiffany over here?
ME TOO!
So if you kept looking through every old document
that might be a list of names for,
hundreds of hours.
If you were lucky you would eventually stubble
on the
*Transcripts of Charters relating to Gilbertine
Houses* from 1161
containing a single Tiffany,
well Tephany with an e p h,
but that's close enough to count,
who lived in Fotherby, England.
How did she get there?
Well, we must across another Truss of Trust,
but Tephany had a Grandfather named Hugh,
who was at just the right time and place
to travel to the Holy Land in
the First Crusade.
And going through the surviving records of
Crusaders from the time
there are candidate Hughs,
and while I can't prove the Tephany/Hugh connection
100%,
which *kills* me.
I'm still calling it that Grandpa Hugh on
his travels
came across an Epiphany Tiffany
and brought the name back to middle England,
and the English language.
As did also French Crusaders to France.
It all fits!
But it does leave the question,
if Tiffany in its modern form is near a millennia
old,
why don't we think of it that way?
Probably just historical happenstance.
A lack of famous Tiffany's.
There were no queens born on the Epiphany
to be named Tiffany
leaving Theophanu as the most prominent Tiffany,
except not exactly a Tiffany,
and Tiphanie Raguenel isn't particularly famous,
until hopefully now, that is.
If you go on your own french Tiffany Crusade,
be sure to tell 'em Grey sent you.
So, aside from these two, the name never landed
on fame to pop in popularity like it would
later.
Just sporadically showing up in written records
in the late 17 and 1800s.
Which, as an alternate history side note,
it does mean that at the time when
Jane Austen was writing *Emma*,
the name Tiffany was infrequently around
with its exact modern spelling.
So if the authoress was looking for an underused
name
with literary potential,
she could have picked Tiffany
and turned the Georgian and Victorian eras
neon as well.
And, I mean, come on, the name Tiffany Woodhouse
is tots perfect for the character.
But sadly, it didn't happen,
and Tiffany remained a name, without fame.
She would get there,
but jumping backwards,
she first she needed to transform.
In 1629, Tiffany does appears on an English
census,
*finally*
this time, for the *first* time
as a last name with one Mr. Henry Tiffany,
who lived and died in Hackney London.
Ok, so he wasn't born a Tiffany.
Were you to track down his christening,
you'd find he was Henry Tiffin at the time,
but once grown up and married,
the record now shows him as the first of the
family of Tiffany.
Why the name change?
It probably wasn't one.
Consistent spelling in the English language
totally wasn't a thing back then.
None other than Tiffen/Tiffany's contemporary
William Shakespeare
never spelled his signature the same way twice.
English was [and still kind of is] very
*whatever* with the written word.
So Henry Tiffan became Tiffany randomly,
and because the world is just too perfect
sometimes,
I'm *also* calling it that this Mr. Tiffany,
the first to appear with the last name in
English language,
is directly responsible for *this* explosion
of Tiffany's
400 years later.
Come with me.
So Henry Tiffany had a son in 1630,
Humphrey Tiffany who moved to the shiny New
England
sometime before 1660.
Humphry Tiffany took the name to America,
and simultaneously removed it from England
as a last name
as he was Henry Tiffany's only surviving son
who would also have a son.
James Tiffany in 1666.
From there James Tiffany Jr., 1697
to Ebineezer Tiffany, 1734
to Comfort Tiffany, 1777
to 1812 Charles Lewis Tiffany.
Which has caused some bulbs in the audience
to light.
But to follow though.
Charles Lewis Tiffany, with some friends,
established a stationary and fancy goods emporium
shop named
Tiffany, Young and Ellis, in 1837.
Charles Lewis Tiffany eventually took control
of the company,
changed the name to *Tiffany & Co*
to focus on jewelry exclusively,
well except for that period during the Civil
War
when he switched to manufacturing swords as
the Tiffany's Experience,
but after that, back to jewelry.
From the late 1800s this New York City store,
for Tiffany was her most prominent placement,
since the Empress or the Astrologer,
and it remained so until 1958 when Truman
Capote walked by.
The name caught the author's attention
as underused with literary potential.
And he wrote and published the Novella
*Breakfast at Tiffany's*.
Prior to this moment Tiffany as a first name
was holding on, but barely.
Averaging under ten babies a year.
After the Novella, there's a slight uptick
in the name,
but that could be a coincidence,
but what definitely isn't is in 1961,
the novella became a movie staring Audrey
Hepbun,
and it would not be understatement to say
that this role
turned her into time-transcending Hollywood
icon,
forever connected with the name in the title.
Tiffany had found her fame.
And the following year the Tiffany's, quintupled!
Setting a solid base for an exponential explosion,
and grew over the next twenty years
as children grew, having seen the movie,
to have children of their own.
Bringing us to 1979 and there are almost 10,000
Tiffany's a year.
Now, we are still on a Truss of Trust for
this Tiffany Theory,
maybe isn't wasn't the store, turned story,
turned movie.
It could have been a coincidence.
If you look at enough random events
you can always draw some convincing correlations.
But, remember, that in ye olden days of the
60s and early 70s
movies could only be seen in theaters.
But by the late 70s there was a new invention.
VHS.
The video home system
So you could watch movies, any time in glorious
480 pixels.
And well, guess what?!?
*Breakfast at Tiffany's* happens to be the
first
Audrey Hepburn movie released on VHS in,
wait for it,
1979.
And one year later total Tiffany's doubled.
Rolling into the 80s torrent of Tiffanies,
where the name was Top Twenty for nine out
of ten years.
The Tiffany ascendancy that had started with
Theophany, in prehistory.
And that is the tale of Tiffany.
She's carried her neon torch though the ages.
And long make she carry it into the future.
To Tiffany.