There is no greater human joy than waking up to a winter wonderland
that with its frosty magic also cancelled school.
Well, no more.
Because schools are cancelling snow days.
Some school systems have decided
This way when there's too much snow
to physically drag students in,
we can still mentally drag them in.
[Grey]
Wha..? Who di...? How...? What kind of villains are you?
Gah! We don't all agree. This is horrifying!
Internet, where are you?
Where's hashtag SaveSnowDays to protect us?
[Boring Bureaucrat]
Shhhh, we don't need that.
[Grey]
No! You can not take away the human experience of being
on a dark winter's night unable to face the next day.
Then when thin clouds appear on the horizon giving you faint hope.
You beg with all of your belief to make it happen.
And when it does happen, it is the most epic experience of low to high
combining the triple joys of snow and freedom and
gettingoutofsomethingthatyoutotallyshouldnthave.
There are only so many of days of such great glory in a human life.
But, say some school boards,
And I fear this snow day cancellation pestilation will spread
because the school system with its bureaucracies
and committees loves its checkboxes checked,
its percentages maxed, and its attendance punch cards punched.
Snows days mess all that up.
So the system,
wielding the ultimate banality of evil,
cancels snow days.
Look, I'm just going to say it.
Yes, I am going to play the won't somebody please think of the children card.
[under his breath]
teenagers, I know you hate this, but its in your best interest to roll with it.
But seriously, protecting snow days is what this card was made to play.
Those who want to cancel snow days
should be forced to look into the wide, excited eyes of a little girl,
waking up to experience her very first snow day and tell her,
[Boring Bureaucrat]
No! you can't play outside.
[Wide-eyed little Girl]
Why?
[Boring Bureaucrat]
Because it's super important that today,
right now,
you learn about what a newspaper frontage, in England,
three hundred years ago, thought was important
and you also must know the French conjugation of the verb "to have fun."
[Boring Bureaucrat]
This... this is what matters.
[Grey]
If you can do that,
while thinking you are doing good,
you are a heartless monster extinguishing the light of a child.
A child who, while on their kiddie conference call,
with their ikkle headset, listening to a teacher tell them
will resolve the cognitive dissonance by deciding
And with a sigh say,
No! This shall not pass.
Don't cancel snow days.
Cancel kill joy committees.
Hashtag SaveSnowDays