Getting to space is hard.
Right now it's like going up a mountain
on a unicycle, with a backpack full of explosives:
Incredibly slow, you can't transport a lot of stuff,
and you might die.
A rocket needs to reach a velocity of about 40,000 km/h
to escape from Earth.
To get to that speed, rockets are mostly containers
for fuel with a tiny tip of payload.
This is bad if you want to go to other planets
because you need a lot of heavy stuff if you want to survive
and maybe even come back.
So is there a way to get to space with less fuel
and more payload?
[Intro music]
A nice thing that solved most of our transport problems on Earth
is what you call infrastructure.
Whether it's roads for cars, ports for ships, or rails for trains,
we've made it easier to get to places.
We can apply the same solution to space travel.
Space infrastructure will make getting into orbit
and out to the moon, Mars and beyond easier, and cheaper.
Great, but what exactly is space infrastructure?
Unlike an Earth-space elevator,
which is currently science fiction,
there is a simple yet promising technology
that does not require new science, magic materials,
or huge investments,
and that has been tested successfully in orbit already:
a cable and a weight,
know as a tether.
The concept is so simple, it's surprising.
What if we put tethers
hundreds or thousands of kilometers long into space,
and had spacecraft use them as ladders
to climb to higher altitudes and gain speed?
This concept is known as the Skyhook.
It works even bettter if we make it spin.
A counter-weight holds a long cable in place
while it rotates around a circle.
A rotating tether slows down its tip relative to the ground at the bottom
and speeds it up at the top like a catapult.
This means that you can transfer energy from the tether
and get a massive boost when released, more or less for free,
equal to twice the tether's rotation velocity.
Specialised fibers already exist that can survive
the extraordinary stresses a Skyhook would be faced with.
To protect against cuts and collisions from debris and meteorites,
we can thread our tether into a web of redundant fibers.
Since our Skyhook would pass over the same spot many times a day,
this would allow small, reusable shuttles to catch up with it.
Of course, it's not that easy.
At its lowest point,
the tether's tip is dashing through the atmosphere
at around 12,000 kilometers per hour.
Because of Earth's atmosphere we can't lower the Skyhook too much,
or it will get too hot from air friction.
So it will dip to a height of 80 to 150 km
and no lower.
To match this we'll need specialised spacecraft that can get to the tether.
While this isn't exactly easy,
it's still much cheaper than getting a big tin can
filled with rocket fuel to go 40,000 km/h.
Catching the tip will be a challenge too.
There's only a short time window of 60 to 90 seconds
to find a tiny thing in the sky
moving at mach 12.
To make this easier, the tip could have a sort of fishing line
a kilometer long with a navigation drone that helps the spacecraft to connect.
Another challenge is keeping our Skyhook in orbit.
As more and more ships latch onto it and pull themselves up,
they use up the momentum that keeps it in place.
If we don't do anything
it will slow down and crash into the atmosphere.
And here, we can cheat the universe a bit.
The Skyhook is a battery of orbital energy.
It's possible to balance the payloads coming in and being sent off.
Arriving ships bringing humans and materials home to Earth
add energy to the tether
which it can give to other ships departing into space.
This way the tether doesn't lose any energy.
The more we use it, the cheaper it gets.
If we're still losing energy with each boost,
we can recover it with small electric or chemical engines
that regularly correct the tether's position.
A set of tethers, one around Earth and one around Mars,
could make trips between the planets fast, straightforward,
and low-cost compared to rockets.
The Earth tether would sit in low Earth orbit to grab people and payloads
and fling them off to Mars.
The Mars tether catches them
and slows them down for a landing on the surface.
In the opposite direction,
the tether could pick up a vehicle travelling through Mars's thin atmosphere
at only about 1,000 km/h,
not much faster than our airliners on Earth,
and fling it back to Earth to be caught and lowered down.
The tethers could shorten trips between both planets from 9 months
down to 5 or even 3,
and reduce the scale of the rockets required
by between 84 and 96 percent.
Even better, people may be able to travel in relative luxury,
as we can afford to invest in passenger comfort.
Tether travel would be first class seats to Mars.
Together, tethers around Earth and Mars
could provide the rapid and cost-efficient transportation backbone
that would make space travel affordable.
But let's go further.
Starting from low Mars orbit,
a tether could boost ships to the asteroid belt.
The first craft sent to a new asteroid would need rockets to slow down
at its destination.
Subsequent arrivals might find a tether waiting to catch them
and send them back for free.
Getting to asteroids cheaply
is a major factor in opening up the resources of the solar system.
Precious metals and valuable minerals
could be delivered to Mars just weeks after they were cut out of their asteroid.
They would be the perfect building blocks
for our interplanetary civilisation.
But why stop here?
Mars moons are very convenient.
No other moons in the solar system orbit that close to their planet.
Phobos is so heavy that we don't need to worry about slowing it down,
making it the perfect attachment point
for super tethers just under 6,000 km long.
The lower tip would fly just over the surface of Mars
and be very easy to catch.
The upper tip can fling ships all the way to Jupiter and Saturn.
The same super-tether
can also bring the inner solar system closer.
Venus and Mercury are a single swing away.
Unlike Mars, they're bursting with solar energy
and are rich in minerals.
In the long term, nothing is stopping humanity from
constructing a zero-propellent transport network
for the terrestrial planets centred on the martian moons.
Tethers are a comparably cheap
and sustainable solution to making space travel affordable
and the rest of the solar system accessible
for exploitation and exploration.
Considering that we have the technology to build them today,
there's really no good excuse to wait any longer.
Parts of the solar system are far away,
but they could be very close.
Speaking of stuff that's hard to reach
but doesn't have to be:
knowledge.
Our friends from Brilliant can hook you up to a universe full of explosive ideas and fun courses.
Brilliant is a website that helps you tackle science in a practical way
with interactive problem solving courses
and daily problems in maths, logic and engineering.
Each problem gives you all the tools you need to crack complex topics all by yourself.
It's learning by doing, but with your brain instead of your hands.
Use your curiosity to get to the bottom of puzzles and courses
about things like classical mechanics,
astronomy, gravitational physics, and much more.
If you click the link in the description or visit brilliant.org/nutshell
you can sign up for free and learn more things than you can imagine.
And there's an extra part for Kurzgesagt viewers:
the first 688 people to use the link
get 20% off their annual membership
which lets you view all the daily problems in the archives
and unlock every course.
Brilliant helps you end your day a little smarter.
You might get "hooked" on the experience.
[Outro music]
[Dog howls]