You were on your way home when you passed away.
It was a car accident.
Nothing particularly notable,
however, fatal.
It was a painless death.
The paramedics did what they could to save you,
but to no avail.
Your body was so broken,
that in the end it was for the best, believe me.
And that's how you met me.
- What happened?
Where I am?
- You died - I exclaimed.
- No need to smooth it out.
- There was... there was a truck,
and it was skidding.
- Yes
- Did I die?
- But don't feel bad about it,
everyone dies.
You looked around you,
there was only "nothing".
Just you and me.
- What is this place?
Is this the afterlife?
- More or less
- Are you God?
- Yes, I am God
- My children! My wife!
- What about them?
- They'll be fine?
- That's what I wanted to see - I exclaimed - You just died,
and your biggest concern is your family.
That's wonderful.
You looked at me with fascination,
for you I did not see myself as "God".
I just see myself as
any man or possibly woman.
An authority figure, perhaps.
- Don't worry - I clarified - They'll be fine.
Your children will remember you flawlessly.
They didn't have time to cultivate
resentment towards you.
Your wife will cry on the outside
but will be secretly relieved.
To be fair, your marriage was falling apart.
If it's any consolation,
Ella will feel guilty for her relief.
- Oh, and what will happen now?
Will I go to heaven?
Or to hell or something?
- None.  You will reincarnate
- Oh
, so the Hindus were right?
- All religions have some reason.
Walk with me.
You followed me as we walked in the void.
- Where we go?
- Nowhere in particular.  It's nice to walk
while we chat.
- What's the point then?
When I reincarnate I'll be a blank slate,
right?
A baby.
So, all my experiences and so on,
everything I've done in this life, it doesn't matter.
- Not quite.
You have within you all the knowledge
and experiences of your past lives.
You just don't remember them right now.
I stopped
and hugged you.
- Your soul is even more wonderful,
beautiful and majestic than you can imagine.
The human mind can only contain a tiny fraction
of who you really are.
It is like putting your finger in a glass of water,
to see if it is hot or cold.
You put a small part of yourself in the container,
and when you take it out you have
gained all the experience it offers.
You were inside a human for the last 48 years,
so you haven't yet stretched out
and fallen into the rest of your vast consciousness.
If we stay here long enough, you'll
start to remember everything.
But there's no reason to do that between lives.
- How many times have I reincarnated?
- Many times... many times.
and in different types.
This time you will be a Chinese peasant in 540 AD.
- Wait, what did you say?  Will you send me to the past?
- Technically yes.
Time as you know it only exists in your universe.
Things are different where I come from.
- "From... where do you come from?"
- Oh, of course, I come from somewhere, another place.
And there are others like me there.
I know you'd like to know what that place is like,
but honestly, you wouldn't understand.
- Oh - you exclaimed, somewhat disappointed
- But wait, if I reincarnate in another place and time.
I may have found myself at some point.
- That's right, it happens all the time
And since each life only experiences itself,
you'll never notice.
- So what's the point of existing?
I look into your eyes
- The meaning of life,
the reason for creating this whole universe,
is for you to mature.
- You mean humanity?  Do you want us to grow up?
- Not only you.
I made this whole universe for you.
Every time you reincarnate you grow and mature,
becoming a bigger and better intellect.
- Just me?
What about the others?
- There is no one else.
In this universe it's just you and me.
You look at me stunned.
- But what about the rest of the people on earth?
- They're all you.  Different reincarnations of you.
- Wait, am I everyone?
- Do you understand now.
Am I all the humans who have ever lived...
...and will ever live?
- That's how it is.
- Am I Abraham Lincoln?
- And you're John Wilkes Booth, too.
- I'm Hitler!
You exclaimed in astonishment.
- And you're the millions he killed.
- I'm Jesus!
- And you are each one of his followers.
You kept silent.
Every time you attacked someone,
you attacked yourself.
Every act of compassion,
you did to yourself.
Every happy or sad moment lived by any human,
you will experience it.
You brooded for a long time.
Why?  Why did you do all this?
Because one day you will become me.
Because that is what you are.
You are one of mine.  You are my son.
- Wow!  - you exclaimed incredulously.
- Do you mean I'm a god?
- No not yet.
You are just a fetus,
you keep growing.
Once you have lived each life through time,
you will have grown enough to be born.
- So the whole universe, it
's just...
... an egg.
- I answered.  -
- It's time for you to move on to your next life.
And I sent you on your way.
"The Egg" by Andy Weir.
"Animated by Kurzgesagt"