When our vegetarian ancestors started
eating meat around two million years ago,
it wasn’t just because animals taste great,
it was pure necessity.
Climate change made many of the plants our ancestors
relied on less available, and meat bridged that gap.
From the discovery of fire at the latest,
meat became a staple of the human diet.
But over the last few years, eating meat has increasingly
been associated with health risks like:
heart disease, certain cancers and an early death.
So how unhealthy is meat, really?
In this video, we’ll only talk about meat.
Dairy products deserve a video of their own.
Biologically, we need to eat for three reasons:
for energy, to acquire materials to fabricate our cells,
and to get special molecules that our
bodies can’t make themselves.
The energy and most of the materials come from the
three macronutrients: fats, carbohydrates and proteins.
Proteins are the most important resource for
repairing and replenishing our cell structures.
The special molecules are a large variety of vitamins
and minerals we need to drive metabolic processes.
Meat provides us with most of these things.
It contains all essential amino acids our
body needs, and a lot of minerals like:
iron, zinc and essential vitamins – some of which
are barely found in plants, like Vitamin B12.
Only one essential nutrient is missing in
most of the meat we consume: Vitamin C.
It appears in almost all plants and supports our immune system,
as well as the development of connective tissues.
After a few months without it, you’d get scurvy.
But meat has another big advantage: its high bioavailability.
Some of the nutrients in meat are broken down faster,
and available quicker than those from plants.
Spinach, for example, contains more iron
than meat, but it’s absorbed much slower
and the body needs more energy to digest it.
Several health benefits have also been observed
in communities that rely solely on meat.
The Inuit, for example, are able to survive in extreme
climate conditions, thanks to a purely meat-based diet.
Since they consume the whole animal including the
organs, they get every single nutrient they need,
including Vitamin C.
So meat itself is definitely not dangerous for us,
but its health effects vary depending on how it’s
prepared and what animal it comes from.
When talking about meat in the Western world,
we generally mean muscle tissues that have a high nutrient density,
but also lack some of the vitamins that
make it possible to survive on meat alone.
The most healthy animals to eat are probably fish.
Fish contains polyunsaturated fatty acids like ω-3,
which may lower the risk of cardiovascular diseases and
support anti-inflammatory immune functions.
As part of a balanced diet, fish can be eaten regularly without worries.
Eating fish comes with its own bag of complications though,
like overfishing and the destruction of the oceans.
We’ll talk about that in another video.
A close second is the most popular meat: chicken.
It’s regarded as the meat with the fewest health risks.
The only negative health effect of poultry is a bit controversial:
fat.
Its high content of saturated fats is associated with a
higher cholesterol level and cardiovascular disease.
But this idea has also been criticised by a large number of scientists
arguing high cholesterol levels might be inherited and not caused by nutrition.
So, in general, if you want meat and are
concerned about your health, go for chicken.
Things start to get problematic with high intakes of
red meats like beef, veal, pork, lamb, horse and goat.
A recently published study recommends, for example,
a maximum of twenty-three grams of red meat per day,
which is a very small steak per week.
However, large-scale meta-analysis studies have shown
that eating one hundred grams of red meat every day
increases the risk of diabetes by 19%, of strokes
by 11%, and of colorectal cancer by 17%.
This sounds alarming. But before we panic, let’s
have a look at how these studies were conducted,
because this brings us to the second big problem
when trying to answer the question of
whether meat is unhealthy or not.
Most studies that linked health risks to
eating red meat were case-control studies,
which means taking a group of people with a disease
and classifying them by their eating habits.
The more red meat they consume, the more
likely they were to contract certain diseases.
The problem is that it’s very hard to eliminate other factors.
People who eat less meat tend to
live a healthier lifestyle in general.
They tend to eat more vegetables and fruit,
and are less likely to smoke and drink alcohol.
Most studies try to eliminate these factors, but it’s
extremely hard to make definitive statements.
Things get worse when we look at processed meat, though.
Processing meat means adding certain chemicals by
curing, smoking, sorting or fermenting.
Or in other words, making it delicious.
Bacon, ham, salami, sausages and hot dogs
contain chemicals that are harmful for us,
like nitrates and nitrites that can damage the DNA
in our digestive system and lead to cancer.
The WHO reviewed eight hundred studies over twenty years,
and concluded that processed meat is strongly
linked to an increased risk of colorectal cancer.
Each extra fifty grams of processed meat
per day increases your risk of cancer by 18%.
When it comes to cancer risk, processed meat
is now in the same category as plutonium,
asbestos and smoking.
The WHO highlights that its research is only
about the question of whether or not something
causes cancer, and not to what extent.
But processed meat may also significantly
increase the chance of suffering from
diabetes, strokes and coronary heart diseases.
It also makes a difference what sort of life our
meat lived when it was still part of a living being.
It’s common to feed large amounts of antibiotics to livestock
in order to prevent diseases, which can spread antibiotic resistance.
Combined, a high consumption of both red and processed meat
could increase your chance of premature death by up to 29%.
This means if your chance of dying is at 3% this year, it’s now 4%.
This might not sound like a lot, but tiny percentages
have a huge impact on societies of millions.
They also seem harmless until they affect you.
To blame meat alone for bad health would be wrong, though.
There is no evidence that the very essence of meat
has any negative effect beyond its high fat content.
And even this point is highly contentious.
Just like with many other pleasures in life,
sometimes too much of a good thing is harmful.
Most public health agencies suggest cutting meat
consumption to five hundred grams a week,
while studies suggest cutting down
processed meat as much as possible.
So if you feast on meat no more than once
or twice a week, you should be good.
For most people, this already means
a drastic change in their diets, though.
The average American consumes around almost one
thousand and six hundred grams of meat a week.
The average German one thousand and one hundred a week.
And many of us eat much, much more.
If you’re not really sure, make a small note
whenever you eat meat for a week or two.
You’ll be surprised how much it really is.
So most people watching this video would
benefit from cutting down on meat.
Aside from health concerns,
there’s still the fact that the meat industry is one
of the largest contributors to climate change,
and has reached a scale where it’s impossible
to deliver millions of tonnes of meat
and still treat animals with dignity.
We’ve already discussed that in detail in another video.
All in all, in moderation, meat is not unhealthy and
you don’t need to become vegetarian overnight
to have a real impact on your health and the planet.
But your lifestyle choices do matter,
for yourself and for others.
They key is being open to trying something new once in a while.
Maybe you’ll discover your new favourite dish.
Until you try, you’ll never know what you’ll enjoy or what you’re capable of.
Maybe after watching hours of Kurzgesagt videos,
you decided you’d like to learn how to animate.
Now you might not know this, but most of our
team actually has a graphic design background.
Learning about design principles first before we go into
animation today was really key to where we are today.
There’s a really great new Skillshare class on using Adobe Illustrator,
the software we use to create artwork,
by graphic designer Aaron Draplin,
and we can personally recommend it.
It’s full of great tips to help understand
and simplify a very complicated program.
If you want to do more afterwards, we have these
animation courses of our own on Skillshare, too.
Skillshare offers over twenty-five thousand classes on topics
like film and video editing, writing, design, and
technology, from an array of skilled experts.
With the Premium Membership, you can access
all of them for only ten dollars a month.
And, as a bonus, the first one thousand Kurzgesagt
viewers to use the link in the description
will get their first two months of Skillshare for free.