Again I hear that whisper of the surf. Who am I?
Where my heart is, only water knows!
A hundred times I promised them not to argue, but
The sea draws me back as if I were its wave.
Every new step, every turn.
Every trace and every sign leads me again.
Into a world of great winds and bottomless waters.
I want to sail away...
And in my eyes every day an ocean boundless
Calls me over the horizon!
I wish I could set sail for the long haul.
He will show all that has been waiting for me there for so long.
Life on the island goes on and on forever.
And people have joy day in and day out.
Everyone knows what their part is, Everyone plays their part.
And maybe I'll have mine.
I will be a chief, I will lead the people!
We shall prosper from year to year.
But that's not what my heart sings about.
What's wrong with me?
I see the sun's way on crystal waves.
It's leading me.
And I know it wants to tell me his secrets.
So go ahead!
Take the first step, conquer your fear!
And in the eyes every day an ocean boundless.
I'm calling out over the horizon
I wish I could set sail and go far away
It will show all that has been waiting for me