Alone again! On horseback again!
Though I don't think it's a sin to love to ride.
But I say, for example, it's time you had some restraint.
You're seventeen years old now!
But still not 117!
Oh, uncle, don't lecture me!
How will you dress, Shurochka?
- You've decided to shine, haven't you? - It's no secret.
- I don't know, somehow... It's time to decide.
I'll still have time. The guests will not soon be in attendance.
The whole neighborhood is talking about the ball.
Ah, I have an idea!
I'll put on a costume to show you a fancy dress...
Hee-hee, you little brat!
Three thousand devils!
My dear!
Report that Brigadier Rzhevsky's nephew...
He has the honor to be with the Major's letter.
Well!!! Well, go on, why are you looking at me like a carrot?
I have an honor - Lieutenant Rzhevsky!
Are you a cornet?
- Ah... Mmm... Your uniform is Pavlogradsky, of course!
- No!... I mean, yes! - What a surprise!
Please accept my brotherly salute to the cornet!
A hussar is a hussar's friend! Isn't it always true?
However, what brings you here?
Mmmm... Perhaps, by the will of providence, you're related to your masters?
- I... yes... - So much the better!
You will tell the truth about them now, without delay!
- I am ready to serve! - Well, in short, here...
The maiden Alexandra lives here, Like a certain Russian rose.
Ah, Shurochka! And she's my... cousin!
So fry everything you know about her.
It's very important to me! Since my childhood days, I am, so to speak...
I'm engaged to her in absentia. Have you heard, perhaps? If she's her cousin?
That's right, I've heard of the affair.
- Is that you, then? - Alas, my friend.
- Why "alas"? - You're pontificating, of course.
- Mmm.... I mean, yes! - You'll understand me then!
I'm a gambler, I'm a gambler, I'm a gambler, I'm a gambler.
But my uncle, an old fart, helped me out, On the condition...
...that I should marry now.
I gave my word without looking, I was desperate...
Or maybe I was drunk and out of my mind.
But now, alas, there's my reckoning.
- I sympathize with you. - But is she rich?
- Tell me? - Not at all.
But I don't care if I sink in the sand or in the rocks.
- And if, for instance... What say you, cornet?
If your cousin does not like you, Lieutenant?
You are a green cornet. Hussars are not green...
They know not the word "no" in love.
And if I dare enter the gates of hell...
Any woman would be glad to be my friend.
But I want to know what she is, your cousin. Is she not pretty?
- Oh, no! - Pretty?
- I know not what to say. - Not so, not so. That's what I expected.
She's what they call in the world, a prude...
The word "ideal" never leaves her lips.
She's fidgety and bawdy and silly, But she can grind rye with her tongue.
- You, however, judge very wickedly. - Cornet, I am older than you.
I know women better.
You must have had too much luck with them.
If I had wanted, I would have had occasion to marry a hundred times...
But I've kept my freedom!
- Are you as careful in battle? - CORNET!!!
I did not mean to offend you, Lieutenant. Forgive me...
Tell me, tell me in honor...
Have you no amorous business with my wife?
- I hope... I swear, Lieutenant, I have not yet shaved...
Where shall I go to steal the hearts of fair fairies?
- You moustachioed love-mongers have your hands full! - From now on I'll bail you out!
- I'm very glad to meet you. - And I am a cornet. A hussar is a brother to a hussar!
Lieutenant Rzhevsky.
Here you are, at last, my light.
- Have you seen your niece? - No, I haven't.
I haven't seen you in a long time.
Yes, there's a ball in our house.
The bride is on her seventeenth birthday.
You are asked to order in the kitchen For the sauce - what kind of broth?
- Lieutenant Rzhevsky. - That's him.
- I'm glad. - I'm happy... very me...
In my own way, forgive me. Keep each other busy.
Are you now coming to us from St. Petersburg or Moscow?
My voyage is from Moscow.
How do you like our quiet city?
You live in it, that's enough to make you like it.
You are too kind.
Hussars are used to speak plainly.
What book do you like?
For example, Quarissa.
The other novels are no match, are they?
How? I'm sorry, I haven't read it.
Will you be with us long?
I've got a month's leave from the regiment.
Yes, a month is running out.
What kind of silks would you prefer for this drawing?
Renge and Bordeaux are in fashion these days.
I dare not advise you. Blue is the prettier of the two.
Not you! Not you! Blue is out of tune, Bordeaux here, and gray thereafter.
- Well, as you like. - Thank you.
Would you like me to give you a pillow? When it's ready.
No, I'm not worthy of such a favor.
I embroidered it with my own hand. Although, alas, it's not a new one.
Let me ask you another question.
- Do you like to cry? - Do I? Ha!
There's nothing in the world sweeter than pure tears.
- Have you read Werther? - No. I haven't read that one either.
- You must read it, Charmaine. - Where is your uncle?
Perhaps you have dreamed with the subject of your heart...
...to sit by the sad moon?
And shed tears in perfect sorrow?
If you have dreamed, I'll tell you a secret.
Sir, the gentleman asks you to his office.
Count Nourin!
Count, we weren't expecting you at all, Such a surprise at our ball.
Such an honor. You know each other?
My niece.
О! Alas. You must have been a child when I left your land.
I wouldn't be surprised if you'd forgotten.
- Well, what of Paris? - Oh, it's paradise
Tell me, is it true that this autumn the French will be at war with us?
Cédreux... There will be no war at all! I think, though I am no coward...
We can't compete with Europe. Is it possible?! La France and us?
No, the best minds in the world would not advise us to fight.
I left you the last cotillion.
I'm happy!
Between the figures let's end our conversation about perfect tears.
I wish I could persuade you, if you don't agree.
There's half a chapter like that in Wurtar...!
- Ah... - Mm-mm!!!
Oh, Shurochka, sing us a verse, What the Lieutenant sang last time.
- At the governor's. - Now?
- Oh, yes. - That's what we're all asking.
/Singing/: Young Pretty Woman, I bid you farewell.
Let a bullet of good fortune cut my way on earth.
If I should fall, in unequal battle...
...but, Armida, remember, remember my short life.
In the bloody saddle my horse bears me.
To the tender green maples From a strange fire.
"My hussar's tunic is on fire, Opened from the shoulder...
...In crimson yellow light, the light of the last ray.
The sunset with its invisible hand Blesses me.
And the memorial willow tree rustles softly...
...There is no higher place in the world To dream, to love and to sing.
And in my native land, in my native land, to fight and die.
- Lovely! - Cut. Sharman.
You should be an actor, Shura.
Their whole life is an affair.
No, it's not my nature.
I'll be back in my masquerade costume.
Mazurka. Madame Angéozhe!
Well, finally, cornet, where have you disappeared to?
I've been looking for you everywhere. It's so boring here.
I'm at your service, sir, all the way. But is it possible to be bored at a ball?
I'll have to reproach my cousin, for she's kept you badly occupied.
I have taken much from her. I'll never forget this day.
By the way, you spoke to her, didn't you?
- Who? - My cousin, damn it.
When I think of her, I feel sick in the back of my head.
Yeah! You played the snake, didn't you?
...and I got all her impressions of the groom candidate.
И? She's in love with him, isn't she?
She's all "ha-ha" and "hee-hee" and "hee-hee-hee.
No, she didn't like you terribly.
What do you mean, she didn't like you?
She said you complimented her in vain.
I did?
She said she had never met a cheekier man.
I beg your pardon, you've got a moustache hanging like a bastard...
What?! You're as bold as she is! I am!... I am!!!
That from manners one can see the habit of horses.
I will not give one mare for a hundred such maidens!!!
That of all the familiar faces she hath not seen, pardon me, a nastier snout.
Aye? A thousand devils! Maybe it's for the best.
If you don't like him, you can't marry him.
Not a bit. She also said...
...that it is no longer for her to change my uncle's will.
That if he commanded it, she would go for the beast.
That she can even train bears.
Enough! I trust you now as a brother.
You are my first friend among all men.
Well, you're a wiggler! Fool! Sour girl.
So, you've decided not to get married?
I wish I could. But I gave my word to my uncle.
I owe him a debt. And with this I pay my debt.
Don't be discouraged at the masquerade! Come, let us dance.
No. I will have a drink with you on the brotherhood.
There's a lovely cliquot here.
Your offer is too flattering.
- But we are of different ranks. - For pity's sake, what nonsense!
Know that wherever a hussar's spurs ring, there's equality.
Attention, gentlemen, I ask for everyone's attention.
Trouble has come upon our homeland.
A storm of war has covered our skies.
On the thirteenth day, Bonaparte's armies have crossed the Neman.
The moment of trial is at hand.
I hope all of you will faithfully do your duty.
All officers, please return to the regiment.
Very well!
We'll meet the hour with dignity.
I beg you, ball, now I'll stop.
- Forgive me, my friend. - Ah, your lordship, what are you.
You're ready to die for your country. There's no happier part under the moon...
Than to die for my country! Isn't that so, Cornet?
- I'll take my leave. - I know it's not my destiny.
Write, my friend.
With you, cornet, we'll find each other.
If we shall not be killed in the war, When our victories shine...
Will you not bid farewell to your cousin? Shall I call?
I will not. I am not worthy of this maiden.
Tell her I bow. Let me kiss thee, in love.
Ah, Shurochka.
Pardon me, the costume is excellent, bravo. And in the spirit of the day.
Lovely, isn't it?
We've been talking amongst ourselves, How we can help the troops.
We've decided to make a corpse out of rags...
- For the infirmary. - Tomorrow at five.
*What did he say? ♪ There's no greater battle for my country under the moon ♪
*♪ If it were up to me, I'd want to die ♪
To die in battle. On a war horse, flying like the wind.
Oh, young lady, what wonders in the world, a hussar. And the posture's perfect.
I wish you had a horse. And a foam on your muzzle. And a sabre, and you'd be on parade.
I'd be glad to serve as such a young man again, though I've served much.
Go to bed. They've all gone from the ball.
Tell me, would you serve with me again, if I were a man?
I begged the master to let me go, if I had reason to be choked, that the enemy was coming to my country.
I'd like to be in battle once more. To shed blood for my people.
Take me with you! I do not laugh!
A hussar before you! I know how to shoot, you taught me!
You just said I should have a horse. I've made up my mind, there's no more way for me!
Are you jesting with an old man? I'll tell the lord to look after you.
You can't stop me with words. If you forbid me, I'll run away all the same.
There's only one thing on Russians' minds now: How to save my homeland.
And I'm here with needlework and dolls.
No, I want to try what I'm worth. And in battle!
And if I'm killed, blame yourself for my death. I didn't want to be my orderly.
To fight with me in the war! Well, farewell!
You'll be recognized!
Fear not, old man, no one will know. So I must go away alone?
God owns the brave. What about my uncle?
He'll go mad if he doesn't find you at the manor in the morning.
A maiden to the camp. And he's all about the wedding.
I'll write to him from the road.
Well, what are you sitting there?
Tell him to lock the doors. I'll go out the window.
Forgive me, according to the Christian faith, If I am foolishly guilty.
I'm ready to serve as a Suvorov soldier.
We'll leave now. I'll wait here for you.
- Saddle your horse. - I'll not deceive you.
# Farewell to my old home, perhaps forever #
*♪ Here my years flowed without a care ♪
*♪ Here I grew up and played and played and played ♪
*Was a child. ♪ I'm a grown-up now ♪
*♪ Say good-bye to my dear, kind, old home ♪
/ Sings a lyrical song:/ Moonlit meadows, The night is as bright as day.
Sleep, my Svetlana, Sleep as I slept.
# In the corner of the pillow, tuck your nose in... #
The stars, like freckles, Shine down peacefully.
The moonlit garden rustles quietly in its leaves.
The day is coming, What does it promise?
The candle burns out, It burns to the ground.
Sleep, my heart, Sleep as I slept.
I hear the noise of battle.
Yes, the army is near. What do you say? Where are you from and who are you?
I'll say I'm behind the regiment. That I want to fight
I want to fight again. No one will reproach me for lying.
Oh, young lady. Do you see there in the rye?
What's the matter with you, Captain?
I have a bullet in my chest.
I have with me a packet of the most important report.
Cornet, I beseech you to finish the task given me by the field-marshal.
and set forth at once. Across the river, our rearguard is fighting Murat.
I'll prove myself trustworthy.
Come, cornet. Ride, God be with you.
He is badly wounded. Stay with him, Ivan.
But, young lady...
Look. See you, Captain!
A package for you, your lordship, from the field marshal.
What, blood? Are you not wounded, Cornet?
It is the messenger's blood. He gave me this packet.
The packet was on his breast, but the bullet pierced his chest.
My friend, we are, unfortunately, at war. And you are a cornet, a cavalryman of talent.
I would gladly take you on. Will you be my junior adjutant at headquarters?
I'm glad.
Murat's gone round, he wants to surround us.
The field marshal has ordered us to retreat.
/There once was Henri the Fourth, He was a glorious king.
He loved wine to hell, but he was sober at times.
La-la, boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom.
La-la, boom-boom-boom-boom, boom-boom-boom, boom-boom-boom-boom.
He loved war, and he fought like a rooster.
And in hand-to-hand combat, he was worth two.
La-la, boom-boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom.
La-la, boom-boom-boom-boom, boom-boom-boom, boom-boom-boom-boom.
One day an old lady came after him with a stick...
...and he struck her in the ear with his knightly hand.
La-la, boom-boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom.
La-la, boom-boom-boom-boom-boom.
But death, full of treachery, has been waiting for him.
She stabbed him with her knife from around the corner.
La-la, boom-boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom. La-la, boom-boom.
La-la, boom-boom-boom-boom-boom, boom-boom-boom, boom-boom-boom-boom.
"The blood spurted from his veins.
And the wicked old man Died as he lived.
La-la, boom-boom-boom.
La-la, boom-boom-boom-boom-boom, boom-boom-boom, boom-boom-boom-boom.
I came from headquarters with the relay.
Oh, you came? Who do you want?
I'm the adjutant.
I can see it in your eyes that you're an adjutant.
- Who shall I hand this package to? Vasilyev on reconnaissance.
And the assistant? Who can I give this order to?
About the assistant, it's easier than that. Lieutenant! To you!
And I'll ask you to stand in front of the headquarters!
/Great laughter/
HQ again? You'd better send some vodka.
What a meeting! Is that you? Lieutenant...
Where are you from, brother, and what's your fate? I didn't think I'd meet you here.
I didn't recognize you at once. But you have come at a good hour.
They know each other!
I brought you orders from the corps headquarters.
I don't give a damn about orders. Gentlemen! Cornet Azarov! My old friend.
Love and respect to the Hussar!
We are glad to see you!
We're always happy to invite you to our tight bivouac circle.
- The hospitality of the partisans is well known. - Is the porridge ready?
We ask you to share our breakfast with your new friends.
By any chance did you bring a bottle with you?
No. I guess you haven't had much experience as an officer.
So, tell me about yourself, Cornet. How are you doing?
Quite happy with my service.
Yes, my cousin asked me to say hello if I meet you.
Well, I beg your friendship, don't think of her.
- Who's that cousin? - I've got Rzhevsky. - Here's your answer.
It's embarrassing to think of that meeting.
Hey, you white-haired bastard.
- It's nothing, really. - We know those tricks.
All right, I'll tell you! He's the witness.
My uncle, the foreman, has decided to marry me.
That's the sorriest day I've ever known. The bride, my God... I'm in a cold sweat.
Is she so ugly?
It's true to say, I think she's a freak of note.
- What are you, cornet? - No, you're not fair! She's pretty!
What are you saying? Her nose is like a plum, her eyes are like a plum, her braids are like bunting.
What a scarecrow.
She's a fool! Isn't she? But she's not ugly! I'll vouch for that.
Our tastes are different, then. In your way, but in general it's disgusting.
And what's most unpleasant, you may imagine, is that she fell in love with me at once.
- What are you cornet? - No, nothing!
There was a ball in the evening! She wandered after me like a shadow everywhere. She never took her eyes off me.
Admit it, Rzhevsky, you didn't tell us everything.
I suppose you kissed her in a ballroom whirl, In some secluded corner...
I, gentlemen, am afraid to be immodest, but I have kissed...
- What's the matter, cornet? - Nay, nothing.
There's no great sin in it, and I could not rightly
when she was about to tear herself from her dress!
Well, good fellow, eh?
I hate with a passion the priggish, sour, sour woman.
If such a one were in trouble, I'd not lift a hand
I would not lift a hand to avert the danger.
What if my cousin were in trouble? Would you not feel pity for her?
- Certainly not! - I'll wager you! I'll wager you!
- You! - You! You slander for nothing!
I'll wager with you that if the occasion should come...
That I'll save a fashionable woman with my own hand, I'll...
You must marry her!
Damn it, that'll never happen!
I'll ask our hands to separate!
There's a French wagon train crawling through the woods!
Follow me, my friends, we'll treat them to Russian!
What's in here? Carpets and piles of silk. Weapons? That's a good one for us, by the way.
There's more trophy there. Wow, hussars rejoice, wine!
Cheers!
Wait! If my eyes do not lie, Germont Louise! Gentlemen, am I dreaming or am I delirious?
- This way, Germont! - From where?
It's very nice, but you're not happy, I see.
I would sooner believe in a bird that suddenly popped out of a brook, ...
Than in this, on the road, here, the goddess of dreams, the dream of fairies. And this is a dream.
Flattery is nice to me. That's me.
Quick, where's Lymov?! Come here! I know you, don't I?
I was a slave to your beauty, wasn't I, last fall.
But tell me more clearly, where are you from? At least the gist of it.
You're spinning on pins and needles, Lieutenant. Let me breathe.
But we will not let the French have you now. Won't we, brothers?
My God. From now on, I have no desire to return to them myself.
Hurrah for Germont! Hurray for Germont!
/ Singing:/ When the punch of purple flames All around again, all around again illuminated.
The chorus of the beloved shall be sung again.
A long time ago, a long time ago, a long time ago!
We're all a little superstitious, But we believe hard, we believe only in wine.
In it we drown all our chimeras.
A long time ago, a long time ago, a long time ago!
The glory of the smoke hangs over us, And only, only one thing torments us.
Hearts without practice rust.
A long time ago, a long time ago, a long time ago!
In battles, not in bed, To part
with life, we are destined to part.
The popes must have been singing us off.
A long time ago, a long time ago, a long time ago!
For the Motherland, Mother Russia!
I, gentlemen, want to say, In many countries I have played,...
But it's only here with you that I cherish my success. I love you all!
Russia has become dear to me, too.
- Yay, Germont! - Now it's your turn to sing.
- Please! - Yes.
No, you're right, gentlemen. I have forgotten everything.
Your memory has always been bad.
Oh no. I remembered one verse.
But don't judge too harshly - War, excitement, the road.
/ Sings: / Call me, my beloved. Forget all that was, my beloved.
Let's forget what happened, my beloved. There is no power more miraculous than the power of love.
Let the wine splash, I drink, it's not enough for me. I drink, I'm not enough, I'm drunk.
I drink, all I can't get enough, I'm already drunk. And the hall is spinning, I drink all I can't get enough.
I'm not drinking enough, I'm already drunk, And the hall is spinning, I don't care anymore!
And if it's the end, I won't cry. I'll tell you without deceit, I won't cry.
I'll tell you without deceit, I won't cry. There's a bottom to the cup, and in the muzzle is lead!
I'm drinking, I'm drinking, I'm drinking, I'm drinking, I'm drinking, I'm drinking, I'm drunk.
I drink all I can't get enough, I'm already drunk, And the hall is spinning, I drink all I can't get enough.
I'm not drinking enough, I'm already drunk, And the hall is spinning, I don't care anymore!
- Bravo! Bravo! - You are worthy to be a goddess!
Don't lose your head, brother.
And I have no pity for you, Louise, All is nothing before you!
The fortune teller is destined to love the brown-haired girl.
- You what? - No, nothing! Sit down, Cornet.
Lymov, I'll tell you a secret, If you're a faithful friend.
I love you more and more every hour.
I don't like actresses! First of all. And secondly... I forgot. Pour it!
Fortune-tellers always lie! For you, Lieutenant, I speak now!
He's very nice.
He's just a boy. No, give me your elbow.
- It's too much. - You're not jealous?
Oh, not at all.
I've never drunk so much in my life I swear on my life, my life...
...Was... Yes, I was! I'll sing!
- You? Yes, now! Please be quiet!
- We ask! - Just don't fake it.
- He's so full of youth. - Mademoiselle, I was listening to you.
/ Singing in a drunken voice:/ They call me a youth without youth. I don't care, I don't care, I don't care!
At least they don't call me a coward!
A long time ago, a long time ago, a long time ago!
Otherwise he twirls his whiskers furiously, Bottles to all, bottles to all, looks at the bottom of them all.
But he himself is only a copy of the Hussar.
A long time ago, a long time ago, a long time ago!
And some swear by passion, But when the wine has been drunk, when the wine has been drunk...
...All his passion is at the bottom of the bottle.
A long time ago, a long time ago, a long time ago!
The sea is knee-deep in lovers. I am with them in this, with them in this.
But treason is waiting for everyone.
A long time ago, a long time ago, a long time ago!
- What's wrong with him? - It's not good.
- Azarov! - Water!
We old hobos don't care about this feast now, do we?
Now, unbutton that uniform.
No, no!!! Я.. I'm a little hot.
I don't like women, though.
How your eyes shine brightly.
- Lieutenant! - Just a kiss, please.
No, no.
Deserve what? Idea! I'll be right back.
Pierre. Do you really not even want to say a word to me?
Believe me...
There's no need to go on, everything is clear without words.
My friend, do you want the truth?
No, I'm not playing this game anymore, I don't want truth or lies.
But, Pierre, please.
I ask you as much, in my life do not confuse me.
- You will be sorry. - Maybe. But even then I won't change.
- Pierre, I have been faithful to you, I swear. - Let's keep our vows, too.
- Here's my surprise! - Flowers? Where did you get them?
In the midst of winter such a miracle? Lieutenant! I promised you nothing.
Have mercy!
I want to give the flowers to the one who is the dearest of you all.
- It's a custom in Provence. - My flowers? But why?
And she will give it to Lymov.
Pour me some more wine. Cornet, I drink a glass to you!
Give me the flower now. Give it to me now!
At least you'll concede. A hop hit him in the head.
- He is devilishly hot in resentment. - Thank you, mademoiselle!
All right! Please come to the barrier. I challenge you! Yes, yes!
Are you silent? The rank of officer, you coward, is not worthy then.
I ask to be my second. Pierre Lymov, you as well as you!
But he is on duty as an adjutant to leave us tomorrow.
Immediately we will fight!
- But where? - Over there!
- However, brothers, how is it possible? - Here, now, a duel?
- Please... No, mademoiselle!
To the barrier!
God... Atonement, I will kiss you myself.
Shit... I'm losing my mind. I am willing to forgive the insult.
But I don't need your condescension!
- What a mess. - Told you I was sorry.
No! If you're not willing to shoot You must ask my forgiveness!
In Russia there will never be this compote, That I ask for forgiveness!
Yes! Shoot here and now!
Another warning. Will you friends make peace after all?
- Oh, you shouldn't have. - I have been insulted here.
Get together! I count. One.
Two.
Three.
- Davyd! - Colonel!
- What's going on here? - A duel with this dandy.
How dare you, in time of military action? In the hour of our fatherland's distress.
Is not occasion enough for another firing? Stand down!
If I hear again of this scandalous cause, I'll punish you with a fitting punishment.
I'll punish him without regard to valor or rank. Where did this cornet come from?
I have brought you a packet from corps headquarters.
You, cornet, have you no other amusement here than to duel?
Bah. What do I see? Are you, mademoiselle? Where did you come from?
Where the devil did you come from? Am I dreaming?
- No, it's me. - It's the wonder of wonders!
Sheherazade in the midst of my hangers-on.
Friends, the field marshal thanks us!
- Himself? - Yes!
- Here's the signature, "N. Kutuzov"! -Oh, really?
Let me see!
If we all beat the French like you, the enemy would be defeated!
It's the partisans' habit to fight without fear of death.
- We beat our enemies wherever we meet them! - Long time ago, long time ago!
Colonel! I beg you. Can't you find a place in the detachment for a cornet?
- I mean, for you? - Yes.
No, my friend, alas. A cornet in a detachment is a bad omen.
Thank you, my brave savior.
Accept my heartfelt gratitude.
But how did you do it?
It all worked out, didn't it? Here at headquarters, you'll find everything you need.
I must go. Excuse me, service.
I'm the adjutant of the sovereign, Count Bolmashov.
See you soon, my brave hero. From now on, I'm forever in your debt.
But I am not accustomed to be long in debt.
- What's your name? - It's Count, it doesn't matter!
- Is Bolmashov still asleep? - He's snoring all over the place.
He must be dreaming sweet dreams when he's frightened.
Ah, Count. - Has the Field Marshal arrived? - We're waiting.
Oh, the cornet at last. What about Zharovsky?
- He sent a package to the Field Marshal. - Is he tired?
- No. Just a little. Wash your face... You can rest from the road.
How long has this valiant cornet been with you?
Since the beginning of summer. His name is Azarov,
He's a fine-looking boy. Only seventeen years old.
But he's a good match for some of the old soldiers. What do you see in him?
I have a suspicion I've met him.
- So what of it? - Nothing, of course.
Only I was less prepared to see him here.
I'm pretty tired from that walk. I'll sigh before the parade.
Give these buns to the prisoners.
I wish this chair were closer to the stove.
And a lower curtain, like this.
I've heard that General Bolmashov is here.
I know of his adventure.
Well, I have no more errands to run. Go, all of you.
/ Snore
Ahem.
- What's that for you, young man? - A package from Count Zharovsky to you personally!
- Come on. What's your name? - Azarov.
Well, that's good. Is Azarov Staff-Major your father?
No, my uncle.
He and I fought together at Ishmael against
against the Turks. Yes. That was years ago.
But our opponent is more famous. Bonaparte himself. How was it? Am I all right?
Very well, Your Grace.
It is. I think it's fine. Your first year in the service?
Your Grace, my first.
And all at headquarters? It must be boring, isn't it?
I couldn't have lasted a week at your age.
- I dare say... - Just give it up.
You can't get your hands dirty in ink. Smell the gunpowder! Yes.
- You've guessed my dream. - That's right.
- Do you want me to leave? - Wait while I read it.
Prince, when I hear that you are here, I want to lay down at your feet.
- HQ? - I am here in the militia.
Our nobility is Svarecki of Alov province, representative of Nurin Count.
I have a question for you, a secret one, so to speak.
Well, what's the secret?
Go away for a minute, cornet, if the count asks it.
Check it out for yourself, Prince.
And I'll vouch for you. All hussars have moustaches, but this cornet...
I'll ask him myself. But in the meantime, don't say a word about the staff.
I swear to you, Prince. I'll be as hot as an oven.
Send him to me.
- You called, Your Grace? - Yes, Cornet.
- Tell me, how old are you? - Seventeen.
Aren't you afraid to fight in the war? Tell me without lying.
- Oh, Your Grace, no! - I cannot lie.
I dare not lie!
And if you dare not lie, then tell me...
No, wait.
- What is your name, by the way? - According to my uncle, my name is Alexander.
Right. Alexander? When you were a kid, was it Sashka?
No. Shurka, Your Grace.
Verkhalyov was in this room just now. Don't you know him? He's yours, from Smolensk.
No!
Hasn't he been to your uncle's house before? On occasions?
Go on. No, wait! One more question.
Don't be surprised if... Well, cornet, are you a woman?!
I can't lie to you, Your Grace. I am a woman.
What? How dare you? To make a comedy out of military honor?
I wanted to be a hero. If my country's in trouble, I have no strength to be at home.
No, Mother, you can't fool me! To make a woman a soldier!
Without such help, we'd have broken Bonaparte's legs!
And we'll drive him out of Russia without women! What trick did you use to get into the headquarters?
I have a cousin. He was with us in winter. He left his uniform...
Home! To madams, nannies, rags, dolls, dances!
Yes. You'll have to get out of here at once! Your uncle doesn't know, does he? Are your parents alive?
I've been an orphan since childhood.
Right. Well, how could you do this deception? A uniform without the right to take it.
May I say, Your Grace?
No, I will not! I won't listen to a maiden's babble. Yes.
The nonsense of the staff already makes my ears grow dull
of the staff's nonsense enough as it is. Yes. I should feel pity for them at my age.
And if the eyes are sharp, the hands are faithful in their sights, and the stirrups are not weak?
And if all - mind, heart, strength, nerves - ask for orders?
For thee, country, mother country, to give all for thee. And if...
I beg you, speak briefly. I am old, mademoiselle. I'm tired of speeches.
And besides, I don't take lectures from young ladies.
Off you go. I tell you, the ball is over. Go now.
- Let me stay. - There's nothing to think of.
Well, I beg you, Prince... Well, Your Grace...
I'm on my knees now! I beg you... I, I...
Here come the tears in two streams.
If anyone comes in... What do you want them to know about you? Я... I don't want to.
Stay here in the hall until the tears are gone. Stop...
I want to ask you something else. Did you go to the army, of course, to get a lover?
I don't believe in sinlessness. I've sinned myself.
- What? - My tears are dry all of a sudden.
Have I offended you? Well, pardon the old man, my friend. But I'm going home tonight. That's not the point.
No report for you, Your Grace.
- Sit down, General. - From the Emperor.
Did you hear the scandal that happened to me?
Yes, it's not good. With a letter like that... Why didn't you have an escort?
I had an escort, but not a big one, alas. If it hadn't been for that young cornet.
The prince, imagine, no. He rode off without telling me his name.
He was in a hurry with his errand. He's just a boy.
That's the kind of boy who makes heroes out of his fatherland.
Yes, Russia. In my mind, the Cross should be awarded to him for this deed.
Are you still here? Go, and be gone by evening.
My respects to your uncle. I'll write to him.
Forgive me, for God's sake. I did not recognise you, my brave friend.
But why are your eyes red?
I guess there's a storm coming over you, my humble hero.
By the way, Your Grace, I remember you wished to give him a cross for his deed just now.
The prince must not retreat. He hath redeemed the provinces by his deed.
And by the article should be awarded the Cross of St. George and the bow.
Without him, I'd never be alive. Well, Prince! Don't you appreciate at all...
...the life of an imperial adjutant? You're welcome to it.
You've earned the cross by right for your exploits. Well, wear it with glory.
I congratulate you.
Let me go. I'll stay at headquarters until the parade.
We shall meet again.
I want no reward other than the right to fight in the war for my country.
- Let me ask you for this award. - If you've earned it, wear it!
That's no way to throw crosses. It's not a hairpin. Say thank you to the general.
- May I stay? - And if anyone finds out?
Like this count, that you... Well, not a man?
I've been here six months. No one in that time has suspected neither face nor rank.
And you will tell the count that he was deceived.
Yes. They've been round me on every side. Well... Serve.
The rank that you have worn so illicitly, it shall be yours.
But don't throw it like a cross. It's not a comb. Off you go, then.
- Thank you, Your Grace. - I'll keep my secret.
I swear I'll keep my military honor! I'll justify your trust.
I do. I do! Go.
- Well? - There's a count at the door.
Well, stay here.
Count! Your anecdote, as I thought it would be, is nonsense.
You should joke so low with an adjutant, not with me.
My God, what a passage. I swear it, Your Grace.
All right, all right. But don't joke so much again.
Gee...
Oh, it's you, Davyd. Well, brag. I love your lies. Who's that with you?
- Lieutenant Rzhevsky! - You look like a hero.
He'll be the first to fight.
I've heard about your desperation. A hero, a hero.
- I am flattered by your trust. - You've lived up to it more than once in battle.
Aye. Well done! You would have been a prettier wench.
- Oh, is that you? - Yes, it's me. Bonjour, Lieutenant.
All the staff business?
Business, don't get any better. How was your affair with Mademoiselle Germont?
Haven't you heard? The squad was surrounded. Her enemies took her back the same night.
Oh, my God, and you ran away?
Three thousand! We'll duel again when we first meet.
Well. You will not have long to wait. I'm joining your troop from headquarters.
I have a riddle to solve. I give you my word that I will keep the secret. Are you or aren't you?
Am I or am I not? But this is new. I am me.
I'm in a hurry now, alas, I have no time for chatter. Goodbye, dear Count!
But still, am I right or am I wrong?
I have taken a prisoner. Of manners, I judge an officer.
Tell me your rank.
Lieutenant. Let me give it back to you From my heart I thank you, forever your friend.
What is the meaning of this oath all of a sudden?
I gave him my coat to keep him warm.
- Are you French? - No, I am a Spaniard.
He is no coward. The cold made him shoot wrong. His hand was shaking.
This is the first time I've met such an enemy. I am glad now that I have not killed you in battle.
Tell me your part. Well, answer me.
I will not answer that question.
Hmm. The song of the French is sung.
Why must you keep your oath of allegiance?
Or, sir, do I not hear you well? Or do you advise me to betray?
What's in this war for you? For you are not a Frenchman.
I could have betrayed them in their glory. But now you have won.
It is my custom to be faithful to them.
By the way, I have a plan for a sortie.
Huh. A plan right off the bat? I can tell you're a staffer.
Well, I'm kidding. Don't be too harsh. We'll talk.
Our little town is on the road...
My lieutenant, this one goes straight to headquarters Through the posts without telling the password.
- We'll find out, go. - A blizzard is raging in the field.
- I've been walking for a long time. I'm tired and so cold. - What do you want here?
- The uniform of the Navarre riflemen. - Are you an officer?
I was a prisoner. I escaped. I'll put my hand on my heart...
...no one has ever endured such infernal suffering.
Only I would know where my part is.
Yes, in war, my friend, as in war.
Navarre riflemen. Go to the other world, if you look for them. Alas, they are gone.
- They can't be! - Come closer to the fire.
Linier. Corneille. Printed in Paris.
I didn't know paper burned like that.
- What's your name? - Vincenzo Salgari.
I'll find a corner so as not to disturb you here.
No, Lieutenant, please wait here with us, the General should be back soon.
He'll want to see you, he'll have plenty of questions. He's very curious, our Dewey.
I'll answer them all with pleasure.
My lieutenant, another fugitive, come in. He swears he's a French officer.
And showed quite a lot of haste, As we called out. Barely got out of harm's way.
I was a prisoner of war. My regiment was broken long ago. With whom to retreat now, I care not.
But where is your uniform and other regalia? Your rank?
I'm a lieutenant. They took my uniform in captivity. My name is Vincento Salgari.
Wait a minute, damn it, I'm seeing double.
It's not... I ask you to repeat your name.
- Vincento Salgari. - And you, my dear knight?
I'm a lieutenant in Murat's corps.
Are you silent? That's great.
Truly, I didn't recognize my brother! He's changed so much, you're alive, Vincento!
- You're both Vincento? - Damn it.
From birth to the grave it's our ancient ancestral law
that all men are called Vincento in the family.
Yes, I confess I haven't seen a moment like this in a long time.
- I thought one of you was a spy. - Yes, but which one, me or him?
Come sit by the fire, you're cold, aren't you?
Yes, from my socks to my head.
Thank you. I had no right to expect this from you.
Allow me to congratulate you. You ran apart, but you met in our place.
What a romance. But the fire is almost out.
What are you burning? Oh, Barney, Rassin.
The disposition of the main Russian forces, I wonder.
What can you tell me? Well, you first.
Ready, my general, to tell me all I know.
No, sit down. You're tired. Well, I'm tired too.
- Where do I start? - Don't say a word, my friend.
- Die, but keep your mouth shut. - What's that supposed to mean?
The ravings of a sick man! Why did you leave your bed? Go upstairs.
No, wait. Which one do you know? Tell me.
You, my angel, do not fear their threats.
Don't answer their questions. For you are a maiden, not a soldier.
Are you a woman?! How could you dare?
She is my niece. I give you my word. She's seventeen years old.
- That's new. - There's a whole family of spies.
Who's the other one? Is he your nephew too? Or who?
Oh, dear...
I don't know who he is. This is the first time I have seen him.
Did you not lend her your uniform, that you betrayed your oath?
I swear I took it without asking! He did not know.
No more questions. Yea, it is clear to me. Take him out. And shoot these men in the morning.
Davyd! The cornet was captured! I barely escaped the pursuit.
Now there's no need to wait for help! Alert! All hands on horseback!
Three thousand devils!
You saved me, I am eternally grateful!
- Madam, I never expected to meet you. - I'm still so happy to meet you.
But your cousin, is he still alive now?
Of course he is! He's locked up there in the closet. I'll get him. No, wait here.
I'm soaked from all this riding. Three thousand devils, a date like in a novel.
- Lieutenant, I am your slave. - I'll settle up with you. Who's that dandy?
Our friend, though a French lieutenant.
You bastards! They started shooting again.
It's dawn.
The general wanted to shoot us at dawn.
He keeps his word... At least as far as I'm concerned.
There's still fighting. Do you hear that thunder? Let's go, Cornet.
We can't leave the house. Orders and maps are here.
It's good booty. Let them know our partisan
It is the custom of our partisans to beat the enemies of the fatherland until they have surrendered.
I know not how to thank you. You saved me,
my uncle and my cousin. She's probably out of her senses now.
It's nothing, brother.
Besides, I'll bet she imagined, of course...
...that you came here so brazenly for her.
Don't talk nonsense. Why don't you load your gun? The fight's not over yet.
Do you remember, Lieutenant, the wager? If you save the girl...
...you will marry her. We shall soon be feasting at the wedding?
That's no good! I wanted to save you, but I don't care about her.
The whole troop witnessed the bet. You shouldn't refuse. I'm awfully glad...
...to congratulate you on your enviable lot in life. So you're getting married?
I don't want to hear any more of your nonsense. I've lost the wager, but know this...
...you will not feast at your wedding! We'll continue the duel.
But, indeed, the occasion is small. And too uncomfortable here at the manor.
If thou art not a coward, I pray thee, come to the barrier!
Save me, and kill me again? Well, that's right, it's too hussar-like. Shall we postpone it?
You're a coward, you punk! Boy!
Shoot on the count of three! I'm counting! One, two...
Stop, gentlemen!
- I made it. - Three thousand devils!
Haven't you had enough deaths in the war?!
Where do you come from, Germont? Be a witness, as to this dandy...
I'll put a bullet in his forehead! Cornet, to the barrier!
My God, who are these people? Don't you dare, gentlemen. I don't want it at all.
I'll make it up to you, just a word. You want to fight over me?
Then know that I love the other. I do not care for either of you.
Alas!
Mademoiselle Germain, what's that got to do with us? You may love the devil. Be my guest.
I am insulted by the cornet. Only by blood can I wash away this insult.
Mademoiselle Germont? That's strange. We're lucky to meet her now.
- The arm, what's wrong with it? - Ah, an empty wound.
Pierre, my friend. For you, believe me, I long.
It's hard to believe it.
Pierre, don't say that. I'm terribly glad. I believe happiness is given to us...
- Mademoiselle Germont! - Louise. Call me as you used to call me.
Kiss me as you kissed me before We quarreled at my whim
- I blame myself. - Louisa. Louisa, I'm an ass.
- Again, Germont! Brother, however, - Where is the cornet?
He and the Lieutenant went there to shoot.
Oh, shit!
No, you can't do without a crowbar here.
I am Azarov. I'm the owner of this house. Retired staff-major.
- And your eternally obedient subject. - Cornet Azarov is your nephew?
- Niece. - What do you mean?
- What is this nonsense? - I think he's delirious. - I see.
You doubt it for nothing. Ivan can tell you. He's been babysitting her since she was a baby.
A maiden, that's right.
What an affair! And I thought the old man was a child!
- Ah, ah, ah! /Shots fired/
- God have mercy. - Break down the door!
- Killed?! - Wounded? - Oh, my God!
- You will answer me now. - There's the duelist, too.
He saw a mouse and fell unconscious. That's the kind of ending that makes me want to shoot.
You did shoot, didn't you?
Yes. In a mouse hunt, I killed a few, missed one. That's a shame.
Please, you've got to slow down.
She's always been afraid of mice, ever since she was a baby.
- She?! Allow me, sir. I must...
You must? Oh, damn, am I dreaming?
I must ask your forgiveness, all of you, for my deceit.
- She's a maiden! - My friend, it's a sin to judge success.
I must present you, for your valor, to the rank of Lieutenant.
to the rank of lieutenant.
- You are too kind. - But how...
Better be silent, brother.
I pray you, gentlemen, champagne. In honour of deliverance.
- What doubt can there be? - You're right, my friend! Come, come!
Lieutenant, wait, where are you going? You and I still have some explaining to do, don't we?
Do you agree with me? How long your astonishment lasts.
Yes, I am not a man. Alas, alas, alas. Are you sorry, too? For you are my teacher...
...in hussar's prowess. Well, why are you silent? Tell me, do you love me?
He that is in sound mind will not live a day who is in love with you.
No, speak plainly, are you in love with me?
He who loves you, yes, would jump out of his mind.
I'm as stubborn as you are. Yes or no?
- I'd like to say goodbye to you forever. - Good. But still, do you love? Well?
Yes. Three thousand devils. No, that doesn't sound like anything.
That's the compote. No, better a hundred deaths. I'm
I'm ashamed to look you in the eye, believe me.
You are in love and beg for death, but why?
You must despise me, I was an ass. Farewell.
Wait. Once we were so friendly, remember, That we were so friendly?
Knit your hands, what the devil am I saying? If
I beg your pardon for that impertinence at the ball.
You kissed me that night, too. I am indebted to you. Now I'll repay it.
Well, you may go. What are you doing?
I'll be right back. Do you remember the bet?
- Well? - If I save the girl...
You must marry her, don't you think? I'll spare you the bet.
It was very unpleasant for you, you do not tolerate my cousin. I mean me.
I swear to you now, I have never loved so!
I'll seek death in battle if you will not agree to be mine.
Farewell forever. I'm going, but if... Shit!
My knight, wait! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
/ Singing a song / Life takes us a long way.
To laugh, to cry or not to cry all the same.
When the chorus is old and old and old
Once upon a time, once upon a time, once upon a time.
I used to fight all kinds of things! Bottles of many, very many have seen the bottom!
But I've never been so in love.
Long time ago, long time ago, long time ago!
To the hero with the puffy moustache My heart, my heart was given forever.
How long have we been enemies?
Long ago, long ago, long ago, long ago!
The years will pass, and from the distance Of years gone by, of years gone by One glimpses:
How our grandfathers fought.
Long time ago, long time ago, long time ago!
And if the enemy, in the blind hope of conquering Russia.
Will come to us again, will come to us again...
We'll chase him, just like before - Long, long, long ago, long ago!
Text: Kabal Kabalych, Kolbasik. Subtitles for YOU prepared by KOLBASIK. 08.07.2012