Human existence is
terrifying and confusing.
Hundreds of thousands of years ago, we had our selves and looked back
at this strange place where
we were.
There were other beings here too.
Some were edible and some were
trying to eat us.
There were liquids to drink and the
ingredients to make other things.
During the day, a small yellow ball floating in the sky
warmed our skin, and the
night sky was full of beautiful light
.
In every way,
it seemed like a place made for us.
There were also beings looking down on us.
We were at home.
This thought relieved my fear and confusion.
But as we get older,
we
start to get to know the world and ourselves more and more.
We
knew that beautiful starlight wasn't twinkling for us.
It was just there.
We also know that we are not at the center of what we call the universe
.
The universe
is much older than we thought.  I also learned that
our bodies are made up of dead little things
.
For some reason, dead things come together
to make bigger things that aren't dead.
And that we
live in an era that is only a brief passage through billions of years of history.
We found, surprisingly, that we live
on a damp speck of dust revolving around an ordinary-sized star, which is
located in the quiet arm of an ordinary galaxy, and is in
a group of galaxies from which we will never leave
.
And the fact that this group of galaxies
is only one-thousandth of a supercluster that is formed by clusters of galaxies.
But even this supercluster is
only one-thousandth of the observable universe.
The real universe may be millions of times bigger than this, but
we'll never know.
I mean, you can do anything.
There are billions of galaxies,
trillions of stars,
and planets on the sub-scale.
But the numbers game is meaningless.
Our brain cannot count these numbers.
The universe is too big and
too many.
However, the concept that is most difficult for us to accept
is not size.
It's time.
More specifically,
it is the time remaining for us.
If you are lucky enough to live 100 years,
you have 5200 weeks of time.
If you are 25 now, you have
3900 weeks left.
If you live to 70, you have
2340 weeks left.
It's not short, but
it's not long either.
And then?
Your biological processes will come to a standstill and the
turbulent waves of life will be quiet.
You will disintegrate until there are no more left
.
Some
say there is something that cannot be seen or touched, but
there is no way to confirm it.
So life will probably end like
this, and after this there will be only eternal death.
But it's not as scary as you might think.
If you
don't remember the 13.75 billion years that passed before you existed, then billions of
eons
will pass in the blink of an eye after you disappear.
Close your eyes and count to one.
That is the way of eternity.
As far as we know, conventionally the
universe will also die and
everything will be frozen forever.
Our videos
create an existential fear in many people.
Same goes for what I said earlier.
So, this
time, I would like to present a different perspective on this.
Let me tell you about Kurzgesakt's unscientific and subjective philosophy.
Just take it as an idea.
We
don't know more about human existence than you do.
overcome existential fear with optimistic nihilism.
What does that mean?
To put
it bluntly, it seems unlikely that so many stars could have been made for us.
In a way, it
seems like the cruelest joke on the planet.
We
barely realized that we were not the protagonists of the story.
Exploring electrons and mitochondria is good, but doing
science doesn't make this melancholic.
Yes, but how about that?
Life is only once.
That's scary.
But it is also a word that gives freedom.
If the universe freezes to death, all
your shame will be forgotten.
The mistakes you make
will end up being nothing.
The bad things you've done will also go blank.
If our life is the only thing we can experience, the
only thing that matters is our life.
If there are no principles in the universe, the
only meaningful principles are those
we set.
If the universe has no purpose, then
we determine the purpose of the universe.
Humans will surely disappear someday.
But before we disappear,
we look at ourselves and the world around us.
We feel emotions.
Eat delicious food, read a book, and watch the
sunrise.
with other people
It is already surprising that we can think of these
things.
It's
easy to think that a line is drawn between us and others, but
that's not true.
We are
just like neutron stars in the universe.
It's like black holes and nebulae.
Actually we are better.
We are the central organ of the universe responsible for our emotions and
thoughts.
We are truly free in the playground of space.
So maybe we dream so happily of building a utopia in space
.
We still have to find out.
We don't know why the laws of the universe are like that.
We do not know how life was born or
what life is.  We
don't know what consciousness is
, and we don't know whether we are alone in the universe.
But you can try to find the answer.
There are many stars to visit, many
diseases to be treated, many
people in need,
many happiness to enjoy,
many games to wake up to.
There's too much to do.
So to wrap up,
you've probably spent a lot of your good time
.
If you can only live one life
,
there is no reason not to live as fun and as happy as possible.
If you make other people's lives better, you
get an extra point.
If it could help build a galactic human empire, that would be the
best.
Do what makes you feel good.
You decide what that means.