[car door slams]
[footsteps on gravel]
crunch
[crunching continues]
[footsteps on dried grass]
crunch, crunch
[crunching continues]
[lock unlocking]
clink
[loud metal noises from chain]
[lock unlocking]
clink
[loud metal noises from chain]
[gate creaking]
Ow!
[Tesla safety noises]
beep, beep, ding, ding
[louder Tesla safety noises]
ding, ding
[scratching of tumbles on car]
[footsteps on gravel]
crunch
[wind blowing]
[door opening]
creak
[metal hitting]
clank
[paper flipping]
Welp.  I guess I need one of these.
[footsteps on gravel]
[wind blowing]
[car driving]
[Tesla safety noises]
ding, ding
[zipper zipping]
[car door slams]
[footsteps on dried grass]
crunch, crunch
[wind blowing]
[crickets chirping]
[far away metal clanging sounds]
[echo of birds flapping wings inside building]
[echo of birds chirping inside building]
Jesus f***ing Christ this is creepy.
Too many things moving around in the dark.
[crickets chirping]
[door slams]
[metal gate opens]
chink
[wind blowing]
Oh, is this how I would turn the power on?
[metal lever]
clank
[straining noises]
Oh, ohhh,.
[low chuckle]
That fuse does not want to be flipped
[sigh]
[footsteps on dried grass]
crunch
[wind blowing]
[crickets chirping]
[metal sliding open]
[metal slides closed]
clank
[metal sliding open]
[metal slides closed]
clank
[files sliding]
[files flipping, pages turning]
[drawer slams]
[footsteps on dried grass]
crunch
Argh.  Argh.
God damn these tumbleweeds.
[tumbles crunching]
crunch, crunch
[footsteps on metal]
[switch flipping]
click, click
I really wish these lights worked.
God, it’s freezing in here.
Oh, wow.
Maybe the computer will turn on.
[switch flipping]
clank
No.
[door closing loudly]
Eww.  I am not going through that door.
Let’s get out of here.
Urrgh!  Oh, God.
[footsteps on gravel]
Ugh.
[metal creaking]
clank
Ughhhh.  Ugh.
Do you think up is locked?  Or is down locked?
[straining noises
[sigh]
Ohhhh.
I have this very nervous feeling that the car is gonna disappear.
But I still… still see her.
Juuust barely on the horizon.
Oh, this one looks open.
Jesus Christ.  Yeah.
No, thank you.
No, thank you, horrible spiky plant.
[metal creaking] clank
Ugh.
[sigh]
Cool.
[switch clicking loudly]
Ohhh, yeah hear that?
[click click]
They don’t make switches like they used to.
[faster switch clicking noises]
Yeah.
When I flip a switch....
[click click]
I want to know it.
Ok, so down is lock- ..err down is unlocked.
[straining noises]
F**k.
[kicks door]
clank, clank, clank
Is that moving?
No, it’s not moving.
[heavy straining]
Huh.
Aww man, so close.
Can’t move this one for anything.
[straining noises]
Okay, maybe there’s another way in.
[tumbles crunching]
[footsteps on metal stairs]
Ah ho, hello.
[deep breathing]
There is a way in.
I’m not going to take it, though.
I’m gonna pass on this little discovery.
[crow caws]
[wind blowing loudly]
[metal clanking]
[deep sigh]
[wind blowing]
[footsteps on gravel]
crunch, crunch
Look, bone.
Sure looks like bone.
[wind blowing]
These tumbleweed are like tribble.
Like a slow motion swarm of tribble trying to knock down the fence.
Sun’s getting low, but I missed a spot back here.
[wind blowing]
[eagle screech]
I think she’s not very happy about me being here.
Oh ho.
I’ve got to go in there.
Ooph.
[wind blowing]
[door opens]
clunk
[metal clanking]
That’s what you want me to think.
[drawer pulling]
click, click
Yeah!
[with disappointment]
Oh.
[drawer opens]
clink
[paper shuffling]
[drawer closes]
Oh God, I can’t see anything down that corridor.
Alright.  Strategic Pride.
Let’s go down there.
[slow footsteps]
[with a sigh]
Okay.
We’re gonna stop here.
[brisk footsteps]
I’m more than a little terrified of these doors locking behind me.
It’s not like you can make an emergency cell phone
call from an underground bunker.
[footsteps continue]
If I’ve learned anything about the way these places work,
this staircase should take me …
to a hole, where that top part was.
[with a sigh]
Yeah.  If it was under there.
It’s got to go up into this building.
[lock door jiggle]
It’s another one of these building on tracks.
Oooh.  There’s a storm coming in.
[eagle screech]
I really should start to skedaddle.
[slow footsteps]
Because this one’s locked, I want to get in the most.
Oh, sweet.
[eagle screech]
[brisk footsteps on metal stairs]
There’s also these little windows to look in.
Like…
[clanking noises]
[straining noises]
Are these windows supposed to line up with…
[crickets chirping]
[metal banging]
clank, thud, thud
[footsteps on gravel]
[eagle screech]
Oh yes.
[metal door opening]
clank.
So these three holes must match the three holes on the outside...
Alright, these three holes on the outside…
So what does that mean though?
Like.
So if I stand here, and turn right around.
I’m looking at that building.
I guess that thing must move off to the side?
I have to figure out how this actually works.
Ok, we’re really almost out of daylight.
[with a sigh]
Time to go.
[wind blowing, increasingly louder]
Ooph.  Didn’t quite make it out before the storm.
[wind blowing]
It’s a little much tumbleweed.
Take it down a notch.
[wind blowing]
Ahhhh.  Huahhh.
[wind blowing, increasingly louder]
[Tesla safety noise]
ding, ding, ding
[gate closing]
clank
[lock locking]
click
[wind blowing loudly]
[crickets chirping]