(The human species, curious by nature...)
(goes through a stage in its development
known for its harshness and cruelty)
(Where only the fittest survive.
This stage is known as: )
("the school")
(There is  a very common kind of
student that experts call "the toilet")
Teacher can't imagine the traffic there was,
but from tomorrow I swear I'll be there early
(He always carries an excuse with him)
My dog died!
Wasn't today Saturday?
Is that halfway I had
to return for the
backpack And the backpack?
(Brute, the backpack!)
M
... Ángel Peréz?
Present
(A kind of extremely curious student
has been called "Halley's comet")
(His presence is an event
that few have seen
) Sofía Albán?
Present
WHAT?
What present
? You here?  But if you never come.
What's more, they put his picture all over the school
. How is that around here?
It's just that the internet went out at
home. Alex Heredia?
(Unlike the previous specimen,
this one is easy to identify and find
) M... I'm not going to catch up, it's time to copy
Valencia, lend me the duty of mate
But mate is due after recess, right
now it's history
Ah, now.  Cool!
(For this species, the words "homework" and "home"
are never related
) W... History duty!
Shh!  Shut up, it seems that he forgot!
Oh,
hey, teacher.  You won't forget to check your homework, will you?
(This species is called "Judas", who for their
own benefit can slaughter the laziest of the herd)
I almost forgot.  You are absolutely right Morales.
He has 2 points more than the partial
(His academic survival is proportionally inverse
to the socio-affective relationship with his peers
) Son of a [ __ ]...
(Who will not hesitate to show him their disagreement)
(This stage, already hard, is  recognizes
even more thanks to the dreaded exams)
(For some this happens as if it were just
about filling the Facebook status)
(With you, the "dedicated student")
(There is also the student who
trusts the skills of the rest)
(  He is called "the copycat")
REMOVE!  REMOVE!
REMOVE!
Remove!  Remove!
(For some, the pressure is overwhelming.
This is the case of the "suffering student")
(While for others...)
Nah!  I still didn't study
(At recess, there is a type of student known
for keeping food rations for himself)
This one has been called: "comesolito")
(An underdeveloped species can also be identified.
The typical "bully" with problems  at his house)
(But he's not worth talking about
) Hey, why?
(The most infallible way to identify
the types of students...
) Let's see, the grades
(are the grades)
Valladares
(For the diligent student, a grade
below outstanding is close to the apocalypse)
NO!
My scholarship went to hell!
Perez
16 Very good!
(For the bum, getting a grade that doesn't have a 0
in front of it is a true personal triumph
) Yes, [ __ ]!  Yes, suck this one!  Yes!
Yes!
Sorry, I was wrong.
This is Edder's grade
(And the student whose life is like the 9 times table)
16?
One more stripe to the tiger
(Not so easy, not so difficult)
Bedoya!
Again!
At this rate he will repeat the year!
(This type of student is called "the eternal")
(For whom repeating the course has become an Olympic sport)
If repetition is the joy
, yes or what, mijo?
Yes, daddy
(But not everything is pressure during this stage)
(Like for a herd of elephants
that hopefully observe the end of the drought...)
(at some point "holidays" arrive)
And well, guys...  It
seems that the last class of the year is over
And for the holidays, I need
the algebra exercises from pages 5 to 146 to be solved