This story was told to us by Shurik. He was collecting folklore during his vacation:
Maybe this story is just a legend...
But according to Shurik it really happened in one of the mountain regions.
He didn't say which one, so as not to be unfair to other areas,
where exactly the same story could have happened...
Where are you going, well...
But... Geez...
The day I sat behind the wheel of that vacuum cleaner be damned!
Don't despair!
Not for nothing did the great and wise Abu-Ahmat-ibn-Bei, the first driver of
of this car: Take note, Edik... - Edik. - Sasha.
Take note, Edik, Allah only knows where the spark goes with this unworthy
in the glorious family of internal combustion engines.
May his carburettor suck off forever and ever!
- Excuse me, please. - Yes?
Excuse me, I have a big favor to ask of you.
- Please. - Can I ask you to go only on the highway, without turning around?
- Why is that? - My donkey follows you like a tethered donkey.
- Donkey? - Yes, it is.
- So he's the one chasing me? - Him, him!
- And I thought... - No, him!
- Are you from around here? - Yes, I'm visiting my aunt on vacation.
I'm on a business trip. How far is it to town?
- Two kilometers. - Thank you.
You see, not a step without you.
- Year of birth? - 42-й.
- Purpose of visit? - Ethnographic expedition.
- I see. Are you looking for oil? - Not exactly. I'm looking for folklore.
I'll be recording old tales, legends, toasts.
Toasts? Darling, you're in luck. I'll help you.
What's this?
- You need a toast. - Yes, I do.
And toast without wine is like a wedding night without a bride.
- No, I don't drink. - Do I drink? What's there to drink?
You misunderstand me. I don't drink at all. Do you understand?
- I don't have the physical ability. - So here's the first toast.
- A toast? I'll write it down... - You can write it down later. Grab a glass.
My great-grandfather said: I want to buy a house, but I can't...
I have the ability to buy a goat, but I don't have the will.
So let's drink to our wishes being equal to our possibilities.
- Good for you. - Okay. - Listen to the other toast. - Okay, uh...
- I'll be right there. - That's okay, I'll just get some air.
I'm going to get some air. It's always study, study, study...
- Where have you been? - What's up?
- My niece. - Nice to meet you. - Nina.
- She's a student. She's a student at the Pedagogical Institute.
- She's going to be grooming our replacement, isn't she? - Ace student, Komsomol member, athlete.
- An athlete? - My uncle knows all about me.
An "A" student and a "Komsomol" student is exactly what we need, right?
What do you need?
- I have an unexpected question for you. - Please.
- How do you feel about getting married? - Well, it's positive, actually.
It's too soon for her to be thinking about it.
It's never too early to think about it and it's never too late, is it?
How do you feel about our opening celebration of the Wedding Palace?
- I'll definitely be there. - You will, won't you? - I will.
I'll have a small but important errand for you. - What kind of errand?
- Well, we'll see, yes. We'll be expecting you. - Well, all right.
So when the whole flock flew south for the winter,
one little birdie said: "Personally, I'm going to fly right into the sun."
It began to fly higher and higher, but very soon burned its wings
and fell to the bottom of the ravine.
So let's drink to the fact that none of us, no matter how high he flies,
would never be separated from the collective.
- What, what happened, dear? - It's a pity about the bird!
And the princess hanged herself with anger on her own scythe, because he
counted exactly how many grains in the sack, how many drops in the sea,
and how many stars in the sky. So let's drink to cybernetics!
Cheers!
Dear friends, today is a joyful,
bright, sunny holiday.
In a few seconds, these silver scissors will cut this silk ribbon...
...and open up a straight path for all the newlyweds in our neighborhood...
to a bright future, you know,
to happiness, love and harmony, you know,
through our Wedding Palace.
The honor of opening the Palace
is given to a beautiful woman, a girl who...
who embodies the new destiny of a woman of the mountains, you know.
She is a student, a Komsomol member, an athlete,
finally, she's just a beauty!
So this is that small but responsible assignment. Please.
As our wonderful satirist Arkady Raikin says,
a woman is a man's friend.
Just a moment... Please slow down, I'm writing it down.
- Who's that? - Probably the press. - Ah, the press.
As our wonderful satirist Arkady Raikin says,
a woman is a man's friend.
Grandiose! Here's to the woman...
Give me the horn, give me the horn, I'm telling you, it's my horn.
...and disrupted the inauguration of the Wedding Palace.
Then on the ruins of the chapel... - Excuse me, did I ruin the chapel too?
No, that was before your time, in the 14th century.
It's all true, of course. It's all true. The paper is written correctly. It's all right.
So that's one side of it, right? But there's another side of the coin.
The intruder is not an intruder, but a major scholar,
a man of intellectual labor. Came to visit us, didn't he?
To collect our fairy tales, legends, you know, toasts...
- Toasts? - Toasts, yes.
And you don't know what you're doing, do you?
We're dealing with an industrial accident here.
I have a wonderful toast!
You, Comrade Shurik, have the wrong idea about our places.
Everyone knows that Kuzbass is an all-Union smithy,
Kuban is the breadbasket, and the Caucasus is the all-Union - what? - Health Resort!
No! The Caucasus is the All-Union smithy, health resort and breadbasket.
Where have you been? Last night I remembered a wonderful toast for you.
- Let's go quickly. - No, wait, my dear.
We'll talk to Shurik, while you write down your toast in triplicate
and present it in writing later. - You got it!
My dream is to record some ancient ritual, and to participate in it,
well that would be absolutely splendid.
You won't find those grandfatherly customs and rituals in our area anymore.
Maybe somewhere high up in the mountains you'll find something for science.
- Let's go to the mountains. - Well, that's right. That's your job.
You came to record fairy tales, and we work to make fairy tales come true!
I brought a toast.
- Bad, huh? - Well... What do you think you're doing?
You asked for three copies...
To live, as they say, is good!
- And living well is even better! - Exactly!
Shame on you. You're hurting the orphan.
She has no one but her aunt and uncle. 25!
- That's not true. I think highly of your niece, but there are limits. 18!
Have some conscience! You're not getting a goat after all, you're getting a wife, and what a wife:
A student, a Komsomol member, an athlete, a beauty! And for all that I'm asking
25 sheep, it's ridiculous to bargain.
You're talking apolitically, honestly.
You don't understand the political situation. You see life from the window of my car.
Twenty-five rams! When our district...
didn't fully pay off the state's wool.
And you don't confuse your personal wool with the state wool!
I, comrade Jabrail, am here to guard the state's interests.
Sit down for now.
- Here's the deal: 20 rams... - 25!
- 20. Rosen lion refrigerator... - What?
Finnish, good, a certificate of merit... - And a free trip... - To Siberia!
- Well, all right. - Well, all right.
So here's the deal. The groom agrees, so do the relatives, but the bride...
We don't bring up our young people very well. Very bad.
It's amazing how they don't take marriage seriously.
And who even asks the bride? A sack on her head, and foo!
Yes, that's right. That's a very good decision.
Only I personally won't have anything to do with it.
Don't worry. It'll be done by complete strangers.
- Yes. And not from our neighborhood. - Of course they are.
It's not a lezginka, it's a twist. I'll show you from the beginning.
With the toe of your right foot you squeeze the butt, like this.
The second butt you squeeze with the toe of your left foot.
And now you squeeze both butts together.
Fish...
- You sold it? - That's my business.
Wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute. It'll pass, it'll pass. Right, yeah, that's it, let's go!
Sheep to the stall. The refrigerator to the house.
Where are you going?
Go home.
You'll never make it. Stealing a girl like that.
An athlete, a Komsomol member.
By the way, in the next district, a groom stole a party member.
Well, Sasha, you are making amazing progress. - Oh, it's nothing. - Nonsense?
- It's nothing, insurance. - Well, I'll give you a more difficult task.
Okay, what is it?
- Pack a sleeping bag. - Yes, sir. - As fast as you can.
- Hold on. It's time. - Yes, yes, yes, yes. - Ready, set, go!
Done!
Will you sleep standing up? Time.
Look out!
Hold on, Shurik. I'm going to pull you up.
There are two of them...
- And this one with a tail. - The one with the tail doesn't count.
- The other one doesn't count. - A witness. - How about...
- No casualties. - Yeah, we should wait.
That's right, we'll wait. Give it up.
- What is this? Is it folklore, too? - No, it's our student song.
- It's a song about bears. - Yeah? But it won't work for you. - Why not?
- It's student folklore. Come on, come on. - Yeah?
All right, listen.
Somewhere in the world, where there's always a frost.
The bears rub their backs against the earth's axis.
"The centuries go by, and the seas sleep beneath the ice,
The bears rubbing their backs on the axis, The earth is spinning.
...the earth is spinning faster.
They're trying to spin the earth's axis,
So that the lovers will have to meet sooner.
♪ So that one morning a year or two earlier ♪
Somebody's got to say what's important.
Following the springtime downpour Early the dawn will come
And for two happy ones Many, many years to come.
The lightning will flash and the streams will ring
The fog will be white as a bear
Somewhere in the world, where there is always frost.
The bears rub their backs against the earth's axis.
Centuries are passing, The seas are sleeping under the ice,
The bears rubbing their backs on the axis, The earth is spinning.
...the earth is spinning faster.
Well, good-bye, Shurik. You go ahead, I'll go to the base.
- Well, Nina, goodbye. - Goodbye.
- Wait, Nina. - What, Shurik? - Let me walk you out.
You have not lived up to the high trust placed in you.
- It is impossible to work. - You give unrealistic plans.
What's that? Voluntarism!
- In my house, no language! - What did I say?
Oh so? Here's your advance... ...we refuse. Take it!
- Well, take it, take it. - Wait a minute.
Well, that's all right. Whoever gets in our way is going to help us.
- Oh, that's another thing. - We'll go for that. - Well, get yourselves together.
- Come here! - Come here, you jerk!
Whose shoe? It's mine, thank you.
Let's go!
Go on. It's late.
Won't you get lost?
Well, go on.
- Comrade Shurik? - Dinner? - No. Alyosha, a bottle of wine.
- You're exceptionally lucky. - In what way?
You wanted to see an ancient, beautiful custom.
Of course, I dream of it.
- Tomorrow at dawn. - What are you talking about?
You can not only watch, you can participate.
- Thank you very much for that. Would you like some juice? - No.
- What's this rite called? - Bride kidnapping. - Kidnapping?
- No, don't think, the bride herself dreams of being kidnapped.
You can go to the registry office, but before that, the bride must be stolen! - Steal?
Oh, man, that's a beautiful custom. Well, what's my role?
- Catch the bride. Put her in a sack. - In a sack? Is that a custom, too?
Genius!
- And hand her over to whom? - A dzhigit in love. - No.
- And give it to the cousins of the dzhigit in love. - Oh, to the cousins?
- That is the custom. - I see.
- By the way, here they are. I'll introduce them. - It would be my pleasure.
- Meet. - Shurik.
They don't speak Russian at all. But everyone understands.
- What does he say? - He says, "Bon appetit.
Bambarbia. Kergudu.
What did he say?
He says if you refuse, they'll slaughter you.
It's a joke.
- A joke... I agree. - That's fine.
Nina will be very happy.
- So the bride's name is Nina? - Nina. My niece.
- Does Nina have a fiancé? - They adore each other.
I completely forgot.
I'm sorry, I can't do this. You can't.
Most importantly, Nina asked you to be the one to do it.
- Nina asked you to do it? - Very much.
Well, tell Nina I agree.
But be warned, custom demands that everything be natural.
Nobody knows anything.
The bride will resist, kick,
...even bite, call the police..,
shouting, "I'm going to complain to the Obkom!"
but don't pay any attention.
I understand. Don't worry. Everything will be natural.
Shurik...
What are you doing, Shurik?
Don't say anything.
What's the matter with you, huh?
I came to say goodbye to you.
- Goodbye, Shurik. - Goodbye, Nina. Be happy.
Goodbye, goodbye.
What are you loading?
The bride was stolen, Comrade Sergeant Major.
Joker! When you roast a kebab with this bride, don't forget to invite her.
- So it wasn't a ritual? She really was stolen. - Yes.
- Who stole it? Ah, yes... Who's the groom?
- We sometimes find out at weddings. - There will be no wedding!
I stole it, I'll give it back!
Comrade Shurik!
- What's the matter? What happened? - A crime, stolen! - What was stolen?
Your donkey was stolen? - The girl, Nina. - Nina?
- I'm the only witness.
No, you're not a witness, you're a kidnapper, a criminal!
Well, I didn't know!
What a shame, I swear, on my word of honor, to the whole neighborhood!
- I didn't know! - I'll look into it personally.
This mysterious fiancé is a lowlife scoundrel! You don't know who it is?
- That's too bad. A scoundrel, a scoundrel, an immoral type, just an immoral type!
Thank you very much for the signal. With this single negative example,
we will mobilize the public, raise the masses... - That's right!
- And I'll go to the police. - What militia, listen? They'll arrest you.
They're formally obliged to put you in jail - they will.
- The only way out is to disappear. I'll do everything myself. Nina will be saved.
We'll put these scoundrels on trial by show trial.
And you will come to the trial as a witness indeed.
- I have no right to abuse your nobility. - What nobility?
You're risking your life because of me. Nina was stolen by me, and I must redeem myself.
Why go to the police? You don't need those victims. Go straight to the prosecutor. He'll understand everything.
- Dear guests, welcome. - Tell me, Marim, do you have the prosecutor?
We've got everything, the whole town is here, just waiting for you. Wine for our dear guests!
- No, I don't drink. We'd like a prosecutor. - We can't refuse. Blood grudge.
A regional hospital? Come immediately to 47 Gogol Street. Kapitanaka house.
Yes, where the name day is. One of the guests is very bad. Please come at once.
You understand that this is a very severe form of the disease. We have to save the man.
Alcoholism makes him obsessive-compulsive. A stolen bride.
He's always trying to save someone,
It's just a mental breakdown, I swear.
Right. Delirium tremens. White hot.
Yeah, he's white, he's hot, he's very white.
We'll have him back on his feet in three days. No, there's no rush. He's our guest.
The important thing is to cure him. It's important to bring him back to society as a whole person.
We'll do our best.
If I were a sultan I would have three wives
And I would be surrounded by three beauties. But on the other hand, in such matters,
So many troubles and cares, Ah, save Allah.
It's not bad to have three wives, But it's very bad on the other side.
It's okay, you can come.
How should we sultans be, Clarity is needed here.
How many wives is good enough: Three or one?
There's a simple answer to that question:
If I were a sultan, I'd be single.
It's not bad at all without a wife, It's much better on any side.
Oh so! All right, then. I'm going on a hunger strike!
And now no one but the prosecutor is coming in here!
Look out!
Typical delirium tremens. Rushing to save some stolen girl,
Anyway, he's behaving just like comrade Saahov warned us.
Yes, yes, he called me too.
Now he's in a state of excitement and demands that you take him in.
If he demands it, we'll take him in.
Be careful.
Comrade Sahakhov's diagnosis is clearly confirmed.
- Did you say Saahov? - Saahov, Saahov.
So he's the one who put me in here?
He didn't put me away, he sent me here in a moment of crisis.
- An acute crisis.
I'll tell you this: Sahov stole this girl.
That's right, he stole her. He buried her in the ground and wrote an inscription.
Go, go. We'll cure you. Alcoholics are our specialty.
Untie me.
- Will you behave yourself? - Untie me.
I understand. You all don't believe me.
Can I see the prosecutor? - You may. Where is the prosecutor?
In Room 6, where Napoleon used to be.
You don't have to eat, you don't have to drink, you don't have to say anything,
it still won't help you.
The best groom in the neighborhood offers his hand and heart.
- The service. - What? The service. - The big set?
- Twelve, 96 pieces. - You have no conscience.
You ignore our customs. What?
It's stupid. It's not like you have any other choice.
You mean they'll come looking for you?
They'll go to a relative, and I'm the relative.
I'll say she dropped out of college, got married and moved away.
Don't interrupt me when I'm talking to you!
So: or you'll come out of there wife - ah, what a groom! Or don't come out at all.
That's another thing. Open the door, you're about to meet the groom.
- Take off your hat. - What? Take off your hat.
Look, it hurts, I swear it hurts, I didn't do anything, I just walked in.
- She's young, she's capricious. - What a naughty girl, look, a bully!
Now I have only two ways out of this house:
Either I take her to the registry office, or she takes me to the prosecutor.
- Don't do it. - I don't want to.
That's all right. In a day she will be hungry, in a week she will be pining,
and in a month she'll be smart. That's all right, we'll wait. - We'll wait.
Remember, comrades. You finally have to live up to the trust placed in you.
And you're responsible for her with your head. We'll do our best, comrade Jabrail.
- Can we think of three? - It's a sin to make fun of sick people.
Seriously, I'll run away, huh?
- You can't escape from here. - There is one way.
Stop, you lunatic!
Why are you running like a madman? Where's your donkey?
- What happened? What's your hurry? - That way, that way. - Get in, I'll give you a lift.
- Where are you going? - I'll tell you everything,
and you decide where to take me.
Just hurry up. - Car's a beast. Listen.
Damn the day I sat behind the wheel of that vacuum cleaner!
Start a new line.
Lunch, underline, no soup.
In brackets, kharcho soup. - Kharcho...
Three portions of kebab - threw into the abyss. - Into the abyss.
Broke two bottles of wine.
- Three. - Write three. - Three bottles...
The fruit is oranges.
- Comrade Saahov's dacha? - Yeah. - Sanitary and epidemiological station.
- Who do you want?
There's an epidemic in the area. Vaccination drives. Foot and mouth disease! Sign here!
- Shirt off? - You don't have to take your shirt off.
Lie down on your stomach.
- Relax. I haven't shot it yet. - Ah. Not yet. Tell me, does it hurt?
- It depends on the diameter of the needle. - Tell me, do you have a diameter...
- Alcohol? - Alcohol.
Lie down without moving. This is the latest delayed-absorption vaccine.
- Is there no one else in the house? - No, there's no one else in the house.
Stay still, stay still. Otherwise, "memento sea".
- Instantly... - To the sea!
Nina is here, I'm sure. Find her and warn her.
- And when will they be asleep? - In half an hour. Go, go.
The filtered FMD virus develops particularly vigorously in the body...
- In short, Sklichasovsky! - You're not interested, don't interfere.
It develops especially vigorously in the body,
weakened by nicotine, alcohol and...
- ...bad things.
Nina, Nina, where are you?
Quiet. Go that way.
Nina, Nina... What's wrong with you?
Nina, are you all right?
Oh, thank God! Thank God! - What for?
Traitor, sneaky mercenary... Judas! Scoundrel! How much did they pay you?
Untie me!
Worthless, venal scum.
Let me go! You bandit, you trash, you stupid..,
chameleon, scoundrel! Alcoholic, miserable folklorist!
Hello, I'm listening. Speak up, come on!
Who's there?
Hello...
I didn't expect to see you here. It's such a surprise for me.
Excuse me, I'll change. - Don't worry about it. They'll change you in the morgue.
We have come to judge you by the law of the mountains.
For wanting to disgrace our clan, you will die like a vile jackal.
You have no right! You will answer for this!
I'll answer for your filthy hide only to my conscience as a jigit...
...my sister's honor and the memory of my ancestors.
Nina, stop them. You and I are modern people.
This is medieval savagery. Well, I've broken that code,
but I'm willing to admit my mistakes.
Mistakes shouldn't be admitted, they should be washed away in blood.
You have no right!
This is vigilante justice! I demand to be judged according to our Soviet laws.
Did you buy it under Soviet laws?
Or under Soviet laws did you steal it?
Let's stop this useless discussion. Sister, turn the TV up.
Don't, I'm begging you, don't. I won't do it anymore! I swear to you,
I won't do it anymore. Well, let me go to the prosecutor's office.
Well, let me turn myself in to the authorities.
Ah, Hamlet, well done, listen.
- Are you out of your mind? - Don't worry, it's only salt.
Stand up! The court is coming!
Long live our court, the most humane court in the world!
Please be seated.
- Be seated. - Thank you, I'll stand.
Citizen judge, he can't sit down.
After the springtime downpour the dawn will come early.
And for two happy ones Many, many years to come.
The lightning will flash and the streams will ring,
The fog will be white as a bear.