Shurik told us this story.
He collected folklore during the holidays:
Maybe this story is
just a legend...
But according to Shurik, it really
happened in one of the mountainous regions.
He didn't say which one, so as not to
be unfair to other areas
where exactly the same story could have happened
...
Well, where are you, well...
But... Damn it...
Damn the day I
sat down  for the wheel of this vacuum cleaner!
Do not despair!
No wonder the great and wise
Abu-Akhmat-ibn-Bey, the first driver of
this car, spoke: mind you, Edik ...
- Edik.  - Sasha.
Bear in mind, Edik, Allah alone knows where the
spark goes for this unworthy
geek in the glorious family of
internal combustion engines.
May his carburetor dry up
forever and ever!
- I'm sorry.
- Yes?
Sorry, I
have a big request for you.
- You are welcome.  - Can I ask you to
go only along the highway, without turning?
- Why is that?  - Yes, my donkey
is following you, as if tied.
- Donkey?
- Well, yes.
So he was following me?
- He, he!
- And I thought... - No, he is!
- Are you from here?
- Yes, I came to my aunt for the holidays.
And I'm on a business trip.
Is it far from the city?
- Two kilometers.
- Thanks.
You see, not a step without you.
- Year of birth?  - 42nd.
- Purpose of visit?
- Ethnographic expedition.
- Understandably.  Looking for oil?
- Not really.  I'm looking for folklore.
I will write down old
fairy tales, legends, toasts.
Toast?  Darling, you are extremely
lucky.  I will help you.
What is it?
- You need a toast.
- Yes.
A toast without wine is like
a wedding night without a bride.
- No, I don't drink.
- Do I drink?  What is there to drink?
You misunderstood me.
I don't drink at all.  Do you understand?
- I have no physical ability.
- That's about it - the first toast.
- Toast?  I'll write it down now...
- Then you'll write it down.  Take a glass.
My great-grandfather says: I have a desire to
buy a house, but I don’t have the opportunity ...
I have the opportunity to buy a goat,
but I don’t have the desire.
So let's drink to ensure that our desires
coincide with our capabilities.
- Well done.  - So.
- Listen to another toast.  - So...
- I'll be right back.
- Nothing, I'll take a breather.
I'll get some air, otherwise it's all an office, an
office, an office ...
- Where are you disappearing to?
- What's the matter?
- My niece.
- Very nice.  - Nina.
- Student.  Studying at the Pedagogical
Institute.
- Will prepare our shift, yes?
- Excellent student, Komsomol member, athlete.
- Sportswoman?
- My uncle knows everything about me.
An excellent student and a Komsomol member - is
this just what we need?
What do you need?
- I have an unexpected question for you
.  - You are welcome.
- How do you feel about marriage?
- Well, generally positive.
It's too early for her to think about it.
It’s never too early for anyone to think about this and it’s
never too late, by the way, right?
And how do you feel about our celebration of the
opening of the Wedding Palace?
- I'll definitely come.  - Come, yes?
- Necessarily.
I will have a small but
responsible assignment for you.  - Which?
- Let's see, yes.
Waiting for you.  - OK then.
And when the whole flock flew
south for the winter,
one small bird said:
"Personally, I will fly right into the sun."
She began to rise higher and higher,
but very soon burned her wings
and fell to the very bottom of the gorge.
So let's drink to the fact that none of us,
no matter how high he flew,
would never break away from the team.
- What, what happened, dear?
- I'm sorry about the bird!
And the princess, out of anger, hanged herself on
her own scythe, because
he accurately counted how many
grains were in the bag, how many drops in the sea,
and how many stars were in the sky.
So let's drink to cybernetics!
To health!
Dear friends!
Today we have a joyful,
bright, sunny holiday.
In a few seconds, these silver
scissors will cut this silk ribbon
and open to all the newlyweds of our
region a direct path
forward to a bright future,
you understand,
fortunately, love and
harmony, you understand,
through our
Wedding Palace.  We give the
honor of opening the
Palace to a beautiful woman, a
girl who
personifies the new destiny of
a mountain woman, you understand.
This is a student, a
Komsomol member, an athlete,
and finally, she is just a beauty!
This is the small
but responsible task.  I ask you to.
As our wonderful
satirist Arkady Raikin says, a
woman is a man's friend.
Wait a minute... Please slow down,
I'm taking notes.
- Who is this?  - Probably the press.
- Oh, the press.
As our wonderful
satirist Arkady Raikin says, a
woman is a man's friend.
Grandiose!  Let's drink to a woman... Give me the
horn, give me the horn, I'm telling you,
it's my horn.
...and disrupted the grand opening
of the Wedding Palace.
Then on the ruins of the chapel...
- Excuse me, did I destroy the chapel too?
No, it was before you, in the 14th century.
All this, of course, is true.  All this is true.
The paper is written correctly.  Everything is fine.
So it's on the one hand, right?
But there is another side of the coin.
A violator is not a violator, but a
major scientific worker, a
man of intellectual labor.
You came to visit us, didn't you?
Collect our fairy tales, legends there,
you know, toasts ...
- Toasts?
- Toast, yes.
And he did not calculate his strength, right?
We're dealing with an industrial accident here
.
I have wonderful toast!
You, comrade Shurik, have a wrong
idea about our places.
Everyone knows that Kuzbass is an
all-Union forge,
Kuban is a granary, and the Caucasus is an
all-Union - what?  - Health!
Not!  The Caucasus is an all-Union
forge, and a health resort, and a granary.
Where have you been?  Last night I remembered a
wonderful toast for you.
- Let's go faster.
- No, wait, dear.
We will talk with Shurik, and for now,
write down your toast in 3 copies
and then submit it in writing.
- Will be done!
I dream of writing down some
old rite, and participating in it,
well, that would be absolutely great.
In our area you will no longer meet
these grandfather customs and rituals.
Maybe somewhere high in the mountains you
will find something for science.
- Let's go to the mountains.  - That's right.
It's your job.
You have come to record fairy tales, and we
are working to make the fairy tale come true!
I brought you a toast.
- Bad, right?  - Well ...
What do you allow yourself, listen?
You asked for 3 copies...
To live, as they say, is good!
- A good life is even better!
- Exactly!
Aren `t you ashamed.
You hate an orphan.
She has no one but her uncle and
aunt.  25!
- Not true.  I appreciate your
niece, but there is a limit to everything.  eighteen!
Have a conscience!  After all, you don’t
get a goat, but a wife, and what kind: a
student, a Komsomol member, an athlete, a
beauty!  And for all this I ask
25 rams, it's even ridiculous to bargain.
You're being apolitical, to be
honest.
You don't understand the political situation.
You see life from the window of my car.
25 sheep!  When our district...
did not fully pay
off the state for wool.
And you do not confuse your personal wool
with the state!
I, comrade Dzhabrail, have been placed here
to look after the interests of the state.
Sit down for now.
- In general, like this: 20 rams ...
- 25!
- 20. Refrigerator "Rosen Lion"...
- What?
Finnish, good, certificate of honor...
- And a free ticket... - To Siberia!
- OK then.  - OK then.
So so.  The groom agrees,
relatives too, but the bride ...
We still educate
our youth badly.  Very bad.
Surprisingly frivolous attitude
to marriage.
And who even asks the bride?
Head bag and poof!
Yes, that's right.
A very correct decision.
Only I personally will not have
anything to do with this.
Don't worry.  It will be done by complete
strangers.
- Yes.  And not from our area.
- Well, of course.
This is not a lezginka for you, but a twist.
I show everything first.
With the toe of your right foot, you crush the cigarette butt,
like this.
You crush the second cigarette butt with the toe of your
left foot.
And now you crush both cigarette butts together.
Fish ...
- Sold?  - It's my business.
Just a minute, yes, yes.  It will pass, it will pass.
Right, aha, like this, forward!
Baranov in the stall.  Refrigerator in the house.
Where are you going?
Go home.
You won't get anything.
Steal such a girl.
Athlete, Komsomol member.
By the way, in the neighboring area, the
groom stole a member of the party.
Well, Sasha, you are making amazing
progress.  - Oh, that's nonsense.  - Nonsense?
- A trifle, insurance.
- Well, I give you a more difficult task.
So, what is it?
- Pack in a sleeping bag.
- There is.  - And as quickly as possible.
- Wait.  Time.  - Yes Yes Yes.
- Get ready, attention, start!
Ready!
Will you sleep standing up?  Time.
Carefully!
Hold on, Shurik.  Now I will take you out.
There are two of them...
- And this one has a tail.
- The tail doesn't count.
- Second extra.  - Witness.
- And if...
- Only without victims.
- Yes, we have to wait.
That's right, we'll wait.  Give it up.
- What is it?  Also folklore?
- No, this is our student.
- A song about bears.  - Yes?
- But it won't work for you.  - Why?
- This is student folklore.
Let's, let's.  - Yes?
Well, okay, listen.
Somewhere in the world
, Where it's always cold.
Bears rub their backs
on the earth's axis.
Centuries are floating by,
Sleeping under the ice of the sea,
Bears are rubbing against the axis, The
earth is spinning.
... the earth is spinning faster.
They twist, trying,
They turn the earth's axis,
So that the lovers had to
meet before.
So that one morning
Earlier, a year or two,
Someone said to someone the
Main words.
Following the spring downpour
Dawn will come earlier
And for two happy ones
Many, many years.
Lightnings will sparkle,
Streams will ring,
Fog will swirl,
White as a bear.
Somewhere in the world
, Where it's always cold.
Bears rub their backs
on the earth's axis.
Centuries are floating by,
Sleeping under the ice of the sea,
Bears are rubbing against the axis, The
earth is spinning.
... the earth is spinning faster.
Well, goodbye, Shurik.  You directly,
and me to the base.
- Well, Nina, goodbye.
- Goodbye
- Wait, Nina.  - What, Shurik?
- Allow me to accompany you.
You have not justified the high trust placed in you
.
- Impossible to work.
- You give unrealistic plans.
Is it like him?  Voluntarism!
- In my house - do not express yourself!
- What did I say?
Ah well?  Here's your advance...
...we refuse.  Take it!
- Well, take it, take it.
- Wait a minute.
Well, it's all right.  The one who
hinders us will help us.
- Ah, this is another matter.
- We'll go for it.  - Well, get ready.
- Go here!
- Go, [ __ ]!
Whose shoe?  Mine, thanks.
Let's go!
Go.  It's already late.
Don't get lost?
Well, go.
- Comrade Shurik?  - Have supper?
- Not.  Alyosha, a bottle of wine.
- You're extremely lucky.
- In what?
You wanted to see
an ancient, beautiful custom.
Of course I dream about it.
- Tomorrow at dawn.
- What are you talking about?
You can not only watch,
you can participate yourself.
- Thank you very much for this.
Do you want juice?  - Not.
- What is the name of this ceremony?
- Bride kidnapping.  - Abduction?
- No, don't think that the bride herself
dreams of being kidnapped.
You can go to the registry office, but before that, the
bride needs to be stolen!  - Steal?
Oh damn, nice custom.
Well, what is my role?
- Catch the bride.  Put it in a bag.
- In a bag?  Is this also customary?
Brilliant!
- And give it to whom?
- To a dzhigit in love.  - Not.
- And hand over to the kunaks the
dzhigit in love.  - Ah, kunakam?
- That's the custom.
- Understandably.
By the way, here they are.  I'll
introduce you now.  - With pleasure.
- Meet.
- Shurik.
They don't speak Russian at all.
But everyone understands.
- What he says?
He says bon appetit.
Bambarbia.  Kergud.
What did he say?
He says that if you
refuse, they will kill you.
Joke.
- It's a joke... I agree.
- Very well.
Nina will be very happy.
- So the bride's name is Nina?
- Nina.  My niece.
- Does Nina have a fiancé?
- They adore each other.
I completely forgot.
Excuse me, I can't
do this.  No way.
Most importantly, Nina asked that you
do it.
- Did Nina ask for it herself?  - Highly.
Well, tell
Nina that I agree.
But remember, custom requires
that everything be natural.
Nobody knows anything.
The bride will
resist, kick,
even bite, call the police,
shout: "I will
complain to the regional committee!" -
but you do not pay attention.
I understand.  Don't worry.
Everything will be natural.
Shurik...
What are you doing, Shurik?
Just don't say anything.
What's wrong with you, huh?
I have come to say goodbye to you.
- Goodbye, Shurik.
- Farewell, Nina.  Be happy.
Farewell, farewell.
What are you shipping?
The bride was stolen, comrade foreman.
Joker!  You will fry the barbecue with this
bride, do not forget to invite.
So it wasn't a ritual?
It really was stolen.  - Yes.
- Who stole it?  Oh yes... Who is the groom?
- We sometimes learn about it
at the wedding.  - There will be no wedding!
I stole it, I will return it!
Comrade Shurik!
- What's the matter?  What happened?
- Crime, stolen!  - What was stolen?
Was your donkey stolen?
- Girl, Nina.  - Nina?
- I'm the only witness.
No, you are not a witness,
you are a kidnapper, a criminal!
Well, I didn't know!
What a disgrace, I swear, on my word,
you understand, for the whole district!
- I didn't know!
- I'll take care of this myself.
This mysterious groom is an
insignificant scoundrel!  You don't know who it is?
- Very sorry.  Scoundrel, scoundrel,
immoral type, simply immoral type!
Thank you very much for the signal.  With this
single negative example,
we will mobilize the public,
raise the masses... - That's right!
- I'll go to the police.  - What
militia, listen?  They arrest you.
They are formally obliged to
imprison you - they will imprison you.
- One salvation - to disappear.
I will do everything myself.  Nina will be saved.
We will judge these scoundrels in a
show trial.
And you will come to the process
really as a witness.
- I have no right to abuse your
nobility.  - What nobility?
You risk because of me.  I stole Nina
and I have to redeem myself.
Why go to the police?  These sacrifices are not needed.
Directly to the prosecutor.  He will understand everything.
- Dear guests, welcome.
- Tell me, Marim, do you have a prosecutor?
Everything is with us, the whole city is with us, only they
were waiting for you.  Wine dear guests!
- No, I dont drink alcohol.  We would like a prosecutor.
- You can't refuse.  Blood insult.
District hospital?  Come immediately
to Gogol Street, 47. House of Kapitanaki.
Yes, where is the name day.  One of the guests is
really bad.  Please immediately.
You understand, this is a very severe form of the
disease.  We need to save a person.
On the basis of alcoholism, he has
obsessions.  The stolen bride.
He is eager to save someone all the time,
just clouding his
mind, honestly.
It's clear.  Delirium tremens.  Delirium
tremens.
Yes, white, hot, completely white.
In 3 days we will put on our feet.  No, there is
no need to hurry.  This is our guest.
It's important to heal.  It is important to return a
full-fledged person to society.
Let's try.
If I were a sultan
I would have three wives
And be surrounded by triple beauty.
But on the other hand, in such cases,
So many troubles and worries,
Oh, save Allah.
It's not bad to have three wives,
But it's very bad on the other hand.
It's all right, you can come.
How to be us, the sultans,
Clarity is needed here.
How many wives just right:
three or one?
To the question,
there is a simple answer to this:
If I were a sultan
, I would be single.
It's not bad at all without a wife,
Much better in every way.
Ah well!  OK then.
I'm on a hunger strike!
And now no one but the prosecutor
will enter here!
Look out!
Typical delirium tremens.  Rushing
to save some stolen girl,
In general, he behaves as
Comrade Saakhov warned us.
Yes, yes, he called me too.
Now he is in a state of excitement and
demands that you accept him.
Requires - accept.
Be careful.
Comrade Saakhov's diagnosis is
clearly confirmed.
- Did you say Saahov?
- Saakhov, Saakhov.
So he hid me here?
He did not hide, but directed
at the time of the crisis.
- Acute crisis.
So I'll tell you this:
Saakhov stole this girl.
That's right, I stole it.  And he buried it in the ground,
and wrote the inscription.
Go, go.  We will heal you.
Alcoholics are our profile.
Untie me.
- Will you be well behaved?
- Untie.
I understand.  You all don't believe me.
May I see the prosecutor?
- You can.  Where is our prosecutor?
In the 6th ward, where Napoleon used to be.
You may not eat, you may not drink,
you may be silent,
it won't help you anyway.
The best groom in the area offers his
hand and heart.
- Service.  - What?  - I got to the service.
- Big service?
- 12 persons, 96 items.
- You have no conscience.
You spit on our customs.
What?
Silly.  You don't have any other choice.
Are you saying
that you will be looked for?
They will turn to relatives,
and the relative is me.
And I will say, she left the institute,
got married and left.
Don't interrupt when someone is talking to you
!
So: either you leave there as a wife - oh,
what a groom!  Or you won't come out at all.
This is another matter.  Open the door,
now you will meet the groom.
- Take off your hat.  - What?  - Take off your hat.
Listen, it's a shame, I swear it's a shame, I
didn't do anything, I just went in.
- Still young, capricious.
- What a capricious, listen, hooligan!
Now I
have only 2 ways out of this house:
either I take her to the registry office,
or she takes me to the prosecutor.
- No need.  - I don't want to.
Nothing.  In a day she will be hungry,
in a week she will yearn,
and in a month she will become smart.
Nothing, we'll wait.  - Will wait.
Remember, comrades.  Finally, you must
justify the trust placed in you.
And you answer for it with your head.
We will try, comrade Jabrail.
- Think for three?
- It's a sin to laugh at sick people.
Seriously, I'm running, huh?
- You can't run away from here.
- There is one way.
Stop, psycho!
What are you running like crazy?
Where is your donkey?
- What happened?  Where are you in a hurry?
- There, there.  - Get in, I'll take you.
- Where to take you?
- I'll tell you everything,
and you'll decide where to take me.
Just come quickly.
- The car is a beast, listen.
Cursed be the day I got behind the
steering wheel of this vacuum cleaner!
Write from a new line.
Lunch, - emphasize,
refused the soup.
In brackets - kharcho soup.
- Kharcho...
Three servings of shish kebab - thrown
into the abyss.  - Into the abyss.
Broke 2 bottles of wine.
- Three.  - Write three.  - Three bottles...
Fruits - oranges.
- Comrade Saakhov's dacha?
- Yeah.  - Sanitary and epidemiological station.
- Who do you want?
There is an epidemic in the area.  Head
vaccinations.  FMD!  Sign!
- Take off your shirt?
- You don't have to wear shirts.
Lie down on your stomach.
- Calmly.  I don't poke yet.  - A.
Not yet.  Tell me, does it hurt?
- It all depends on the diameter of the needle.
- Tell me, what is your diameter...
- Alcohol?  - Alcohol.
Lie down without moving.  This is the latest
slow digestion vaccine.
- Is there no one else in the house?
- No, there is no one.
Calm down.
Otherwise - "memento sea".
- Instantly...
- At sea!
Nina is here, I'm sure.
Find and warn her.
- When will they sleep?
- After half an hour.  Go, go.
The filterable FMD virus
develops particularly rapidly in the body...
- In short, Sklikhasovsky!
- You're not interested, don't bother.
It develops especially rapidly
in an organism
weakened by nicotine, alcohol and...
- ...bad excesses.
Nina, Nina, where are you?
Quiet.  Go there.
Nina, Nina... What's wrong with you?
Nina, are you alive?
Thank God!  Thank God!
- For what?
Traitor, vile mercenary...
Judas!  Scoundrel!  How much were you paid?
Untie me!
Insignificance, venal skin.
Let me go!  Bandit, trash, stupid,
chameleon, scoundrel!  Alcoholic,
unfortunate folklorist!
Hello, I'm listening.
Speak, well!
Who's here?
Hello ...
I did not expect your arrival at all.  Such a
surprise for me.
Sorry, I'll change.
- Do not worry.  Change clothes in the morgue.
We have come to judge you according to the law of the mountains.
Because you wanted to disgrace our kind,
you will die like a vile jackal.
You have no right!
You will be responsible for it!
For your filthy skin, I will answer
only to my conscience as a horseman...
...the honor of my sister and the memory of my ancestors.
Nina, stop them.
We are modern people.
This is medieval savagery.
Well, I broke that code,
but I'm willing to admit my mistakes.
Mistakes must not be recognized,
they must be washed away with blood.
You have no right!
This is self-judgment!  I demand that I be
tried according to our Soviet laws.
Did you buy it according to Soviet laws?
Or, according to Soviet
laws, did you steal it?
Let's stop this useless discussion.
Sister, turn up the TV louder.
Don't, I beg you, don't.
I won't do it again!  I swear to you,
I won't do it again.  Well, let me
go to the prosecutor's office.
Well, let me turn myself in to the authorities.
Ah, Hamlet, well done, listen.
- Are you out of your mind?
- Don't worry, it's just salt.
Get up!  Judgment is coming!
Long live our court - the most
humane court in the world!
Please sit down.
- Sit down.
Thanks, I'll stand.
Citizen Judge, but he can't sit down.
Following the spring shower
Before the dawn will come
And for two happy
Many, many years.
Lightnings will sparkle,
Streams will ring,
Fog will swirl,
White as a bear.