MOSFILM presents
Shurik - Alexander DEMYANENKO
ABDUCTION IN THE CAUCASUS,
Or New Adventures of Shurik
With
Natalya VARLEY
Vladimir ETUSH
Frunzik MKRTCHIAN
Ruslan AHMETOV
Yuri NIKULIN
Georgy VITSIN
Evgeny MORGUNOV
N.AVALIANI
N.GREBESCHIKOVA
M.GLUZSKY
E.GELLER
G.MILLYAR, D.MKRTCHIAN
N.REPNIN
Written by Ya.KOSTIUKOVSKY
M.SLOBODSKOY, L.GAIDAI
Directed by Leonid GAIDAI
Director of Photography
Konstantin BROVIN
Production Designer
Vladimir KAPLUNOVSKY
Music by A.ZATSEPIN
Sound by V.KRACHKOVSKY
Shurik told us this story.
During vacation
he hunted for folklore -
local legends and myths.
This story may well be a legend
but Shurik says it really happened
in one of the mountainous areas.
He didn't say which one
not to be unfair to other places
where the story
might have happened.
Giddi yap!
Cursed be the day
when I mounted this hoover.
Don't despair.
As the first driver of this car,
the great and wise
Abu-Ahmad ibn-bay,
said, take care, Edik.
- Edik.
- Sasha.
Allah only knows
what happens to the spark
of this unworthy bastard
in the fine family of
internal combustion engines.
May its carburettor wither
and fall off!
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
Excuse me.
- Do me a favor.
- Yes?
Will you walk straight on and on.
- Why?
- My donkey's following you.
So it's he who's pursuing me?
That's him alright.
- I thought--
- No, it's him.
Are you local?
- Yes. I'm here on vacation.
- I'm here on business.
- Is it a long way to town?
- About 2 km.
- Thanks and bye.
- All the best.
Whoa.
He won't move without you.
- Year of birth?
- 1942.
- Purpose of visit?
- Ethnographic expedition.
- Prospecting for oil?
- Not really.
I'm studying folklore,
collecting tales, legends, toasts.
Toasts?
You're lucky, dear.
I'll help you.
LUNCH BREAK
What's that?
You want a toast.
A toast without wine
is like a nuptial bed
without the bride.
- Thanks, but I don't drink.
- Do I?
What's there to drink?
You don't understand.
I don't drink at all.
I can't physically.
Here's the first toast.
- Let me write it down.
- Later.
Take the glass.
My great granddad says:
I have a wish to buy a house
but I've no means.
I've means to buy a goat
but I've no wish.
May our wishes
always match our means.
Attaboy.
Here's another toast.
- I'll be back.
- It's alright.
I'll take some fresh air.
I spend all day
in the office.
- Where were you?
- Why do you ask?
- This is my niece.
- How do you do.
- Nice to meet you.
- I'm Nina.
She's a student
at a teachers training college.
She'll teach our successors.
An A-student, a Young Communist,
an athlete.
Uncle knows everything about me.
An A-student and a Young Communist.
Just what we need.
- And what do you need?
- I've got--
a surprise question.
What do you think of marriage?
- Well, I'm all for it.
- Too early to think about it.
It's never too early or too late
to think about it.
Start the engine.
What if I ask you to open
the Marriage Palace?
I'll be there, I promise.
There's an assignment for you.
- What assignment?
- Come and see.
Okay.
When the flock flew southward
for winter
one small but proud bird said:
"I'm flying to the sun."
It soared up
but soon it singed its wings
and fell into
a very deep canyon.
May none of us,
no matter how high we fly,
break ties...
with the work collective.
- What's up?
- What is it, dear?
I'm sorry for the bird.
The infuriated princess
hung herself on her own plait,
cos he said how many grains were
in the bag
and how many drops in the sea
and how many stars in the sky.
Here's to cybernetics!
Your health!
MARRIAGE PALACE
Dear friends,
today is a joyful,
bright and sunny holiday.
A few seconds later
these silver scissors
will cut this crimson silk ribbon
and open for the newly-weds
of our district
a straight road
to the bright future,
to happiness, love and harmony,
you see...
through our Marriage Palace.
The honor of opening the palace...
We have conferred here
and decided to grant the honor
of opening the palace
to the beautiful woman,
to the girl whose fate
embodies the new status
of female mountain dwellers.
It's a student,
a Young Communist, an athlete
and last but not least, a beauty.
This is my assignment.
To quote our renowned satirist,
"A woman is a friend to man."
Hold on, speak slowly please.
- I'm putting this down.
- Who is it?
- The media probably.
- Oh, the media!
So... To quote
our renowned satirist,
- "A woman is a friend to man."
- Great!
Here's to the women.
Give me the horn, now.
...He disrupted the solemn opening
of the Marriage Palace.
Then on the ruins of the chapel...
Did I ruin the chapel?
No, that was before you,
in the 14th century.
...On the ruins of the chapel...
Quite so. This is true.
It's written correctly.
It's all right.
On one hand.
But there is the other side
of the medal.
The wrongdoer is not a wrongdoer
but an eminent research worker,
a worker by brain.
He has come to us, okay?
To collect our myths, legends,
you see... toasts.
- Toasts?
- Yes, toasts.
But he hit more
than he could chew, right?
We are dealing here
with an industrial accident.
I've got a wonderful toast.
You have a wrong idea
about our parts.
As we all know, Kuzbass is--
...national smithy.
Kuban is a national granary.
And the Caucasus is a national what?
Health resort!
Wrong! It's a national smithy,
granary and health resort.
Where have you been?
There's a great toast.
Excuse me.
- Come on.
- Wait a minute.
We'll talk to Shurik
and you write down your toast
in three copies for me.
Yes, sir!
I'd like to see an old ritual
or, better still, take part in it.
My, look around, okay?
You won't see
those grandpa's customs
and grandma's rituals.
Not in our parts.
Maybe high up in the mountains...
you might find something
for your science.
- Let's climb the mountains.
- Right.
That's your job, okay?
You are here to collect tales
and we here work to make them
a reality you see.
- Oh yes.
- I've brought the toast.
- Is it bad?
- Yes.
- What's the big idea?
- You said 3 copies.
To live, so to say, is good.
But to live well is even better.
You've said it!
Manager
Comrade Saakhov
For shame!
Are you trying to harm the orphan
who only has an aunt and uncle?
- Twenty five.
- You're wrong.
I respect your niece
but there's a limit to it.
- Eighteen.
- Have a heart!
You're getting a wife, not a goat.
She's a student, a Young Communist,
and athlete and a beauty -
all for 25 sheep.
- It's absurd to haggle.
- Those are apolitical ideas.
I swear, honestly, you don't see
the political situation.
You see life through the window
of my personal car.
Twenty-five sheep at a time
when our district
hasn't yet reckoned
with our country.
Don't mix what's yours
with the country's.
Comrade Jambrail,
I was sent here
to take care of the state interests.
Sit for a while.
To sum up...
- 20 sheep.
- 25.
Twenty.
A Finnish vacuum cleaner.
A letter of commendation.
- And a free voucher.
- To Siberia.
- Okay.
So...
The bridegroom has consented,
his family too.
As for the bride...
We don't bring up our youngers well,
we don't.
They are not serious
about marriage.
Anyway, why should I ask the bride?
Throw a bag on her head and--
That's right.
The right decision.
But leave me out of this.
Don't worry.
Other guys will do it.
- Not from our district.
- Sure.
DANCE SCHOOL
PAYMENT - ONE RUBLE
This not your lezginka.
This is twist.
I show you all over again.
Press the butt with the toe
of your right foot.
The toe of your left foot
presses the second butt,
now press the two butts at once.
MULTI-PLAY DOMINO SESSION
PAYMENT - ONE RUBLE
Game over.
- Did you sell her?
- That's my business.
Hold on.
Move to the right!
Go!
Get the sheep to the shed
and the fridge inside.
What are you up to?
- Go home.
- It won't work.
Stealing such a girl!
An athlete, a Young Communist!
One guy
in the neighboring district
walked away
with a Party member!
You're making progress.
Great progress.
- It's nothing.
- Nothing?
Just securing myself.
Okay, I'll give you a more
difficult assignment.
Like what?
- Get packed in a sleeping bag.
- Right.
Quickly... Hold it... Now.
Ready.
Steady. Go.
Done.
Are you gonna sleep on your feet?
- Now.
- Yes, yes.
Careful.
Hold on, I'll pull you out.
There are two of them.
The other's with a tail.
The donkey doesn't count.
The second's one too many.
- A witness.
- What if--
- No casualties please.
- Let's wait.
Yes, let's wait. You deal.
Is it folklore too?
No, it's a student song.
About Polar bears.
- You don't want it.
- Why not?
It's student folklore. Go ahead.
Okay.
There's a place on the globe
Where it is freezing cold,
Where the Polar bears
Rub against the Pole.
Ages and centuries float by,
Under the ice sleep seas.
Meanwhile the Polar bears
Keep rotating the earth.
The bears work with purpose
Spinning the earth with might
So that future lovers
Meet each other might.
Bye, Shurik. You go straight on
and I go to the base.
And thank you.
- Good bye.
Nina!
- Wait!
- What?
Let me see you off.
You didn't justify
our confidence.
- How can we work?
- Your plan is unrealistic.
It's... er...
Voluntarism!
Mind your language
in my home!
What did I say?
Here's your prepayment.
We quit!
- Take it.
- Wait a minute.
It's alright.
The guy who is in our way
will help us.
Now you are talking.
- We're with you.
- Get ready.
- Come here!
- Do it, you oaf!
Whosee shoee?
Minee... Thanks.
Let's go.
Go. It's getting late.
See you don't lose your way.
Please go.
Comrade Shurik?
- Good evening.
- Hello.
- Supper?
- A bottle of wine.
You're exceptionally lucky.
You want to see
a beautiful old ritual?
Yes, very much.
- Tomorrow at dawn.
- What?
You can take part too.
Many thanks.
- Juice?
- No, thanks.
What is the ritual called?
Abduction of the bride.
- Abduction?
- Not quite.
The bride wants to be abducted.
Her parents don't mind.
According to our custom
the bride should be stolen
before registration.
Stolen? It's a beautiful custom.
Where do I come in?
- Catch the bride.
- Catch...
- Shove her into the bag.
- The bag?
Is it the custom too?
Fantastic!
And give her to whom?
- The enamoured man.
- Nope.
Friends of the enamoured man.
Oh, friends!
- Such is the custom.
- I see.
Oh, here they are. Meet them.
My pleasure.
Please meet...
Shurik.
Sorry. Sit down please.
They don't speak any Russian
but they understand it.
What did he say?
He said good appetite.
- Go on, eat.
- Thanks a lot.
Smart.
What did he say?
He says if you refuse
they'll knife you.
- That's a joke.
- A joke...
A joke. Okay.
Good. Nina will be happy.
So the bride's name is Nina?
She's my niece.
So Nina has a boyfriend?
They adore each other.
I quite forgot.
Tomorrow I've got...
I mean I'm sorry,
I can't do this.
Comrade Shurik,
the point is
Nina wants you
to do it.
Did Nina say that?
Yes.
Well, tell Nina
I'll do it. See you.
The custom prescribes
doing it naturally.
The bride will offer resistance,
she'll kick, bite, call the police,
cry "I'm going to complain
to authorities!"
You ignore her,
it's a fine custom.
I see.
Not to worry,
it will all be natural.
Later.
Shurik!
What are you doing?
Say nothing.
What's with you?
I've come to say goodbye.
Goodbye, Shurik.
Goodbye, Nina.
- Be happy.
- Goodbye, goodbye.
What is it?
The stolen bride.
You joker! Don't forget to invite me
when you make barbecue
out of this bride.
EAGLE NEST
So it wasn't a ritual?
- She was really stolen.
- Yes.
Who stole her? Oh...
Who's the bridegroom?
This usually becomes known
at the wedding.
There'll be no wedding.
I stole her, I'll redeem her.
Comrade Shurik!
- What happened?
- A crime. Stealing!
What's stolen? Your donkey?
A girl. Nina.
I'm the only witness.
You are not a witness,
you are an abductor.
- A criminal!
- I didn't know!
It's a disgrace on a district scale,
I swear, honestly.
- I didn't know!
- I'll handle that.
Who's this mysterious man,
a paltry scoundrel?
Do you know him? No?
Too bad. He's an immoral character,
immoral.
Thanks for the tip-off.
This negative occurrence
will help us mobilize the public.
Right. I'm going to the police.
Police? They'll arrest you.
They'll have to.
Have you got money?
Your salvation is in vanishing.
I'll do the rest.
Nina will be rescued
and those bastards tried.
You'll appear in court
as a witness.
I have no right
to abuse your goodwill.
You're taking chances
harboring a criminal.
I must atone for my guilt.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Comrade Shurik,
why the police?
We don't want sacrifices.
Go to the prosecutor.
He'll understand.
Welcome, dear guests.
- Is the prosecutor here?
- Sure. The whole town's here.
We were waiting for you.
Wine for the dear guests!
Thanks, I don't drink.
I'd like to see the prosecutor.
You can't refuse.
It's a mortal offense.
- Please.
- This way, please.
Hospital?
Come quick.
Kapitanaki's house.
One of the guests is quite bad.
Please come now.
Cut it. The man's singing.
What's happened? A runover?
The man's had a drop too much.
It's a complex case.
We must save him,
it's serious, I swear.
Owing to alcoholism
he has a fixed idea.
He's bursting to rescue
a stolen bride.
A clouded mind, honestly.
Yeah. Delirium tremens.
- D.T.
- He's very bad indeed.
He'll be as good as new
in three days.
There's no hurry.
What's important is
to cure our guest.
And return a sound man to society.
- No hurry at all.
- We'll do what we can.
If I was a sultan,
I would have three wives
And I'd be surrounded
By triple beauty, guys.
But upon second thought
Given such affairs
I would have - Allah knows!-
Only trouble an' cares.
On one hand it's so good
To have three young wives
But on the other
It's not so, guys.
It's okay,
you can come.
What should we, sultans, do
Faced with this setup?
Should we have - gee! - three wives
Or make do with one?
There's no need to think long,
The answer's well known.
If I was a sultan,
I would live alone.
Open up!
So that's what it is?
I'm going on a hunger strike.
No one but the prosecutor
enters here.
Take care!
MENTAL HOSPITAL
Typical delirium tremens.
He's bursting to rescue
a stolen girl,
comrade Saakhov says.
Yeah. He called me.
He's now in a state
of catatonic agitation.
- He demands to see you.
- I'll see him, if he demands.
Careful.
Comrade Saakhov's diagnosis
has been confirmed.
Saakhov?
- Did you say Saakhov?
- I did.
He incarcerated me here.
He sent you here
when you were in crisis.
- Acute crisis.
I'll tell you what.
Saakhov stole this girl.
Sure. Stole and buried her.
- And wrote an epitaphy.
- Listen. Saakhov is...
Relax, we'll set you on your feet.
Alcoholics are in our line.
Untie me!
Will you behave?
Untie him.
I see you don't believe me.
Can I see the prosecutor?
You can.
Where's the prosecutor here?
Ward 6. Napoleon was there before.
Don't eat, don't drink,
don't speak if you like,
it won't help you.
The worthiest man in the district
offers you his hand and heart.
- A dinner set.
- What?
- It's a dinner set now.
- A big set?
For 12 persons, 96 pieces.
You've no conscience.
You spit on our customs.
What?
It's silly. You've no choice.
You mean they'll miss you?
They'll turn to your family.
And your family is me.
I'll say you quit college,
got married
and left.
Let me tell you...
Don't interrupt me!
So...
Either you agree to marry
comrade Saa--
Or you stay here for good.
There's a good girl.
Open the door.
You'll meet your dear fiance.
- Take off my hat.
- What?
Take off my hat.
I'm disappointed I swear.
I didn't do anything, okay?
Just walked in.
- She's too young and fickle.
- Fickle? She's a hooligan!
Get this straight.
There are two ways
I can leave this house.
Either I take her
to the registry office
or she takes me
to the prosecutor's office.
- No.
- Of course not.
Don't worry.
She'll get hungry in a day,
depressed in a week
and wise in a month. Let's wait.
Remember, comrades:
you've got to justify
the great trust placed in you.
You answer with your lives for her.
We'll do our best,
dear comrade Jabrail.
- How 'bout a drop or two?
- It's a sin to mock at patients.
- I can run for it.
- You can't run away from here.
I know how.
MENTAL HOSPITAL
Hey, psycho!
Where are you running like mad?
- Where's your donkey?
- Hi.
- Where are you going?
- That way.
Jump in, I'll give you a lift.
Where to?
I'll tell you my story
and you decide where.
- Make haste.
- It's a terrific vehicle.
Cursed be the day when I mounted
this hoover!
To quote the great wise--
A new paragraph.
Lunch.
Underline it.
She refused to eat soup.
- Refused...
- Mutton soup in brackets.
Now...
Three plates of shashlik.
She threw it out.
Now wine.
She broke
two bottles.
- Three.
- Write three.
Three bottles.
Go on.
Fruit.
Oranges...
EAGLE NEST
- Comrade Saakhov's dacha?
- Yep.
It's the epidemiological station.
What is it?
What do you want?
It's about a murrain epidemy.
Mass vaccination.
Sign here...
It's mandatory.
SOPORIFIC DRAUGHT
- Do I take off the shirt?
- Not necessarily.
Lie on your belly.
Relax. I'm not injecting yet.
Oh... Is it painful?
It depends on the needle's diameter.
What's your...
Already?
- Spirits?
- Spirits.
Don't fidget.
It's the latest vaccine
of prolonged effect.
- Anybody else in the house?
- Nobody.
Be quiet
or else - "memento mori".
- Momentarily...
- Into a mere.
- Get it?
- Yes.
Assistant, water!
I bet Nina is here.
Go find her.
When will they pass out?
In half an hour.
The filtering murrain virus
is especially virulent...
Cut it out, doc.
Shut up... Please go on.
...in an organism
weakened by nicotine,
alcohol and--
- Bad excesses.
- Right.
Nina!
Where are you?
Hush. In there.
Nina,
what's with you?
Are you okay?
Thank God.
- Why?
- Traitor, mean hireling.
- Hold it!
- Judas, bastard!
- How much did they pay you?
- Wait!
Untie me!
Worthless, venal creature!
Let me be, gangster.
Rotter, dolt, chameleon.
Scoundrel!
Alkie! Despicable folklor--
Hello.
Come on, speak.
Who is there?
Hello.
What a surprise!
I must change, excuse me.
They'll change you in the morgue.
We are here to try you
by the law of the mountains
for disgracing our clan.
You'll die like a mean jackal.
You have no right.
You'll answer for this.
I will answer for your lousy skin
only to my conscience,
my sister's honor
and my ancestors' memory.
Nina, stop them.
We are modern guys.
It's medieval barbarity!
I have broken the code of honor
and I admit my mistake.
Mistakes are not admitted,
they must be atoned with... blood.
You can't do this!
It's the mob law! I demand
a trial by the civil law.
Did you buy her by the civil law?
Did you steal her by the civil law?
Cut this fruitless debate.
Sis, turn on the tellie
to full capacity.
No.
Please. I won't do it again.
I swear, I won't.
Let me go to the prosecutor's.
I'll hand myself in to authorities.
Hamlet. Good bird.
Are you in your right minds?
Easy, it's only salt.
All rise. The court is in session.
Glory to our court, the most humane
court in the world!
All sit.
- Sit down.
- Thanks, I'd rather stand.
Your honor,
he can't sit.
After the springtime downpour
Bright dawn is sure to come.
Lovers for many years
Will admire
The glowing skies.
Rivulets will be purling,
Mist will be coyly swirling,
White as a Polar bear.
Translated by Raisa Svirina