Three Reasons to Stop Nuclear
Weapons 1. Proliferation of
Nuclear Weapons Nuclear Technology Puts the World in Tension
1944 The following year after a successful experiment
Two bombs destroyed two cities
After that Nuclear technology
developed as a power source, but
always  Nuclear weapons cannot be made without nuclear weapons technology that was linked to nuclear weapons technology The
Nuclear Proliferation Prevention Treaty
states that the transfer of nuclear weapons technology
is limited to peaceful uses,
but now five countries have
acquired nuclear weapons with this technology.  It is difficult to distinguish
between a nuclear weapons program and the peaceful use of nuclear weapons. Nuclear
technology was sold to a small country as a peaceful technology, but
it became a
nuclear weapon.
2. Nuclear waste and pollution
Used nuclear fuel contains radioactive and toxic
plutonium.
It takes tens of thousands of years to become non-harmful.
Plutonium can be extracted from it by a process called
reprocessing, and it becomes a
nuclear weapon.  It
can be used and reused,
but there is no suitable nuclear reactor for reuse.
1 mg kills a person and a bomb can be made with a few kilograms. A
wonderful country Germany
has tons of this. In the
old days, reprocessing was good.  It's because I saw it. The
dumping place is also a problem. The
sea is banned, so I'll bury it, but
I haven't found a place to last for tens of thousands of years.
Only Finland has
3. Accidents and Disasters There were seven major accidents
in the use of nuclear weapons for more than 60 years,
three of
which
released large amounts of radioactivity into the environment
1957 1986 2011
Russia Ukraine Japan
has created an uninhabitable place for decades. It
is believed that there are thousands of deaths.
Disasters occurred in different types of nuclear reactors at
different times in different countries
.  Is the energy supply
worth the disaster every 30 years?  Is
30%
worth Fukushima every 10 years
? Where can I contaminate?
Where is the line that is impossible anymore
? Should nuclear power be used?
Risks come with benefits, but
you should think more ethically than profits and losses Anyone
who wants to know another aspect of nuclear power