The 12,018 Human Era Calendar is now available.
Order the limited edition...
... for the short time of 10 days and then never again.
It's like a regular 2018 calendar with one important difference.
It is for the year 12,018 of the human era.
In our video "A New Calendar for Mankind" we explained why this should be the calendar we use.
For last year's calendar we received a lot of feedback and we took it to heart...
...what you guys wanted.
The calendar for 12.018 has much more space for notes.
A spiral binding, we got the shipping costs down.
And it will arrive in time for Christmas.
It's printed on high-quality paper,
has a gold cover,
and is produced in Seattle to ensure quality that is in short appropriate.
The calendar itself features 12 detailed illustrations...
... of human cultures around the globe.
Order now, it's only available for a limited time of 10 days...
...until October 20th.
The Human Era Calendar is a project of passion for us...
...representing the ideas of human unity and progress...
...and that we must work together to survive and travel to the stars  .
This is the second time we've done one like this and we're trying to do it like this from now on.
Thank you to everyone who loves the idea of a new histo
iography.  Without this group of like-minded people, we couldn't achieve any of this.
[Dog barks]