It's the most wonderful time of the year.
The 12,020 human space era calendar
has arrived. You can order it now,
until we sell out
and then never again.
In the last few years we've looked back
at the achievements of our ancestors that
pave the way for our modern world
more than 10 thousand years ago.
This year, we'll turn our gaze to the future
of humanity and how we would explore space
in the next 10 thousand years.
12 illustrations will take you to the liquid
gas oceans on Titan, colonies on Mars,
the storm clouds on Uranus and many more
stops on humanity's biggest journey yet.
Enjoy solar-system-wide delivery, shipping from
the US and finally also from Europe.
Order now to get our limited edition calendar
in time for the holidays to make your kids,
family and friends happy,
or to distract yourself from the looming void within.
Y'know, whatever works for you.
You can get the calendar together with a
duck plushie, a hoodie or a poster if you want,
we've put together a few deals.
Thank you so much to the thousands of people
who got the calendar last year.
Because of you, we can keep this channel free
for everyone and make even more beautiful things.
A happy interstellar year, 12,020.
Captions created by @plarmknacsd on Twitter.
*dog howls*