Black holes are one of the weirdest things out there.
They don't seem to make any
sense Where do they come from?  And, what happens if you fall into one?
♫
Stars are incredibly massive collections of mostly hydrogen atoms
that have collapsed from huge clouds of gas under their own gravity
In this way, nuclear fusion crushes hydrogen atoms into helium
, thus releasing a tremendous amount of energy.
form of radiation, force against gravity.
Maintaining a delicate balance between the two forces
As long as there is fusion in the core, the star remains stable
But for stars much more massive than our Sun
The heat and pressure in the core allows it to fuse heavier elements until IRON is reached
Different  of the elements that came before, the fusion process that created iron does not generate energy
Iron accumulates in the center of the star until it reaches a critical amount
And the balance between Radiation and Gravity is broken
The core collapses
And, within a fraction of a second, the  star implodes
Moving at approximately 1/4 the speed of light, feeding even more mass to the center of the core
It is at this very moment that all the heaviest elements in the universe are created
As the star dies, exploding in Supernova
This produces a Neutron Star
Or, if the star is massive enough, the entire mass of the core collapses into a black hole.
If you looked into a black hole, what you would actually be seeing would be  The Event Horizon
Anything that was going to cross the Event Horizon
would have to be traveling faster than the Speed of Light to escape. In ot
er words, it's impos
ible.  So we just see a black sphere, reflecting nothing.
But if the Event Horizon is the black part, what is the ''Hole'' part of the Black Hole?
The Singularity
We don't know what it is, exactly
A Singularity can be of infinite density
Which is to say that all its mass is concentrated in a single point in space, with no surface or volume
Or something completely different
At the moment, we just don't know
It's like  the age of ''Dividing by Zero'
' Black holes don't happen to suck things up like a vacuum cleaner
If we were to trade the sun for a black hole of equivalent mass
Nothing much would change on Earth, except that we'd freeze to death, of course  .
What would happen to you if you fell into a Black Hole?
The feeling of time is different around Black Holes,
From the outside you would seem to slow down as you approach the Event Horizon
So time slows down for you
At some point you would seem to freeze in time, slowly turn red,
And disappear
Whereas, from your perspective, you could watch the rest of the universe at advanced speed
Kind of like seeing the future
At the moment, we don't know what would happen next, but we think it could be one of two things:
One: You die a quick death.
Black Hole curves space so much that once you cross the Event Horizon
There would be only one possible direction
You can understand that literally inside the Event Horizon you can only go one direction
It's like being in a very tight alley that closes behind you  you after each step
The mass of a black hole is so concentrated
that at some point even tiny distances of a few centimeters would
mean that gravity would act millions of times m  More force in different parts of your body
Your cells would be ripped out as your body is stretched further and further
Until you become a stream of boiling Plasma, the size of an atom
Two: You die a very quick death
As soon as you cross the Event  Horizon, you would hit a wall of fire and be wiped out
None of the options are exactly
fun How fast you would die depends on the mass of the Black
Hole A small Black Hole would kill you before you even enter Event Horizon
While you could probably travel inside  a Super Massive Black Hole for a good amount of time
So the farther away from the Singularity you are, the longer you live
of an asteroid
And there are also the Super Massive Black Holes, which are found at the heart of every Galaxy
And it has been feeding for billions of years.
The known Super Massive Black Hole is S50014+81
Forty billion times the mass of our Sun
It is 236.7 Billion kilometers in diameter
Which is 47 times the distance from the Sun to Pluto
Even though Black Holes are so powerful
They will eventually evaporate  through a process called Hawking Radiation
To understand how this works, we have to look at ''Empty Space''
''Empty Space'' is not really empty,
but filled with virtual particles, shooting into existence, and nullifying  each other
When this happens on the edge of a Black Hole, one of the particles will be drawn into the Black Hole
And the other will escape, becoming a real particle
So the Black Hole will lose energy
This happens very slowly at first
But it gets longer  fast as the Black Hole shrinks
When it gets to the mass of a large asteroid it will be radiating at room temperature
When it has the mass of a mountain it will radiate approximately with heat  of our Sun
And in the last second of its life, the Black Hole radiates with the force of billions of Nuclear Bombs in one big explosion
But this process is incredibly slow
The biggest Black Holes we know can take up to a Googol years to evaporate
That's  so long that when the last Black Hole ceases to exist, nothing will be alive to witness
The Universe will have become uninhabitable long before
This is not the end of our story, there is still a lot to talk about Black Holes
And we will talk more about them in  Part
2 Big thanks to Fraser Cain for helping with this video
We happened to make some Kurzgesagt wallpapers in 4K for different screen sizes
You can get them on our Patreon page Which
also helps us to make more videos like  this December, the first month with 3 videos