[Plays "Better Than You" from Duman]
[sounds of schoolchildren]
♪ I haven't seen anyone ♪ ♪ Prettier than you ♪
♪ I didn't know anyone ♪ ♪ Prettier than you ♪
♪ I didn't even look at anyone ♪ ♪ What's on my mind ♪
Stop ya stop.
It's not happening bro, it's not happening. I'm getting off because of the plane tree.
What? Is it because of me?
Yes, because of you.
My voice is bass barter. You're playing tittiti, brother.
Not with Cinar. We are still looking for a guitarist.
Can't find my tone guys.
You eliminated ten guitarists, brother. There's the guy you eliminated because he had a small foot.
I eliminated it once because it couldn't keep up.
What about the boy you sent because his ears are not symmetrical?
Ears are very important in music.
Oh brother, choose one now. There is very little time left for the competition.
If necessary, we can race without a guitarist, but not from this kid.
-Dot. -I swear it will.
I promise I will work hard, I will find the tone.
It is very important for me to participate in this competition.
I record your voice. I listen for days.
Maybe if you listen to my voice for days.
Ok, well I accepted.
Come on. This is it. Super. thumbs up.
Then I'll start working right away.
It's great, long live.
Glad loser . [laughs]
My dear. Pray, I'm not in the mood for a soloist.
Otherwise, I wouldn't have joined the group. Yes, it's time for tonsil massage.
[Eser] I need to turn up my voice.
[shouting] Mi, ma, me.
[joyful music player]
-[music end] -Let me get an autograph over there.
Dad, Zeynep, I have great news for you.
-I have some news for you too, son. - Dad, leave it. Mine is more important.
I am participating in the Musicians of the Future competition.
[Çınar] They took me to the school's group.
Finally Dad, I'm finally going to enter this contest.
[Çınar] Why are you buying my guitar?
-What's going on? -The thing is, my child.
His partner defrauded your father. So your father went bankrupt.
We're taking away all these items, groceries, everything now.
[man] Do you see the smoke?
There was something you said when you entered this door,
-Like a music band or something. -Yup?
Forget it, let it go too. Get a job now.
Help your father. So support. Look what our man has become.
Your work is your strength, lay lay lom dear.
But sir, you have ruined my ten years of pedagogical approach in an instant.
Let me talk to my child, right?
talk. Am I telling you something? Talk.
My son, my partner Necip defrauded our architecture office and ran away, that's how we got into this situation.
-[Mehmet] So the things are gone. -A, just the stuff gone?
Tell the boy the truth.
My son is completely gone home, home.
-You have no place to sleep. -What? Is our house gone?
Uncle, which series are you bad at?
-Hold on, but let my father explain. -Well.
Sir, do you have a watch?
It's quarter to three.
No, that's why I didn't ask. I need to get my watch too. Like this.
Thank you so much. Ismet Bey, if it's okay, let's go.
Look, help your father.
[man] Be supportive.
Let's go.
Dad, how are our things going? My guitar is our home.
Where will we stay now, father? Where will we go?
We will go to our village, son.
Do we have a village?
[lyre voice]
[joyful road music]
[bus sound]
[joyful road music ends]
-[bus sound] -[rooster crow]
Dad, we had a village but why didn't we know about it?
Because I had a bad relationship with your grandfather, son.
I never thought of returning here.
Why were you at odds with my grandfather?
Like you, I lost my mother at a young age.
When my father married someone else
Well, we broke up. Then I built a new life for myself in Istanbul.
And so, well, I don't know, we fell apart.
E, do we have a grandmother now?
Yes, you have a lovely grandmother. Oh, you also have an uncle.
-Our uncle? -Uh huh.
When the nation wins the lottery, their relatives come out. It came out to us when it sank.
-[Mehmet laughs] -Think about it well, dad?
Well, just like dad. If you don't sink, we won't be able to recognize our relatives.
Dad, we'll stay for a while and come back, right? We won't stay long.
You better buy it, Cinar. You will love this place as soon as you step in.
[sound of disgust] My basketball shoes are ruined.
I hated it as soon as I stepped in.
Don't enlarge it, you wipe it with a tissue.
You will love it here. I swear.
♪ There's a village far away ♪
♪ That village is our village ♪
[Çınar] Admit it immediately. Crow loud.
[rooster and chicken sounds]
-[Plate and bowl sounds] -By God, I don't know that, Omer.
[Sevim] You were going to sell the corn and buy me bracelets.
You promised. I've been waiting for two harvests.
Because of you, I can't go to the village fountain and get water.
-Why? -[Sevim] My arms are empty.
I can't take my arms off my embarrassment.
What if this woman did it well.
Let those corn prices be announced, I'll buy your bracelet. Ugh.
It surprises people. A two letter drink.
Milk. No milk.
That's water. That.
Baba.
[music]
[goat voice]
Get a loan.
[Omar] Mehmet Bey.
Did you know the way around here?
Does one ever forget the way home?
He forgets. If it is useless, he forgets.
Fine then, let's go if you don't want to.
[Omar] Stop.
[sad music]
Come here kerata.
-[chicken sounds] -Come.
This is your house.
Dad, daddy, if you don't choke me.
OK.
[coughs]
This is my son.
my grandchildren. Do you remember me grandchild?
Sure, how would you remember?
What about you Zeynep? I have never seen you.
You were a hand, you became a hand.
I love you already, tontis grandpa.
Ah. dear.
Have you heard? My grandson called me "grandpa tontis".
[music ends]
Welcome Mehmet.
Welcome, sister Sevim.
Then should your sister Sevim put three more plates on the table, huh? Let's.
Let me put it.
So that dishonest partner cheated on you, huh?
Anyway, this is a big house. Stay here as long as you want.
Hey, as much as you want. I look at you.
I'll do your laundry, your cooking, your ironing and even your soup.
Anyway, I'll make the beds. You want to sleep.
Now you will manage until you find a job.
Is it work? What job?
We have work, son. We have animals. We have fields.
I only saw medicated fertilizers in front of the door.
We can give the same effect with a drug-free method.
[Zeynep] I can prepare a simple mixture for this.
And the profit share you will get according to the square meter
It can make you rich in a short time.
Is he rich?
In all that talk, I only understood this.
-That's enough for me. -Well, when will my uncle come?
Your uncle will drip soon.
Mother. I'm hungry mom.
Ana.
-O, is there a guest, Dad? -Yeah. huh huh.
-Who is this brother? -This is your brother, my son.
What? Is it my sister?
Oy, did my brother come from Istanbul?
If I'm not happy, who should be?
I've wanted to meet you for years, man.
Be the kerata, be the.
Look, these are my kids too. Cinar and Zeynep.
What? Are these your children?
Wow wow. I became an uncle. My dear nephews.
Come on, kiss my hand.
Why would we kiss? You are younger than us.
My son is half of uncle and father. Get up bro.
-Ha? -Get up. Get up.
Look, I'm half your father.
Come on kiss my hand. I'm your elder nephew.
You are not. Father.
Plane. Son, get used to each other. You will both stay in the same room.
- In the same room? -Uh huh.
[clears throat]
Daddy, my dear brother…
…my grandfather whom I just met…
…and you, little one.
Of course there is a place to stay. But what about school?
I ask you…
...where will this poisonous girl study, huh?
What about the promising me? Where will I study? Where?
Is there a school here?
There is.
Ugh. What a big class this is, friend.
Also, what about a merged class?
But if you think positively, you will have more friends in the crowd.
Don't listen to him. Excessive amount of everything is harmful.
Three people sitting in a row?
Nothing is enough for anyone. There is little of everything here.
what less? Look, there are even two of us.
If you think positively, you can discover the beauty of sharing in absence.
What will you share about your absence? You don't have either. It's not there either.
You'll get bored of here already.
Are you an angel and a demon?
A, you know, I'm Melek.
You didn't know me. I'm Shema.
I'm Cinar. Very pleased to meet you.
-Can you excuse me? -No.
-Can i pass? -[voice of objection]
Will you allow me? Can i pass?
-[joyful music player] -A!
Maybe it has the internet.
Where does this board come from?
Come on, open up.
-[music end] -Where does this board come from?
The board is pretty clear now.
How is it open?
Isn't that a smart board? Why isn't it working then?
By God, our board is smart, but it doesn't work.
[everyone laughs]
Look at the class. It doesn't even have a smart board.
You're also missing a board. Are we telling you something?
[nida]
What's going on here?
Did you think this child was homeless?
Anyone who makes fun of this kid will find me.
He is my nephew.
I am not.
Halis, Muhlis, distribute the bite, my son.
Eat guys.
No, what is this a celebration of?
What if I became an uncle yesterday and I'm giving away his bite. Let's enjoy.
What is this? You give sugar cubes for bite.
Are we horses?
Moon. It's humorous as well, asshole.
Zeynep, how are you, my nephew?
Do you have pocket money? Look, or I'll give it to you.
-I'm giving you a look. -I do not want. giving me unnecessary pocket money
Responsibility and personal development assignments that I have to earn during this period.
do not interrupt.
Yes, look, it's like poison, it's a bit naive.
[Emrah] Look at me, my nephew from the city.
If you have a problem, come to the back row. I'm sitting there. Okay?
-[Emrah] Walk. -Repent, repent.
-Can i pass? -No.
Öf be.
I understand you best, Cinar.
[Salim] I'm also from the city.
I lived in Gebze for about a week.
Ah Istanbul ah.
I dropped my Istanbul card.
Speaking of Istanbul cards, don't you think there is a metrobus suffocating in the air?
-I have never taken the metrobus. -Oh, by the way
Let me introduce you to my friend Sibel. Sibel.
[stammering] Nice…
…welcome.
Hello.
Thank you again, Ms. Gul.
Thanks to you, we registered the children immediately.
I hope they get used to it quickly.
Don't worry, Mr. Mehmet. They will get used to it.
I do my best so that the children do not miss anything.
My job is above everything for me.
-Lovely. You are idealistic. -Thank you.
My children are very talented. All of them have a passion for art and music.
I don't just take his classes,
I also attach importance to their development in artistic fields.
For example, I'm thinking of building a big art center here.
Wouldn't it be great if we built Europe's largest open-air stage here?
It's possible.
Yes, but as an architect, it would be a bit expensive.
Think big, Mr. Mehmet.
It is an imposing structure that can be seen even from the satellite.
Maybe one day the children will perform a musical play here.
[surprised] I'm late. Let's go to class. Nice to meet you.
[Mehmet] Me too.
Ben the.
[classroom hum]
[silence]
Sit down.
-How are we today? -[students] We're fine.
Beautiful.
New friends joined us.
Zeynep, Cinar.
They will also be reading with us this year.
Hah, if you call it reading.
Plane.
-What happened? Didn't you like our class? -What should I like, teacher?
Look at this. Who will learn what in this crowd?
For example, this friend.
[kekeleyerek] Ben mi?
Oho, school's over before you talk.
Especially in this crowd, the girl finishes school in ten years.
-[contest button sound] -False detection.
Çınar ranked third in Sibel district.
Okay, let's say he's the third in the county.
What about this boy?
♪ Ma ma mi mi ♪ [Laughs]
Oho, what if he read this, what if he didn't?
District first.
[English] Yes!
-And this? -Get your hand off. Annoying.
City first. Full shot.
What are you eating and drinking? How did I fall into the class?
How did this become the first in the province?
Cinar, don't make fun of your friends.
Teacher, I am his uncle. I am his parent.
Dont worry. I will take care of him.
Boy, didn't I tell you not to make fun of your friends?
Are you going to humiliate me in front of my villager?
-No, this is new too, teacher. - Let it go, let it go.
Emrah. Let me sit down instead.
[everyone laughs]
Hişt!
Yes, our lesson is music.
Let's practice the last song I taught you.
Ayşe, take out your flute.
Let's wipe the rust off our ears.
Hah, how is he going to wipe the rust off our ears with a block flute?
[clears throat]
[Plays the song "Gezsen Anadoluyu"]
What kind of village is this?
♪ How beautiful would you find it ♪ ♪ Traveling Anatolia ♪
♪ You get rid of your troubles ♪ ♪ Travel Anatolia ♪
♪ They have crystalline rivers ♪ ♪ They have springs of ice ♪
♪ What a beautiful land they have ♪ ♪ Traveling Anatolia ♪
Rose teacher is right in my head. He thinks project oriented, super.
I loved it here.
Well done Zeynep. Go and tell my father like that so that we can stay here forever.
I'm saying that too. You hit it right.
[sound of squeaking]
I pressed it.
Again?
[everyone laughs]
What's going on guys? What happened to the sycamore?
My teacher Cinar fucked up.
Muhlis, speak properly.
[laughs off]
[clears throat] Teacher, Çınar shit.
[laughs]
[joyful music plays and ends]
Son, you are in the village now.
-Learn to walk by looking straight ahead. -Ugh. OK.
Don't kiss the big one.
Elsewhere you lament, "His uncle didn't teach." they say.
Mother. Daughter, get my nieces and nephews dinner.
What are you shouting, father disguised? What are you shouting huh?
You go wash your hands first.
Look, it's still here. Walk. Deh. Get up, go.
Get out, get out.
Aunt Sevim, is there anything I can clean my shoes with?
I also stepped on animal feces.
Well, it's always like this here, my Cinder, Zeynep.
[Sevim] So your shoes can get dirty too,
your clothes may be torn.
E-dishes are not that good around here.
There is no internet pattern in any house.
Therefore, it cannot be lived here. You understand? What?
-Then how do you live here? -He?
Your tongue is as big as a shoe, huh, as much as a shoe.
I'll go and get you a diaper.
Emrah!
[mouth smacking]
-[sound of knocking on the table] -[cry of fear]
I'm sorry mom. I eat with my hands, I couldn't find a fork.
-By the way, the bite is very nice. -Eat while there is abundance.
Because these may be your last bite.
How?
You care for your nephews like this, it's beautiful.
But why did they come? -Why did they come?
They will take our house away from us.
Will they take our house away from us?
Is the moon just our home? Our field, our tractor, our animals…
-…the room. -What? my room?
My room is my red line. I'm so angry right now.
Beautiful.
[crickets chirping]
Drop that car. That car is mine. Get out of that bed. That bed is mine.
But they gave me this bed. -What's wrong with me bro?
This room is mine. That bed is mine. This bed is mine.
-Where will I sleep now? -I don't know, friend. Lie on the ground.
Gee. Who are you bro?
my uncle. Whatever I say happens.
What if it's an uncle who still has milk teeth?
Enough is enough, it's come this far now.
And how far can yours go anyway?
Irreverent.
Hey guys, are you asleep yet?
We didn't sleep bro. No more sleep for me.
Why? What happened?
Look, you're my brother, you're my senior, you're older, but this kid didn't exist.
He listens neither big nor small. It's a Zirzop, it's official.
Cinar, what does Emrah say?
Father, I swear it's not my fault. The real problem is itself.
"This is my room," he says. He says "go", he says "lie down".
Yes, is it a lie?
You always have eyes on our tractor and animal.
We can't eat bite, these are the last.
You're going to throw us at the door. These are always for you…
-…small. -Emrah, my son, what are you saying?
Don't be sorry. Where does he hear these words now?
-But mom, you said. -Did I say?
"Our nephews are guests." I said, "We should embrace them." said.
-The lands? -Look, it still says "lands".
So what are we doing now?
We brush our teeth before bed, right?
Come on, don't worry. Let me see.
-[Emrah] But mother. -[Sevim] No buts, come on.
[Emrah] But mom.
Don't bother.
Squeezing.
They will also get used to us.
But I won't get used to it, Dad.
[music enters]
Good night, son.
-[crickets chirping] -[end of music]
-[student #1] Ayşe. -[student #2] Are you crazy, what are you doing?
[classroom hum]
What are you doing?
I write the speakers.
Well, I'm not talking.
Look at that noise. There are a lot of people besides me.
Look, it's still writing. Give me that chalk.
-Come on, I'm the class president. -I said give it.
-My fathers. -I don't care what your father says.
What are you guys doing? break up.
Sit down.
What is happening? What is it that you can't take?
Teacher, I was sitting very well at my desk.
He wrote me to the speakers.
A, Emrah. Is it really that much of a cross, baby?
But teacher now if my actions as a president are to be questioned
I will leave the presidency.
OK, let it go.
Ha? How?
You've been president for years.
If there are friends among you who want to be other candidates
We can make a new choice.
I am a candidate teacher.
Wonderful. Cinar candidate.
Teacher, if this is an annoying candidate, I am also a candidate.
-Annoying. -Beautiful. Ayşe is also a candidate.
Then homework for you.
You are preparing a speech for your own election campaign.
Tomorrow we will have an election in the schoolyard.
[cries of joy]
talk?
Zeynep, help me.
I can't bro. We have agricultural work with my grandfather.
Agricultural?
[drill sound]
Yes, dear villagers. The corn you gathered with a thousand and one effort
you can remove the middleman by just doing this operation.
we sell it to the wholesaler for four times as much.
Moon Omer. Omer, I'm glad they came. Good thing they came.
-We'll get the bracelets now, right? -We'll take it, ma'am.
Masallah.
The intelligence of my poisonous granddaughter Zeynep,
combined with my technical ability
We built a drying system in our warehouse with our own means.
We turn on the button, it heats up in two minutes.
Masallah.
Yes, dear Saklıca people. We can earn more by acting together.
I invite you to bring all your corn to this barn.
Thank God. Oh my grandson.
It's beautiful, mashallah. Masallah.
I came first.
No, I came. My hand is down.
-If I come first, I enter first. -No, I'll go in.
What's going on guys? Why are you bickering again?
Dad, I came first. It's my turn.
This house is my son. What if it's your turn?
All right, Cinar, let Emrah come first. We are both guests.
Yeah like that. Everyone will know their place.
Anyway, let me get this and pass the time.
I will obviously stay long. Let me prepare my speech for tomorrow.
-Whew. Dad, I'll prepare another speech. -What speech?
I'm running for class president at school tomorrow.
Can you help me?
My son accountant jobs on the one hand,
They couldn't catch the partner, they couldn't find him yet, on the one hand.
How can I help you with all this work?
- Should I deal with that too, son? Then I will withdraw my candidacy.
Besides, Teacher Rose had invited you too. You don't have to come, dad.
My son, if there is such an important matter, why don't you tell your father?
Look, your teacher wanted me too. What should I wear?
Dad, don't talk, don't talk yet.
Cinar son, I will write you such a speech that
Everyone will talk about you.
What should I wear?
Whew. Let's.
[nida]
[zurna and halay voice]
Here you go.
You are a lion, father. Thank you so much.
[kissing voice] Come on son. Let me see you.
Dear teacher, my dear friends,
too dear, too handsome...
…my father.
[kiss voice]
I thought about our vision
Engaged in the level of civilization
The time has come to do it.
-[cries of surprise] -School should change their scripts...
-…try it… -Degenerate.
…to those who dictate ideas that have happened…
…deterministic thoughts should stop…
…to information and innovation
We must be open.
Don't you agree with me too?
[shouting] Bravo! br…
We warn you all the time, but the parents still do the homework.
I never liked it, Mr. Mehmet.
But that's the thing. Ms. Rose, that's it.
We just moved here...
Dad, what did you do?
[zurna and halay voice]
[end of music]
Napoleon.
Sultan Suleiman.
Gandi.
Alexander the Great.
[laughs]
What is this picture? What did you do son?
And it's me.
Leadership is not accidental.
If you choose me as your president again
I will make this school high school.
Bravo! Well done!
I'm going to build a bridge to this school!
Bravo.
I will establish a factory and provide employment for this school!
Finish school here and get the right job.
Also if you choose me, sweeter than me to all of you.
Distribute, son. Muhlis.
-[microphone hums] -[Ayşe] Yes, friends.
I'm not going to do what these two bitches would do.
[all] Bravo.
Ayse President!
My seat is gone because of you. You will pay very badly for this.
Ms. Gül, there was something I wanted to talk about with the children.
Is there a place to have a drink nearby?
[sheep bleat]
I mean, what a clear person you are, Ms. Gul. I appreciated it indeed.
When we say let's have a drink, the fountain is right away.
[sheeps bleat from behind]
That's how it is here.
Yes, I'm listening to you, Mr. Mehmet.
I'm so sorry for preparing Cinar's speech.
But lately it has gone through a lot of changes. I also tried to help.
-But… -You failed.
I've never been able to do it?
Although if you have children, you will understand me more easily.
Of course, I also have a daughter and a son.
Yes?
God bless.
[goats and sheep bleat]
If you don't get it wrong…
I say "you". -Sure, relax.
Where is your wife? In Istanbul?
No my wife...
We lost her when Zeynep was very young. Then it was just the three of us.
So you're both mom and dad.
Hard work. Good job.
I have two children, but yours… Of course, yours is more difficult.
There are both your children and those at school, right?
What were yours this time? Those at school?
-Mines are here. -Is he here?
-This is my son Bulut. -[lamb bleats]
This is my daughter Badem.
What about when I say children...
I, I will eat these children.
I place you. [Laughs]
-Comik mi? -Ha?
What? If there's something funny, tell me and we'll laugh.
A, I just relaxed right away.
Why should I eat these children? Why should I eat? I do not eat.
I was also a vegetarian for a while.
I'm kidding. How did you stretch?
Girl, how did she get tense? [kisses]
[melemeler]
-Was that almond called? -Almond.
-Almond. -[Rose laughs]
Almond.
-Eh, are we here? -Not long now.
[adventure music plays]
Here we come.
Çıncı, this is the only place in our village where the internet and the phone are clear.
Instagram Hill.
-[music end] -[message tone]
Born?
Are we climbing the hill like goats just to get on the internet?
Of course.
We do all our internet related activities here.
It's almost like we are in Gebze.
Now let's move on to a place where I can meet, huh?
Where does it shoot best?
On our bus.
Bus?
-[adventure music plays] -[chicken cackles]
hi bro. I didn't have any credits so I called from here.
-I'm Cinar. -Plane?
Who is Cinar?
- His brother is a guitarist. He was going to listen to your voice and record it all day.
Oh, I remembered.
Where are you? Are you calling when the egg is at the door?
I can't explain what happened to my brother.
Your father is bankrupt. They took everything from you.
You moved to your grandfather's village as a family.
Your father had his enrollment in the school there.
Actually, I guess I could tell.
Tell me what you want quickly.
I still play in the band, right?
So, actually, I'm sorry about it. You know,
I am not a selfish man. I can still understand.
Super. I promise I'll join you as soon as I get the guitar.
Look, you have a week.
You got the guitar, you got it. You didn't get it, you're not with us. [English] Goodbye.
-[chicken cackles] -[blows plane tree]
Brother, I need urgent money. But from where?
[breaking sound]
[chicken and rooster sounds]
[nida]
[Çınar] God!
-He's coming. Cyst. Shoo. - Cinar, are you okay? Plane.
Salim.
Brother, I have to go back to Istanbul now.
Look at this, I was missing a beating from a chicken.
He did too.
You are right bro.
My dear nephew, come here.
I was not willing to be offended with you.
After all, we are relatives.
Let's make peace, come on.
OK. I don't have a problem with you anyway.
Well, that's nice. Let's go home together.
My dear Muhlis, you leave Salim at home. It's against our way.
Don't come back alone, kid.
It's okay bro. Come dear.
So, nephew, how's school going?
How are the lessons?
My dear nephew, how beautifully he walks.
Emrah is very fond of you, Cinar.
He says my nephew but doesn't say anything else.
Don't miss it.
Although it is a little difficult to be exact at this height.
[shouts]
[laughs]
What about my nephew, did you take your size?
If you haven't, give me a size.
Oh, by the way, you'll need it for your shoes.
Al sana mendil. Al.
-A, that's mud too. -[both laugh]
Seriously, don't laugh.
You spoil the charisma of the event.
We do evil, not cuteness. Walk.
You see.
Oh, what am I going to do now?
What will I wear? My shoes are ruined. My clothes are ruined.
I hate this village.
Of ya.
[joyful music player]
Thanks.
[kekeleyerek] Rica
I will.
Sibel.
Oh, I'm so sorry for what I said at school.
[chicken voice]
Let's work, lords. Keep screwing up.
Tomorrow we will announce the agricultural revolution.
How long is this grandpa?
16, my grandson.
Girl, we're a little tired, can we take a break now?
call? When the wholesaler arrives tomorrow
"We took a break, we couldn't make it. Sorry." shall we say father?
It's not worth a break, work, dad.
-Here you go. Come on quickly. -Okay girl, okay.
I'm officially afraid of my own daughter.
Let's work hard today so that our children will be comfortable tomorrow.
Let them smile.
Everything for better tomorrows. Is food without labor befitting a farmer?
[together] It doesn't fit.
So keep working.
Continue.
[music rises and ends]
And excellent plays.
Perfect. Emrah. Shoot Emrah...
That, my nephew, rubber shoes look good too.
You get used to the village.
The village is beautiful, but it has a lot of flies.
You know, small little, cheeky, limitless.
The fly is small but nauseous, be careful, nephew.
-Be smart, convince your father. Get out of here. -I won't go.
What are you going to do? Come on, I'm not going. I will stay here just to spite you.
You will not stay. You will go.
I will stay. I'll even take your room.
Well, he confessed. You have your eyes on our goods.
-That's why you came here, isn't it? -Son, you can't talk to my family.
I will tell. I am your uncle. You're too much huh.
You too are missing a lot.
You are one and a half.
Allah Allah.
-[moving music player] -Come here.
[Çınar] I said come here, come.
Mom, they're fighting. Omer, let's separate them.
Omer, come, God.
If you leave. God.
-Leave! -[music end]
Are you a thug?
What, you can't share?
You two are the same age. Go play well.
What fight is this?
He started it.
No, he started it.
-You started. -[Çınar] You started it.
-[Emrah] You. -Don't start again.
What punishment should I give you?
Shall I wait in the garden on one leg, hungry and thirsty, until the evening?
Daddy, it's not like meddling in your business, but we can't reach a solution by punishing like that.
I think we need to find an activity that the kids can do together.
What should we do?
I don't know, it's like camping. Like trekking, like mountain hiking.
So they walk on the mountain?
Exactly.
Hmm.
-[goats and lambs bleat] -How did it get here from trekking?
I really didn't understand.
And how do these animals listen?
And, host.
Come on kitty kitty.
-[linking sound] - ♪ She thinks she's a cat sucker ♪
♪ They hurt my nephew ♪
♪ Emrah tells but doesn't listen ♪
♪ You're going to eat mint tonight ♪
Let's stop mania and help me out a little bit.
Whew. Okay okay. What do you know about grazing animals anyway?
I'll take the goats. You have the sheep.
No? There are 5 goats, 30 sheep.
I have the goats, you have the sheep.
-Goats suit you anyway. Stubborn goat. Son, can't I get rid of you?
-Tell your father, get out of here. -I won't go.
-You will go. -I won't go.
You will go.
I will not go.
Son, you missed the goats. The sheep and goats are all gone.
look at it. Either because of you. My father is going to destroy us.
No, because of you. He will ruin it because of you.
Because of you.
-What are we going to do? -Goat, where are the others?
-Where are they? -Where are the others?
-kucu kucu, pisi pisi. -Çon çön.
Are they here? Where are they? Where are they?
Are you going to drive me crazy? Son, did the wolf descend to the herd?
We took the herd all the way from the other mountain. You deserve a good punishment this time huh.
Yup.
I also give you credit. So now it's time to make a deduction.
In this sense, I also consider a punishment appropriate.
So trekking mireking again?
No, of course not.
This time it's much worse unfortunately.
Criminal mat.
For the first time, you spoke wisely, huh.
Here's the penalty mat. Do not come home without thoroughly cleaning.
The wholesaler will come tomorrow.
Dad, I don't like meddling in your business, but
When you say punishment mat, you keep the kids somewhere, you know?
-As punishment… -Are you happy at work?
I was punished again because of you.
I'm tired of you, I'm tired of you.
It's like I adore you so much. You have eyes on our land.
What will I do with your land?
I want to go back to Istanbul, to my old school.
Take it, your soil and your mop.
Don't mess with me.
[sad music plays]
Here you go, the battery is dead.
What will I do now?
Thank you.
Where did you find these?
I disassembled the radio.
I lit the stoves in case it would be cold at night, nephew.
Oh, I just got a little too out.
Sorry.
It doesn't matter, nephew. It happens between uncle and nephew.
Isn't he too old to listen to the music in his hand?
What are you listening to on that tape?
My mother's voice.
My mother was a singer.
[nostalgic music]
[Çınar] Sometimes he would go out of town to give concerts.
He recorded his songs on this tape because I couldn't sleep without his voice .
On nights without her
They used to put me to sleep by listening to this tape.
[The song "The Road Appeared Again to the Exile"]
[mom] ♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
-Is that why you play the guitar? -[music end]
Yup.
When my mother was a child
He participated and won the Future Musicians competition.
If I win that competition
Maybe I'll feel a little closer to my mother.
But what guitar do I have now?
nor do I have money to go to Istanbul.
If you have such a problem, tell your uncle.
Uncles for today. I'll buy you a guitar.
[Laughs]
Thanks. You've had enough.
You know, it's like I'm starting to warm to you.
We lit the stove, that's why.
-Exactly. A little too hot? -[small explosion sound]
-Did I hear a sound? -[explosion]
It's like something has passed.
-[corn explodes] -Alas!
The corn started to pop when it got too hot.
-God! -Turn off that heater.
I can't go, how can I turn it off?
-Oh my eye. -The lights are coming!
Turn it off, turn it off.
[Emrah] It comes to my mouth. do i turn it off?
[music ends]
So when you deduct costs, you subtract four years' worth of earnings from one harvest.
Ay, honey is dripping from your mouth, my grandson.
-Midwife. -If?
Çınar's problem is actually this music competition.
That's why it's all grumpy.
I know we've been a burden to you but
If we could buy the child a guitar, he would participate in the music competition.
The wholesaler will come tomorrow, the wholesaler. Did I buy the coins a guitar for my grandson!
After receiving the bracelet, of course.
OK. A bracelet for you.
A guitar for my grandson.
Mehmet, this corn business is going to explode. It will explode!
[music player]
[corn popping sounds]
What are we going to do now?
How are we going to clean them?
Do not worry. Let's take a break for ten minutes and eat our corn.
Then we will continue from where we left off, nephew.
[eats corn hungrily]
[rooster and chicken voice]
[cow voice]
My bracelets.
-What are we going to do? -My God is gone. Moon.
We are ruined.
The corn business has exploded, son.
Dad, is there a penalty for us?
No son, no.
The punishments we give you are returned to us as punishment.
Let me see, guys. I will talk to you about something.
-My God. My bracelets are gone, aren't they? -[the villagers revolt]
Calm down.
It's time to travel the land.
-Sweetie Aunt! -He?
Prepare my horse.
horse? Girl, where will I find the horse for you?
Forget the bracelets then.
Do you see? She's very convincing, huh.
said the bracelet. He was convinced.
Let's.
Friends, today is the day of sacrifice.
We will reveal what we have and what we do not have.
Is not it? That guitar will come here.
Is not it? Here you go. Cotton hands in pocket.
It's all for art guys.
No for society.
for art.
For society.
Guys, please shut up. For my memory.
Anyway, come on. Let's see the allowances.
Well, then it's from me.
Hişt Çınar.
Don't worry. Come.
Yes, let's see what was collected.
The magnifying glass is fine. It's possible.
Pocket watch.
Torch.
Pocket book.
Pocket joke.
Not a single pocket money.
Are you aware friend? Only my nephew and I have money here.
Never mind guys. It was enough for you to try.
Thank you so much for thinking of me.
My nephew, don't tie it to the arabesque right away.
We will find that money, right?
Salim, why are you looking so far away?
Why don't you show something?
You know how to say "My city buddy, my closest" when it comes to.
Yes, Salim. Come on, come up with something.
Got a scorpion in your pocket?
Yes, look, take it.
[panic screams]
There is a scorpion!
Are you crazy bro?
Does a person carry a scorpion in his pocket? It's poisonous.
No, this is Şükrü. It's poisoned. It's harmless.
Sorry guys, I can't give Şükrü either.
Scorpio men get emotional.
[kiss voice]
No bro, it won't be like this.
What are we going to do?
What did you do guys?
[cries of surprise]
This soon makes our caravan.
Where did you find the horse, girl?
It's not a horse, it's a pony.
Anyway, that's not the point.
E, what did you do, did you find the money?
No, we couldn't find it.
We've got these things that won't cost money, plus a ton of popcorn.
If only we could turn it into money somehow.
Where does most popcorn go?
I found. At the cinema.
TO? It's like we have a cinema.
-There is. -Where?
Here it is.
Repent, my Lord.
Oh my poor nephew. The girl's brain got watery from the excess oxygen.
Here, with this magnifying glass, we enlarge the image from the phone and send it to the screen.
It wasn't that big of a deal. [Laughs]
You know the magnifying glass, magnifying…
Okay, I kept quiet.
-What movie are we going to show? -Of course, Hababam Class .
Well, that movie is very old. Who would come to watch it?
Some movies never get old, don't worry.
[from the movie playing Damat Ferit] Here is the first surprise of the night.
Cow Saban and Mother Hafize.
[the song "Firefly" plays in the movie]
Come on.
-[Salim] Here you go. -[Zeynep] Get another one?
[Salim] Here you go. I'll take five lira. Thank you so much.
♪ Are you my pearl flower that adorns my garden of love? ♪
He is my nephew, I want my good news.
How? Is money out? Is our guitar job done?
It was my nephew. Run and raise the news, come on.
Hey! I am coming now.
How rejoiced was the poor.
It was good though. Making children happy is a virtue.
[song continues in movie]
-[movie cuts] -[audience shouts]
What's going on?
Alas, everyone wants their money back. What are we going to do?
I will try to fix the movie. You stall the nation quickly.
God, quick.
Guys, the show must go on.
-What are you doing, bro? -[crickets]
Who are you?
I'm Cinar bro, you know the guitarist.
No, I didn't know.
Don't find work, dude. Guitar is ok.
I also set my toll. I'm there next week.
What's wrong with me, son? We have already found our guitarist.
[nasty laugh]
-But you promised. -[sad music]
Were you going to wait for me?
[Eser] Son, don't you understand yet?
I don't wait, I wait. [English] Goodbye. [nasty laugh]
[They play the song "Firefly"]
♪ Are you my pearl flower that adorns my garden of love ? ♪
♪ Lighting up my night ♪ ♪ Are you my firefly? ♪
♪ Youth is smoke in my head ♪ ♪ My first love, first excitement ♪
♪ Running away after chasing ♪ ♪ Are you my firefly? ♪
Son, don't be silly. How can we participate in the competition?
There is no money to take us all to Istanbul to compete.
We don't even have an instrument to play, let alone participate in the competition.
Ours is very old.
How do we participate? There is little time left for the competition.
Oh well, friends. You played very well yesterday.
If we believe and work, we will grow.
Teacher Rose also helps us.
Are you there?
[together] We're here.
Where am I going to my nephew?
Then let's get started right away.
Where do we start?
First thing we have to do is find a soloist.
I mean, you guys are good as a choir, but it can't be done without a soloist.
Where will we find the lead singer?
Don't worry, I have a great idea.
Let's see, welcome all of you to the music competition.
[clapping sounds]
No way. Looking for such a soloist?
And what are these seats?
Did you spend the money we earned from the cinema on these seats?
This is the thing, my nephew. Everyone finds it that way. That's how we'll find it.
Yes, Salim.
Ladies and gentlemen, here are our candidates for soloists.
♪ Tin tin tini mini lady ♪ ♪ Tin tin tin tin tini mini lady ♪
♪ loves you dear ♪
♪ Are you mad at me sweetie ♪ ♪ You haven't looked at me since ♪
♪ Let's make up if you're offended ♪ ♪ Smell like a dove... ♪
[gasps]
♪ Hazelnut branches are green again ♪
♪ Do you need love or do you need trouble ♪
♪ Tell me my love what do we need ♪
♪ Tin tin tini mini lady ♪ ♪ Tin tin tin tin tini mini lady ♪
♪ Do birds land on telegraph wires ♪
♪ I'm brunette, beautiful tuti tongue ♪ ♪ I'm on fire oh my God ♪
♪ I love you so much ♪
♪ Are there cranberries ♪ ♪ Are the bins full ♪
♪ Tin tin tini mini lady ♪ ♪ Tin tin tin tin tini mini lady ♪
♪ Amaney greened hazelnut branches ♪
♪ Hazelnut branches were always green anyway ♪
♪ Ma ma microphone show ♪
♪ Ma ma, mi mi ♪
♪ Mi mi microphone show ♪ ♪ Mikrofon show ♪
[English] Yes.
Hist Cinar, turn me around.
-Help me. -OK.
Hasan, thank you very much for participating in the competition.
You chose a difficult song, my dear. But I have a lot of similar voices.
That's why I couldn't come back, [English] baby.
I actually liked the tone in her voice. But my team is full unfortunately.
[Emrah] Got it?
And how do they sound? I have repented to music since morning.
Yes, Hasan, our jury did not choose you. What would you like to say?
First of all, can I have a round of applause for Tarık Sezer and his orchestra?
[confusion effect]
You can't.
Are you crazy bro, there is no such person there.
We listened to 30 people. Not any of them.
Especially not Hasan.
Distinguished members of the jury, before sending me off, I would like to say this.
I didn't study after primary school.
Son, we are in the same class.
None of us have ever studied beyond primary school anyway.
[Emrah] What are you living for?
Come on bro. Hasan, look, you are wasting our time.
Can you come out please? Hasan, get out.
Shit, he didn't eat.
-Good job. -Yes, we are sending Hasan as well.
Let's see who will come now.
We will not find it for sure, for sure.
What are we going to do?
♪ Before a spark falls ♪
♪ It grows slowly ♪
♪ You'll see, it's a volcano ♪
♪ You're on fire friend ♪
♪ Can't fill the void ♪
♪ Neither mother nor sister ♪
♪ This is the most beautiful, this is the hottest ♪
♪ It's a feeling friend ♪
♪ Being a partner is every joy ♪
♪ To all sorrows ♪
♪ And walking is a lifetime ♪
♪ Hand in hand together ♪
♪ No, he's so sincere ♪
♪ Tears in smiling eyes ♪
♪ Even if we come and leave one day ♪
♪ Friend with you ♪
How were we, teacher?
You were incredible.
Thanks to you, my teacher.
Sibel, how beautiful is your voice.
[stammering] Thank you teacher.
The main soloist was right next to us, but we didn't notice.
I will do whatever it takes to participate in this competition.
Teacher, I don't have a guitar. E, your friends also have very bad instruments.
[Çınar] Need to buy new ones.
Because from the wires of my curam, only kadayif can be made, my teacher.
Also, I am an expensive teacher in Istanbul. You don't know. A lot of money to stay there.
I mean the way, the food, the stay, the instruments.
We have a lot of expenses, teacher.
- So, fire without saying three or five, teacher. -[all laugh]
Don't worry guys. I will find that money for you.
How much do you need?
Teacher, I am making a rough calculation like this.
[calculator key sound]
-That's all I need. -[surprise melody]
Where will I find all that money?
I swear I'm good at sinking money. I don't have the find part.
Of.
I called National Education. I called all my acquaintances. No.
I wish I could get the kids but…
A minute.
Of course.
I would like.
I go, I say, I say like this, I ask parents.
Hey, live with your mind. [clears throat]
Why did you come?
You were going to talk to me about something.
I look at the village…
I looked at the village. He's changed a lot, oho. Changed.
I mean the moon, so I wonder if someone who knows could show me the village?
What a change, my dear. 35 households and 1 fountain. Same for 30 years.
I am not the same. I have changed a lot.
[Rose laughs]
Alright. [clears throat]
Parent meeting.
Lets go.
Yes, dear parents.
Now, of course, you don't know why we gathered you here.
Did our children do something wrong again, sir?
What are you doing here, Emrah?
-I'm a parent too, sir. -[parents laugh]
I'm having my two nephews study here.
OK, I'll handle it.
Brother, but no such thing.
Brother, I am also a parent. Uncle is half of father.
-Parent meeting is also my right. -I don't know if you realize
but your children have a great talent.
-He? -[Laugh] Yeah.
And they got together and formed a great band.
Now they want to participate in a competition together.
I say, what do we have and what do we not have
Let's give them all our money to enter this contest.
Say what?
Repent, repent.
[parents clear their throat, pretending not to hear]
But do something.
Uncle Omar.
Ha?
-Did he tell me? -He.
Sir, when our warehouse explodes
I couldn't work.
So you will understand
So we don't have much money.
Sir, what do we have, what should we give?
But if there's anything else we can do, we'll be happy to do it, of course.
I'll let you know if anything is needed then.
[rooster crows]
-Ugh! We could not find money for the children. -[The sound of water comes from the fountain]
Let's drink cold water now.
Gel.
I think the name of this fountain should be the lovers' fountain from now on.
Like in Rome. You know, in Rome.
So it is. [Laughs]
Come on, let's make a wish and throw money for the children. Ha?
Did you get your wish?
I throw.
Hop.
[children excitedly] Money!
My money.
Gold is gold!
For!
Horse it too, my nephew.
[coin sound]
Gül Teacher could not find support either.
What are we going to do?
How much money do we have left?
We cannot buy all instruments, not even a zurna, with this money.
We are at the place where the zurna calls zırt, so you can say.
Of ya of.
Do you have a nephew?
When my son sees you so sad
but a part of me is breaking away.
[idea melody]
-Does a part of you break off? -What.
Will you make a sacrifice for us, uncle?
What? Uncle?
My niece finally called me "uncle".
This moment is my happiest day. Tell me it's one of your uncle's.
What should I do for you? What kind of sacrifice do you want from me?
[kissing sound]
I kiss.
[drum clarion sound]
I said a part of me, inside of me.
My son, is there such a sacrifice just because we will earn money from jewelry?
You finished me, you finished me.
Little Emrah's neck is bent.
You are a lion. We will succeed because of you, my uncle.
No friend, I thought I put my hat in front of me.
I will not come to your uncle gas.
I'll take it.
Thank you, Çetinci.
Quarter gold.
I swear it's a quarter gold. Quarter gold. Hey!
I mean, what would it be like to buy a bracelet from those jewelry, huh?
In other words, we would invest in the future, gari.
No, mom. I started this way. We will participate in that competition with this money.
[kiss voice]
[plays zeybek with drums and zurna]
-[cup sound] -Welcome.
Thank you.
How's it going? Are ours satisfied?
I swear the children seem to have collected the money.
Good for the kids. Look how they got together and collected the money.
But what happened happened to our little Emrah.
[Laughs]
Rose.
-What? -Always smile.
Well…
Miss Rose. You laugh. laugh.
-[sound of slurping lemonade] -[chokes, coughs]
[zeybek ends]
[game mood plays]
Guys, we finally made it.
This money is enough.
[together] Oley.
OK.
Where is Sibel? Let me give him this good news.
Her mother is over there. If you want, go and ask him.
-OK. Thanks. -Let's.
-[excited voices] -Don't. Shake. Shake.
A, my baby. If only he could talk.
It could be resolved in seven sessions.
If I can take my daughter there, she will get rid of this disease.
How much money do they want?
A lot of money, a lot.
But his stuttering will go away for good. They said you can speak like me.
God help you.
I'm so bored. Take me for a little tour.
I am bored. Remove it.
[circumcision wedding entertainment music]
O people of Saklıca!
Since I was circumcised for this cause, let's celebrate gari.
Then let our song be played.
Let's play Emrah. Come on, everybody to play.
[plays folk song with baglama]
♪ Emrah went to the highlands too ♪
♪ He brought tulips, he brought tulips ♪ ♪ He brought hyacinths, too ♪
♪ He brought mushrooms from the mountains ♪ ♪ He brought sycamore ♪
Who is gone?
[all in unison] Emrah is gone.
What did he bring?
[all in unison] Cintar brought it.
♪ Cinar has gone to the highlands too ♪
♪ He brought tulips, he brought tulips ♪ ♪ He brought hyacinths, too ♪
♪ He brought mushrooms from the mountains ♪ ♪ He brought sycamore ♪
Who is gone?
[cakes] Sycamore is gone.
What did he bring?
Hyacinth.
-[song ends] -[emotional music begins]
[crickets chirping]
[music ends]
kids. Your Cinar friend will make a statement.
[applause, cheers]
[exhales]
Friends.
When I came here, I had no friends.
-[emotional music] -Until I get to know you
your friend is a sibling, a family
I didn't know it was a soulful soul.
You have added so much to my life in my most difficult times.
Let me tell you how much I love each and every one of you
I can talk all day.
-Tell me, the lesson will boil. -[laughs]
I learned sacrifice for friendship here.
I learned that you have to do everything for your friends with whom you set out on the same path.
I learned from you that I can love someone else as much as myself.
I know that we all contributed to the money we collected.
And what I'm going to do soon
I also know that you will wholeheartedly support me.
Because friendship requires it.
Sibel.
The money you need for your treatment.
[cry of affection from the whole class]
That you can talk freely, that you are happy,
It is more important to us than all competitions and championships.
[emotional music rises]
This money system will be destroyed.
Thanks for everything guys.
Thank you to your sea sister. He will take us to the bus station.
-[emotional music ends] -You're welcome, anytime.
Come on girl.
[stammering] Goodbye.
-See you. -Goodbye, Sibel.
-See you. -Goodbye.
-[car starts] -[door chime]
[emotional music begins]
[exhales]
Let's not be upset.
We will also attend next year.
This year was my last year. I'm not old enough to grow up next year.
-No chance this year? -[music ends]
Anyway, there's nothing to do.
Is it more important than Sibel?
Let's go. Let's.
[guitar plays, song begins]
[mother] ♪ The road appeared again to the land ♪
[cries of children playing ball]
♪ Fall has come, leaves have fallen ♪
♪ Seagulls migrated ♪
♪ Cranes floated ♪
♪ Again the road appeared to the foreign land ♪
♪ Even if it's black winter in my village ♪
♪ Even if the lovers bow their heads ♪
♪ If I say that you are coy ♪
♪ Even if it comes to mercy ♪
♪ Again the road appeared to the foreign land ♪
♪ Pain, sorrow always to me ♪
♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪
♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
♪ Pain, sorrow always to me ♪
♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪
♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
This earthwork will be solved today. As long as this village is not developed, there is no sleep for us.
Suitable agricultural land will be found today.
But girl, you don't like any place either.
Look, this is our oak tree. Didn't you like this place too?
-Let's see. -Let's see.
Let's see what? What are you looking for?
See deciğim.
Let's see how the soil is here.
[joyful music player]
[sound of surprise]
Black Diamond!
-Aha, the sun fell on our girl's head. -[Sevim laughs]
We went too far.
What apple girl?
No grandpa, that's really a diamond, a diamond.
Isn't this place close to Instagram Hill?
-Yes, we are right on the slope. -Huh.
-[shutter sound] -I took the picture.
Ask the engineer.
Let's.
[Zeynep] Huh! "The product you have sent a photo of is truffles."
[exhales]
I told you, this is the diamond.
Gather the entire village immediately. We have to search everywhere, quick.
You heard my grandson. Come on, search the whole village, come on.
-Let's. Come on girls. -Come on, you're looking for diamonds.
-[Sevim] Come on, run, gari. Let's. -[digging shovel sounds]
[end of music]
-[cup sound] -[tea drinking sound]
[crickets chirping]
Oh.
"You always bring it to the fountain." you were saying.
I said let's come here this time.
It's changed a lot around here. It's so beautiful.
Ay.
You will also see this place on summer nights.
It's pitch dark. Villagers hunt eels from the lake.
Then all the people barbecue and set tables here. Moon.
It gets lively in here.
[romantic music]
[romantic music ends]
Oh, are you going to get me into the mud again? Come on, open my eyes now.
We can't. You've been pouting for a week.
-Let's see if that will cheer you up. -Hungry.
Oh, guitar. And from the best. [kiss voice]
Where did you find this?
The whole village has collected money for you. They couldn't stand to see you sad, nephew.
Thank you so much. Thank you.
Good bye, my nephew.
Guys, we found the money.
-What? -Did he say I found the money?
How did you find the money?
There are truffles in many parts of the village.
We also consulted with the agriculturalists. It popped up almost everywhere.
Yes there is. Interest. It comes out whenever we dig the soil.
-What's wrong with that? -Truffle, that's smart.
It costs thousands of pounds.
We removed the middlemen and met directly with the seller.
We even sold the first batch. They got it right away.
The money is also in our account. Well…
[in unison] So…
We can now enter the contest.
[cries of joy]
A minute!
Well, the contest is tomorrow. How do we join now?
The application deadline has already passed.
It's not over until I say it's over.
After all, we also have a weight in this community.
Please or please? What if the rose of the sisters, one of the sisters.
Please, my sister, you can do it.
Sister, it is very important for us to participate in this competition.
What will you do, my sister? Take us to your competition. what would you be!
You really have a lot of weight in the community.
Look, as I just said,
The deadline for our competition has already passed.
[woman] There's nothing we can do, unfortunately.
Look, my nephew's happiness is at stake here.
Do you know what I gave for this competition?
I am circumcised. They took meat from my flesh.
Please don't hurt so many children. [gasps]
Do not break!
-Don't break it. -I beg.
Guys, don't talk like that, please.
Moon, what's going on there?
Music group from a village called Saklıca.
They collected the money at the last minute to come here.
They want to apply. -A band from the village?
Give me these.
Guys, just a second. I am giving the presenter of our competition, Doğa Rutkay.
Nature gives Rutkay.
-Doga Rutkay. -Okay, shut up.
Hello.
Hello, hello sister Nature.
We love you so much. We're watching as a family.
Help us sister.
Look, we worked hard. We believed a lot.
It is for us to participate in this competition
very important. Take us to your competition, take us.
Do you really want to participate in this competition?
More than anything.
OK then. I approve your application.
[Doğa Rutkay] You can participate in the competition.
Confirmed. We agree.
[cries of joy]
[Laughs]
I swear, don't look like that. How happy do you hear?
I approved it.
Ok, the application part is done, but all the planes are full.
Buses leave tomorrow evening. How will we go?
Does anyone in the village have a car?
There aren't enough cars to take all the kids.
Don't do it, teacher, isn't there another way?
Where.
there is.
There is a way to take you all to Istanbul.
Come with me. Let's.
[voice coming out of rows]
My teacher.
Slow.
[joyful music player]
Give me 13-14, girl.
-Give. -Get. Quick.
[excited voices]
[helping villagers voices]
huh. Give me a cloth. It's leaking water. Let me see.
Take it grandpa, please do it quickly. What happens?
OK girl. Don't choke, man.
[Omar] We're trying.
Oh, let's see.
[Omar] Tired man.
-I hope it will work. -Hopefully.
[continued music]
-[session head] -Huh.
Finished.
Now we have to start a march.
[excited shouts]
-[music goes up] -[cranking sound]
Low.
It's not working. oh!
[female parent] Come on baby.
[session motor]
[cries of joy]
Worked.
[continued music]
[music ends]
-[Villagers seeing off the children] -[Sevim] They're leaving. Good by!
-[Mehmet] Cinar. -[Sevim] Come on.
My God, don't let your chords fade, my Lord!
Lord, less than three octaves in the chorus
of our sabers, the Lord Rabbul of the world.
[Sevim] Amen.
They're going to the moon. Let's. I hope your path is clear, my Lord.
Hush, by the way, these are Trabzon huh. either.
Let's.
[joyful shouts]
I still can't believe we went to Istanbul to compete.
I still can't believe this bus is gone.
-Oh dad, we'll catch up, right? -I hope we will catch up, son, we will catch up.
Guys, first we will pick up Sibel from her hotel.
-[applause, cheers] -Oh.
Group Hidden!
And we have also ordered your instruments.
We will take them from a place very close to the competition.
[together] Oley.
Teacher Rose!
-Mehmet brother! -Father!
[adventure music]
[whistles are added to ongoing music]
[door opening sound]
[children's cries of joy]
[joyful music]
[end of music]
-[audience applause] -This year's 36th edition
Welcome to the Future Musicians competition.
[audience applause]
If you wish, let's say hello to our valuable jury before we move on to our competition.
Hello dear Iskender Stakeholder.
[audience applause]
And dear Yonca Evcimik.
And dear Burak Kut.
[audience applause]
And without getting the kids excited anymore
what shall we say? Shall we begin?
Here we go, sir.
[audience applause]
[teacher cries]
-We're enough, right? -We grow up.
I called and talked to the contest. They threw us at the end.
Hah.
Let's hope.
You missed the sights of Istanbul.
No, I swear my eyes never called.
My view is so beautiful.
[emotional music begins]
[stammering] Thank you so much for everything.
I am so happy.
[stuttering less] I stutter less already.
[surprised] A, how well you speak.
If you're happy, I'm happier.
We are officially in Istanbul. There's nothing like hometown.
-[breathes deeply] -[end of music]
Oh Istanbul, my dear Gebze.
Salim, my brother.
I held myself so that I wouldn't be sad, but...
…Gebze is not in Istanbul.
How? How is it not?
Gebze is connected to Kocaeli.
[pathetic hook player]
My son, it is painful to steal.
I've been living a lie for years.
[laughs]
♪ Never mind my crazy heart ♪
♪ Let it go ♪ ♪ You sing songs ♪
♪ Ay ay ♪
[audience applause]
You were great girls, congratulations to you.
Let's see how many points our jury will give you.
Dear Yonca Evcimik.
First of all, congratulations girls. I'm in love with the girl group.
But as I found it a bit dull, for him…
[audience applause]
Very nice. Dear Alexander Stakeholder.
Eight from me.
-[audience applause] -Great.
And dear Burak Kut.
Congratulations, you said it very well. I love it. It's a song I love.
[audience applause]
Wonderful. This sweet group gets 24 points in total.
A big round of applause to all of them. -[audience applause]
Come on grandpa, let's hit the gas. Raise us, grandpa. Come on.
Ok guys, calm down.
We will win for sure. Come on guys, we'll do it.
Of course, son. We're going to blow smoke.
[session motor]
Here we go, we made the smoke go away. The engine has boiled water.
What's going on?
Did the water boil? What are we going to do?
What are we gonna do? We're going to fix it.
Ugh. We can't catch up in life, we are very close to leaving.
Should I call the contest and talk to them again?
No.
-I have a much better idea. -What?
Run son, run!
Let's run. Run.
♪ I haven't seen anyone ♪ ♪ Prettier than you ♪
♪ I didn't know anyone ♪ ♪ More special than you ♪
♪ I didn't even look at anyone ♪ ♪ What's on my mind ♪
♪ I didn't know anyone ♪ ♪ Prettier than you ♪
[running sounds]
♪ Prettier than you ♪
♪ Where did I meet you? ♪ ♪ I've been blown away ♪
♪ I saved myself for you ♪ ♪ Prettier than you ♪
♪ I don't care about anyone ♪ ♪ I won't change if I die ♪
♪ I didn't know anyone ♪ ♪ Prettier than you ♪
-Kids run! -[running sounds]
♪ Prettier than you ♪
[audience applause]
Bravo. It was really great.
Let's see how our jury will give points for Grup Eser.
Alexander Stakeholder.
Top performance from me.
[audience applause]
-Burak Kut. -Congratulations. You were very good.
Nine points.
[audience applause]
And Clover Evcimik.
I give nine points to this handsome friend and Grup Eser.
[audience applause]
28 points in total.
[clapping, cheering]
That's it! I think the leader is clear.
So we have one last group.
Let's see who will get our award after that group.
Come on now, let's take your place.
And next is Grup Saklıca.
[panic, rushing cries]
-Run, run! -Slow.
run.
Group Hidden.
[panic, rushing cries]
Unfortunately, they can't be with us right now.
Unfortunately, they couldn't catch up.
In this case, there is no need for further ado.
The winner of the competition…
[voices from behind] Here we are.
We came. stop. We came.
We came. Attention, we're here.
We came.
Run.
-We came. Quick. -Run.
We came. Run, we're here.
-Are you here now? -[all] We're here.
[Doğa Rutkay] So you made it.
[all] We've grown.
Wonderful. Then the stage is yours. Here you go.
You huh! What if you're ready?
[nasty laugh]
My dear, you play.
I'm waiting for you with my first trophy.
I'll take it. Yup.
Come on guys, we can do it. We can do this.
[all] We do it.
Come on everybody in their places, we'll do it.
-We will do. -We will do.
Well, can we get a chair over here?
[clears throat and volume checks]
-[dropping sound] -[laughs]
[stuttering] Voice. One two.
[nasty laugh]
Let's start.
[drumstick four beats]
[The song "The Road Has Been Appeared Again To the Exile" plays]
♪ Again the road appeared to the foreign land ♪
♪ Fall has come, leaves have fallen ♪
♪ Seagulls migrated ♪ ♪ Cranes floated ♪
♪ Again the road appeared to the foreign land ♪
♪ Even if it's black winter in my village ♪
♪ Even if the lovers bow their heads ♪
♪ I would say that even if the coy lover comes to mercy ♪
♪ Again the road appeared to the foreign land ♪
[chorus] ♪ Pain, sorrow, always to me ♪
♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪
♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
♪ Pain, sorrow, always to me ♪
♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪
♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
[solo] ♪ Who should I tell my troubles to? ♪
♪ I am the strange Barış, what should I do? ♪
♪ Away from mother, father, home ♪
♪ Again the road appeared to the foreign land ♪
[chorus] ♪ Pain, sorrow, always to me ♪
♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪
♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
♪ Pain, sorrow, always to me ♪
♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪
♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
♪ Pain, sorrow, always to me ♪
♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪
♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
[link solo]
[gitar only]
♪ Pain, sorrow, always to me ♪
♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪
♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
♪ Pain, sorrow, always to me ♪
♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪
♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
-[song ends] -[clapping, cheering]
A truly magnificent performance.
Let's see if our jury agrees with me.
Alexander Stakeholder.
I think you are a very original group. Nine from me.
Oley be!
Hey, thumbs up.
They gave nine.
Clover Evcimik.
I love it. You are my first. So ten.
-[applause, group rejoices, cheer] -Ten points! Ten points!
and Burak Kut.
You've all been amazing. I congratulate you.
How many points?
[intriguing music]
-On. -Oley be!
-[clapping, cheering] -That's it! That's it!
[cries of joy]
[in an enthusiastic voice] And 29 points in total!
-[audience applause] -Great.
And the 36th
The winner of the Future Musicians competition…
…Group Hidden.
Oley be.
-[victory music] -[claps of joy, applause]
[cheers]
Uncle Omer, we won.
Did we win? Really?
-We won. -Well done guys.
Mehmet won. We won.
[cries of joy]
E, say something? What happened.
They caught my partner. I'm taking everything back now.
We can return to Istanbul.
I'm so glad.
Oh, and ask me.
[Doga Rutkay] You…
Once again, I congratulate you very much.
And so be it, your reward.
Thanks.
All my loved ones are with me when I receive this award.
My father…
[kiss voice]
…my grandfather,
my teacher,
my brother,
my friends
my uncle…
…My mother.
Mom, this song you gave me
it's our song now.
Our village song.
Thank you friends.
Of.
[clapping, cheering]
He is my nephew.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, fellow countryman.
Goodbye, my villager.
[they kiss]
[sniffs]
-Take care of yourself. -You too.
my brother.
-My brother. -[breakup music]
Zeynep, my dear.
-My nephew. -My uncle.
Take this and keep it.
I know you entered this contest for your mother.
But remember, we're your family too, nephew.
You are the best uncle in the world.
Son, you're going to make me cry.
My uncle.
[sighs]
Let's go.
Don't worry, grandpa. I'll call you and tell you everything about agriculture.
Do I feel sorry for her, girl?
How nice I found you. I'm losing again.
I'm crying for him.
Don't worry dad. We will come again.
Just don't come. I'll break those legs.
[hand kissing sound]
-My grandson. -My grandfather.
[they kiss]
My daughter.
[hand kissing sound]
[they kiss]
Come to me.
My teacher.
[kisses]
See you, teacher.
-[sigh] -[music ends]
We've come to the end.
Isn't it the last?
I do not know. Our place is clear. Easy.
We are always there if you come.
Maybe you will come here.
I do not think so. When we go, not many come to our place.
There are also a lot of projects. He will make more art centre.
I have a lot of work.
Take care of yourself.
[emotional music begins]
[door slamming sound]
[bus starter and engine sound]
[bus driving away]
I will say something.
Why are we staying?
My daughter, your school is here. My life is here.
Dad, don't eat us. You are in love with Gül Teacher. Admit it.
How are you talking to your father? Rose Teacher, me and so on.
Is it okay dear?
Is there such a thing? I'm seriously asking.
Of course, why not?
For the first time since my mother, we and you both smile thanks to these people.
Why should we live apart from them?
We want our father to be happy.
Let's decide, they're leaving. What are we gonna do?
We will run, children, we will run.
Then run.
-[adventure music plays] -Wait for us!
[Zeynep] Wait!
[Mehmet] Stop.
-[Zeynep] Wait. -[Cinar] Children.
[joying sounds]
♪ Again the road appeared to the foreign land ♪
♪ Fall has come, leaves have fallen ♪
♪ Seagulls migrated ♪ ♪ Cranes floated ♪
♪ Again the road appeared to the foreign land ♪
♪ Even if it's black winter in my village ♪
♪ Even if the lovers bow their heads ♪
♪ I would say that even if the coy lover comes to mercy ♪
♪ Again the road appeared to the foreign land ♪
♪ Pain, sorrow, always to me ♪ ♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪
♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
♪ Who should I tell my troubles to? ♪
♪ I am the strange Barış, what should I do? ♪
♪ Away from mother, father, home ♪
♪ Again the road appeared to the foreign land ♪
♪ Pain, sorrow, always to me ♪
♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪
♪ If it were mine, the whole world wouldn't be enough ♪
♪ Pain, sorrow, always to me ♪ ♪ Brother, sister, mother, father ♪