For the fifth time we present
to you the Human Era Calendar for the year 12,021 -
this time it is  all about the journey of humanity, beginning tens of thousands of years ago,
leading into the revolution of agriculture, to ancient high civilizations and the beginning of modern times,
culminating in a vision for our future.
You can get the limited Edition now until we
sell out and then never again.
As always the calendar features 12 illustrated pages printed on high quality paper in Europe and the US.
And this year the cover is especially shiny.
Not only does the calendar look great on walls and makes it easier to dream about a glorious future
and realize how far we have come as a species.
It is also the best way to support kurzgesagt.
The calendar enables us to put in the time our videos need and release them for free, for everyone.
If you want, you can get the calendar with a Hoodie or infographic posters or plushie. We've made a few deals for you.
Thank you so much to the thousands of
people who get the calendar every year
and to the birbs who love what
we try to do on this channel.
We wish you a happy year 12,021 – And let’s all hope that it will be less exciting than 12,020!