- Sit down, daughter. - Nothing, nothing, thank you, sit down.
- Citizen, give way, stand up! - If I stand up, you'll lie down.
Citizen, these seats are for children and disabled people.
- What is she, children or handicapped? - She's getting ready to be a mother.
- And I'm getting ready to be a father! - What are you talking nonsense!
- That's exactly what a handicapped person is. - Ah, an invalid. - What do you say now?
- The law is the law! - Please sit down.
You sighted one! Now you'll be blind.
- Do you confirm it? - Affirmative! Affirmative.
So... So the victim...
- You work in construction? - Part-time.
- What do you mean "moonlighting"? - I'm a polytechnic student.
A student!
Fifteen days!
Well, citizens alcoholics, hooligans, slackers,
who wants to work today?
Today's assignments are: Sand pit - 2 people.
Sandy Quarry, two men.
- Give me the whole list, please. - Sandpiper Quarry, two men.
Street cleaning, 3 men.
Meatpacking...
has not sent outfits as of today.
There's an order for an apartment building, a cement factory...
No orders for the liquor store?
Please.
Careful.
First of all, I want you to meet our wonderful team,
which you are temporarily joining.
- How much is a comrade joining? - Full, 15! - Aha! A decade and a half.
Don't be late for lunch!
I'm sure you and I will spend this decade and a half in an atmosphere of friendship and
- of mutual understanding. - Yeah.
Cork. A gift from Africa. Yes! Right this way.
Imagine with the power of your imagination the housing estate that will be created here.
There will be 7,40 gas stoves installed in this one alone,
which is 7,40 times more than there were in the whole city before 1913. Please!
Romance. And if you take all the work done by our SMU floor-by-floor.
during the first quarter and put those floors one on top of the other, you get a building
will be twice as tall as the world-famous Eiffel Tower,
or three times as tall as the famous Notre Dame de Paris.
Which means Notre Dame de Paris. What, what mother?
Paris. Notre Dame.
Please.
Our SMU has built as much living space as one city like Chita, 10 like Khvalynsk, or 32 like Kryzhopol.
city like Chita, 10 like Khvalynsk, or 32 Kryzhopol.
It's breathtaking to think that...
than in America. That way, you, too, can do your part.
to the work accomplishments of our construction and installation department.
- What what department? - The erection department. - I'm ready!
Shurik!
- Yes, Pal Stepanych? - Well, Sanya, here's your partner.
Finally, Pal Stepanych, thank you!
- Well, now we'll work. - Let's work together.
Well, I can see that you will work together. Stand up, Shurik.
I wish you success in your work and great happiness in your personal life.
Thank you for your attention.
Listen, have you had any accidents at the construction site?
- No, there haven't been any yet. - There will be... let's go...
Lord have mercy!
- What's in there? - Shh!
Listen, where have you been? I've been looking all over the building for you. There's work to be done.
The work is standing, and the deadline is running. Don't forget, you're counting in rubles, and I'm counting in days.
- So, Shurik, how's your partner? - Re-educated. - He's doing great.
Why are you whispering? Asleep. Asleep?!
While our spaceships are sailing across the universe...
and it's not without reason that all the continents applaud the workers of our great ballet...
Folk wisdom teaches us that patience and hard work will make everything better - one!
Finish the job - walk bravely - two!
Work is not the wolf - into the woods ... No, don't do that...
To the light bulb!
- And the compote? - The compote!
- Hands... - Huh? Washed? - А... Yes, yes, yes.
So... To the sand pit!
- Here we go... - Bon appétit.
What's that?
I say: He who does not work - he eats. Study, student!
Understand, student, nowadays you have to be gentler to people, and look at the issues more broadly...
Do you think I got 15 days?
We're the ones who got 15 days. What for?
So that you could educate me... And I grow on myself.
Go on, tell me how spaceships sail... Big theater...
I'll take a nap.
That's right... And keep the flies away.
- You what?! - Fly. - Well done!
Oh, you're in trouble, four-eyes, aren't you?
It's just an advance. That's it! Well, student, get ready.
Soon you'll be wearing a wooden raincoat and your house will be playing
music... But you won't hear it.
Water!
Thank you.
Stop, I'll kill... Student!
That's hooliganism! You'll get 15 days in jail!
I'm going to complain!
Are you going to hit me? No. Why?
To educate you.
- Shurik... Are you a Komsomol member? - Yes. That's not our method.
Where's the humanism? Where is man to man? Understand, Shurik, at a time when
spaceships, as you know, are sailing... - What's your name?
- Fedya... And you, Shurik... - Married? - Yes, my wife Lyubushka
and two kids, Lena and Alyosha. So there's a family. Yes, we do.
- How old are you? - 41.
Maybe you shouldn't, Shurik?
- I won't do it anymore. - No, you have to, Fedya... You have to!
Mama.
Mom.
Well, citizens, alcoholics, slackers, hooligans.
Who wants to work? Я! Wait.
For today's outfit: Sand pit - 2 people. - Я! - Wait a minute!
Give me the whole list, please.
So, the cement factory... Я!
- Loading coal... - Я! Cleaning the stables... Я!
Also... Я! Wait a minute, citizen.
You're on personal duty for the full 15 days. Take it!
- Did you pass? - Deal! - How much? Well? - Five.
- Give me the synopsis... Burning. - No, I gave it to the guys, they're reading it.
You can turn it upside down.
Ticket number 7, first question...
The principle of the synchrophasotron. Kostya, how do you hear? How do you hear?
Can you hear me? Over.
I got it, I got it. I hear you all right,
I'll answer the first question of the seventh ticket. The synchrophasotron is based on the principle
is based on the acceleration of charged particles by a magnetic field.
A field. Let's move on.
- Dub! Do you have a synopsis? - There's no synopsis, don't interfere.
- What are you listening to? - Van Cliburn. Go!
- Great! - That's great! - Do you have one? - What?
Oh, I already asked you!
- Careful, citizen. - Don't get distracted. - Excuse me, please.
- Next Garden! - Ours, let's go!
Take it.
Who?
Hello, Aunt Zoya. Can I have the key, please?
- You have an exam today. - You've got three more hours.
I'll study with my girlfriend.
- Mustards! - Uh-huh!
It's stuffy! Don't flip it.
Ira, unbutton it.
It's hot! Take off your clothes.
It's time.
- Did you pass? - 4!
You what? Calm down. I see.
Get your ticket!
- Professor, can I have some more? - Please.
- More! - Take it!
- For yourself! - What do you mean, yourself?
- Oh, I'm sorry, Professor. - No, I'm sorry.
- You'll come next time. - Too much.
A beauty's heart is prone to cheating and change... One, two, three, I'll give you a sample.
Kostya, do you read me? Three, two, one, over!
- Hello, professor. - How do you do?
- What's wrong with you? - My ear hurts.
- Will it bother you? - No, Professor, don't worry.
On the contrary, it helps. No noise distracts you from your exam.
What's that about? Do you have a holiday today?
The exam... for me... always a holiday for me, Professor.
That's commendable.
Please... ticket!
Ticket number 9. Over!
- What-what did you say? - What? What reception?
I said not reception, but with him. Ticket No. 9, and in front of him - the task.
- I see. Go get ready. - All right.
Oak, can you hear me? How can you hear me? You didn't get it, did you?
I'm dictating the answer to question 1 on ticket 9. So...
- What's the matter with you? - It shoots in my ear!
Here's the deal. I got an A for invention and an F for the course.
The professor, of course, is a lump, but he has the equipment.
Can you hear me? Can you hear me?
- You're welcome. - Thank you very much!
Did you pass?
- Who's that? - Where? There... floating.
Oh, it's Lydka from the parallel stream!
Lida... Amazing girl...
- Why haven't I ever seen her before? - Would you like to meet her?
- No... no! - Oh, come on! Lida!
Can I talk to you for a minute?
- Did you pass? - I did! - How many? - 5! - Congratulations! - Thank you!
- Meet your friends. - Lida! - Petya! Eh, Sasha!
Lida!
Please.
I'm off.
- Well, I'm home now. - This is where you live?
Nice neighborhood you got here. Never been here before.
I don't know. It must be the new tenants. How do I get in?
Very simple. It's a distraction. I'll take care of the dog,
- and you make a quick run for it. - All right.
Jack... Jack! Dumka... Smokey... Polkan!
Polkan! Almochka... Almochka... Almochka...
Come on!
- Do you happen to have any sausage with you? - Yes, doctor's sausage.
- There was a doctorate... Now it's an amateur... - What's that? - Sleeping pills.
- It's not... - No, it's perfectly harmless.
No, Bobiku... Bob!
Here we go, in three minutes we'll have a deep, healthy sleep. There you go!
Ah, that's it! Well, we'll see who's who. I'll be right back.
- What about you back? - The next step is this: On my signal.
You open the front door, but remember, only on my signal. Here you go.
Places, everybody. Okay.
Open up!
- Only you already have to walk. - Don't get used to it, the elevator often breaks down.
- I'm very glad to meet you. - Me too, goodbye.
- Sasha! What have you got there? - Where? Here!
- A dog! - Let's go upstairs, I'll sew it up. - No, it's the first time in the house and like this...
- No, let's go. - No way, no.
And I have a throat. - Your throat? And your head? No brains! No brains...
- Hello! - Well, did you pass? - 5! - Well done!
- And the girlfriend? - I don't know... Let's go! - Goodbye!
Turn around, I'll sew it up.
- No, let me do it. - Please.
Well, I won't bother you...
- Lida! It's okay! - I'll be right back!
Lida, do you know what my favorite poem by Yaroslav Smelyakov is?
- What is it? - Listen to this.
Along the little white houses Acacia trees are in full bloom.
Good girl Lida On South Street lives.
Reflected in the window pane She walks slowly through the world...
and then you forget the rest?
In the window pane Reflecting in the world walks slowly...
- Good girl Lida... - What's she good for?
Ask the boy who lives across the street,
He goes to bed with that name and rises with that name.
Not without reason on the stone slabs Where the sweet shoe has gone.
"Good girl Lida" He wrote in despair.
People can't help but be touched by the boy's stubborn fervor.
That's how Pushkin must have fallen in love... That's...
What's wrong with you? - No, nothing. Where was I? - Pushkin.
Yeah... Yeah... Pushkin... there's a miracle, there's a wizard... A mermaid...
- Wait, what mermaid, Sasha? - Hanging on the branches... Lying...
I think you've overtrained.
No, I'm not overtraining. That's not what I have.
Lida, I want to ask you a serious question.
- It's very important to me. - Go ahead.
Don't you ever come to a place for the first time, and it seems to you
You think you've been here before, and everything is familiar to you: Objects, smells, sounds.
Doesn't that happen to you? - No, it doesn't. I always remember where I was, when and with whom.
I have a feeling I've been here before.
And now I feel like I've been here before. - Come on, Sasha!
Yes, yes, I've seen everything here before.
Now I'm going to pull back this curtain,
and there's a crystal jug behind it!
There was!
- Sasha! So you're a telepath! Wolf Messing! - You think so?
- That's right! Let's try... - Let's do it.
You walk out the door... I write my wish on a piece of paper...
And when you come back, I'll mentally order you to grant my wish...
- Shall we? - Let's do it.
Come in!
- Did you get it? - Almost.
Then I'll try again?
It's time.
See you tomorrow. - No, the day after tomorrow. The day after tomorrow is an exam. - So do I.
- I'll study tomorrow... - So am I.
- So the day after tomorrow, after the exam? - Yes, the day after tomorrow...
Citizens of the new settlers! Get the culture going: Hang mats on the drywall.
No modernism, no abstractionism,
Keeps the walls from damp, you from rheumatism.
Get in, get in a hurry, buy the painting.
I recommend, the classic subject "Mermaid", based on the opera of the same name,
- music by Dargomyzhsky, words by Pushkin. - The humbug!
There is a quite neutral plot, even recommended for use
in children's institutions. Please. Oh, not that, sorry, here... please.
Wrap it up.
Wrap it up. There's a case.
- Where the hell is the invalid? - Don't make any noise, I'm an invalid.
- This is what we have today. - Not us, but you.
- What can save us from revision: - Excuse me, not us, but you!
The only thing that can save us from an audit is theft!
- With or without burglary? - Well, burglary, of course.
Article 89, paragraph 2, up to six years. No deal.
There won't be any theft.
- Everything's already been stolen before us... - Everything's been stolen before us...
It's nothing. All you have to do is fake a theft.
You have to pick the lock, break into the warehouse, leave traces of the theft
and walk away without taking anything. Have you got it all figured out?
Don't worry, Comrade Director. People want to find out what's what.
- It's natural! - Legally!
- This case is new for us, not mastered. - Exactly, untapped.
Tell me, is this event...
Or should I say... operation... Ы!
Operation Y!
Why "U"?
- Why "Y"? - So no one would guess.
Idiot!
Well, get to the point. First of all, you need to neutralize the watchman...
- Not us, but you. - This time it's you! - Yes? Yes!
What do you mean, neutralize?
- Article 193, paragraph 2. Up to three years. No, he won't. - No, he won't.
No...
The watchman is gently sedated with chloroform and tied up.
Legally, the whole operation is just disorderly conduct.
Yes, and keep in mind that for this petty hooliganism I pay a lot of money.
There will be an advance!
Is the watchman strong?
On the night of the operation there will be a guard on duty, a grandmother - God's dandelion.
- Is she armed? - Blanks! Any other questions?
- How much? - Three hundred!
- You can't be serious! - No, it's not. - You don't know us and we don't know you.
Look for fools. - I'll make more money on mermaids. - Come on, let's go.
- It's a laughing matter. - It's only 300! - Wait!
What are your terms?
- 330! - Agreed. - Everyone! - I agree!
Godspeed!
Stop, stop, stop. What are you guys doing? We've been rehearsing for an hour.
I let them mutilate my own barn for this, and it's no use.
Here you are, as a passerby, to approach the old woman
and get her attention with a simple question. And what did you ask?
- How to get to the library? - At 3 o'clock in the morning! Idiot!
- And you? What were you supposed to do? - Stand guard...
and appear before the police in the form of a vigilante, if the old woman whistled.
- Did the old lady whistle? - No. Then why did you come?
- Dummy. - I agree.
And you?
You idiot, you're not supposed to steal those bottles, you're supposed to break them.
- Break them? - Break them. - Half a pint? - Half a pint.
- In pieces? - Of course, smash it.
- I'll get you for that... - But! But! But!
Let's all take our places and go through it one more time.
Lullaby, lullaby, lullaby my granddaughter.
The birds are asleep and the fish are asleep...
- Marya Ivanovna! - Shh! What are you doing? Wake Lena up.
Lullaby, what happened to you?
I brought you the money for the apartment in January.
Thank you, that's good. Put it on the dresser.
- It's good that you came. - What's the matter?
All of a sudden the director makes me be on duty today.
- Don't worry, I'll sit with Lenochka. - Thank you.
- And, as if by golly, I put the dough in. - I'll sit with Lenka,
and I'll watch the dough, and go on duty... - Well, I'll be off then.
Wait, locomotive, don't knock, wheels. Conductor, hit the brakes.
I send my last regards to my mother.
I'm in a hurry to show my face.
- Will you tell me what time it is? - What's the matter with you? Have you lost your mind?
- Hard to study, easy to work. - Practice on him. All right.
Don't expect me, mother, a good son.
Your son is not like he was yesterday.
I am sucked into a dangerous quagmire.
And my life is an eternal game.
- Can you tell me how many degrees below zero it is today? - What's that?
- You what? - I'm practicing.
You should be practicing...
- on cats. - You're welcome.
Wait, locomotive, don't knock the wheels. There's time to look our fate in the eye.
Before it's too late to stop.
Conductor, hit the brakes.
No more walking.
Well, it's time! Let's get to work!
I can't help it. This is some kind of nightmare.
Marya Ivanovna, I'm begging you, go home!
- Yes, go, I'll take care of you. - All right, I'll be quick.
Don't worry, Marya Ivanovna, everything will be all right.
- If you need anything, just give me a holler. - Yes. - Well, let's go.
- Grandma! Got a smoke? - What?
- Where's Grandma? - I'm for her. - You are? - I am.
What's wrong with you?
Who's there?
- Who are you? - Guardian. - Where's Granny? - I'm for her.
- Where's the exit? - Over there... Hands up!
- Who whistled? - Я.
- Where's Granny? - And who are you? - I'm the vigilante! And you? - A watchman.
- Let's tie this one up. - This one?
А... friend...
Damned embezzler of socialist property. You bastard!
Run, call the police, and I'll keep watch.
- If anything happens, blow the whistle. - All right.
- Where's the phone? - There's a pay phone on the corner two blocks away.
- Get up, get up. - Where am I?
Come on, hurry up to the car, get up.
- Did they call you already? - Not yet, do you have 2 kopecks?
Militia 02, no coin.
Get up... Wake up!
- Can you tell me where the bathroom is? - I found the time! - Thank you.
Hurry up, the police are coming!
Hands up!