i have chosen batumi instead of tbilisi because i thought it would be
cheaper to orient an partner and bottom
in es sense its east's very easy to go to batumi from turkey
of stolen well no like you still
need to to use the plane and it's not
that different because you still flag
fire from istanbul and turkey's huge in size
steel so ye and
so i spent one month in turkey then two months in
georgia and the reason why i decided to relocate to
armenia is just because georgia doesn't give residents permits
to russians because like their policies
that well you can stay here for the whole year and then you do a visa ran and so
you don't need a residence permit so and
i really really need that because i eventually want to go to europe
that's my that's my dream and
and then so it was
tough choice because i could have stayed in georgia
and yeah like work and work from there
and make a lot of like mine for
georgia by georgian standards like really really a lot
but i decided that no i better go to armenia and
in the future i move to europe so like europe
is it is better even even despite that
it involves relocation and it involves
losses in in terms of reality of income because everything
in europe is more expensive than compared to georgia and armenia
but still like europe is un but anyway salaries are also
based on my research poland for example is not that expensive
like warso
the capital of poland is comparable to prewar moscow
as makes sense yet i
think here
it isn't rare they are expensive thinker
publicly i know is quite inexpensive my friend
she moved to berno about three years ago
yes and she
chose pernod because it's cheaper than prague
well armed
as far as late know
chich republic is well maybe it's more expensive than
poland not that expensive but
anyway countries like germany and then the lands to not ye not like
netherlands netherlands is just crazy and i actually have a friend from
the netherlands and i speak dutch but
the antulevel great yeah
and i'm so so sad that now it's basically useless
like i told you already that i
am basically a language north and
is so my actually i really love foreign languages like human languages
more than programming once that's why i have not a developer
and i have never been a developer ah yes so you are
a p m but can
you actually cold stuff i think no
i studied applied informatics at the
university here in ranee and actually we can be
we had subjects like basics of programming
i can know a little as the theoretical de
and only to see so sharp
elsie says little bit jeoscript that
works with not the back and la camascript that were grown each stimulant
the assassin little beats not pine but h p
but it's very very low
and actually and
we also had the departments
of software engineering and a lot of people
who gradiated who studied software engineering for career and
equalan worked in a baneful office out of software engineers
and they they can really they can really cold but i
can't and actually actually coding actually programming has
always been a challenge for me even when i got
prepared even when i prepared for the unified state exam
and i didn't i i
didn't do the task the
these are very but in the unified states set there is a
task i think in my time in my types it was the last one
as the most difficult related to rate some code but
i never never did it but anyway i know some basic
point anyway i decided that i've never been i will never be a programmer
that's quite hard for me and actually a void in cometic it's
it's like system analysis business analysis
may distant from they be a project manager that's a ca ye i bussian
actually
i went to event to all this it shield
because i didn't know what to do or to study how
to school and actually i
just prepared a lot for the universitat examined
during the tenth and the eleventh once i
was to take you i got a good results like
seventy nine points for me that was
really good and that it and the answer first
years at the university i didn't really understand what what
we what we started there
what we would become after graduation
and also i studied there arnstead to the translation
course is like an additional program and
i received two
on diplomas well
i have so i more i'm a bachelor in flat informatics and
and i'm also a translator and when i took
the final exam irina ideational yoga
head of
that aches she was in the
oh she was at that examined she invited me
that's how i started my career in it it started
two weeks before the global locked down
work in twenty twenty
right one second one second i need to do
in
i
so i decided to
stop the recording and reload it so to make sure that
defile is saved and now it sericorian the new
file because maybe maybe there
will be issues with obus later
so just to just be safe at least
south no tools everything in case ye so