i have chosen batumi instead of tbilisi because i thought it would be cheaper to rent an apartment and batumi sense easier it's very easy to go to batumi from turkey well no you still need
to to use the plane and it's not that much different it's not that different because you still fly from eastanbul and turkey is huge in size steel so and so i spent one
month in turkey then two months in georgia and the reason why i decided to relocate to armenia is just because georgia does not give residents permits to russians because like their policy is that well you can stay here
for the whole year and then you do a visa ran and so you don't need a residence pyramid so and i really really need that because i eventually want t go to europe that's my that's my dream and and then
so it was a tough choice because i could have stayed in georgia and yeah and work from there and make a lot of like many for georgia by georgian standards
like really really a lot but i decided that no i better go to armenia and in the future i move to europe so europe it is better even even despite that it involves relocation and
armenia but still like europe is use but anyway salaries are also
based on my research poland for example is not that expensive like warso the almost makes sense yet i
think i think well yeah i think poland isn't very very expensive cheek republic none is quite inexpensive my friend as she moved to burn about three years ago
yes and she chose pernod because it's cheaper than prag chichi think as far as late know
cherch republic is just croatia and i actually have a friend from the
netherlands and i am so so sad that now it's basically useless like i told you already that i am
basically a developer and they have never been a developer yes so you are a
stuff i think no i studied applied informatics at the university here in ranova and actually we had like we had subjects
like basics of programming i can you know a little as the theoretical and a very very primitive on level and only to sychar nelse says little jew script that works with not the back and
i camoscript that works on each timl in cs little beats not bite but h p but it's very very basic at very very low level actually as we started to make a pliant
informatics and we also had the departments of software engineering and a lot of lot of people who graduated from who studied software engineering work here in equal worked in an office a lot of software engineers and they they can really they can read
the cold but i can't and actually actually coding actually programming has always been a challenge for me even when i got prepared even when i prepared for the unified state exam and i didn't
i didn't do the task this vary in the unified states en there is a task i think in my time in my types it was the last one less the most difficult related to rate some code
but i never did it but anyway i know some basic anyway i decided i've never i will never be a programmer that's quite hard for me and actually if it in chromatics it's it's like system analysis business analysis
may distinct from may be a project manager that's okay
and actually i just prepared a lot for the university exam during the tenth and the eleventh forms i fasted i got good results like seventy
nine points for me that was really good and that's it and i've answer the first years at the university i didn't really understand what would what we would
become after graduation and also i studied the how university studied the translation courses like an additional programme and i received two
non diplomas well so i'm i'm a bachelor in a plate informatics and and i'm also a translator and when i took the final exam irina r national ovah of now it's bumped
oshis then it was ivan watches head of that office she was in the she was at that examined she invited me to an interview after that examine that's how i started my career
in at it started two weeks before the global locked down begin to twenty twenty all right one second one second i need to do one thing
so so i decided to stop the recording and reload it so to make sure that defile is saved and now is tricorn the
new file because maybe maybe there will be issues with abies later just to just be safe at least not to ever so yeah so you