i have chosen batumi instead of tbilisi because i thought it would be cheaper to rent an apartment and batumi
easy it's very easy to go to batumi from turkey well no like you still need
to to use the plane and it's not that much different it's not that different because you still flag fly
from eastanbul and turkey is huge in size steel so ye and so
i spent one month in turkey then two months in georgia and the reason why i decided to relocate
to armenia is just because georgia does not give residents permits to russians because like their policy is
that well you can stay here for the whole year and then you do a visa ran so you don't need a residence permit so and i really
really need that because i eventually want to go to europe that's my that's my dream and
and then so it was a tough choice because i could have stayed in georgia and
yah like work and work from there and make a lot of like mine for georgia
by georgian standards like really really a lot but i decided that no i better go to armenia and
in the future i move to europe so europe it is better even even despite that it involves
relocation and it involves losses in in terms of relative income because everything in europe is
more expensive than compare to georgia and armenia but still like europe is used but anyway salaries are also in
on my research poland for example is not that expensive like
warso the capital of poland is comparable to prewar moscow
as makes sense here i think i think you here oh well yeah i think her pollent isn't
real very expensive cherubino is quite inexpensive my friend she moved to
because it's cheaper than prague chia
as far as i know chieh republic is well maybe it's more expensive borland does not
that expensive anyway countries like germany and ethel yeah i know that like netherlands
netherlands is just crazy and i actually have a friend from the netherlands and i speak dutch at about that level
it's basically useless
like i told you already that i am basically a language nord and is so i actually i
really love foreign languages like human languages more than programming once that's why i have got a developer and i've never been a developer
m but can you actually code
stuff i think no i studied applied informatics at the university here in ranova
and actually we can be we heads like we had subjects like basics of programming i can know a little
as the theoretical and very very primitive on the level and only to cease sharp that ames says little
beats
not parent but p h p but it's very very weak very basic at very very life can
and a lot
of people who graduated from who studied software engineering work here in aquilmworked in a wonderful office
out of software engineers and they they can really they can really code but i can't and actually programming
has always been a challenge for me even when i got prepared even when i prepared for the
unified state exam and i didn't i didn't do the tasks
states en there is a task i think in my time in
my types it was the last one it is the most difficult related to write some code but i never did it but anyway i know
i've never been i will never be a programmer that's quite hard for me and actually
if wide in cosmetics it's it's like system analysis business analysis my be a project manager that's a
kate yes i went to
all this it shield because i didn't know what to do what to study after school and actually i
ones
i got good results like seventy nine points
for me that was really good and that it and i've answered the first years at the university i didn't really understand
what we would become after
graduation and also i studied there how university studied the translation courses like an additional program
and i received two two non diplomas
well i'm a bachelor in a flat informatics and and i'm also a translator and when i took
the final exam irina are national ovo head now its bumbaoffice then it was ivan aches
head of at otic she was in she was at that exam and she invited me
how i started my career in at
it started two weeks before the global locked down begin to twenty twenty
ah all right one second one second i need to do one thing
so so i decided to
stop the recording and reload it so to make sure that the file is saved and now is recording the new
file because maybe maybe there will be issues with abies later
so just to just be safe at least south no to everything in case ye so you