I HAVE CHOSEN BATOMI INSTEAD OF BELISY BECAUSE I
THOUGHT IT WOULD BE A
PER DOR ANT AN APARTMENT IN BATOMIA
I'M HERE SINCE IT'S SO EASIER
IT'S VERY EASY TO GO TO BATUMIPHONE TURKEY
AH HELEN WILLER WILL KNOW YOU LIKE
NTO TO USE
THAT
DIFFERENT BECAUSE YOU STILL FLYK FLY FROM EASTERN WALLE
TURKEYIS HUGE IN SIZE
SO I
SPENT ONE MONTH IN TURKEY THEN TWO
MONTHS I IN A GEORGIA AND THE
REASON WHY I DECIDED TO A
I JUST
BECAUSE GEORGE DOESN'T GIVE PRESIDENT PERMITZ TO RUSSIANS
NA BECAUSE IT'S LIKE THEYRE
POLICYIS THAT VALUE YOU CAN STAY HERE
FOR THE WHOLE YEAR AND THEN YOU'LL DO A VISERON AND SO YOU DON'T NEED A RESIDENCE
A
SO AND I REALLY REALLY NEED THAT BECAUSE I EVENTUALLY WANT
TO GO TO A EUROPE AH THAT'S MY THAT'S MOY DREAM
A AND THEN AM
SO I IT WAS A TOUGH
CHOICE BECAUSE I COULD HAVE STAYED IN A
WORKING AND WORK FROM THEIR END
ON A LOT
OF FER LIKE MINE IN FOR A GEORGIA
LIKE BY GEORGEON STANDARDS LIKE REALLY REALLY A LOT A BUT
I DECIDED THAT NO I BETTER
THO ID BETTER GO TO ARMENIA AND
IN THE FUTURE I LIKE MOVE TO EUROPE SO LIKE EUROPUS
IT IS BETTER EVEN EVEN DESPITE AH THAT
IT INVOLVES RELAXATION AND IT
IN THE WOLVES ARE LOTUS IN
AM IN TERMS OF A RELATIVE AND CAN BECAUSE EVERYTHING AND EUROPES
ARE MORE EXPENSIVE THAN
COMPARED TO GEORGA AND THE ARMENIA BUT STILL LIKE EUROPESENTA
NOR BUT ANNWITH CELERIES ARE ALSO
I AM THERE
LITTE IT WAS I AT
AND ALSO A BASED ON MY RESEARCH
POLAND FOR EXAMPLE IS NOT THAT EXPENSIVE ARIT
YABO LIKE A VOR
SO THE CAPITALS POLLEN
OF POLAND IS COMPARABLE TO PREVAR MOSCOW
O
ONLINK SO SKIP I THINK
CRUEL
NOBETO
I THINK YOUR POENT ISN'T TRO
THEY'RE EXPENSIVE
CERPUBLICAN
I KNOW I'S  QUITE AND EXPENSIVE MY FRIEND
AS HE MOVED TO BURNO
ABOUT THREE YEARS AGO YES AND TE
OR
IS A STUDENT THERE AND SHE CHOSE WERE
NOY BECAUSE IT'S CHEAPER THAN PROG
M
AND
KNOW
CHE REPUBLIC IS AA WELL MAYBE IT'S MOREO
IT'S MORE ESPENCIALY TE OWN PORLAND THAT NOT THAT
THAT EXPENSIVE ANYWAY OER COUNTRIS LIE
JOWENE A
LIKE MA AMATERONONSU NETER ONOS RUSTE CRAZY
AND I ACTUALLY HAVE A FRIEND FROM FROM THE NERALS AND
I SPEAK DUTCH
ARE ENTERED ABOUT INTO A LEVEL WA RET
AH YE AND I'M SO SO SAD THAT NOW IT'S BASICALLY USELESS
N LAKE I
LIKE I TOLD YOU ALREADY THAT IAM BISIC LANGUISH NORT AH
AND LAKO SA MY FIN
IRENELO
OR IN LANGUAGES LIKE HUMAN LANGUAGES MORE THAN PROGAIN
ONCE THAT'S WHY IHAVE NOT TO DEVELOP
AND I'VE NEVER BEEN A DEVELOPER
AH YES ALSO YOU ARE A YPEAM BUT A
CAN YOU ACTUALLY COLD STUFF
I THINK I THINK NO I STARTID O
O APPLIED IN FOMETICS
AT THE UNIVERSITY HERE IN RUNWOF
AND ACTUALLY WE HAD SAWIT WE HAD
BASICS OF PROGRAMMI
I CAN
NOW A LITTLE IT
IS THE THEORETIC ONDIB AND OLY
SEY SHARP HASTY MILSI SAYS
E LITTLE JEALOUS CREAPTO THAT FORETHE NIGHT WORK
SWET NOT THE BECCONDLY
JUST KET THE TOKON EACH DEMOLENCEASSASS
LITTLE BET SONG
NOT FRIGHTENED BUT IT'S
A VERY VERY LIK PAIR OF ERY BASICS AT VERY VERY LOW LEVEL
NO AT SWEETNESS
MUINGAN AND AXUALLY
VERE STUDEDLYAPL
INPORMATICS AND WE ALSO HAD THE DEPARTMENT
OF
BUT OF PEOPLE WHO GRADIATED FROMR WHO STUDIED SOFT MAR ENGINEERING FOR
INVICUA
IINVOKED IN THE WONDERFUL OFFICE A WAT OF A SOFT VERY INGENIOUS
AND THEY
THEY CANN REALLY THEY CAN RELLY COD BUT I CAN'T INTECTION
SHAL ACORDING THAT MY BECLY PROGRAMI HAS
ALWAYS BEEN A CHALLENGE FOR ME YOUWEO GRAN
GOD ILL NOT PREPARED UN EVEN WHEN I PREPARED
FOR THE UNIFIED STATE EXAM
WAS AND
MADITE TO GO
I DIDDIN'T DO THE TASKOR THE
THES  THIS
OF VERY
IN THE UNIVERSE ITSENT THERE IS A TASK OR I THINK
INVETED IN MITED IT WAS THE LAST PLAN
IT AS THE MOST DIFFICULT RELATED
T ONCOLD
BUT I NEVER NEVER DID IT BUT ANYWAY I KNOW SOME BASICS
IN ANY WAY
I DECIDED I'VE NEVER BEEN I WILL NEVER BE A BROGER MY
THIS
WENT OUT FOR ME ENDACTUALLY
NE VOID AND POMATICI SLIGHT
O THEN MY ERLY SLIP SYSTEM ANALYSIS BUSINESS ANAL
S MIGHT BE TIN INKING O PROJECT MANAGE WITHOUT
A BETE
AND ACTUALLY
AIN
O
I WENT TO AL
MIS T COLDER BECAUSE I
DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO DO OR TO STUDY HELTY SCHOOL
AND ACTUALLY I O
N
ADJUSTED OR PREPARED A LOT FOR THE TENTH AND
THE ELEVEN
YOS
AS TO TAKE
I GOT
THE PUNTO RESULTS
SEVENTEEN
BIN
BOINS
FOR ME THIS WAS REALLY GOOD
AND HAD THE SEAT AND DAVE ANSWER FIRST
HEAS AT THE UNIVERSITY I DIDN'T REALLY UNDERSTAND
WAT
WIN
WHAT ASTO PUT MISTAD INTO THE
WAT ME
AO
WHAT WOULD BEBE WHAT WE WOULD BECOME AFTER GRADUATION
AND ALSO I STARTED THERE AT THE AWINSTESAT
OF COURSE IS LIKE AN ADDITIONAL PROGRAMM
ROD INTO
ESE
DO
BOON
AT TALL
NANTICONAS
BTIT WASNT WELL I HIM SO  MOER I'M A BACHELOR IN
THE PLAD AN PORETICS AND I ALSM AND WHEN
I
THE FINDAING ER
ART
ERENA HEINISH ME OVER HEAD OF
NOW WITH BUMPER BE OFF HIS
SHE WAS SO
IN THEE
ANDO
SHE WAS AT THAT EXAMINE SHE INVITED ME
AN INTERVIEW
AFTER IT'S EXAMINED THIS WAY
AND THAT'S HOW I STARTED  MY CAREN IN AT IT WAS
INSTARTED TWO WEEKS BEFORE THEE
BORB ON DOUT
THEY CAN
BECKAN TRENTE TRENTY
AH LL RIGHT
ON WHAT ONE THING
I
SOM
SO I DECIDED TO
STOP THE RECORTING AND RELOAD IT SO TO MAKE SURE
THAT THE FILE IS SAVED
I AM NO SECORION THEY NEW OF
FILE BECAUSE O
LIKE MAYBE WE KAN MAYBE THERE WILL BE
ISSUES WITH A OBEOS A LATER SOGH TO DO JUST TO JUST
BE SAFE IE
YOUE ATLEST SORTIN NOT TO LOSE EVERYTHING
AN CASE      YET SO YOU