chosen batumi instead of tbilisi because i thought it would be cheaper to rent an apartment than bat
it's easier it's very easy to go to betome from turkey helen well like you
still fly
from eastern bullet turkeys huge are in size so
i spent one month in turkey then two months in georgia and the reason why i decided to
relocate to armenia it is just because georgia doesn't give residence permits to russians because their
policy is that while you can stay here for the whole year and then you'll do a wiser and and so you don't need that
because i eventually want to go to europe that's my small dream
and it it was a tough choice because i could have stayed
in georgia and workwork from there and make a lot of like money
id better better go
to armenia and the future like move to europe so like europe it is better even
despite that it involves relocation and it involves are loses in in form of a
relative and can be caserta in europe are also
based on my research poland for example
is not that expensive like worse the capital of sentis comparable to
pre-war mose i think i think
isn't very very expensive chichi republic is quite an expensive
my friend she moved to burn about three years ago
and she chose berno because it's cheaper than prag
as far as i know cherubim be
is more expensive than or expensive anyway countries like german
the crazy and i actually have a friend from i speak
dutch at about eight level i'm so sad that now
it's basically languish nor
and i actually i really love foreign languages like human languages more than programming once
that's what i have not to develop and i've never been a developer yes so you
actually cold stuff i think no i studied
to apply informatics at the university here in vanward and actually can we we had subjects
like basics of programming i can know a little at the theoretic at a very very primitive one level
see see sharpers little gels network not the
back and as cut that works on ten olence assassin little beat not fatoutbut it's a very very like farmer
basic at very very low level is very lignactually and we
also had the department of software engineering and a lot of lot of people who graduated from who
studied software engineers they
they really they can rarely code but actually actually actually programming has always been a challenge for
the unified state exam
i didn't i didn't do the tasks the these they are
into the most difficult
some basics anyway
i decided i never i will never be a programmer this hard for me and actually it incomaticsits like
the it system analysis in project mall
i went to i went to own a shield because i
didn't know what to do or to study house school and actually
to prepare a lot for the university examine during the tenth and eleventh once a
good results like seventy nine points that was really good
and i answer first years at the university i didn't understand what we
started there what would what we would become after graduation
and also i perceived
two uniforms
bachanalians and i and i'm also a translator and when i took the final
exil a irina national yo head of now papal office and was one office head off
at office she was in the s was at that exam and she invited me
after that examine that's why how started my career in it it was started
two weeks before the globe worked out in ten twenty
one second one second i need to do one thing ah
so i decided to
stop the recording and reloaded so to make sure that the file is saved and now its recording the new
file because maybe maybe there will be issues with obese later
so to just to just be safe easy